[ Broots ]
RAINES'S ESTRANGED WIFE ESCAPED
THAT MENTAL HOSPITAL...
JUST TO TELL YOU ABOUT
YOUR MOTHER AND MIRAGE? WHY?
[ Miss Parker ]
EDNA RAINES SAID MIRAGE
WAS MY MOTHER'S WORK.
WORK I'M SUPPOSED TO FINISH.
WELL, NO ONE SEEMS TO REMEMBER
ANY CENTRE PROJECT BY THAT NAME.
COULD IT BE
ONE OF HER DELUSIONS?
YOU DIDN'T SEE HER EYES.
SYD, IN THAT MOMENT,
SHE WAS AS SANE AS YOU AND I.
[ Scoffs ]
BROOTS, YOU BEEN
DOWNLOADING PORN AGAIN?
MY E-MAIL SERVER
IS WHACKED.
[ Sighs ]
SOMEONE AROUND HERE HAS HEARD
OF MIRAGE. YOU CAN BET ON IT.
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
I'M HERE TO COLLECT
BURN BAGS FOR INCINERATION.
I... KNEW HER.
EXCUSE ME?
CATHERINE.
SHE WAS
A SPECIAL PERSON.
YOU KNEW MY MOTHER?
AND SHE ALWAYS SEEMED LIKE
A BRIGHT AND SHINING SPIRIT...
EVEN IN THE DARKEST HOURS.
SORRY FOR THE INTERRUPTION.
MAYBE WE COULD...
TALK AGAIN.
IF YOU-- IF YOU
WOULDN'T MIND, MR., UM--
NAME'S LEONARD.
AND IT WOULD BE MY PLEASURE.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
EVERYTHING BURNS.
MISS PARKER'LL WANT TO SEE THIS.
I SAID EVERYTHING BURNS.
MISS PARKER MUST SEE THIS.
BIG MISTAKE, YOU DUMB--
[ Grunts ]
[ Gun Cocking ]
I HAVE TO TALK TO MISS PARKER.
[ Woman ]
DETAILS ARE SKETCHY, BUT AFTER
THE ROBBERY, THE FIVE SUSPECTS,
POSING AS JANITORIAL STAFF,
FLED MAGNA TECHNOLOGIES
IN A BROWN VAN.
A HAZMAT TEAM HAS BEEN
DISPATCHED, AND THE WAREHOUSE
DISTRICT HAS BEEN QUARANTINED.
WE'LL KEEP YOU UPDATED
AS THE STORY UNFOLDS.
REPORTING LIVE FROM
THE WAREHOUSE DISTRICT,
NOW BACK TO YOU IN THE STUDIO.
[ Man Screaming ]
LET ME OUTTA HERE! LET ME OUT!
[ People Coughing ]
MY THROAT IS ON FIRE.
I CAN'T BREATHE.
SOMETHING IS VERY WRONG HERE.
OH, IT'S THIS.
IT'S WHAT WE STOLE.
[ Hissing ]
[ Coughing Continues ]
OH, MY GOD.
HEY, SCIENCE GUY.
YOU'RE MAKING ME NERVOUS.
WHAT IS IT?
[ Sirens Wail ]
SOMAN NERVE GAS.
- THAT STUFF COULD KILL US,
COULDN'T IT?
- IT ALREADY IS.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN, IS?
- IS. IS!
BARRING SOME MIRACLE,
WE'RE ALL GOING TO BE DEAD
IN LESS THAN SIX HOURS.
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
- [ Miss Parker ] HE DEFENDS
THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
- [ Jarod ] LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
- [ Broots ] MISS PARKER.
- GOOD NIGHT, BROOTS.
THAT GUY WENT POSTAL
DOWN IN SL 26.
STARTED SHOOTING UP THE PLACE.
- THAT GUY?
- LEONARD, THE CLERK!
THE BURN BAG GUY
THAT KNEW YOUR MOTHER!
[ Broots ]
GOD.
WE TRIED TO
NEGOTIATE WITH HIM.
HE WASN'T INTERESTED.
SO YOU TRADED THE OLIVE
BRANCH FOR AN UZI.
IS THAT YOUR CHRISTIAN WAY,
RAINES?
HE WAS ARMED AND OUT OF CONTROL.
HE TRIED TO KILL ONE OF MY MEN.
THERE MUST HAVE BEEN
ANOTHER WAY.
I WILL NOT TOLERATE UNSTABLE
BEHAVIOR FROM CENTRE EMPLOYEES.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS
A JOB REQUIREMENT.
BROOTS.
I WANT THE SURVEILLANCE
FOOTAGE OF WHAT JUST
HAPPENED HERE. QUICK.
[ Man ]
AIN'T BAD ENOUGH THERE'S COPS
SEARCHIN' FOR US EVERYWHERE.
NOW YOU'RE TELLIN' US
WE GOT SIX HOURS TO LIVE?
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU TO BE
PRONOUNCING US DEAD ON ARRIVAL?
I DON'T HAVE TO, MR. JOB.
YOU CAN ALREADY FEEL IT,
CAN'T YOU?
YOU ALL CAN.
IT'S ON YOUR SKIN.
IT'S IN YOUR LUNGS.
AND IT ONLY GETS WORSE.
[ Coughing ]
ELIJAH NEVER SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT STEALING NERVE GAS.
POINDEXTER HERE'S PROBABLY
TALKING OUT HIS ASS.
I MEAN, US, WE KNOW
EACH OTHER, RIGHT? BUT HIM?
WHO THE HELL IS HE?
FOR ALL WE KNOW, HE'S SOME
OUT OF WORK PHARMACIST.
I THINK WE SHOULD CALL ELIJAH.
EVE'S RIGHT. WE WERE SUPPOSED TO
STEAL COMPUTER CHIPS.
YEAH, NOT TO MENTION
100,000 EACH FOR OUR EFFORTS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I SAY WE CALL HIM.
ELIJAH SAID THE TARGET WAS
A BOX. THAT'S ALL HE SAID.
WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE?
HE OWES US ANYWAY, RIGHT?
SCREW IT.
I'M GONNA CALL ELIJAH.
NO. ELIJAH CALLS US!
ALWAYS HAS, HE ALWAYS WILL!
[ Eve ] I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I'M NOT JUST GONNA SIT HERE
AND WAIT TO DIE.
THERE MUST BE SOMETHING
WE CAN DO ABOUT THIS SOMAN GAS.
IT AFFECTS THE CHEMICAL
STRUCTURE OF THE BRAIN.
IT'S ONLY A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE OUR PARANOIA
TURNS INTO PSYCHOSIS.
- WAIT. WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WE ALL GO CRAZY?
- EXACTLY.
IT BREAKS DOWN OUR TISSUES.
FIRST WE'LL FEEL NAUSEOUS,
THEN THE TREMORS,
AND THEN, OUR INTERNAL ORGANS
WILL LIQUEFY.
OUR INSIDES WILL LOOK SOMETHING
LIKE, WELL, SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
THEN YOUR NOSE WILL START TO
BLEED, AND IT JUST WON'T--
NO, STOP. OKAY? I JUST--
MAKE HIM STOP.
ALL RIGHT, I CAN'T--
[ Gags, Coughs ]
LOOK. LOOK.
IT'S-IT'S ELIJAH'S LAPTOP.
HE'S GONNA HELP US.
[ Eve ]
AND WHAT?
WE WAIT FOR HIS CALL AND-AND
THEN SURF THE WEB, MR. JOB?
I HEAR BLEEDOUT.COM HAS
SOME REAL INTERESTING GRAPHICS.
YOU'RE REALLY TURNING INTO
ONE SARCASTIC BITCH,
YOU KNOW THAT?
OOH, YOU REALLY DO
HAVE ISSUES WITH WOMEN.
WHAT WAS IT?
TRAUMA WITH TRAINING PANTS?
OR DID MOMMY HAVE STOLI
WITH HER CORNFLAKES
EVERY MORNING?
SHUT UP!
OR WHAT?
YOU WANT TO SMACK ME AROUND
A LITTLE, HMM?
OKAY. THAT'S ENOUGH.
AS SICK AS WE'RE GOING TO GET,
WE NEED TO STICK TOGETHER.
[ Hard Typing ]
THIS IS ELIJAH'S LAPTOP.
THE QUESTION IS WHY HASN'T
HE TRIED TO CONTACT US?
HE USED US
AS GUINEA PIGS IS WHY.
LOOK. ARE WE REALLY GONNA--
ARE WE GONNA DIE?
NO, BROTHER.
WE'RE NOT GONNA DIE.
I PROMISE YOU THAT, OKAY?
I'M GONNA TAKE CARE OF YOU.
DON'T I ALWAYS TAKE CARE OF YOU?
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU.
ME AND MY BROTHER, WE'RE GETTIN'
THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
- AND EXACTLY WHERE
DO YOU THINK YOU'RE GOING?
- TO A HOSPITAL.
USE YOUR BRAINS, MR. CAIN.
WHAT'S LEFT OF THEM.
THE WAY THE BLACK-AND-WHITE'S
ARE CIRCLING AROUND OUTSIDE,
YOU AND YOUR BROTHER
WON'T GET A BLOCK
BEFORE THEY PICK YOU UP.
ABRAHAM'S RIGHT. OUR BEST CHANCE
IS IF WE STICK TOGETHER AND
WAIT FOR ELIJAH TO CONTACT US.
ALL RIGHT.
BUT IF THINGS GET OUT OF HAND,
THE LAST RATIONAL THOUGHT I'M
GONNA HAVE IS PUTTING A .38 SLUG
IN THE BACK OF YOUR HEAD.
IF THIS GETS OUT OF HAND,
I WILL CONSIDER THAT A FAVOR.
[ Coughing ]
[ Job ]
HEY, I'M GETTIN' SOMETHIN'.
[ Woman ]
THE ROBBERY OCCURRED IN DALLAS'S
INDUSTRIAL DISTRICT.
NOW, FOR UNKNOWN REASONS,
THE AREA'S BEEN CORDONED OFF.
AND AN EMERGENCY
EVACUATION ORDER HAS GONE OUT...
TO CLEAR THE AREA
OF ALL NONEMERGENCY PERSONNEL.
EVACUATION. COPS ALREADY
KNOW WHAT WE STOLE.
IF THEY KNOW, THEN ELIJAH KNOWS.
YEAH, WELL, ELIJAH'S GONNA
WANT HIS STUFF, RIGHT?
SO HE'S GONNA COME DOWN AND-AND
GET US OUT OF HERE, RIGHT?
RIGHT. MAYBE HE'LL SEND A FLOCK
OF FLYING MONKEYS, MORON.
HEY, LEAVE HIM ALONE. NOW.
[ Job ]
EASE UP, TARZAN.
YOU KNOW, I KNEW
I SHOULD HAVE CUT AND RUN...
WHEN I REALIZED
YOU THOUGHT GROUNDHOG DAY
WAS A NATIONAL HOLIDAY.
I'M NOT SAYING
IT'S A MAJOR HOLIDAY.
I'M JUST SAYING
IT'S RIGHT UP THERE
WITH, UH, SECRETARY'S DAY.
SECRETARY'S DAY ISN'T
A NATIONAL HOLIDAY EITHER, JOB.
AND LIKE YOU'VE EVER
HAD A SECRETARY ANYWAY.
I HAD A SECRETARY ONCE.
AND THEN LUNCH WAS OVER,
WE PUT OUR CLOTHES BACK ON.
SHE WENT BACK TO HER TYPING.
[ Laughs ]
EH, SPEAKIN' OF SECRETARIES,
HOTSHOT, WHAT ARE YOU,
SOME KIND OF A ENTRY EXPERT?
THE NAME MR. ELIJAH
GAVE ME IS MR. ABRAHAM.
AND, YES, BREAKING AND ENTRY
IS ONE OF MY SPECIALTIES.
I'LL BET YOU ROBBED A GIRL
OF HER VIRGINITY ONCE,
WHICH I FIND IMPRESSIVE.
- WELL, YOU SHOULD.
SHE WAS YOUR SISTER.
- AHH! [ Laughing ]
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
LAUGHIN' AT, HALF-WIT?
YOUR MAMA IS YOUR SISTER.
- HEY.
- HOW DID YOU PEOPLE PULL OFF
20 SCORES IN THREE YEARS?
I'LL TELL YOU HOW. WE DON'T KNOW
A DAMN THING ABOUT EACH OTHER.
RULE NUMBER ONE
IN THE BOOK OF MR. ELIJAH.
[ Electronic Ringing ]
[ Electronic Female Voice ]
YOU HAVE A VIDEO PHONE CALL.
GOOD MORNING, CAMPERS.
I ASSUME YOU'VE ALL MET AND
BONDED WITH MR. ABRAHAM HERE.
HE'S A STRONG ADDITION
TO OUR TEAM.
HE'S AN EXPERT IN MANY AREAS,
MOSTLY THE SCIENCES.
-WHAT? LIKE WE'RE MOPES
OR SOMETHING?
-GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN TOO, JOB.
I GOTTA AGREE WITH JOB
ON THIS ONE. WE'VE DONE
FINE ON OUR OWN, MR. E.
HAVE WE?
I'M PUTTING MR. ABRAHAM
IN CHARGE OF THIS ONE.
WHAT?
I GOTTA TAKE ORDERS
FROM SCIENCE GUY HERE?
YOU KNOW, WE MADE
A LOT OF SCRATCH FOR YOU
IN THE PAST FEW YEARS, PAL.
I DON'T HAVE TO SIT HERE
AND TAKE THIS CRAP.
WELL, THEN I GUESS
THE OTHERS WILL HAVE TO SPLIT UP
YOUR HUNDRED THOUSAND.
WE GET A HUNDRED GRAND EACH?
[ Elijah ]
IT'S BIG.
BUT LET'S SEE
IF WE CAN DO THIS ONE
WITHOUT ANY BLOOD ON IT. DEAL?
WHAT DEAL DOESN'T
HAVE BLOOD ON IT?
[ Coughing ]
ISN'T THIS CUTE?
[ Jarod ]
WHAT IS IT?
BRITTANY TATE?
WHO'S BRITTANY TATE?
LAST JOB WE DID,
THREE MONTHS AGO,
A KID WAS MURDERED.
[ Job Coughing ]
"BRITTANY TATE, AGE NINE,
WAS SMOTHERED TO DEATH...
"DURING A ROBBERY
AT A WESTBROOK ESTATE.
"ONLY EVIDENCE FOUND AT
THE SCENE WAS A PILLOW
USED IN THE SUFFOCATION,
A SPILLED BOTTLE OF PERFUME
AND A BROKEN MUSIC BOX."
WELL, I GUESS THAT'S WHAT
ELIJAH MEANT WHEN HE SAID,
"ONE WITHOUT BLOOD."
WHICH ONE OF YOU GENIUSES
DID HER?
[ Job ]
NONE OF US KNOWS.
NOBODY'S TALKIN'.
MR. CAIN'S
GONE STRANGELY SILENT.
- SO?
- SO, YOU KILLED
THAT LITTLE GIRL.
[ Chortles ]
LADY, YOUR BRAIN'S ALREADY
BEGINNING TO MELT.
WHAT DIFFERENCE
DOES IT MAKE WHO DID IT?
IT'S DONE.
[ Electronic Ringing ]
[ Eve Coughing ]
YOU HAVE A VIDEO PHONE CALL.
TOUGH EVENING, EH?
[ Job ] TOUGH?
WE'VE ALL BEEN EXPOSED
TO NERVE GAS!
WHICH MEANS YOU'VE ACCOMPLISHED
YOUR MISSION. WELL DONE.
YOU SET US UP?
YOU KNEW WHAT WE
WERE STEALING WAS DEADLY!
WOULD YOU HAVE TAKEN
THE ASSIGNMENT OTHERWISE?
ASSIGNMENT?
WE'RE DYING IN HERE!
ONE OF THE CANISTERS LEAKED.
WE'VE ALL BEEN EXPOSED
TO THE GAS.
I REALIZED THAT THAT
MIGHT BE A POSSIBILITY.
CHECK THE DISPATCHER'S OFFICE.
I'VE LEFT MATERIALS THERE
FOR YOU TO WORK
A LITTLE CHEMISTRY, ABRAHAM.
NOW, I'M SENDING
A COUPLE OF MY MEN OVER
TO PICK UP THE CANISTERS.
THEY SHOULD BE AT YOUR LOCATION
WITHIN THE NEXT FEW HOURS.
AND JUST KNOW THE CONTINGENCY
PLANS ARE BEING IMPLEMENTED.
FORGET ABOUT CONTINGENCY.
WHAT ABOUT CURRENCY?
PATIENCE, JOB. PATIENCE.
MY MEN ARE ON THE WAY.
[ Job ] NO, NO, WAIT.
WAIT. DAMN IT!
OH, GOD.
HE'S-HE'S LEAVIN' US
HERE TO DIE.
SHUT HIM UP, OR I WILL.
[ Coughing ]
ELIJAH WILL NOT LEAVE US
HIGH AND DRY, OKAY?
WHAT'S THIS STUFF?
ELIJAH LEFT ME EVERYTHING
I MIGHT NEED TO
CREATE AN ANTIDOTE.
- YOU THINK YOU CAN SAVE US?
- NOW DON'T YOU WISH
YOU'D BEEN NICER TO ME?
HEY, HOW LONG?
FIVE HOURS. MAYBE LESS.
HOW-HOW DO WE KNOW
THAT YOU CAN DO THIS?
I WAS AN ARMY MEDIC IN
DESERT STORM. I KNOW A FEW
THINGS ABOUT CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
HEY, SCREW THIS.
THIS GUY COULD BE A WACKO
FOR ALL WE KNOW.
I AGREE WITH CAIN.
I'M GONNA TAKE MY CHANCES
WITH THE HOSPITAL.
YOU WON'T MAKE IT.
AND EVEN IF YOU DID, THEY WON'T
HAVE THE ANTIDOTE YOU NEED.
YOU'VE GOT ALL THE ANSWERS,
DON'T YOU?
I'M OUTTA HERE.
[ Metal Clicks ]
SOMEONE'S COMING.
[ Job ]
COPS.
[ Radio Chatter ]
HEY, COME ON.
IT'S EMPTY. LET'S KEEP MOVING.
[ Man On Radio ]
THIRTEEN, SERGEANT,
ONE AND CENTRAL.
- [ Door Closes ]
- THEY'RE GONE. WE'RE CLEAR.
[ Light Coughing ]
WE HAVE TO DO THIS
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
[ No Audio ]
- LEONARD DIDN'T KILL ANYONE.
- GOD, THEY JUST
MOWED THEM DOWN.
REWIND, BROOTS.
BEFORE THEY GET SHOT.
WHO'S HE CALLING?
CAN'T TELL.
THE IMAGE IS TOO SMALL.
MAYBE IF I ENHANCE THE VIDEO,
ISOLATE HIS HANDS
AND MATCH THE MOTION.
YOU CAN DO THAT?
WELL, YEAH.
IT WOULD TAKE ABOUT AN HOUR.
[ Sighs ]
CLOCK'S TICKING.
♪♪ [ Piano ]
[ Abel ]
SONG REMINDS ME
OF WHEN MOM USED TO SING IT.
[ Eve Coughs ]
♪♪ [ Resumes ]
[ Static Hissing ]
SIGNAL'S COMIN' BACK.
THE LATEST REPORT IS THAT
THE SECURITY GUARD,
A FATHER OF SIX,
WAS FOUND NEARLY STRANGLED
TO DEATH IN THE ROBBERY AT
MAGNA TECHNOLOGIES, LIMITED.
HIS CONDITION
IS CONSIDERED TO BE
LIFE-THREATENING.
POLICE ARE STILL COMBING
THE AREA FOR THE SUSPECTS.
WHO DID IT?
WHICH ONE OF YOU IDIOTS
STRANGLED THE GUARD?
-WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE?
-IT MIGHT MAKE A BIG DIFFERENCE,
IF WE SURVIVE.
THE QUESTION IS,
WHICH ONE OF YOU
HAS THE ITCHY TRIGGER FINGER?
♪♪ [ Piano Continues ]
[ Coughing ]
TELL ME SOMETHING. WHAT DOES
ELIJAH SEE IN THAT ONE?
IT'S LIKE A HORSE RACE ENTRY.
YOU WANT CAIN, YOU GET ABEL.
[ Coughing Hard ]
I GOTTA GET OUTTA HERE.
I GOTTA GET OUT. I GOTTA--
HEY, CALM DOWN.
NO, I GOTTA GET OUTTA HERE.
CALM DOWN.
CALM DOWN. CALM DOWN.
PLEASE!
YOU KNOW SOMETHING? I THOUGHT
I WAS A REALLY GOOD JUDGE
OF PEOPLE. GUESS I WAS WRONG.
WHAT'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
THOUGHT I WAS WORKING
WITH PROFESSIONALS.
YOU SNUFF OUT A LITTLE GIRL.
NOW A RENT-A-COP.
DID YOU DO IT?
WHAT ABOUT YOU, MR. JOB?
[ Laughs ]
YEAH, HE'S GOT THE GUTS.
OH, YEAH.
KILLIN' A LITTLE GIRL,
THAT TAKES A LOT OF GUTS.
FACE IT, YOU KNOW.
IT COULD'VE BEEN
ANY ONE OF US.
SPEAK FOR YOURSELF.
LOOK, IT WASN'T ME.
WELL, ONE GUILTY,
ALL GUILTY.
I'LL TELL YOU ONE THING.
MR. SPARKY AND HIS
2,200 BOLTS OF DEATH,
HE DOESN'T MUCH CARE.
WHAT ABOUT YOU, HUH?
YEAH?
YOU COULD'VE POPPED THAT GUARD
JUST AS EASY AS ANY ONE OF US.
YEAH. WE ALL KNOW EACH OTHER.
WE'VE BEEN DOING THIS A WHILE.
YOU? WE DON'T EVEN KNOW YOU.
NO. YOU DON'T.
JOB WILL ACCESS
THE MAIN SECURITY PANEL AND
BREAK THE VARIOUS DOOR CODES,
AND CONTROL PANELS
TO THE SECURITY CAMERAS.
EVE, CAIN AND I WILL TAKE
THE UPPER FLOOR,
WITH EVE MANNING
THE INFRARED THERMAL SENSOR,
AND ME SECURING THE TARGET.
YOU SURE THE TARGET'S
ON THE UPPER FLOOR?
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE.
WHAT I DO KNOW IS THAT
IT'S KEPT IN COLD STORAGE.
THAT'S WHERE THE INFRARED
THERMAL GRID COMES IN.
- WHAT ABOUT HIM?
- WE WALK IN PAST
THE SECURITY GUARD.
THE JANITOR UNIFORMS
ARE ALREADY SET.
[ Chuckles ]
JANITOR?
HEY, A GUY LIKE ME IS
GONNA BE HARD-PRESSED
TO PASS FOR A BUCKET JOCKEY.
YOU HAVE A BETTER IDEA,
MR. JOB?
YEAH. I DO.
I, FOR ONE, WANT TO KNOW
WHO THE HELL YOU ARE,
MR. PEABODY.
YOU KNOW ELIJAH'S RULE.
TOTAL ANONYMITY. NO NAMES,
NO PASTS, NOTHING.
- I ALREADY BROKE THAT RULE.
- WHAT? WHAT ARE YOU
TALKIN' ABOUT?
I SWIPED YOUR GLASS FROM
THE COFFEE SHOP LAST WEEK. I HAD
A FRIEND OF MINE RUN THE PRINTS.
THERE AIN'T SQUAT
ON YOU OUT THERE.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
I MEAN, HELL, EVERY DECENT
CRIMINAL I KNOW HAS GOT
SOME KIND OF SHEET.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU NEVER
BROKE THE LAW BEFORE?
I BROKE PLENTY.
I AM JUST TOO DAMN SMART,
TOO DAMN GOOD...
AND LIKE MY FREEDOM
TOO DAMN MUCH
TO EVER GET CAUGHT.
BUT, YOU, MR. JOB,
ON THE OTHER HAND--
[ Chuckles ]
WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
WELL, LET'S JUST SAY THAT
I RAN A LITTLE FINGERPRINT CHECK
ON YOU AS WELL.
DO YOU MIND TELLING ME
EXACTLY WHAT DETERMINES
A LEWD ACT... AT A KENNEL?
[ Coughing ]
HEY, SIMPLE SIMON, FINI.
WHY IS, UH, THIS GUY SO MUCH
WORSE THAN THE REST OF US?
EACH ONE OF US IS DIFFERENT.
[ Sighs ]
WE'LL ALL UNRAVEL
AT OUR OWN GENETIC PACE.
OH. WELL, HE'S DEFINITELY
BRINGING UP THE REAR.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, MR. ABEL
AND HIS FIVE-PIECE CONCERTO.
WELL, SIX,
IF YOU COUNT THE GREEN BEAN.
[ Grunts ]
LEAVE HIM ALONE.
[ Coughing ]
I'M SO SORRY. MAMA'S
GONNA BE SO MAD AT ME.
COME ON!
I GOTTA CLEAN THIS UP.
- DON'T DO THAT!
- I GOTTA CLEAN THIS UP.
COME ON. GET OUTTA THERE.
MOM'S DEAD!
YOU IDIOT! YOU STUPID IDIOT!
SHE'S DEAD!
HAS BEEN FOR 10 YEARS!
WAKE UP!
I'M GONNA KILL THE NEXT PERSON
WHO SAYS A WORD.
HOW'S IT COMING ALREADY, HUH?
- I'M WORKIN' ON IT.
- YEAH? WELL, HURRY.
YOU SHOULD SIT DOWN. IT WILL
SLOW THE EFFECTS OF THE TOXIN.
[ Coughing, Gasping ]
LOOK, I, UH--
I DIDN'T
GIVE YOU MY BLOOD BEFORE
BECAUSE I WAS WORRIED.
ABOUT WHAT?
I'M PREGNANT.
FOUR MONTHS.
DO THEY KNOW?
YEAH, SURE.
THEY'D GIVE ME
A PERFECT LITTLE BABY SHOWER,
DON'T YOU THINK?
SO WHAT'S THIS GAS
GONNA DO TO MY BABY?
AIRBORNES-- THEY CAN'T PASS
THROUGH A PLACENTA.
ACTUALLY, YOUR BABY'S
SAFER THAN YOU ARE.
OKAY.
Y-YOU CAN TAKE MY BLOOD.
AS-AS LONG AS IT'S SAFE
FOR THE BABY.
I PROMISE.
GOT IT?
GOT IT.
BUT YOU'RE NOT GONNA LIKE IT.
HE'S DIALING 2725.
[ Miss Parker ]
MY EXTENSION.
MY GOD.
[ Beeps, Rewinds ]
MISS PARKER, THIS IS LEONARD.
I SAW SOMETHING I PROBABLY
SHOULDN'T HAVE.
SOMETHING MEANT TO BE
BURNED. MEMO B437.
IT'S SOMETHING ABOUT
AN E-MAIL FILE INTERCEPTED
FROM YOUR COMPUTER.
MISS PARKER,
YOU SHOULD SEE THIS.
[ Gunfire ]
[ Leonard Grunts ]
SOMEONE BROKE
INTO YOUR COMPUTER. THAT'S WHY
YOUR E-MAIL WASN'T WORKING.
DOESN'T THE CENTRE'S
SYSTEM KEEP, UH,
DUPLICATES OF-OF
ALL INCOMING
AND OUTGOING E-MAILS?
YEAH, IN THE FILE
ALLOCATION DUMP. NONE OF US
HAVE CLEARANCE THERE.
GET ME THAT E-MAIL, BROOTS.
OR SOMEONE MIGHT FIND
ALL OF US IN THE DUMP.
NOW I'M GONNA DIE
'CAUSE OF MARK BEYER'S BIKE.
COME AGAIN.
FIRST THING I EVER STOLE.
YOU KNOW, IT HAD
THIS SPEED SHIFTER
AND THIS BANANA SEAT.
IT WAS THE MOST BEAUTIFUL THING
I EVER SAW.
IT WAS ALMOST WORTH THE COPS
CHASING ME JUST SO I COULD RIDE
THAT THING DOWN ARLINGTON HILL.
WHERE DID ELIJAH
RECRUIT THESE TWO?
THE BOY SCOUTS?
HEY, LOOK AT THIS.
THAT BRITTANY GIRL,
HER BODY...
WAS FOUND STUFFED IN A TOY CHEST
JUST LIKE THIS, WASN'T IT?
WHAT THE HELL
IS GOING ON?
I MEAN, THE PAPER IS ONE THING,
BUT THIS? THIS IS ELIJAH!
- HE'S MESSING WITH OUR MINDS!
- WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE?
WE NEED TO KEEP OUR MINDS IN
THE HERE AND THE NOW. WHO CARES
WHAT HAPPENED MONTHS AGO?
I AGREE! THE HERE AND NOW!
LIKE-LIKE HOW I
WANT MY HUNDRED GRAND.
HERE AND NOW.
WHERE'S THE PAY? HUH?
WHERE?
WE DID THE JOB!
WE DID THE DAMN JOB!
[ Beeping ]
- [ Beeps ]
- THERE WE GO, BOYS AND GIRLS.
READY TO LOOP SIGNAL
ON SECURITY CAMERA ONE.
[ Beeps ]
CLEAR.
GO.
SECURITY DOOR CODE
IS 88656.
[ Beeping ]
YOU'RE CLEAR.
[ Eve ]
I HAVE INFRARED READINGS.
I'M GETTING EXTREME
TEMPERATURE DROP IN ROOM 2108.
THAT ONE.
SECURITY CAMERA--
CLEAR. SECURITY DOOR CODE
IS 61684.
YOU'RE IN THE CLEAN ROOM.
THE COLD ROOM
CHAMBER DOOR CODE IS...
202018.
[ Beeping ]
[ Bang ]
- NEXT TIME, KNOCK.
- YOUR LIMO AWAITS.
JOB, ARE WE CLEAR?
JOB, ARE WE CLEAR
TO COME OUT? JOB?
- [ Jarod ] COME ON.
- WAIT. JOB, ARE WE CLEAR?
THE HELL WITH IT! COME ON!
THERE'S NO GUARD.
WHERE'S THE GUARD?
MY COMMUNICATION PIECES
SHORTED OUT. SORRY.
DON'T YOU EVER LEAVE ME
HANGING OUT LIKE THAT AGAIN.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
- [ Alarm Beeping ]
- COME ON, MOVE!
LET'S GET OUTTA HERE! MOVE!
[ Eve Coughing ]
[ Groans ]
MY INSIDES
ARE STARTING TO BOIL.
COME ON.
IT WON'T BE LONG NOW.
[ Groaning ]
I DON'T WANT TO
LOSE MY BABY.
YOU WON'T.
NOT-NOT IF I CAN HELP IT.
[ Crying ]
THANK YOU. THERE'S NOT A LOT OF
LOVE IN THIS ROOM, YOU KNOW?
[ Coughing ]
♪♪ [ Music Box ]
OH, MY--
IT'S HER STUFF.
- [ Job ] WHOSE STUFF?
- [ Abel ] BRITTANY TATE.
THE DEAD GIRL'S STUFF.
IT'S HER STUFF.
WHAT?
HER STUFF.
WHAT ARE YOU BABBLIN' ABOUT?
NOTHIN' IN THERE.
NO. NO.
NO. I SAW A DOLL, AND A PILLOW,
A PICTURE, A MUSIC BOX.
LISTEN, I SMELLED PERFUME.
[ Coughs ]
THE GUY'S STARTIN'
TO LOSE IT HERE.
I DON'T WANT TO DIE. I DON'T
WANT TO DIE. NOT LIKE THIS.
[ Gasping ]
[ Eve ]
OH, MY SKIN'S ON FIRE.
COME ON, SCIENCE GUY.
WHAT'S TAKIN' SO LONG?
FREEZE!
ELIJAH'S NOT GONNA LIKE IT
IF YOU EXECUTE HIS MESSENGERS.
- ELIJAH?
- SENT US TO PICK UP THE GAS.
[ Cain ] DIRTY COPS
AS MESSENGER BOYS?
TYPICAL ELIJAH.
HEY, MAN,
YOU GOT OUR MONEY?
- WHAT IS THIS? A JOKE?
- WHAT? WHAT IS IT?
THERE'S LIKE 10 GRAND HERE.
HEY, THE DEAL WAS
ONE HUNDRED GRAND EACH.
MR. ELIJAH IS
LESS THAN SATISFIED WITH
THE WAY THE JOB WENT DOWN.
- NOT FOR 10 LARGE.
- [ Electronic Ringing ]
- GET OVER THERE. MOVE!
- YOU HAVE A VIDEO PHONE CALL.
WHERE'S THE DAMN MONEY
YOU PROMISED US?
IT'S GOING TO BE MUCH HARDER
TO SELL NOW THAT IT'S BECOME
SUCH A SOUGHT AFTER COMMODITY.
SOMEBODY'S GOING TO HAVE
TO PAY FOR THAT. THAT SOMEBODY
IS YOU PEOPLE.
YOU'RE SCUM! YOU KNOW THAT?
I'M GONNA FIND YOU, PAL.
I WILL!
EVEN IF YOU KNEW
WHERE I WAS, MR. JOB,
YOU'D NEVER HAVE THE NERVE.
WELL, MAYBE NOT HIM, ELIJAH,
BUT YOU FORGOT ABOUT ME.
NOW, I'M GOING TO SEND
YOUR HEALTHY MESSENGER
BACK FOR OUR MONEY.
IF HE ISN'T HERE IN TWO HOURS,
THE POLICE GET THE CANISTERS.
IS THAT CLEAR?
CLEAR ENOUGH.
I JUST HOPE YOU ALL
LIVE LONG ENOUGH.
OH, BY THE WAY,
THIS NOW ENDS
YOUR BROADCAST DAY.
[ Beeping ]
WAIT A MINUTE. MIRAGE.
THE E-MAIL WAS
FROM EDNA RAINES.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
SHE CAN BARELY SPEAK.
IT SEEMS SHE'S HAD ANOTHER
MOMENT OF CLARITY.
THAT'S NOT ALL.
IT'S MR. RAINES WHO STOLE IT.
HOW WOULD MR. RAINES KNOW
WHAT WAS IN MY E-MAIL?
LOOKS LIKE THEY'VE BEEN
MONITORING YOUR M-MAILBOX SINCE
LAST TUESDAY, MISS PARKER.
TUESDAY?
THAT'S THE VERY DAY EDNA
ESCAPED FROM THE INSTITUTION.
HE MUST HAVE ANTICIPATED HER
CONTACTING YOU.
WHAT WAS IN THE E-MAIL?
WELL, THE TEXT FIELD WAS EMPTY.
BUT THERE WAS A VIDEO FILE
ATTACHED.
- [ Typing ]
- PLAY IT.
[ Beeps ]
UH-UH.
THE ONLY WAY TO ACCESS
THE ACTUAL FILE IS FROM THE
COMPUTER IT WAS TRANSFERRED TO.
MR. RAINES'S OFFICE.
THEN WHAT ARE WE WAITING FOR?
I'M BLEEDING TO DEATH.
LIKE ANY OF YOU CARE.
[ Coughing ]
SHOULDN'T HAVE
KILLED THAT LITTLE GIRL.
THAT'S WHAT MADE
ELIJAH SO ANGRY.
NOW THERE'S THE GUARD.
WHICH ONE OF YOU DIRTBAGS
IS INTO SUFFOCATION, HUH?
WAS IT YOU?
[ Groans ]
WHAT HAPPENED THAT NIGHT?
- [ Coughing ]
- [ Siren Wails In Distance ]
OH, WHAT THE HELL.
YOU'RE GONNA
BLEED TO DEATH ANYWAY.
A HUGE ESTATE IN WESTBROOK.
INSIDE WERE
INTELLIGENCE DOCUMENTS.
[ Scoffs ]
WORTH A FORTUNE.
ELIJAH HIRED US TO GET 'EM.
WHOEVER FOUND THEM WAS SUPPOSED
TO BRING THEM BACK TO THE VAN.
BUT SOMEBODY GOT GREEDY,
DECIDED TO TAKE A LITTLE
SIDE TRIP INTO THE GUESTHOUSE.
CARETAKER'S DAUGHTER
WASN'T SUPPOSED TO BE THERE.
I THINK CAIN DID HER.
SHUT UP!
ALL FOR A FEW EXTRA BUCKS.
[ Crunches ]
AAH!
SHUT UP!
SHUT YOUR MOUTH!
[ Man Coughing ]
MARK?
MARK, IS THAT YOU? HEY.
LOOK.
I'M REALLY-- I'M REALLY
SORRY ABOUT YOUR B-BIKE.
♪♪ [ Piano ]
[ Sniffing ]
WHAT'S THAT SMELL? IT SMELLS--
IT SMELLS LIKE PERFUME.
CUT IT OUT, GREEN BEAN.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
THAT SONG AGAIN.
[ Gun Cocks ]
GO AHEAD. PLAY IT AGAIN, SAM,
JUST ONE MORE STINKIN' TIME.
I DARE YOU.
[ Sniffs ]
WHAT IS THAT SMELL?
IS THAT THE ANTIDOTE?
[ Jarod ]
NO. IT'S CHAMPS DE NUIT.
MY MOTHER WORE IT.
[ Helicopters Whir In Distance ]
I COULD SMELL IT WHEN
SHE'D TUCK ME IN BED AT NIGHT.
[ Scoffs ]
MAYBE THAT'S A LIE.
'CAUSE I CAN BARELY
REMEMBER EVEN
IF I HAD A MOTHER.
♪♪ [ Calm ]
THE INGREDIENTS IN PERFUME,
THEY'RE KNOWN AS NOTES,
DID YOU KNOW THAT?
THE PERFUMER,
HE ACTS AS COMPOSER.
NOW, ME, I ALWAYS WENT
FOR THE HEART.
SOME PEOPLE, THEY COULD
ONLY SMELL THE TOP NOTES.
I WENT DEEPER TO
SEARCH FOR THE SOUL.
♪♪ [ Faster ]
PERFUME.
SPARKLING CITRUS NOTES,
LIKE LEMON. DARK RESONANT NOTES,
LIKE BALSAM.
♪♪ [ Loud, Heavy ]
[ Crash ]
♪♪ [ Stops ]
THE MEDICAL REPORT JUST HANDED
TO ME STATES THAT THE MAGNA
TECHNOLOGIES, LIMITED...
SECURITY GUARD HAS
DIED FROM INJURIES SUSTAINED
DURING THE ROBBERY.
WELL, THAT WAS SMART.
HE'S DEAD! DIDN'T YOU
HEAR THAT? HE'S DEAD!
[ Jarod ]
HE AIN'T THE ONLY ONE.
[ Eve ]
GREAT. THAT'S ONE MORE
CORPSE ON OUR HANDS.
OH, MY GOD.
I'M BLEEDING. OH, MY GOD.
YOU'VE GOTTA FINISH THE STUFF.
I'M GONNA DIE. YOU'VE GOTTA
FINISH THAT STUFF!
I'M FINISHING IT NOW.
LET GO OF ME!
♪♪ [ Music Box ]
OH, NO.
OH, GOD, IT'S HER.
IT'S HER. IT'S THE TATE KID.
SO WHAT? IT'S HER.
SO WHAT?
- SHE'S DEAD! JUST LIKE
WE'RE GONNA BE.
- I DIDN'T KILL HER. ALL RIGHT?
I DIDN'T SAY YOU DID!
IT'S NOT EVEN HER PICTURE.
I DIDN'T KILL HER.
OH, DAMN IT!
NOW THERE'S ONLY
ENOUGH ANTIDOTE F--
FOR FOUR OF US.
[ Eve ]
SO WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
[ Jarod ]
I GUESS THAT MEANS THAT
ONE OF IS GOING TO DIE.
THE QUESTION IS, WHO?
[ Helicopter Whirs In Distance ]
[ Eve ]
SO HOW DO WE DECIDE
WHO GETS THE ANTIDOTE?
[ Jarod ]
WE'LL LEAVE OUT THE ONE
WHO KILLED BRITTANY TATE.
ONLY PROBLEM IS WE DON'T
KNOW WHO THE KILLER IS.
- WELL, WE DO.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
PROCESS OF ELIMINATION. I MEAN,
IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN ME
BECAUSE I WASN'T THERE, RIGHT?
I DIDN'T KILL HER. I SWEAR.
I DIDN'T KILL HER.
NO. I KNOW YOU DIDN'T.
AND I KNOW YOU DIDN'T.
AND I KNOW...
YOU DIDN'T.
[ Gasps ]
WHAT'S GOING ON?
GIVE ME THE ANTIDOTE.
- YOU DON'T DESERVE IT.
- WHAT? BUT WHY?
BECAUSE...
YOU KILLED BRITTANY TATE.
MR. ABRAHAM, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU THINK YOU KNOW,
BUT YOU'RE WRONG.
AM I? FOR STARTERS, YOU'RE NOT
REALLY PREGNANT, ARE YOU?
THAT WAS JUST A FABRICATION SO
NO ONE WOULD BELIEVE YOU COULD
EVER POSSIBLY MURDER A CHILD.
AND I CHECKED YOUR BLOOD FOR
THE PREGNANCY HORMONE, H.C.G.
[ Imitates Buzzer ]
- THANKS FOR PLAYIN'.
- THE GAS IS MAKING YOU CRAZY.
THE MOST CONVINCING
EVIDENCE WAS BRITTANY HERSELF.
NO ONE SAW HER THAT NIGHT
EXCEPT FOR THE KILLER.
HER PICTURE WASN'T IN THE
PAPERS. IT WASN'T ON THE NEWS.
YOU WERE THE ONLY ONE
WHO RECOGNIZED THAT PHOTOGRAPH
AS A FAKE.
BECAUSE YOU REMEMBER
WHAT SHE LOOKED LIKE
THE NIGHT YOU KILLED HER.
- [ Job ] WHOA! HEY.
- PUT YOUR GUN DOWN.
PUT YOUR GUN DOWN.
LOOK, IF SHE KILLED THE KID,
THEN SHE'S THE TICKET TO
OUR MONEY FROM ELIJAH.
YOU SHOOT ME,
I TAKE AT LEAST
TWO OF YOU WITH ME.
STARTING WITH LITTLE BROTHER.
[ Groans ]
UH-OH, BLOODY NOSE.
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS.
YOU TELL ME THE TRUTH,
I'LL GIVE YOU HALF MY DOSE.
[ Gasping ]
DISINTEGRATION
OF YOUR INTERNAL ORGANS.
THE COMPLETE MELTDOWN OF
YOUR PSYCHE. IT ISN'T PRETTY.
[ Sobs ]
THE LITTLE GIRL
WASN'T SUPPOSED TO BE THERE.
[ Jarod ] BUT SHE WAS THERE!
AND YOU KILLED HER IN COLD BLOOD
JUST TO ASSURE HER SILENCE!
[ Gasping ]
OH, I CAN'T BREATHE!
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE THIS WAY.
TELL ME THE TRUTH,
AND I'LL GIVE THIS TO YOU.
YES, I KILLED HER!
I KILLED HER!
NOW GIVE IT TO ME!
- OOPS.
- [ Screams ]
[ All Panting ]
BLANKS.
YES. UH, EXCEPT FOR MINE.
[ Gunshots ]
OH, AND HIS.
I THOUGHT YOU'D NEVER END THIS.
I ALMOST SNEEZED.
[ Wheezing ]
W-WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON?
I'M NOT EXACTLY
WHO I PRETEND TO BE.
I'M AN AGENT WITH THE TEXAS
BUREAU OF INVESTIGATION.
I PURPOSELY EXPOSED YOU ALL
TO FIND OUT WHO KILLED
BRITTANY TATE.
BUT YOU WERE GONNA GET KILLED
BY THE GAS TOO.
THERE WAS NO SOMAN GAS.
IT WAS JUST A 12 HOUR
INTESTINAL VIRUS...
WITH A LITTLE KICKER TO
WEAKEN THE SINUS CAVITY
AND CONSTRICT BREATHING.
NOT TO MENTION A MILD
HERBAL HALLUCINOGEN.
IT'S COMPLETELY HARMLESS.
[ Creaking ]
[ Radio Chatter ]
[ Eve ]
I-I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THE REPORTER, THE COPS?
IT WAS ALL A HOAX.
MR. ELIJAH CUT A LITTLE DEAL
TO HELP US.
AND TO SHORTEN
HIS STAY IN PRISON.
NOW YOU SEE THEM.
NOW YOU DON'T.
THESE WERE ALL THE LAST THINGS
THAT BRITTANY SAW
BEFORE YOU KILLED HER.
[ Lid Slams ]
NONE OF THIS WAS REAL?
NOTHING.
EXCEPT YOUR CONFESSION.
AND THAT'S
A LIFETIME OF REAL.
[ Radio Chatter ]
[ Broots ]
I'M INTO RAINES'S HARD DRIVE.
THERE'S THE E-MAIL.
BUT THE VIDEO ATTACHMENT'S
BEEN DELETED.
- DAMN IT.
- HANG ON.
DELETING E-MAILS
IS SORT OF LIKE
LOSING YOUR CAR KEYS.
THEY'RE NOT GONE, JUST LOST.
FAINT MAGNETIC TRACES OF
THE ORIGINAL CAN STILL
LINGER WHERE THEY WERE STORED.
I JUST HAVE TO LINK
ALL THE PIECES.
THERE. I GOT IT.
IT'S EDNA RAINES. SHE SURE
DOESN'T LOOK CRAZY THERE.
MAYBE SHE'S NOT.
PLAY IT, QUICKLY.
MISS PARKER,
I NEED TO TALK TO YOU.
IT'S TIME THAT YOU LEARNED
EVERYTHING ABOUT YOUR MOTHER
AND MIRAGE.
PLEASE ANSWER THIS MESSAGE
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE, AND I'LL
SEND YOU THE WHERE AND WHEN.
IT COULD BE A MATTER
OF LIFE AND DEATH.
[ Sighs ]
FOR LEONARD, IT ALREADY IS.
LET'S JUST HOPE IT'S NOT TOO
LATE FOR THE REST OF US.
IF ANYONE FINDS OUT
HOW WE PULLED THIS OFF,
SOME HEADS ARE GONNA ROLL.
- STARTING WITH MINE.
- WE CAUGHT A BABY KILLER,
DIDN'T WE?
[ Radio Chatter ]
RIGHT.
I'LL SEE YOU
BACK AT THE OFFICE.
COME BOOK THESE ANIMALS.
UH, DON'T WAIT FOR ME.
- YOU HAVE OTHER BUSINESS?
- FAMILY BUSINESS.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Engine Starts ]
♪♪ [ Plays ]
♪♪ [ Continues ]
♪♪ [ Piano ]