[ Jarod ]
LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU BUY PERSONAL ITEMS
FOR A SMALL AMOUNT OF MONEY,
YOU SELL THEM TO PERFECT
STRANGERS FOR A LOT MORE MONEY?
IS AMERICA
A GREAT COUNTRY OR WHAT?
- [ Bells Jingle ]
- YO, TONI.
I GOT A NICE SURPRISE
FOR YOU TODAY.
YOU GOT A JOB?
WHO NEEDS ONE WHEN YOU CAN
FIND RICH STUFF LIKE THIS?
A DIGITAL CAMCORDER.
IT'S GOT LIQUID CRYSTAL DISPLAY,
DIGITAL SOMETHING,
HEADPHONE JACK.
NICE!
- LOOKS LIKE
IT FELL IN THE RIVER.
- IT DID.
I FOUND IT IN THE WASHBASIN
BELOW KOOMER FALLS.
I FIGURE SOME MOPE
MUST HAVE BEEN MAKIN'
A HOME MOVIE AND DROPPED IT.
GIVE YOU 20 BUCKS FOR IT.
TWENTY?
I WAS LOOKING FOR
MORE LIKE A HUNDRED.
YEAH, AND PEOPLE IN HELL
ARE LOOKIN' FOR ICE WATER.
ONE ANDREW J.
TAKE IT OR LEAVE IT.
YOU DRIVE A HARD BARGAIN.
[ Bells Jingle ]
[ Door Closes ]
WHAT'S A-- A HOME MOVIE?
DID YOU GROW UP IN
A BASEMENT OR SOMETHING?
- OR SOMETHING.
- YOU KNOW, MOM, DAD
AND THE KIDS...
GO OFF ON THE GREAT
AMERICAN FAMILY VACATION...
AND RECORD IT FOR POSTERITY,
IN CASE ANYBODY
WANTS TO WATCH IT
WITHOUT A GUN TO THEIR HEAD.
I WOULD.
I'D LOVE TO.
HOW MUCH?
HUNDRED BUCKS.
SOLD.
LIKE I SAID,
IS AMERICA A GREAT
COUNTRY OR WHAT?
IT'S TUESDAY THE 9th,
DAY FOUR OF OUR VACATION,
AND TODAY WE'RE OFFICIALLY
STARTING OUR TRIP
DOWN MEMORY LANE.
HERE ON THE BANKS
OF "KOONER"--
WHAT IS THIS?
A STREAM OR--
IT'S A CREEK. KOOMER CREEK.
KOOMER CREEK. YEAH.
WELL, WHATEVER IT'S CALLED,
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
WHAT?
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Girl ] I THOUGHT THIS WAS
GONNA BE STUPID, BUT IT'S NEAT.
REALLY? YOU MEAN MOM'S
NOT A COMPLETE MORON?
WELL, NOT COMPLETE.
HA, HA, HA.
SO THIS ALL USED TO BE
PART OF GRAMPS'S LAND?
YEAH. THIS IS WHERE
I GREW UP.
RIGHT OVER THERE ON THAT LOG
IS WHERE YOUR DAD
FIRST KISSED ME.
OH, MY GOD.
LOOK. IT'S STILL THERE.
WHAT?
LOOK.
HERE. LET'S GET A SHOT.
"NANCY AND TED."
DAD TOLD ME THERE WAS
A PLACE NEAR HERE,
LIKE, A CABIN OR SOMETHING,
YOU GUYS USED TO GO TO,
TO BE ALONE.
HMM. IT'S AN OLD MILL.
YEAH?
MM-HMM.
IS THAT WHERE
I CAME FROM?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN "CAME FROM"?
WELL, YOU SAID
THIS TRIP WAS SOMETHING
ABOUT MY HERITAGE.
I WAS JUST WONDERING
IF YOU AND DAD GAVE--
[ Chuckles ] YEAH.
A WHOLE NEW MEANING
TO "GRINDING THE CORN."
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING,
YOUNG LADY.
HITTING TOO CLOSE TO HOME.
UM, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I FORGOT MY FANNY PACK IN
THE CAR. I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
OKAY. YOU KNOW, THIS PLACE
ACTUALLY DOESN'T SUCK.
CAN'T BELIEVE YOU DIDN'T
BRING ME HERE BEFORE NOW.
MOM, ARE YOU LISTENING TO ME?
I'M BEING SERIOUS FOR ONCE,
AND SHE'S NOT LISTENING TO ME.
[ Nancy ]
STOP IT! NO!
[ Girl ]
MOM, YOU OKAY?
LEAVE ME ALONE!
- MOM?
- HELP!
MOM, ARE YOU OKAY?
IF YOU'RE JOKING AROUND,
THIS ISN'T FUNNY.
WHERE ARE YOU?
MOM. MOM. MOM!
ARE YOU OKAY?
WHAT HAPPENED?
RUN. RUN.
WHAT?
RUN. HE'S--
HE'S COMING BACK.
- [ Man ]
HEY.
- RUN.
HELP!
SOMEBODY HELP ME, PLEASE!
[ Screams ]
[ Man ]
SHUT UP.
HELP!
[ Screams ]
HELP, PLEASE!
HELP ME!
SOMEBODY HELP US, PLEASE!
[ Screams ]
HELP ME.
[ Rewinding ]
SOMEBODY HELP US, PLEASE!
[ Beeps ]
SOMEBODY HELP US! HELP!
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
- [ Miss Parker ] HE DEFENDS
THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
- [ Jarod ] LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
LEIGH, HONEY, MOVE OVER CLOSE
TO THE SIGN. OH, I SURE HOPE
THIS IS GONNA WORK.
SO, IT'S MONDAY THE 8th,
DAY THREE OF OUR VACATION,
AND WE ARE HERE AT... SLADE.
OH, GUESS WHAT, DAD.
SHE'S GONNA LET ME DRIVE
FOR A WHILE.
YOUR CAR.
[ Mouths Word ]
[ Nancy ]
YEAH, NOW, THAT'S PRETTY.
BOY, DAD'S GONNA LOVE THAT.
DO YOU HAVE TO RECORD THIS?
[ Nancy ]
DON'T YOU HAVE
SOMETHING TO SAY?
UM, I HAD A LITTLE ACCIDENT
IN YOUR MUSTANG.
AND WE NEED A NEW TAILLIGHT.
BUT MOM'S GONNA CHECK AND SEE
IF THEY HAVE ONE HERE.
AND I PROMISE
I'LL PAY FOR IT ALL.
[ Nancy ]
YEAH, RIGHT. OKAY, HERE.
NOW, I'M GONNA GET SOME GAS.
AND THEN I'LL CHECK AND SEE
IF THEY HAVE A NEW LIGHT.
[ Leigh ]
"J.R.'S SERVICE STATION."
I FEEL LIKE WE'RE IN MAYBERRY.
ONLY IT LOOKS LIKE GOOBER'S
HAD A LOBOTOMY.
HEY.
[ Chuckles ]
BUT BARNEY'S GOT
A CUTE BUTT.
[ Nancy ]
LEIGH, BEHAVE YOURSELF.
[ Leigh ]
LIKE YOU DIDN'T NOTICE.
WHAT? I DIDN'T NOTICE.
[ Leigh ]
YEAH, RIGHT.
- [ Beeps ]
- [ Pop ]
[ Sydney ]
ANY NEWS FROM JAROD?
IN A MANNER OF SPEAKING.
HE'S UP TO HIS OLD TRICKS,
BUT THIS TIME WITH A NEW TWIST.
ONE THAT'S RIGHT UP YOUR ALLEY,
BROOTS. [ Snaps Fingers ] SIT.
MY ALLEY. OOH.
TURN IT ON.
[ Electronic Female Voice ]
YOU HAVE MAIL.
WELL, HELLO, MISS PARKER. I'VE
PUT TOGETHER A LITTLE POSTCARD
FOR YOUR VIEWING PLEASURE.
JUST CLICK AND ENJOY.
HEY. THIS IS COOL.
WHEN DEBBIE AND I GO TO
ROCK CITY, I CAN SEND YOU
ONE OF THESE.
NOW, YOU'VE ALREADY MET EDNA,
WHO DESPITE BEING LOCKED
IN AN ASYLUM FOR DECADES BY
HER LOVING HUSBAND, MR. RAINES,
IS AN AMAZING HISTORIAN
OF THE CENTRE.
EDNA KNOWS THINGS ABOUT
YOUR MOTHER, MISS PARKER.
THINGS SHE WON'T TELL
TO ANYONE BUT YOU.
SHE WOULDN'T EVEN TELL ME.
EDNA WANTS TO COME HOME,
BUT SHE CAN'T.
THERE'S AN ARMY OF SWEEPERS
OUT THERE LOOKING FOR HER.
SHE TOLD ME HER REDEMPTION...
WILL BE TO TELL YOU WHAT
SHE KNOWS BEFORE THEY CATCH HER.
SO YOU BETTER HURRY.
BE CAREFUL.
AND KNOW THAT EDNA SAID
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
SHE WANTS YOU TO KEEP DIGGING.
THAT THE SECRET
YOUR MOTHER WANTED TO TELL YOU
WHEN YOU WERE LITTLE...
IS BURIED OUT THERE,
AND YOU NEED TO FIND IT.
HUH.
[ Beeps ]
IT'S LIKE AN ELECTRONIC TRAIL
OF BREAD CRUMBS.
THAT WE BETTER GET BUSY
FOLLOWING BEFORE SOMEONE
GOBBLES EVERYTHING UP.
[ Coughing ]
DAMN IT.
[ Siren Blares ]
[ Coughs ]
HAVIN' A LITTLE TROUBLE?
YOU COULD SAY THAT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
TO IT.
I DON'T BELIEVE I'VE SEEN YOU
AROUND HERE BEFORE.
I'M JUST PASSING THROUGH.
OR I WAS PASSING THROUGH.
LOOKS LIKE I'M GONNA BE STAYING
HERE FOR
A WHILE.
WELL, J.R.'S JUST UP
THE ROAD UP THERE.
HOP IN.
I'LL GIVE YOU A PUSH.
SEE IF WE CAN GET YOU
ON YOUR WAY.
[ Taps Car ]
[ Chattering On Police Radio ]
LOOKS LIKE I'M GONNA HAVE TO
ORDER THE PARTS FROM FLAGSTAFF,
SEEING AS WE DON'T STOCK PARTS
FOR VINTAGE CARS LIKE THAT.
BE TOMORROW BEFORE
YOU'RE UP AND RUNNIN' AGAIN.
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT
MIGHT BE WRONG WITH IT.
CORN MAN A-COMIN'.
- THE CORN MAN?
- WELL, YOU'RE A STRANGER.
THERE'S A CURSE
ON STRANGERS COME TO SLADE.
CURSE OF THE CORN MAN.
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE HAVING
TROUBLE WITH THE CAR.
- NEWT, SHUT UP ABOUT
THAT OLD WIVES' TALE.
- AIN'T NO WIVES' TALE.
STARTED WHEN
THAT STRANGER SHOWED UP AT
OLD MAN KOOMER'S PLACE...
BACK IN THE OLDEN DAYS.
STRANGER CHOPPED UP THE FAMILY.
THE WHOLE FAMILY.
TINY LITTLE PIECES.
THEY FOUND THEM ALL
DOWN AT THE CORN MILL.
THE CORN MAN'S SOUL
AIN'T NEVER RESTED.
YOU CAN SEE IT LIGHTIN'
UP THE SKY AT NIGHT.
HIS GHOST
STILL HAUNTS STRANGERS
THAT COME INTO THIS TOWN.
- I SAID SHUT UP, NEWT.
- YOU CAN TELL ME
TO SHUT UP ALL YOU WANT.
CORN MAN'S STILL A-COMIN'.
NOT THAT I'M PUTTIN'
ANY STOCK IN NEWT'S CURSE,
BUT DOES SEEM LIKE
YOU'VE BEEN HAVIN' A STREAK
OF BAD LUCK LATELY.
I HAD A COUPLE OF WOMEN
BASH RIGHT INTO ME.
THEY SAID THEY WERE
PASSING THROUGH HERE.
MOTHER AND DAUGHTER.
DRIVING A RED
MUSTANG CONVERTIBLE.
OH, THEY WAS PRETTY.
THE BLONDES.
LOOKED LIKE
THEY COULD BE SISTERS.
THEY NEEDED A TAILLIGHT,
AS I REMEMBER, BUT I DIDN'T
HAVE ONE FOR A '65.
THEY JUST GOT SOME GAS
AND HEADED OUT.
I HAVEN'T SEEN THEM SINCE.
[ Bell Dings ]
FILL HER UP, LITTLE BROTHER.
AND BE SURE AND PUT IT
ON THE DEPARTMENT'S ACCOUNT.
YOU EVER GET TIRED OF TELLING ME
WHAT TO DO, BIG BROTHER?
BROTHERLY LOVE,
YOU UNDERSTAND?
YOU MUST BE THE GUY
THE SHERIFF RADIOED IN ABOUT.
WORD SURE TRAVELS FAST
AROUND HERE.
YEAH. WELL, YOU KNOW,
WE LIKE TO STAY
ON TOP OF THINGS.
ANYTHING I CAN HELP YOU WITH?
ACTUALLY, MAYBE YOU COULD
RECOMMEND A MOTEL.
LOOKS LIKE I'M GOING TO
BE HERE FOR A WHILE.
WELL, CLEARWATER INN'S
THE ONLY ONE IN TOWN.
DON'T GET MUCH BUSINESS,
EXCEPT FOR AN OCCASIONAL
TRUCKER, BUT, UH, IT'S CLEAN.
I CAN GIVE YOU A LIFT.
AH, NO, THANKS.
ACTUALLY, I'D-- I'D RATHER WALK.
GET TO SEE YOUR TOWN.
DON'T BLINK.
YOU'LL MISS IT.
CORN MAN A-COMIN'.
[ Beeps ]
[ Leigh ]
THE CLEARWATER INN.
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO STAY
AT A ZERO-STAR RESORT.
LEIGH, TRY AND BE NICE
FOR FIVE MINUTES.
I AM BEING NICE.
- [ Man ]
WELCOME TO CLEARWATER INN.
- [ Nancy ] THANK YOU.
[ Man ]
ROOM'S ALL READY.
ROOM 14.
[ Nancy ]
ROOM 14 IT IS.
[ Man ] PRESIDENTIAL SUITE.
WHAT PRESIDENT STAYED HERE?
MILLARD FILLMORE?
WELL, ACTUALLY,
I JUST CALL IT THAT...
SO I CAN CHARGE MORE
TO SMART-MOUTHED KIDS
AND THEIR MOTHERS.
[ Leigh Chuckles ]
CLEVER.
I'M SURE IT'LL BE JUST FINE.
THANK YOU, RAYMOND.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
[ Beeps ]
HELLO.
I'D LIKE TO
RENT A ROOM, PLEASE.
FILL THIS OUT. BE SURE
AND PUT DOWN THE MAKE
AND MODEL OF YOUR CAR.
ACTUALLY, I'M GOING TO
NEED A RENTAL.
UH, TWO BLOCKS THAT WAY.
AND GOOD LUCK
WITH WHAT YOU GET.
WELL, IT DOESN'T MATTER.
JUST WANT TO DRIVE AROUND.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL HERE.
[ Chuckles ]
WELL, THAT'S IN THE EYES
OF THE BEHOLDER.
SOME FRIENDS OF MINE
SEEMED TO HAVE THOUGHT SO.
AS A MATTER OF FACT, I THINK
THEY STAYED HERE A COUPLE OF
DAYS AGO. A MOTHER AND DAUGHTER.
BEAUTIFUL, BLONDE.
MMM. DON'T REMEMBER 'EM.
I HEAR YOU ONLY GET
THE OCCASIONAL TRUCKER
THROUGH HERE.
SURELY YOU REMEMBER
TWO BEAUTIFUL WOMEN
IN A RED CONVERTIBLE.
HMM. WELL,
YOU'D THINK I WOULD.
BUT I DON'T,
BECAUSE THEY WEREN'T HERE.
HERE WE GO.
THINK WE'LL PUT YOU
IN ROOM NUMBER FIVE.
I'LL TAKE NUMBER 14,
PLEASE.
IT'S MY FAVORITE NUMBER.
SURE.
FOURTEEN IT IS THEN.
YEAH, THERE'S SOMEONE HERE
ASKING ABOUT 'EM.
EVEN KNEW WHAT ROOM
THEY WERE IN.
MOM. DO YOU BELIEVE
IN GHOSTS?
[ Nancy ] GHOSTS?
YEAH. YOU KNOW,
THE SOULS OF THE DEAD.
THEY CAN COME BACK
TO HAUNT THE LIVING.
I DON'T KNOW, HONEY.
I NEVER REALLY GAVE IT
THAT MUCH THOUGHT.
[ Leigh ]
THEN HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
THOSE FLASHES?
[ Nancy ]
IT'S CALLED HEAT LIGHTNING.
- AND IT'S BEEN HAPPENING
AROUND HERE FOR A LONG TIME.
- WHATEVER IT IS, IT'S FREAKY.
LIKE THAT STORY
THAT GUY WAS TELLING ME
BACK AT THE GAS STATION.
YOU KNOW, THE ONE
THAT GAVE ME THIS.
HE WAS TELLING ME
ABOUT THE CURSE.
ALL STRANGERS ARE CURSED.
HMM.
IT ALL STARTED BACK WHEN SOME
CORN MAN HACKED UP A FAMILY
OUT BY GRANDPA'S OLD RANCH.
[ Nancy ] HONEY, THAT'S JUST
AN OLD TALE THAT PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN TELLING FOR YEARS.
IT'S RIDICULOUS.
I HOPE SO.
IT IS.
OKAY.
WAIT. HOW DO YOU
TURN THIS OFF AGAIN?
LITTLE RED BUTTON.
MOM.
WHAT?
MOM, THERE'S
SOMEBODY OUT THERE.
WHAT? WHERE?
BY THE TREE.
HE WAS STANDING--
HE'S STARING AT ME.
[ Nancy ]
OKAY.
LOOK.
[ Nancy ]
I DON'T SEE ANYONE.
HE WAS RIGHT THERE
BY THE TREE.
I SWEAR.
[ Nancy ]
IF THERE WAS SOMEONE THERE,
THEY'RE NOT THERE NOW.
HE WARNED US
WE'D BE IN DANGER.
MAYBE HE WAS RIGHT.
MAYBE THE CORN MAN'S
COMING, MOM.
[ Nancy ]
THAT'S NOT HAPPENING.
GO TO BED.
HOW DO I
TURN THIS OFF AGAIN?
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Young Sydney's Voice ]
JAROD, A 15-YEAR-OLD GIRL...
IS FOUND BRUTALLY MURDERED
IN HER BEDROOM.
PART OF AN UPPER-CLASS
COMMUNITY IN A SMALL TOWN.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
BETWEEN THE TIME
SHE LEFT HER FRIENDS...
AND WHEN SHE WAS MURDERED.
WHAT IS IT
YOU WANT ME TO DO, SYDNEY?
TAKE THE EVIDENCE.
USE YOUR SKILLS AS A PRETENDER.
BECOME THE VICTIM.
DO WHAT SHE DID.
FEEL WHAT SHE FELT.
[ Leigh ]
IT'S TUESDAY THE 9th,
DAY FOUR OF OUR VACATION,
AND TODAY WE'RE OFFICIALLY
STARTING OUR TRIP
DOWN MEMORY LANE.
HERE ON THE BANKS OF "KOONER"--
WHAT IS THIS?
A STREAM OR--
- [ Nancy's Voice ]
IT'S A CREEK. KOOMER CREEK.
- [ Leigh ] KOOMER CREEK.
YEAH. WELL, WHATEVER
IT'S CALLED, IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
[ Nancy ]
THIS IS WHERE I GREW UP.
[ Leigh ]
YOU KNOW, THIS PLACE
ACTUALLY DOESN'T SUCK.
CAN'T BELIEVE YOU DIDN'T
BRING ME HERE BEFORE NOW.
[ Nancy ] STOP IT!
NO!
MOM?
LEAVE ME ALONE!
YOU OKAY? MOM?
- HELP!
- MOM, ARE YOU OKAY?
MOM, IF YOU'RE KIDDING AROUND,
THIS ISN'T FUNNY.
WHERE ARE YOU?
MOM!
MOM.
[ Leigh ]
MOM. MOM.
ARE YOU OKAY?
WHAT HAPPENED?
RUN. HE'S--
HE'S COMING BACK.
RUN.
I CAN'T SEE IT, SYDNEY.
I CAN'T FIGURE IT OUT.
YOU HAVE TO FIGURE IT OUT.
THE FAMILY IS COUNTING ON YOU.
[ Screams ]
SOMEBODY HELP US, PLEASE!
[ Newt's Voice ]
CORN MAN A-COMIN'.
[ Echoing ]
WELL, MISTER,
YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
FUNNY THING,
PARTS SHOP SAID...
THEY NEVER HEARD
OF THIS HAPPENING
WITH THIS MODEL BEFORE.
WELL, THAT IS FUNNY.
NOT IF YOU'RE A STRANGER
IT AIN'T.
IT'S THE CURSE.
THAT'S WHY I WENT
AND MADE YOU THIS HERE
CORN MAN TO KEEP YOU SAFE.
IF YOU'RE GONNA
STAY AROUND HERE,
YOU'RE GONNA NEED IT.
THANKS.
I THINK.
[ Bell Dings ]
[ Man On Police Radio,
Indistinct ]
WELL, I SEE KENT'S GOT YOU
ALL FIXED UP THERE,
MR., UH--
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT SURE
I GOT YOUR NAME.
I'M NOT SURE
I GAVE YOU MY NAME.
GUESS YOU'LL BE
ON YOUR WAY THEN.
WHO KNOWS? MAYBE I'LL STICK
AROUND. I'M GROWING KIND OF
ATTACHED TO THE PLACE.
YOU DON'T GOT A JOB
OR A HOME TO GO BACK TO?
I'M SORT OF IN BETWEEN
BOTH RIGHT NOW.
WELL, I'D ADVISE YOU GET
ONE OR THE OTHER.
IDLE HANDS ARE
THE DEVIL'S PLAYTHINGS.
I DON'T PLAN TO BE IDLE.
I'M NOT TOO FOND
OF STRANGERS.
I HOPE THE CORN MAN
DON'T GET HIM.
ANY LUCK FINDING EDNA?
[ Broots Clears Throat ]
I'VE ENHANCED THIS PHOTO FROM
JAROD'S E-MAIL. THERE'S NO ONE
WE RECOGNIZE IN THE CROWD,
BUT FROM THE SIGNAGE AND
LICENSE PLATES, IT LOOKS LIKE
A STREET SCENE IN NEW YORK CITY.
SOMEWHERE IN HARLEM.
[ Broots ]
HMM.
- [ Beeps ]
- [ Jarod's Voice ] EDNA WANTS
TO COME HOME, BUT SHE CAN'T.
THERE'S AN ARMY OF SWEEPERS
OUT THERE LOOKING FOR HER.
SHE TOLD ME HER REDEMPTION...
WILL BE TO TELL YOU WHAT
SHE KNOWS BEFORE THEY CATCH HER.
SO YOU BETTER HURRY.
HMM.
HOME. REDEMPTION.
OF COURSE.
ONE OF MY MOTHER'S
FAVORITE CHARITIES...
WAS A HALFWAY HOUSE
IN HARLEM CALLED
REDEMPTION HOME.
[ Broots ]
JAROD'S TELLING YOU
THAT'S WHERE YOU CAN FIND EDNA.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
MR. WRIGHT?
MM-HMM.
I HAVE TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT YOUR WIFE
AND YOUR DAUGHTER.
THERE'S BEEN SOME TROUBLE.
TROUBLE? WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I-- I JUST SPOKE WITH THEM.
- WHEN?
- THIS MORNING.
THEY SAID THEY WERE FINE.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
WE'VE HAD
A MINOR CAR ACCIDENT.
WELL, THAT'S STRANGE.
NANCY DIDN'T MENTION
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
THAT IS STRANGE.
THAT CAR MUST MEAN
A LOT TO YOU.
ACTUALLY,
IT WAS YOUR DAUGHTER
WHO WAS DRIVING. LEIGH.
SHE BACKED INTO ME.
UH, YOUR WIFE GAVE ME
THE NAME AND NUMBER
OF YOUR INSURANCE COMPANY,
BUT I-- I SEEM TO HAVE
MISPLACED IT.
IS YOUR WIFE
EXPECTED HOME SOON?
NO. THEY'RE BOTH STILL OUT OF
TOWN. LOOK. ALL MY INSURANCE IS
HANDLED THROUGH WESTERN MUTUAL.
BUT, YOU KNOW, I PREFER
TO HANDLE THIS MYSELF.
SO WHY DON'T YOU GET
AN ESTIMATE, AND I'LL SEND YOU
A CHECK FOR THE FULL AMOUNT.
YES, BUT I WOULD NOT-- UH--
I'LL BE IN TOUCH.
SOMEBODY WAS HERE.
HE WAS ASKING ABOUT THEM.
TALL GUY. DARK HAIR.
[ Electronic Twittering, Beeps ]
[ Horns Honking ]
[ Broots's Voice ]
EDNA RAINES IS IN THIS BUILDING.
HERE IN ROOM 24.
BUT THE GUY SAID THAT I WAS
THE SECOND PERSON TO LOOK
FOR HER IN THE LAST HALF HOUR.
- [ Sydney ] RAINES.
- [ Raines ] WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WHAT THE HELL
SHE WAS MY WIFE.
- WAS?
- [ Sydney ]
EDNA RAINES IS DEAD.
AN OVERDOSE.
HOW CONVENIENT.
I CAN ONLY ASSUME
SHE COULDN'T
FACE THE WORLD ANY LONGER.
WITH YOU IN IT,
WHO COULD BLAME HER?
I'LL MISS HER SO MUCH.
IS THAT WHY YOU KEPT HER
LOCKED UP FOR 30 YEARS?
THAT WAS TO PROTECT HER.
YOU NEVER PROTECTED ANYONE
BUT YOURSELF, RAINES.
YOU CAN BURY HER
AGAIN, RAINES.
ALONG WITH ALL THE SECRETS
SHE DIED FOR.
SHERIFF.
YEAH.
WE NEED TO TALK.
[ Phone Rings ]
UH, JUST A SECOND
THERE, SIR.
YEAH. SHERIFF'S OFFICE.
WHAT? NO.
YOUR BROTHER'S NOT HERE.
YEAH. HE-- HE IS
THE DEPUTY, KENT.
HE'S ON PATROL.
YEAH. I'LL TELL HIM
TO CALL YOU WHEN HE GETS BACK.
ALL RIGHT. OKAY.
SORRY ABOUT THAT. WHAT, UH--
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM NOW?
I FOUND SOMETHING, AND I WANT
TO SHOW YOU. I WAS--
[ Phone Rings ]
DAMN IT.
SHERIFF'S OFFICE.
YEAH. UH, LISTEN.
I CAN'T TALK RIGHT NOW. UM--
I UNDERSTAND. I--
I'LL GET RIGHT BACK WITH YOU.
SOON. ALL RIGHT? YEAH.
JUST STAY THERE.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Sheriff's Voice ]
WAKE UP.
I SAID WAKE UP!
START TALKIN'.
TALKIN' ABOUT WHAT?
EVERYTHING YOU KNOW
ABOUT NANCY AND LEIGH.
FROM THE BEGINNING.
I KNOW THEY DISAPPEARED
FOUR DAYS AGO.
AND I KNOW THAT MR. WRIGHT HERE
HAS TAKEN OUT A RATHER LARGE
INSURANCE POLICY ON THEM.
HEY. WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU SAYIN'?
I'M SAYIN' THAT
YOU AND THE SHERIFF HERE...
HAVE CONSPIRED TO MURDER
YOUR WIFE AND YOUR DAUGHTER...
SO YOU COULD COLLECT
INSURANCE MONEY.
MURDER?
- PAL, WE'RE TRYING
TO SAVE THEM.
- THAT WHY YOU TRIED TO KILL ME?
- KILL YA? WE FOUND YOU.
- YOU KIDNAPPED
MY WIFE AND DAUGHTER.
- YOU'RE GONNA
TELL US WHERE THEY ARE.
- KIDNAPPED?
I DIDN'T KIDNAP THEM.
I'M HERE TO FIND THEM.
LOOK. THERE'S A CAMCORDER OVER
THERE. THERE'S A TAPE IN IT.
IT WILL EXPLAIN EVERYTHING.
[ Beeps ]
ARE YOU OKAY?
WHAT HAPPENED?
RUN. RUN.
WHAT?
RUN. HE'S--
HE'S COMING BACK.
RUN.
HELP!
[ Man ] HEY.
HELP ME, PLEASE!
[ Screams ]
HELP.
HELP!
SOMEBODY HELP US, PLEASE!
[ Ted ]
OH, MY GOD.
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
I WAS ON VACATION WHEN
THIS SORT OF FELL INTO MY LAP.
- JAROD WILSON, U.S. MARSHALS.
- [ Ted ]
A FED.
- DAMN IT, FRANK. HE FINDS OUT,
HE'S GONNA KILL THEM.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
FOUR DAYS AGO
I GOT A CALL. A MAN.
HE SAID IF I WANTED TO SEE
MY WIFE AND DAUGHTER AGAIN...
TO GET $500,000
BY TONIGHT...
AND NOT TO CONTACT
THE AUTHORITIES.
TED GOT A HOLD OF ME
AND MADE ME PROMISE I WOULDN'T
BRING IN ANY OUTSIDE HELP.
WE'VE BEEN, UH, FRIENDS
SINCE HIGH SCHOOL--
AND RAYMOND HERE.
THEN YOU STARTED SNIFFIN'
AROUND, AND WE FIGURED
YOU WERE INVOLVED.
DO YOU THINK
IT'S SOMEONE LOCAL?
WELL, A LOT OF LOCAL PEOPLE
ARE AWARE OF TED'S FINANCIAL
SUCCESS AND HIS FAMILY.
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TO GO ON.
AND EVEN LESS TIME.
[ Sydney's Voice ]
I WAS EDNA RAINES'S THERAPIST.
I CAN ASSURE YOU THAT
SHE WOULDN'T HAVE TAKEN HER OWN
LIFE-- AT LEAST NOT WILLINGLY.
EDNA KNEW SHE WAS IN DANGER.
THAT'S WHY JAROD WAS
SO CRYPTIC ABOUT HER LOCATION.
- [ Beeps ]
- [ Jarod's Voice ]
BE CAREFUL.
AND KNOW THAT EDNA SAID
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
SHE WANTS YOU TO KEEP DIGGING.
THAT THE SECRET
YOUR MOTHER WANTED TO TELL YOU
WHEN YOU WERE LITTLE...
IS BURIED OUT THERE,
AND YOU NEED TO FIND IT.
BURIED? BUT WHERE?
WHO'S THE MOST ADEPT
AT BURYING THINGS AROUND HERE?
[ Gulps ]
MR. RAINES.
[ Printer Whirring ]
GOT THE CASH.
EVERYTHING'S READY TO GO.
HE SHOULD'VE CALLED
BY NOW TO TELL ME
WHERE TO DROP THE MONEY.
HE'S GOING TO CALL,
MR. WRIGHT.
JUST BE PATIENT.
I DON'T WANT TO BE PATIENT.
I WANT MY FAMILY BACK.
TED, HE'S ON OUR SIDE.
[ Cell Phone Rings ]
KEEP HIM ON THE LINE
AS LONG AS POSSIBLE.
TELL HIM YOU DEMAND
TO SPEAK TO NANCY--
THAT YOU WON'T MAKE
A DELIVERY UNTIL YOU KNOW
THAT YOUR WIFE IS SAFE.
- [ Ringing Continues ]
- [ Computer Beeps ]
[ Beeps ]
THIS IS WRIGHT.
[ Man ] PUT THE MONEY
IN A DUFFEL BAG. AT MIDNIGHT,
YOU, AND YOU ALONE--
[ Distorted Voice ] WILL TAKE IT
AND LEAVE IT IN THE TRASH BIN AT
THE BRIDGE ON LONG TUNNEL ROAD.
- I WANT TO TALK TO MY WIFE.
- [ Man ] YOU'RE NOT IN
A POSITION TO MAKE DEMANDS.
[ Nancy Whimpers ]
- TED?
- NANCY.
OH, TED, THANK GOD.
ARE-- ARE YOU
AND LEIGH ALL RIGHT?
YEAH. WE'RE A LITTLE GROUND UP,
BUT WE'RE, UM-- WE'RE ALIVE.
JUST HANG IN THERE, SWEETIE.
EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE OKAY.
TED, I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU TOO.
BOTH OF YOU.
- MIDNIGHT.
- I'LL BE THERE.
I GOT IT.
[ Bird Squawking ]
[ Ted On Walkie-talkie ]
I MADE THE DELIVERY.
[ Sighs ]
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S BEEN OVER AN HOUR.
I HAVEN'T SEEN ANYTHING YET
IN MY POSITION.
HOW ABOUT YOU, RAYMOND?
[ Ted ]
YEAH. DO YOU SEE ANYTHING?
HOW'S IT GOIN'?
NOTHIN' SO FAR.
[ Frank ]
WELL, KEEP YOUR HEAD UP.
- JAROD.
- I DON'T LIKE THIS, SHERIFF.
- HE SHOULD'VE SHOWN UP BY NOW.
- [ Raymond ] JAROD,
I THINK I GOT SOMETHING.
- [ Gunshot On Walkie-talkie ]
- DAMN! RAYMOND!
- RAYMOND, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
WHAT THE HELL HAPPENED?
I SAW THE GUY
COMING STRAIGHT AT ME.
[ Sighs ]
HE WAS ON A MOTORCYCLE.
I THOUGHT I COULD STOP HIM.
NEXT THING I KNEW I WAS DOWN.
THE BULLET ENTERED
FROM BEHIND.
[ Owl Hooting ]
HOW CAN THAT BE?
THERE ARE TWO KIDNAPPERS.
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
NEVER AGAIN. YOU HEAR ME?
DON'T EVEN ASK. NEVER AGAIN.
CALM DOWN
AND CHECK YOUR PANTS.
[ Sighs ]
NOW TELL ME WHAT YOU FOUND.
NOTHING. WELL, ALMOST NOTHING.
[ Clears Throat ]
EXCUSE ME.
I CROSS-REFERENCED EVERYTHING IN
RAINES'S FILES WITH EDNA'S NAME,
AND THE ONLY THING--
THE ONLY THING
I CAME UP WITH...
WAS SECTION "G,"
14, DASH, SIX...
IN A COMMUNIQUÉ INTERCEPTED
BY RAINES FROM EDNA TO YOU.
WH-- WHAT?
SECTION "G."
ROW 14, PLOT SIX.
THAT'S MY MOTHER'S GRAVE.
JAROD'S E-MAIL
SAID TO KEEP DIGGING.
THE ANSWERS...
ARE BURIED OUT THERE.
YOU DON'T THINK JAROD
WANTS YOU TO DIG HER UP?
MISS PARKER,
IT'S YOUR MOTHER'S GRAVE.
GET SHOVELS.
WE'VE GOT WORK TO DO.
[ Sighs ]
[ Ted's Voice ]
THEY'RE DEAD.
IF THE KIDNAPPERS
HAVEN'T KILLED THEM ALREADY,
THEY WILL NOW FOR SURE.
[ Sighs ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
I'M GONNA
WATCH THIS VIDEO AGAIN.
MAYBE I MISSED SOMETHING.
CAN'T BELIEVE YOU DIDN'T
BRING ME HERE BEFORE NOW.
[ Leigh ]
ARE YOU OKAY? IF YOU'RE JOKING
AROUND, THIS ISN'T FUNNY!
WELL, NOT COMPLETE.
HA, HA, HA.
[ Young Jarod's Voice ]
I'VE STUDIED THE EVIDENCE
AND READ THE INTERVIEWS, BUT...
IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
THE ANSWER'S
RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU.
EVERYTHING YOU NEED IS THERE.
BUT I CAN'T SEE IT.
BUT SHE CAN.
SEE WHAT IT IS THAT SHE SEES.
LOOK, JAROD.
LOOK HARD.
DID YOU SEE THAT?
WHAT?
THAT.
THE ANSWER'S THERE.
IT WAS THERE THE WHOLE TIME.
SHE SEES HIM.
[ Frank ]
ADAMS? HE WAS
IN THE PARKING LOT?
[ Ted ]
ADAMS? WHO'S ADAMS?
- MY DEPUTY.
- AND ONE OF THE KIDNAPPERS.
- THEN WHO'S THE OTHER ONE?
- MY GUESS IS
HIS BROTHER KENT...
FROM THE GAS STATION.
SO THESE GUYS HAVE GONE
TO KILL MY FAMILY?
NOT IF WE GET TO THEM FIRST.
WAIT A MINUTE.
LISTEN TO THIS.
[ Ted's Voice ]
NANCY.
- [ Nancy ]
OH, TED, THANK GOD.
- ARE YOU AND LEIGH ALL RIGHT?
WE'RE A LITTLE GROUND UP,
BUT WE'RE, UM-- WE'RE ALIVE.
WE'RE A LITTLE GROUND UP--
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
"GROUND UP."
ON THE VIDEO,
LEIGH KEPT REFERRING
TO AN OLD MILL.
YEAH, NEAR MY FATHER-IN-LAW'S
RANCH. NANCY AND I USED TO
GO THERE ALL THE TIME.
YOU WIFE WAS TRYING TO TELL YOU
WHERE SHE AND YOUR DAUGHTER
WERE BEING HELD.
LET'S GO.
LET'S JUST HOPE
THEY'RE STILL ALIVE.
[ Crickets Chirping ]
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Broots ] YOU'VE MADE ME DO
A LOT OF THINGS I DON'T
WANT TO DO, MISS PARKER,
BUT THIS HAS GOTTA BE
THE WORST.
WHAT IF SOMEONE FINDS US?
THEN YOU'LL JUST HAVE TO
HOLD THEM OFF
WHILE I GO FOR HELP.
OH, GREAT.
THAT'S-- THAT'S LOVELY.
ROW 14'S OVER HERE.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Clank ]
[ Broots Whispers ]
WHOA. SORRY.
I FEEL LIKE I'M IN
A SCOOBY-DOO CARTOON.
[ Owl Hoots ]
WAIT. WHAT WAS THAT?
SETTLE DOWN, SHAGGY.
IT'S AN OWL.
[ Owl Hooting ]
THIS IS IT.
MISS PARKER,
THIS JUST ISN'T RIGHT.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU WANT TO DO THIS?
JAROD'S DONE
A LOT OF TWISTED THINGS,
BUT HE WOULD NEVER
LEAD ME HERE
JUST TO TORMENT ME.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
NOW DIG.
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
[ Vehicle Door Opens ]
WHERE THE HELL
HAVE YOU BEEN?
WRIGHT TIPPED OFF THE SHERIFF.
- WE GOTTA GET OUT OF HERE.
- NO ONE FOLLOWED ME.
THAT'S BECAUSE
I PUT A BULLET IN THE LEG
OF THE GUY WHO COULD'VE.
WHAT ABOUT THEM?
THIS WASN'T
PART OF OUR PLAN.
YEAH, WELL, PLANS CHANGE,
LITTLE BROTHER.
THEY CAN IDENTIFY US.
[ Grunts ]
LEIGH, NOW! RUN!
I'LL GET THE DAUGHTER.
YOU TAKE CARE OF HER.
DAMN, MOM. THAT HURT.
IF THAT'S THE WAY
YOU'RE GONNA BE--
OH, I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Groans ]
- NANCY.
- I'M FINE.
BUT LEIGH-- SHE RAN OUT,
AND THE DEPUTY WENT AFTER HER.
[ Panting ]
[ Panting, Whimpers ]
[ Adams ]
YOU CAN'T GET AWAY.
[ Groans ]
GET AWAY FROM ME!
DON'T WORK THAT WAY.
IT'S NOTHING PERSONAL.
YOU UNDERSTAND.
PLEASE. I WANT TO GO HOME.
JUST BUSINESS.
- THE ONLY PLACE YOU'RE GOING
IS IN KOOMER'S CREEK!
- NO! [ Screams ]
STOP SCREAMIN'.
NO ONE CAN HEAR YOU
SCREAM OUT HERE.
I CAN.
COME HERE!
[ Groans ]
ARE YOU OKAY?
[ Sobbing ]
IT'S OKAY.
[ Whispers ] IT'S FINE.
IT'S FINE. IT'S FINE.
[ Nancy ]
LEIGH.
GO. GO.
BABY. OH.
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO
THANK YOU, JAROD.
JUST TAKE CARE OF THEM.
I WILL.
YOU READY TO GO?
LET'S GO HOME.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
WELL, THIS IS IT.
MISS PARKER, ARE YOU SURE
YOU WANT TO DO THIS?
AH.
HUH?
[ Sighs ]
OPEN IT.
MISS PARKER--
[ Sighs ]
WHY DON'T WE JUST
GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE...
AND LET HER REST IN PEACE?
[ Sighs ]
I WANT TO REST IN PEACE.
NOW OPEN IT.
ARE YOU SURE?
GO AHEAD.
[ Grunts ]
OH, MY GOD.
WHAT?
MISS PARKER,
YOUR MOTHER--
SHE'S NOT IN HERE.
THEN WHERE THE HELL IS SHE?
[ Miss Parker ]
JAROD, I'M ONLY
GOING TO ASK YOU THIS ONCE.
HOW DID YOU KNOW
SHE WOULDN'T BE THERE?
I DIDN'T.
THEN WHO?
EDNA DID.
SHE KNEW ALL THE SECRETS.
ESPECIALLY ABOUT
THE MIRAGE PROJECT.
UNFORTUNATELY,
SHE TOOK THEM TO HER GRAVE.
WELL, I AM SORRY FOR YOU.
EDNA WAS SOMEONE
YOU COULD'VE TRUSTED.
UNLIKE THE CENTRE.
OR MY FAMILY.
YOU WERE RIGHT IN PUTTING
YOUR TRUST IN YOUR MOTHER.
SHE KNEW THE IMPORTANCE
OF FAMILY.
OF HELPING PEOPLE.
IF SHE KEPT
ANY SECRETS FROM YOU,
IT WAS TO PROTECT YOU.
PROTECT ME FROM WHAT?
THE TRUTH.
KEEP SEARCHING, MISS PARKER.
BUT REMEMBER.
YOU CAN'T BELIEVE
EVERYTHING YOU SEE.
AFTER ALL,
LIFE IS A MIRAGE.
SOMETIMES THE THINGS
THAT SCARE YOU THE MOST...
CAN BE THE THINGS
THAT SAVE YOUR LIFE.
[ Beeps ]