[ Bell Dings ]
AFTER THE CEREMONY,
I'LL HAVE YOU TRANSFERRED
BACK TO THE HOTEL.
I'VE ALSO TAKEN THE LIBERTY
OF CONTACTING
A REAL ESTATE AGENT.
WE NEED TO TALK.
I'M BUSY.
WHO'S THE GUY?
NOT NOW, OKAY?
MY SINCEREST APOLOGIES.
[ Shutter Clicking ]
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
EXCUSE ME.
[ Shutters Continue
Clicking ]
[ Gavel Raps ]
WELCOME TO WHAT I'M SURE
IS THE BEGINNING
OF EXCITING NEW LIVES...
AS UNITED STATES CITIZENS.
IF YOU'LL RAISE
YOUR RIGHT HANDS
AND REPEAT AFTER ME--
I HEREBY DECLARE,
ON OATH,
THAT I ABSOLUTELY AND ENTIRELY
RENOUNCE AND ABJURE...
[ Thinking: Screeching ]
THAT I ABSOLUTELY
AND ENTIRELY
RENOUNCE AND ABJURE...
ALL ALLEGIANCE AND FIDELITY
TO ANY FOREIGN PRINCE...
TO ANY FOREIGN PRINCE,
[ Judge ] POTENTATE,
STATE OR SOVEREIGNTY...
[ Shouting In Cambodian ]
[ Candidates ] POTENTATE,
STATE OR SOVEREIGNTY--
[ Shouting Continues
In Cambodian ]
[ Gavel Rapping ]
[ Judge ]
MA'AM, PLEASE!
MA'AM!
[ Gavel Rapping Continues ]
[ Judge ]
SECURITY!
[ Cambodian ]
SOMEONE PLEASE
GET SECURITY HERE NOW!
[ Gavel Rapping Continues ]
ORDER! PLEASE!
- [ Fire Alarm Ringing ]
- [ Judge ]
PLEASE REMAIN CALM!
REMAIN CALM
AND FILE IN AN ORDERLY MANNER
TO THE NEAREST EXIT!
PLEASE REMAIN CALM!
[ Shouting In Cambodian ]
[ Fire Alarm
Continues Ringing ]
[ Muttering In Cambodian ]
DID YOU SEE THE LOOK
ON THAT POOR WOMAN'S FACE?
I KNOW SHE'S BLIND,
BUT SHE ACTED LIKE
SHE'D SEEN THE DEVIL HIMSELF.
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
- [ Miss Parker ] HE DEFENDS
THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
- [ Jarod ] LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
[ Broots ]
I PULLED A STILL FRAME OFF
THE FRONT GATE SECURITY CAMERA.
WELL, HE SIGNED IN
UNDER THE NAME KI MAK.
SOUNDS THAI.
CAMBODIAN. RUN IT THROUGH
OUR INTERPOL SERVER,
SEE WHAT POPS UP.
- OKAY.
- HE HAS A TATTOO.
- A TATTOO?
- ON THE BACK OF HIS RIGHT HAND.
IT'S A SNAKE EATING ITSELF.
I'LL MAKE A NOTE.
-THINK LYLE IS UP TO SOMETHING?
-I KNOW LYLE IS UP TO SOMETHING.
THE QUESTION IS, WHAT?
[ Woman ]
JUST MAKE SURE THE INVOICES
ARE SIGNED AND INITIALED.
THANKS.
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Woman ]
AGENT BERGER, I.N.S.
UH, NO, SIR,
I CAN'T DEPORT SOMEONE
BECAUSE YOU DON'T LIKE
THE PRICE OF CIGARETTES.
WELL, I SUGGEST
YOU SHOP AT ANOTHER STORE.
NO, SIR, THAT'S--
THAT'S NOT A JOKE.
THAT'S AMERICA.
[ Line Hangs Up,
Dial Tone ]
CAN I HELP YOU,
MR., UH--
AGENT. ELLIS.
JAROD ELLIS.
I WAS SENT DOWN
ABOUT A BLIND WOMAN.
SENT DOWN?
YES, FROM D.C.
I WAS WORKING A CASE OUTSIDE
OF STOCKBRIDGE WHEN WE GOT
THE CALL FROM YOUR OFFICE.
FROM WHAT AGENT?
RINKER.
- MIKE RINKER?
- [ Phone Ringing ]
- JACK.
- [ Ringing Continues ]
EXCUSE ME.
[ Punching Keypad ]
[ Man On Radio ]
SECURITY
TO THE SOUTHWEST DOOR.
CAROL. IS JACK RINKER
STILL IN HIS OFFICE?
HE'S GONE.
WOULD YOU GET ME
HIS CAR PHONE? THANKS.
I GIVE UP.
ONE HOUR, AND ALL I GET IS
HER NAME AND THE SAME THING
OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
[ Repeats Phrase Twice
In Cambodian ]
I'M FLUENT IN FIVE ASIAN
LANGUAGES, BUT I'LL BE DAMNED IF
I KNOW WHAT SHE'S TRYIN' TO SAY.
SHE'S THIRSTY.
SHE WOULD LIKE
A DRINK OF WATER.
- YOU SPEAK CAMBODIAN?
- DOESN'T EVERYBODY?
I'VE GOT JACK RINKER
ON A CAR PHONE.
SHOULD I PUT HIM THROUGH?
TELL HIM
TO HAVE A GOOD VACATION.
SHE'S ALL YOURS.
KIM CHAY.
[ Speaking Cambodian ]
JAROD.
COULD WE TRY THIS IN ENGLISH?
COULD YOU TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED
TODAY AT THE CEREMONY?
I MEAN YOU NO HARM.
WELL, YOU'RE MY SECOND
SURPRISE VISIT FROM D.C. TODAY.
- SECOND?
- AGENT JAROD ELLIS?
JAROD?
6'2", 180 POUNDS,
DARK HAIR, DARK EYES?
- YOU KNOW HIM?
- WE'VE MET.
MAY I SEE YOUR IDENTIFICATION?
I'M AGENT GREENE.
THIS IS AGENT HILL.
INTERNAL DIVISION.
[ Jarod ]
I REALIZE THIS
IS ALL VERY CONFUSING,
BUT I CAN'T HELP YOU
UNLESS I KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
IT WAS REPORTED...
THAT YOU KEPT SAYING
THE WORD "BUTCHER" OVER AND OVER
AGAIN AT THE CEREMONY.
CAN YOU TELL ME WHY?
[ Greene ]
WHERE IS HE?
HE'S IN
THE LAST INTERROGATION ROOM,
RIGHT DOWN THE HALL.
DAMN!
[ Ki Mak ]
THIS PROBLEM MUST BE
DEALT WITH IMMEDIATELY.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THE WOMAN YOU SAW
AT THE CEREMONY
THIS MORNING...
IS AN UNFORTUNATE LINK
TO MY PAST,
WHICH NOW MAKES HER
A LINK TO YOURS.
I AM SENSITIVE TO YOUR CONCERNS.
BUT IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN,
SHE WAS ALSO BLIND.
UNDER ESTIMATING THE MEEK
HAS BROUGHT MORE THAN ONE ARMY
TO ITS KNEES.
WE HAVE A VERY GOOD ARMY HERE.
- [ Door Opens ]
- [ Clears Throat ]
[ Door Closes ]
DID YOU FIND HER?
[ Whispers ]
THE BLIND WOMAN
HAS BEEN TAKEN.
TAKEN?
BY WHOM?
BY JAROD.
I SUGGEST
YOU TELL YOUR SOLDIERS
THIS IS WAR.
[ Bells Pealing ]
HERE.
LET ME GET THAT.
[ Pealing Continues ]
IS THAT A PICTURE
OF YOUR FAMILY?
MOTHER.
FATHER.
BROTHER.
WHERE ARE THEY NOW?
DEAD.
ALL MURDERED BY THE BUTCHER.
ALL MURDERED
BY THE BUTCHER.
[ Broots ]
MAK CAME TO THE UNITED STATES
THREE MONTHS AGO FROM VENEZUELA.
I'M MORE INTERESTED
IN HIS CONNECTION TO LYLE.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW
IF IT'S RELATED,
BUT LYLE'S MADE THREE
BUSINESS TRIPS TO CARACAS
IN THE PAST 12 MONTHS.
AS FAR AS I CAN TELL,
THE CENTRE HAS NO TIES TO ANYONE
OR ANYTHING IN THAT COUNTRY.
- NOT ON PAPER, YOU MEAN.
- I DID HEAR SOMETHING ELSE.
I WAS IN THE BATHROOM
AND I OVERHEARD
A COUPLE SWEEPERS SAYING...
THAT WILLIE
HAD A CLOSE ENCOUNTER
WITH JAROD TODAY.
- WHERE?
- THE MEN'S ROOM, SL-10.
THE ENCOUNTER WITH JAROD,
YOU BOOB.
OH. VIRGINIA.
ACROSS THE RIVER.
BUT THAT'S NOT ALL.
WILLIE HAS BEEN ASSIGNED SPECIAL
TEMPORARY DUTY TO LYLE'S TEAM.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO HAVE A LITTLE TALK
WITH BABY BROTHER.
[ Bells Pealing ]
[ Kim Chay ]
ALL MURDERED BY THE BUTCHER.
IN A HURRY?
EXTREME.
HEY, DID YOU EVER
WONDER WHY
A CAMBODIAN CITIZEN...
WOULD CHOOSE TO
LIVE IN VENEZUELA?
ISN'T THAT INTERESTING?
I SUPPOSE IT COULD BE
THE CLIMATE. OR THE COFFEE.
OR IS IT, PERHAPS,
VENEZUELA
HAS NO EXTRADITION TREATY
WITH THE WEST?
SOMETHING ON YOUR MIND,
SIS?
WHO'S KI MAK?
AND WHY IS RAINES'S GUARD DOG
BABYSITTING HIM?
SHOULDN'T YOU BE
OUT HUNTING FOR JAROD?
IT'S FUNNY
YOU SHOULD ASK THAT,
CONSIDERING I HEARD YOUR PEOPLE
HAD A CLOSE ENCOUNTER
WITH HIM TODAY.
CAN I GET
A LITTLE PRIVACY?
NO.
NOW, DO YOU WANT TO TALK TO ME,
OR SHOULD I GO PUT MY FOOT DOWN
ON WILLIE'S THROAT?
MAK IS A FORMER LEADER
OF THE CAMBODIAN
FREEDOM FIGHTERS.
HE FLED SOUTHEAST ASIA
AFTER SAIGON FELL.
HE WENT UNDERGROUND
FOR HIS OWN SAFETY.
WHAT'S HE DOING HERE?
WE MET IN THAILAND
ABOUT FIVE YEARS AGO.
HE HELPED ME
OUT OF A SITUATION.
I PROMISED
TO RETURN THE FAVOR.
TRUST ME,
OUR LITTLE BRUSH WITH JAROD
WAS PURELY COINCIDENCE.
GO ON.
MAK NEEDED A SPONSOR
TO BECOME A U.S. CITIZEN.
I PULLED SOME STRINGS, GOT HIM
A COMMISSION AS CULTURAL LIAISON
AT THE LOCAL PORT AUTHORITY.
[ Water Running ]
NOW, I SUGGEST
YOU REFOCUS YOUR ATTENTION
ON JAROD...
AND CLIMB OFF MY BACK
BEFORE I RUN OUT
OF PATIENCE.
IS THAT A THREAT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
YOU MUST REALLY LIKE
SUGAR DATES.
ACTUALLY...
THEY'RE FOR A FRIEND.
THESE PRAYER BEADS
BELONG TO--
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M A FRIEND OF KIM CHAY'S.
I NEED TO ASK YOU
SOME QUESTIONS.
I BUILT THIS
FOR THE OTHER CAMBODIANS
IN THE AREA.
A LITTLE PIECE
OF WHAT WE LEFT BEHIND.
COME. WE'LL TALK
IN THE BACK ROOM.
PLEASE.
MY COUNTRY IS VERY BEAUTIFUL,
BUT IT HAS SEEN MUCH PAIN--
THE WAR WITH AMERICA,
THE GENOCIDAL MARCH OF POL POT.
THE LEADER
OF THE KHMER ROUGE.
YES.
PLEASE, SIT.
NEARLY 25 YEARS HAS PASSED,
BUT I CAN STILL SMELL
THE BURNING BODIES.
I KEEP THESE TO REMEMBER,
TO NEVER FORGET
WHAT MAN IS CAPABLE OF.
KIM CHAY WAS TORTURED
BY THE KHMER ROUGE.
WORSE, I'M AFRAID.
I HAD A BROTHER
WHO LIVED IN HER VILLAGE.
KIM CHAY'S FAMILY WAS AT HOME
WHEN THE SOLDIERS CAME.
HER FATHER, HER MOTHER,
HER BROTHER...
WERE EXECUTED
IN FRONT OF HER.
YOU SEE,
SHE WASN'T BORN BLIND.
IT IS TOLD THAT SHE ATTACKED
THE OFFICER IN CHARGE...
TO TRY
AND SAVE HER FAMILY,
THAT SHE
DREW HIS BLOOD...
WITH HER BARE HANDS.
SHE WAS SIX YEARS OLD.
THIS MAN?
YES. THIS MAN
IS COLONEL CHEN THON.
HE WAS AN OFFICER
IN THE KHMER ROUGE--
AN EVIL KILLING MONSTER.
DID YOU WITNESS THON
COMMIT THESE MURDERS?
NO.
THE ONLY WITNESS
STILL ALIVE IS KIM CHAY.
SOME OF THE WORST OFFICERS FLED
TO THE GOLDEN TRIANGLE...
AND FLOURISHED
IN THE HEROIN TRADE.
IF COLONEL THON IS HERE,
THEN KIM CHAY'S LIFE
IS IN GREAT DANGER.
AND NOW, I FEAR, SO IS YOURS.
IT TURNS OUT MAK IS BEING
SWORN IN BY THE PORT AUTHORITY
TOMORROW AFTERNOON.
- AND YOU INTEND TO BE THERE?
- LYLE KNOWS HIS TICKET
TO THE TOP IS STILL JAROD.
BUT ALL HE SEEMS TO CARE ABOUT
IS MAKING GOOD ON A PROMISE
HE MADE FIVE YEARS AGO...
TO A VIRTUAL STRANGER.
YOUR POINT?
THERE'S MORE TO THIS
THAN WE KNOW.
AND THIS MAK CHARACTER
IS THE KEY.
HELL, MAYBE JAROD'LL
EVEN MAKE A SURPRISE APPEARANCE.
[ Sighs ]
WELL?
IT'S LIKE MAK
JUST APPEARED
OUT OF THIN AIR.
THERE'S NO
BIRTH CERTIFICATE,
UH, SCHOOL RECORDS,
NOTHING.
- RECORDS CAN DISAPPEAR.
- THEY CAN ALSO BE ERASED.
I TRIED TO OPEN UP
A COMPUTER FILE ON MAK
I HAD FOUND EARLIER TODAY...
TO DOUBLE-CHECK
SOME INFORMATION.
IT WAS GONE. WIPED OUT.
IT'S LIKE ANY HISTORY
OF THIS MAN IS--
- BEING DESTROYED
BEFORE OUR EYES.
- LYLE.
HE TOLD ME
HE MET MAK IN THAILAND.
BROOTS, TAKE THAT PHOTO,
RUN IT AGAIN FOR A VISUAL MATCH.
AND THIS TIME
ISOLATE THE PRIMARY SEARCH
TO SOUTHEAST ASIAN TARGETS--
BOOKS,
MAGAZINES, NEWSPAPERS.
AND HURRY.
THIS GUY COULD BE GONE BEFORE
WE FIND OUT WHO HE REALLY IS.
KIM CHAY?
[ Bells Pealing ]
[ Bell Tolls ]
KIM CHAY?
I KNOW YOU DON'T WANT TO
TALK ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED,
BUT I'M NOT
GOING TO JUST GO AWAY.
I NEVER HAD A REAL HOME.
I UNDERSTAND PAIN...
AND LOSS.
TELL ME
ABOUT YOUR BLINDNESS.
IT WAS THE TIME OF YEAR ZERO.
POL POT AND HIS FOLLOWERS
WANTED TO STOP THON,
BEGIN THE WAR WITH THEMSELF
AS THE ONLY POWER.
THE KILLINGS BEGAN
WITH THE TEACHERS.
THEN THE SPIRITUAL LEADERS.
AND FINALLY THE ARTISTS.
YOUR MOTHER AND YOUR FATHER.
THEY WERE WRITER OF POETRY.
WORDS OF COMFORT AND JOY
TO THE PEOPLE.
COLONEL THON MAKE MY FATHER
READ FROM HIS OWN BOOK.
THEN HE KILL HIM...
AND THE OTHER MEMBERS
OF MY FAMILY.
THIS WAS THE DAY
THE SUN WENT AWAY.
I WANT TO HELP THE SUN
RETURN FOR YOU.
BUT I HAVE TO
EXAMINE YOUR EYES.
CAN I DO THAT?
I FEEL YOUR PAIN
AND LONELINESS.
YOU HAVE LOST MANY PEOPLE
THAT YOU LOVE.
YES.
[ Bells Pealing ]
[ Phone Beeps ]
[ Line Rings ]
THIS IS SYDNEY.
I CHECKED KIM CHAY'S EYES.
THERE'S NO SIGN
OF DAMAGE OR DISEASE.
HAVE YOU EVER ENCOUNTERED
SOMETHING CALLED TERROR SILENCE?
FIRST CASES SURFACED...
AFTER THE BOMBING
OF HIROSHIMA AND NAGASAKI.
HOSPITALS BEGAN SEEING
PATIENTS QUITE UNABLE
TO COMMUNICATE.
AND YET THESE PEOPLE
SHOWED NO SIGNS
OF PHYSIOLOGICAL DAMAGE.
THEIR AFFLICTIONS
WERE PSYCHOSOMATIC REACTIONS...
TO THE HORRIFIC SAVAGERY
THEY WITNESSED.
I BELIEVE
THAT KIM CHAY'S BLINDNESS
IS A FORM OF TERROR SILENCE.
WELL, THE HUMAN MIND
IS CAPABLE OF ALMOST ANYTHING
IN ORDER TO PROTECT ITS HOST.
SHE DOESN'T DESERVE
A LIFE OF DARKNESS, SYDNEY.
WHAT APPROACH SHOULD I TAKE?
IN SOME CASES,
THE STRICKEN
HAVE RESPONDED...
BY CONFRONTING
THE OBJECT OF THEIR TERROR.
BUT BE VERY CAREFUL.
IF SHE'S PUSHED TOO HARD,
SHE MAY NEVER EMERGE
FROM THE DARKNESS.
[ Knocking ]
SYDNEY!
OH, BY THE WAY,
MISS PARKER IS PLANNING
A LITTLE TRIP ACROSS
THE RIVER THIS AFTERNOON.
IT SEEMS
SHE HAS BECOME INTERESTED
IN LOCAL POLITICS.
A CERTAIN PORT AUTHORITY
COMMISSION HEARING,
TO BE MORE PRECISE.
I THOUGHT YOU'D BE
INTERESTED TO KNOW.
VERY INTERESTED.
[ Beeps ]
KIM CHAY.
I BELIEVE YOU HAVE
SOMETHING THAT'S KNOWN
AS A CONVERSION DISORDER.
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
WHEN SOMETHING EMOTIONAL,
SOMETHING TRAUMATIC
HAPPENS TO A PERSON,
IT CAN MANIFEST ITSELF
IN A PHYSIOLOGICAL WAY.
IN YOUR CASE,
BLINDNESS.
CAN THIS DISORDER
BE CURED?
I BELIEVE IT CAN.
BUT--
WHAT?
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO FACE
THE THING THAT TRIGGERED IT.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
FACE COLONEL THON.
[ Trembling, Sobbing ]
HE'S GOING TO
REMAIN A FREE MAN
UNLESS YOU STEP FORWARD.
KIM CHAY,
THERE IS SO MUCH BEAUTY
IN THE WORLD.
DON'T LET THIS MONSTER
TAKE IT AWAY FROM YOU.
I HAVE LIVED IN THE DARKNESS
FOR SO MANY YEARS,
TRYING TO ERASE
THE FACE OF THE KILLER.
I CANNOT LET THE MONSTER
BACK IN AGAIN.
I'M SORRY.
OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
WE'LL FIND
ANOTHER WAY.
WE'LL FIND ANOTHER WAY.
SHH-SHH-SHH-SHH.
[ Sighs ]
OKAY. I RAN THE PICTURE
OF MAK AND GOT A HIT
FROM A BANGKOK NEWSPAPER.
IT'S A STORY THAT
RAN FIVE YEARS AGO.
IT TURNS OUT MAK'S
REAL NAME IS CHEN THON.
HE WAS SOME MILITARY BIGWIG
WITH THE COMMUNISTS.
[ Miss Parker ]
SO, LYLE LIED ABOUT MAK.
WHAT A SURPRISE.
- WHAT'S IT SAY?
- I WOULD'VE TAKEN THE TIME TO
HAVE THE NEWSPAPER TRANSLATED,
BUT I KNEW
YOU SPOKE THE LANGUAGE.
WELL, I'M NOT GETTING IT ALL,
BUT APPARENTLY LYLE
WAS ARRESTED FOR ASSAULTING
A COUPLE OF PROSTITUTES.
LYLE? WHAT--
WHAT IS WITH THIS GUY?
FIRST IT'S THE MURDER
OF CHAY LIN.
THEN IT'S THE TWO SISTERS
IN COLLEGE, AND THEN
THE BLOODY TORTURE CHAMBER,
A-AND NOW THIS?
PARKER, YOU OKAY?
FINE.
[ Parker Retching,
Coughing ]
[ Toilet Flushing ]
[ Woman ]
I'M SORRY, SIR.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
I DON'T NEED EXCUSES.
JUST GET IT DONE.
I WANT ANY REMAINING TRACE
OF THON'S PREVIOUS LIFE
WIPED OUT.
AND MAKE SURE
THE SUPPLIERS IN THAILAND
ARE READY TO MOVE.
EXCUSE ME, MR. LYLE?
[ Door Closes ]
MR. MAK CALLED AND ASKED
IF YOU COULD MEET HIM
RIGHT AWAY.
HE SAID
HE HAS NEW INFORMATION...
CONCERNING THE WOMAN
FROM THE CEREMONY.
HE'S WAITING FOR YOU
DOWNSTAIRS IN HIS CAR.
UM, LUCY?
YES, SIR?
THAT'S A LOVELY DRESS
YOU'RE WEARING.
THANK YOU, SIR.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
DRIVER, WHERE'S--
WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
WHERE'S MAK?
I AM SORRY, SIR,
BUT THERE'S BEEN
A SLIGHT CHANGE OF PLAN.
YOU DIDN'T THINK
I'D LET YOU SLEEP THROUGH
ALL THE FUN, NOW DID YOU?
TAKE THIS THING OFF MY HEAD!
OH, QUIT YOUR WHINING!
YOU WON'T GET AWAY
WITH THIS.
- THEY'LL BE LOOKING FOR ME.
- MEANING COLONEL THON?
DIDN'T THINK
I WAS GONNA ALLOW YOU
TO LET THAT GENOCIDAL MANIAC...
FREE IN THE WORLD AGAIN,
DID YOU?
- THAT'S A DONE DEAL.
- OH, YES.
THAT PORT COMMISSION THING.
NOT A TOTALLY IDIOTIC PLAN.
YOU HAVE YOUR GUY APPOINTED TO
THE PORT COMMISSION,
AND THEN YOU HAVE
AN OPEN PIPELINE TO SMUGGLE IN
HEROIN FROM SOUTHEAST ASIA.
IT'S JUST BUSINESS.
JUST BUSINESS.
WITH A MAN WHO BUTCHERED
THOUSANDS OF INNOCENT PEOPLE
IN COLD BLOOD.
[ Chuckling ]
YOU KNOW MY PHILOSOPHY, JAROD.
DON'T ASK, DON'T TELL.
BESIDES, YOU CAN'T
SHOW YOUR FACE
AT THAT HEARING.
MISS PARKER WILL HAVE
A SMALL ARMY
WAITING FOR YOU.
MISS PARKER.
WELL, THAT COULD POSE
QUITE A PROBLEM, COULDN'T IT?
UPS-A-DAISY.
[ Grunts ]
- WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
- TIME.
I'M GOING TO DIAL MISS PARKER.
YOU'RE GOING TO TELL HER
THAT YOU CAPTURED ME.
YOU'RE GONNA GIVE HER
THE ADDRESS HERE.
SHE'S GONNA
COME DOWN THOSE STAIRS,
TRIP THIS WIRE AND...
I THINK YOU CAN
GUESS THE REST.
[ Exhales ]
AND IF I REFUSE?
THAT'S NOT REALLY AN OPTION.
WHEN YOU USED TO TORTURE ME
AT THE CENTRE,
I HAD TO
APPLY A TECHNIQUE THAT
I LEARNED AS A LITTLE BOY...
TO HELP BLOCK OUT
THE PHYSICAL PAIN.
I HAD TO GO TO PLACES
IN MY MIND.
YOU, ON THE OTHER HAND,
HAVE YOU?
YOU--
[ Groans ]
[ Exhales ]
INTIMIDATING, ISN'T IT?
I TOOK IT OFF
THIS RANCHER IN MONTANA
WHO WAS ABUSING HIS CATTLE.
I KNOW-- YOU'RE THINKING
IT'S NOT THE SAME THING.
AND YOU'RE RIGHT.
THE CATTLE DIDN'T DESERVE IT.
SHALL WE MAKE
THAT PHONE CALL?
HMM?
[ Sydney ]
INTERESTING READING?
OR CAN'T YOU
BELIEVE WHAT IT SAYS?
I'VE KNOWN YOU
SINCE YOU WERE
A LITTLE GIRL, PARKER.
I CAN TELL WHEN YOU'RE
TRYING TO HIDE SOMETHING.
IT JUST DOESN'T SEEM LIKE
THE KIND OF THING YOU COULD SAY
ABOUT A BLOOD RELATION.
[ Exhales ]
THE STORY
ISN'T ABOUT AN ASSAULT.
IT'S ABOUT A DOUBLE MURDER.
LYLE WAS THE PRIME SUSPECT.
HMM.
ACCORDING TO THE PAPER, HE USED
AN UNIDENTIFIED MILITARY SOURCE
TO CUT A DEAL WITH THE POLICE.
COLONEL THON.
AND THAT ISN'T ALL, IS IT?
THESE GIRLS
WEREN'T JUST KILLED.
THEY WERE MUTILATED.
MUTILATED?
SOME OF THEIR...
INTERNAL ORGANS...
WERE REMOVED.
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Beeps ]
WHAT?
ARE YOU SURE?
I HEAR YOU.
I'M ON MY WAY!
[ Beeps ]
THAT WAS LYLE.
HE'S CAPTURED JAROD.
I CALL THIS APPOINTMENT SESSION
OF THE PORT AUTHORITY
COMMISSION TO ORDER.
TODAY'S BUSINESS
INCLUDES THE CONFIRMATION
OF MR. KI MAK...
AS CULTURAL LIAISON
TO THE P.A.C.
- GOOD MORNING, MR. MAK.
- MS. OWEN. GENTLEMEN.
AS I REVIEW THE DATA BEFORE ME,
I HAVE TO SAY I HAVE NEVER,
IN MY 23 YEARS
AS A MEMBER OF THIS COUNCIL,
COME ACROSS
SUCH AN EXEMPLARY LIST
OF RECOMMENDATIONS.
MY LIFE HAS BEEN, UH,
DEDICATED AND DEVOTED...
TO SERVING
MY FELLOW MAN.
I BELIEVE EACH OF US
IS GIVEN THE OPPORTUNITY
TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
IT IS
OUR OBLIGATION AND DUTY
TO DO OUR VERY BEST.
WELL, IF THERE
AREN'T ANY OBJECTIONS,
I SUGGEST THAT
WE DISPENSE WITH FORMALITY
AND PROCEED TO THE VOTE.
THAT WOULD BE
A VERY BAD IDEA.
WHO ARE YOU?
OH, IT'S NOT IMPORTANT.
IT'S THE MAN TO WHOM
YOU'RE ABOUT TO GIVE
THE KEYS TO THE CITY...
YOU SHOULD
CORRECTLY IDENTIFY.
YOU KNOW HIM AS KI MAK, SCHOLAR,
HUMANITARIAN, FAMILY MAN.
BUT HIS REAL NAME
IS COLONEL CHEN THON,
AND HIS LEGACY CONSISTS
OF THE TORTURE AND GENOCIDE...
OF THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE!
MR. MAK,
DO YOU KNOW THIS MAN...
OR UNDERSTAND ANY OF THESE
OUTRAGEOUS ACCUSATIONS?
MADAM, MY LIFE IS AN OPEN BOOK,
ONE YOU HAVE SITTING BEFORE YOU.
AS FOR THIS MAN,
I CAN ASSUME THAT HE'S
CONFUSED ME WITH SOMEONE ELSE.
WHAT'S CONFUSING
IS THAT YOU'VE BEEN ALLOWED
TO LIVE THIS LONG.
COLONEL THON WAS THE COMMANDER
OF AN ELITE KILLING SQUAD...
RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE COLD-BLOODED MURDER
OF INNOCENT MEN,
WOMEN AND CHILDREN.
THIS IS NONSENSE!
LOOK, I DEMAND THAT
YOU REMOVE THIS MAN--
I REALIZE ALL THIS SOUNDS
INCREDIBLE, BUT IF YOU WOULD
SUSPEND THESE PROCEEDINGS--
I DID NOT COME HERE
TO HEAR SLANDER
AND FALSE ACCUSATIONS!
TO INVESTIGATE THESE CHARGES,
YOU WOULD OVERTURN A LIFE
FRAUGHT WITH TORTURE AND DEATH!
MR. MAK.
CAN YOU SPEAK
TO THESE CHARGES?
AMERICA STANDS
AS THE LAST GREAT HOPE
FOR LIBERTY,
A LIBERTY MANY OF MY COUNTRYMEN
HAVE FOUGHT AND DIED FOR.
LET ME JUST SAY,
IF I AM THIS--
THIS MONSTER
THAT I'M BEING ACCUSED OF,
LET THERE BE ONE VOICE,
ONE PERSON...
STEP FORWARD
AND PROVE THAT I'M GUILTY.
[ Owen ]
I AGREE.
CLEARLY, THIS IS MEANINGLESS
WITHOUT EYEWITNESS TESTIMONY.
IS THERE ANYONE THAT CAN CONFIRM
THESE HORRIFIC ACCUSATIONS?
[ Kim Chay ]
I CAN.
[ Spectators
Murmuring ]
- AND YOU ARE?
- MY NAME IS KIM CHAY.
I WAS BORN
IN THE SIAM VALLEY
OF NORTHERN CAMBODIA.
THE MAN
STANDING BEFORE YOU...
IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE MURDEROUS DEATHS...
OF MY MOTHER,
FATHER AND BROTHER.
- YOU WITNESSED THESE KILLINGS?
- I DID.
AND YOU CAN CONFIRM
THE IDENTITY OF THIS MAN
THAT STANDS BEFORE US...
AS THIS COLONEL THON?
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
THIS WOMAN IS OBVIOUSLY BLIND.
HOW CAN SHE ACCURATELY
IDENTIFY ANYONE?
FOR SO MANY YEARS,
I HAVE LIVED IN THE DARK,
AFRAID OF THE MEMORY
OF YOUR FACE.
I WILL NOT
BE AFRAID ANYMORE.
[ Shutter Clicks ]
THIS IS THE MAN...
WHO KILLED MY MOTHER,
MY FATHER AND MY BROTHER.
THIS IS HIS BLOOD--
BLOOD DRAWN BY
A TERRIFIED SIX-YEAR-OLD GIRL,
AND THAT WAS ME.
I SUGGEST
THAT WE SEAL THE BUILDING...
AND HAVE SECURITY
TO HOLD THE ACCUSED
FOR PROPER AUTHORITIES.
[ Shouting In Cambodian ]
[ Gavel Rapping ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Gavel Continues Rapping ]
[ Broots ]
MISS PARKER!
I KNOW YOU'RE NOT IN
A VERY GOOD MOOD HAVING TO SPEND
THE NIGHT TRAPPED WITH MR. LYLE.
LORD KNOWS,
ANYBODY WOULD BE BUMMED OUT.
NOT TO MENTION
BEING DUPED BY JAROD AGAIN.
I MEAN, IT'S LIKE THE GUY--
THE GUY GETS
INSIDE YOUR HEAD.
YOU CAN'T MAKE A DECISION
WITHOUT HIM BEING
TWO STEPS AHEAD OF YOU.
GO AWAY!
I FOUND OUT
WHAT THE TATTOO
ON THON'S HAND MEANS.
CONGRATULATIONS.
IT'S THE CAMBODIAN SYMBOL
FOR CANNIBALISM.
IF YOU'RE THINKING
OF JUMPING,
I SUGGEST
YOU GO UP ON THE ROOF
AND DO IT RIGHT.
YOU STILL HAVEN'T MASTERED
THE CURIOUSLY SIMPLE ART
OF THE KNOCK.
YOU LOOK TERRIBLE.
I HAD TROUBLE
SLEEPING LAST NIGHT.
I COULDN'T STOP
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT...
WHY JAROD DIDN'T FINISH YOU
WHEN HE HAD THE CHANCE.
- I NOW KNOW THE REASON.
- WHAT'S THAT?
HE DIDN'T WANT
TO KILL THE DRAMA.
I MEAN,
THERE ARE SO MANY...
TASTY LITTLE SECRETS
LEFT...
TO BE SERVED UP.
NOT A VERY FLATTERING PICTURE,
IS IT?
I KNOW
YOU KILLED THOSE GIRLS.
AND AFTER SEEING
THAT ARTWORK ON YOUR ARM,
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE REST OF THEM.
WELL, YOU MUST NOT HAVE
FINISHED THE ARTICLE,
BECAUSE I WAS ACQUITTED
OF ALL THE CHARGES.
AND AS FOR THE TATTOO,
WELL, IT'S JUST ONE OF SEVERAL.
WANT TO SEE THE OTHERS?
YOU BOUGHT YOURSELF
OUT OF JAIL...
AND USED A WAR CRIMINAL
TO BROKER THE DEAL.
WELL, YOU HAVE BEEN...
A BUSY LITTLE BEAVER,
HAVEN'T YOU?
OKAY.
[ Exhales ]
FOR THE SAKE OF ARGUMENT,
LET'S SAY THAT...
I DID THESE HORRIBLE THINGS
YOU'RE ACCUSING ME OF.
THERE'S STILL
NO WAY TO PROVE IT.
I HAVE MAK.
OR COLONEL THON,
AS IT TURNS OUT.
I PUT THE RIGHT DEAL
ON THE TABLE,
HE'LL OFFER UP YOU AND
YOUR PSYCHO-PATHETIC SINS
ON A SILVER PLATTER.
NO PUN INTENDED.
AND...
TO WHOM ARE YOU GOING
TO GIVE THIS INFORMATION?
THE TRIUMVIRATE,
FOR STARTERS.
I'M SURE THEY'D BE VERY
INTERESTED TO KNOW...
THEY HAVE
A FLESH-EATING SERIAL KILLER
RUNNING THEIR ORGANIZATION.
I CUT A DEAL WITH THON,
AND YOU'RE FINISHED.
OH, UM, I'M SURE THE COLONEL
WOULD BE INTERESTED
IN YOUR OFFER...
IF, OF COURSE,
HE COULD HEAR IT.
[ Chuckles ]
SO I GUESS YOU DIDN'T READ
THE PAPER THIS MORNING, HUH?
THE AUTHORITIES ARE CALLING IT
A TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
I PREFER TO THINK OF IT
AS KARMA.
I'M JUST CRAZY ABOUT LEFTOVERS.
AREN'T YOU?
MY GOD.
YOU'RE INSANE.
[ Judge ]
AND THAT I
TAKE THIS OBLIGATION FREELY...
AND THAT I TAKE
THIS OBLIGATION FREELY...
WITHOUT
ANY MENTAL RESERVATION...
WITHOUT ANY
MENTAL RESERVATION...
OR PURPOSE OF EVASION.
SO HELP ME, GOD.
CONGRATULATIONS. YOU ARE NOW
ALL UNITED STATES CITIZENS.
I DIDN'T THINK YOU WOULD COME.
ARE YOU KIDDING? I WOULDN'T
HAVE MISSED IT FOR THE WORLD.
HOW DOES IT FEEL
TO BE A CITIZEN?
LIKE I FINALLY HAVE A HOME.
YOU HEARD
THAT COLONEL THON DIED
IN A CAR ACCIDENT?
I SAW THE PAPER.
BUT YOU ARE WRONG.
HE DIED WHEN YOU GAVE ME
THE COURAGE TO FACE HIM.
WHAT MADE YOU
CHANGE YOUR MIND
ABOUT CONFRONTING HIM?
A FRIEND REMINDED ME
HOW MUCH BEAUTY THERE WAS
IN THE WORLD.
THANK YOU, JAROD.
I HOPE YOU FIND A WAY
TO LET THE LIGHT
BACK INTO YOUR LIFE.
THANK YOU.