[ Phone Beeping ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Miss Parker ]
WHAT?
[ Jarod ]
ALWAYS THE WORKAHOLIC.
JAROD--
TORMENTING HOURS
ARE FROM 9:00 TO 5:00.
CALL BACK TOMORROW.
WHO SAID I WAS CALLING
TO TORMENT YOU?
MAYBE I WAS JUST
FEELING NOSTALGIC.
IF YOU'RE FEELING HOMESICK,
COME VISIT.
I HAVE A ROOM ALL READY FOR YOU.
GENEROUS OFFER,
BUT I WILL REGRETFULLY DECLINE.
SO. WHAT IS IT, JAROD?
I WAS HOPING YOU'D GIVE MY BEST
TO THE REST OF OUR
DYSFUNCTIONAL FAMILY.
PARTICULARLY MR. RAINES.
OH, I'LL BE SURE
TO SAY HEY,
NEXT TIME I SEE HIM.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU SAW HIM?
HE HASN'T BEEN AROUND
MUCH LATELY, HAS HE?
I COUNT RAINES'S ABSENCE
AS A BLESSING.
I DON'T QUESTION IT.
IF YOU DON'T QUESTION,
YOU DON'T LEARN.
[ Beeps ]
I BROUGHT THE
TRIUMVIRATE PHONE LOGS
YOU REQUESTED.
BACK BURNER, BROOTS.
I HAVE A HOLIER CRUSADE
FOR YOU.
FIND OUT WHERE RAINES
HAS BEEN LATELY.
[ Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
[ Beeps ]
HELLO?
WELL, IT'S
ABOUT DAMN TIME.
TELL ME YOU FOUND HIM.
LOOK, I'M PAYING YOU
ALL THIS MONEY...
'CAUSE YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE ON THE INSIDE.
THIS BOY SHOULD
BE DEAD BY NOW.
BOLTON, MINNESOTA
MUST BE A PODUNK,
NOTHING TOWN.
HOW HARD CAN IT BE
TO FIND HIM?
WELL, HE GOES
TO SCHOOL, DOESN'T HE?
THE CLOCK IS TICKING.
MY NEW TRIAL IS IN FIVE DAYS,
AND THIS BOY'S TESTIMONY
IS THE ONLY THING
THAT THEY'VE GOT ON ME.
I WANT YOU TO FIND HIM.
I WANT YOU TO KILL HIM.
OTHERWISE, YOU'RE DEAD.
GOT ME?
DON'T LET ME DOWN.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM, BUDDY?
YOU IN SOME KIND
OF HURRY?
YEAH.
AS A MATTER OF FACT, I AM.
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Claps ]
GOOD MORNING, CLASS.
MY NAME IS MR. BRODIE.
I'M YOUR SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
- [ Miss Parker ] HE DEFENDS
THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
- [ Jarod ] LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
MR. CONKLIN,
YOUR REGULAR TEACHER,
IS ON VACATION,
SO BEFORE WE GET STARTED,
I'D LIKE TO GET TO KNOW
ALL OF YOU A LITTLE BIT BETTER.
DO YOU KNOW ABOUT SEX?
[ Laughter ]
MR. CONKLIN SAID WE'RE
GONNA START OUR SEX
EDUCATION THIS WEEK.
MY MOM SIGNED
A PERMISSION SLIP.
KEVIN--
INTERESTED IN BIOLOGY.
GOOD.
[ Boy ]
I ALREADY KNOW ABOUT SEX.
- MY DAD HAS THE INTERNET.
- JOEL-- LIKES COMPUTERS.
MR. BRODIE?
ARE YOU MARRIED?
UH, NO, UH, GEMMA.
- I'M NOT.
- DO YOU HAVE A GIRLFRIEND?
- YEAH. DOES SHE KNOW
ABOUT SEX?
- [ Laughter ]
I'M THE ONE THAT'S
SUPPOSED TO BE ASKING
THE QUESTIONS, REMEMBER?
WHAT ABOUT YOU, UH, MATTHEW?
- WHAT ARE YOU
INTERESTED IN?
- UH--
I LIKE TO READ, I GUESS.
YOU LIKE TO READ.
THAT'S A GOOD THING.
AND YOU, UH, ERIC.
WHAT ARE YOUR INTERESTS?
COOL STUFF. ESPIONAGE.
COUNTERINTELLIGENCE.
YOU KNOW, I COULD TELL YOU MORE,
BUT, UH, I'D HAVE TO KILL YOU.
[ Laughter ]
ERIC'S A FREAK!
HE CAN'T EVEN WRITE.
IT'S ALL GIBBERISH.
IT'S NOT GIBBERISH, JOEL.
IT'S A SECRET CODE,
SO KNUCKLE-DRAGGING MOPES...
LIKE YOU CAN'T READ IT.
OH, YEAH?
IT'S PROBABLY A LOVE LETTER
TO YOUR GIRLFRIEND MOLLY
OVER THERE.
[ Laughter ]
ALL RIGHT. CAN WE, UH,
GET BACK ON TRACK HERE?
- [ Laughing, Chattering ]
- UH, CLASS.
- CLASS.
- [ Laughing, Chattering
Continue ]
ENOUGH!
[ Whistles ]
COULD YOU CUT ME
A LITTLE SLACK HERE?
IT'S NOT EASY BEING
THE NEW KID IN SCHOOL.
I'LL BET SOME OF YOU
KNOW ABOUT THAT.
TELL ME SOMETHING.
HOW MANY OF YOU
WERE BORN HERE?
HOW MANY OF YOU SPENT
YOUR WHOLE LIFE IN BOLTON?
MR. BRODIE? I WAS BORN HERE,
BUT MY BROTHER WASN'T.
OKAY. AND HOW MANY OF YOU
HAVE BROTHERS AND SISTERS?
- DOES THIS MEAN WE'RE NOT
GONNA LEARN ABOUT SEX?
- [ Laughter ]
[ Woman ]
IT WAS A CHILD'S
EYEWITNESS TESTIMONY...
THAT SEALED ESPOSITO'S FATE
TO A LIFE IN PRISON.
HOWEVER, JUST LAST MONTH
THE COURT GRANTED ESPOSITO
A NEW TRIAL...
BASED ON A PROCEDURAL
TECHNICALITY.
THE CHARGES AGAINST ESPOSITO
STEM FROM THE BRUTAL MURDER...
OF A BROOKLYN SHOP OWNER.
ACCORDING TO POLICE,
ESPOSITO BLUDGEONED AND THEN
BURIED THE VICTIM'S BODY,
UNAWARE THE CRIME WAS BEING
WITNESSED BY A FIFTH GRADER...
ON A FIELD TRIP FROM NEARBY
WOODBURY ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHAT'S OUR RULE
ABOUT OTHER PEOPLE'S THINGS?
- EXCUSE ME.
- THOSE AREN'T YOUR FILES,
ARE THEY?
UH, NO, BUT THERE WAS
NOBODY IN THE OFFICE
SO I JUST--
OUR RULE ABOUT
OTHER PEOPLE'S THINGS
IS, "WE DON'T TOUCH THEM."
- I UNDERSTAND, BUT THERE WAS--
- BUTTS BELONG IN ASHTRAYS,
MISTER.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, MRS. WARNER.
JAROD'S OUR NEW
SIXTH GRADE TEACHER.
I'LL EXPECT THOSE BACK,
YOUNG MAN.
DON'T WORRY
ABOUT MRS. WARNER.
SHE'S A LIFER.
- A LIFER?
- BEEN HERE 32 YEARS.
TEACHING A 10-YEAR-OLD
IS THE ONLY LANGUAGE SHE KNOWS.
KIND OF SCARY, ISN'T IT?
JUST LIKE BEING IN GRADE
SCHOOL ALL OVER AGAIN.
OR FOR THE VERY FIRST TIME. HI.
HI.
JAROD, RACHEL DALY,
OUR STUDENT COUNSELOR.
JAROD'S TAKING OVER
THE SIXTH GRADERS
WHILE MR. CONKLIN'S IN HAWAII.
YOU BELIEVE CONKLIN'S LUCK?
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN TALKING
ABOUT HAWAII,
AND OUT OF NOWHERE
HE WINS A TRIP.
SAID HE DIDN'T EVEN
REMEMBER ENTERING THE CONTEST.
HMM. UNBELIEVABLE.
WELL, IF YOU'LL
EXCUSE ME,
I'VE GOT A FOURTH GRADER
WHO IS HABITUALLY
PULLING FIRE ALARMS.
NICE TO MEET YOU,
JAROD.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
PRINCIPAL BAUER,
WHILE I'VE GOT YOU HERE--
I HAVE A STUDENT IN MY CLASS--
UH, MATTHEW REESE.
HIS RECORDS ONLY
GO BACK 11 MONTHS,
AND BEFORE THAT...
- IT'S LIKE HE DOESN'T EXIST.
- MATTHEW ONLY MOVED HERE
LAST YEAR.
BUT EVEN STILL,
WOULDN'T HIS OLD SCHOOL
TRANSFER THE RECORDS OVER?
NORMALLY, BUT ACCORDING
TO HIS MOM, HIS LAST
SCHOOL HAD A FIRE.
ALL THE FILES
WERE DESTROYED.
WELL.
I GUESS THAT EXPLAINS IT.
[ Miss Parker ]
RAINES HAS BEEN GOING
TO AN INSANE ASYLUM?
UH, THE PRATT INSTITUTE.
IT'S ABOUT AN HOUR
SOUTH OF HERE.
HE'S BEEN GOING
A COUPLE OF TIMES A DAY.
LOOK. THERE HE IS.
CUE MEN WITH
BIG BUTTERFLY NETS.
NO, NO. HE'S NOT A PATIENT.
HE'S VISITING SOMEONE.
THERE'S A WOMAN.
A WOMAN WHO MEANS
SOMETHING TO JAROD.
THE QUESTION IS,
WHO IS SHE?
[ Sydney ] MY GOD.
SYDNEY?
- [ Sydney ] IT'S EDNA RAINES.
- RAINES'S WIFE?
- IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
- KICK THE ROCK OVER, SYD.
WHAT AM I NOT SEEING?
EDNA RAINES COMMITTED SUICIDE
MORE THAN 20 YEARS AGO.
OR SO
YOU WERE TOLD.
BROOTS, GET A TOWN CAR.
NO, IT'S TOO LATE.
THE GUY AT THE HOSPITAL
TOLD ME SHE ESCAPED LAST NIGHT.
[ Children Laughing,
Chattering ]
OKAY, A TEACHER'S PAY
IS ONE THING, JAROD,
[ Laughing ]
BUT EATING
THE SCHOOL LUNCH--
WHAT, DO YOU HAVE
A DEATH WISH?
I WAS INTRIGUED.
A TUBE OF PROCESSED MEAT
COVERED BY A DEEP-FRIED
CARBOHYDRATE...
AND SKEWERED WITH A STICK
SO THAT IT'S FULLY PORTABLE.
- SORT OF A MEAT POPSICLE.
- IS THAT YOUR FIRST CORN DOG?
MMM. GOOD.
[ Laughs ]
YOU'RE MUCH BRAVER
THAN I AM.
I'VE NOTICED THAT MATTHEW
DOESN'T SOCIALIZE MUCH...
WITH THE OTHER CHILDREN.
ARE THERE ANY ISSUES
ABOUT HIM I SHOULD KNOW ABOUT?
MATTHEW'S BEEN A LITTLE
SLOW ASSIMILATING SINCE
HE TRANSFERRED HERE,
BUT SOME KIDS
ARE JUST LIKE THAT.
- WHY THE INTEREST?
- I JUST FIGURE THE MORE
I KNOW ABOUT MY KIDS,
THE MORE I CAN HELP THEM.
[ Esposito ]
THREE DAYS AND COUNTING.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
YOU'RE GETTING CLOSE.
I WANT TO HEAR
THAT THIS KID IS DEAD.
IF YOU CAN'T FIGURE OUT
WHICH BOY IT IS
AND GET THIS JOB DONE,
THEN I'M GONNA
COME DO IT MYSELF.
YOU BETTER WORRY
THAT I JUST DON'T
BURY YOU WITH HIM.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
- HELLO.
- HI.
MY SON SAID THAT THERE
WAS A NEW TEACHER
IN TOWN,
SO I WANTED TO BRING YOU
A LITTLE SOMETHING
TO SAY WELCOME.
THAT'S VERY NICE.
THANK YOU.
OH!
IT'S HOT.
I'D PROBABLY BETTER DO THIS.
I KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO BE NEW IN TOWN.
MATTHEW AND I JUST
MOVED HERE OURSELVES
LAST YEAR.
YOU SAID, UH, MATTHEW.
MATTHEW REESE?
OH! I'M HIS MOM.
I DIDN'T SAY THAT,
DID I?
- NO.
[ Laughs ]
WHERE DID YOU TWO
MOVE HERE FROM?
FROM BACK EAST.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
EXCUSE ME.
- HELLO.
- UH, HELLO.
- HELLO, JUSTINE.
- HELLO, GAIL.
YOU TWO
KNOW EACH OTHER?
YEAH.
WE'RE IN THE SAME
SINGLE MOMS' COOKING GROUP
HERE IN TOWN.
OH, UH--
MMM.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
[ Jarod ]
IT'S PRETTY COOL, HUH?
YOU CAN SEE A WHOLE WORLD
OF THINGS THAT ARE TOO SMALL
TO SEE WITH YOUR HUMAN EYE.
HEY, MAYBE WE
CAN USE IT TO SEE
ERIC'S TINY LITTLE BRAIN.
- [ Laughter ]
- MR. BRODIE, HOW DO THEY
SWIM AROUND LIKE THAT?
THAT'S A VERY GOOD QUESTION.
WHY DON'T YOU ALL
READ CHAPTER FOUR
AND FIND OUT?
[ Students Groaning ]
I LOST THAT BOOK.
[ Chuckles ]
GET TO WORK.
- IT'S PRETTY NEAT, HUH?
- YEAH.
BUT I'VE SEEN PROTOZOANS
AND STUFF BEFORE.
WE HAD MICROSCOPES
IN THE SCIENCE ROOM
AT MY OLD SCHOOL.
DID YOU LIKE YOUR OLD SCHOOL?
I GUESS.
MUST HAVE BEEN PRETTY TOUGH--
LEAVING YOUR OLD FRIENDS
LIKE THAT.
MOM SAID WE DIDN'T
HAVE A CHOICE.
WE HAD TO MOVE.
I'M NOT REALLY SUPPOSED
TO TALK ABOUT IT.
[ Bell Ringing ]
COME ON, JOEL.
THAT'S FOR MY EYES ONLY.
OH.
I'M SORRY, DUDE.
HERE.
[ Laughs ]
THIS IS SWEET.
IT'S WAY OVER YOUR HEAD.
OH, YEAH? LET'S FIND OUT.
HI. I'M ERIC GANTRY,
AND I'M A SCRAWNY LITTLE FREAK,
AND I'M SO MADLY IN LOVE
WITH MOLLY.
[ Joel On Recorder ]
HI. I'M ERIC GANTRY,
AND I'M A SCRAWNY LITTLE FREAK,
AND I'M SO MADLY IN LOVE
WITH MOLLY.
WHAT'S OUR RULE
ABOUT OTHER PEOPLE'S
THINGS, JOEL?
WHAT?
WE DO NOT TOUCH THEM.
PRETTY MANLY, FREAK--
ALWAYS HAVING A TEACHER
RESCUE YOU.
IT SEEMS
HE HAS IT IN FOR YOU.
IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
WHAT'S A SECRET
AGENT WITHOUT
AN ARCHENEMY, RIGHT?
JUST FORGET ABOUT IT.
- HEY!
- [ Car Starts ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
HEY!
[ Sydney ]
I STILL CAN'T
BELIEVE EDNA'S ALIVE.
[ Miss Parker ]
YOU SOUND AS IF
YOU LIKED HER, SYD.
THERE WAS SOMETHING
MORE ALIVE ABOUT HER.
THERE'S ALSO SOMETHING
FAMILIAR ABOUT HER.
SHE WAS WORKING
AS A PHYSICIAN,
RIGHT HERE AT THE CENTRE,
IN THE STAFF DISPENSARY.
RIGHT.
IN FACT, I THINK SHE SAW ME
WHEN I HAD THE MUMPS.
- YOUR MOTHER TRUSTED HER
COMPLETELY.
- SHE DID?
EDNA, YOU SEE, HAD
MANY ADMIRABLE QUALITIES.
SHE WAS AS VOCAL
IN COMMUNITY POLITICS...
AS SHE WAS AT CENTRE
COCKTAIL PARTIES.
HOW DID SHE END UP
MARRYING RAINES?
AFTER THE MURDER
OF THEIR DAUGHTER,
EDNA FELL APART.
I WAS TOLD SHE TOOK
AN OVERDOSE OF BARBITURATES.
I WAS AT THE FUNERAL, PARKER.
I WONDER WHAT'S
REALLY BURIED OUT THERE
IN THE CENTRE CEMETERY.
I'VE GOT BROOTS OUT
HUNTING FOR EDNA.
[ Sydney ]
RAINES MUST BE DOING THE SAME.
I THINK IT'S TESTING
HIS NEW-FOUND INNER PEACE.
[ Knocking ]
NOT A WORD TO ANYONE, SYDNEY.
GOOD NIGHT.
BROOTS, TELL ME SOMETHING GOOD.
OH, IT'S SO GOOD
TO SEE YOU AGAIN, CATHERINE.
[ Bell Ringing ]
GREAT LITTLE TOWN
LIKE BOLTON--
NEVER THOUGHT WE'D HAVE
SICKOS HANGING AROUND
OUR SCHOOL.
DID YOU GET
A GOOD LOOK AT HIM?
NO, AND HE DIDN'T STICK
AROUND FOR QUESTIONS.
REMINDS ME.
KIDS ARE HAVING
A BIG DANCE ON FRIDAY--
SADIE HAWKINS--
IN LIGHT OF YESTERDAY,
I'D FEEL BETTER IF WE HAD
ANOTHER CHAPERONE THERE.
OH. I LOOK FORWARD TO IT.
AND I CAN'T WAIT
TO MEET THIS MISS HAWKINS.
WAIT, HONEY.
FORGOT YOUR LUNCH.
REMEMBER,
I'M WORKING LATE, OKAY?
SO LEFTOVERS FOR DINNER.
BYE.
EXCUSE ME, MRS. GANTRY.
MY NAME IS JAROD BRODIE.
I'M ERIC'S NEW TEACHER.
I WAS WONDERING
IF I COULD TALK TO YOU
ABOUT SOME TROUBLE HE'S HAVING.
OH, YOU MEAN JOEL?
YEAH, ERIC TOLD ME
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY.
JOEL IS A BIT OF A PROBLEM.
BUT YOU THINK
ERIC'S ALL RIGHT OTHERWISE?
- "OTHERWISE"?
- OH, YOU KNOW,
I JUST WORRY, THAT'S ALL.
YOU KNOW, WITH THIS WHOLE
"SECRET AGENT"...
SPY GAME OF HIS.
PRETENDING ISN'T SO BAD.
YEAH, AS LONG AS
HE'S NOT HIDING IN IT.
BUT IT IS THE SIXTH GRADE.
I'M PROBABLY JUST
BEING SILLY.
HEY, IT'S NOT SILLY
TO CARE ABOUT YOUR SON.
I'LL HAVE A TALK WITH HIM.
[ Bell Ringing ]
THANK YOU.
EXCUSE ME, MRS. WARNER.
THE PARKING STICKER
YOU GAVE ME--
I CAN'T FIND IT ANYWHERE.
I MUST HAVE LOST IT.
BOYS-- THEY'D LOSE THEIR HEADS
IF THEY WEREN'T ATTACHED.
WELL, TECHNICALLY,
LACK OF CRANIAL ATTACHMENT...
WOULD NULLIFY
ALL OTHER MOTOR SKILLS,
THEREFORE THE NOTION--
UH, IF IT HELPS, I BELIEVE
IT WAS STICKER NUMBER 48.
NO, MR. BRODIE, YOU HAD 55.
NUMBER 48 BELONGS
TO LARRY GRASSO,
OUR JANITOR.
THANK YOU.
MR. BRODIE! HI.
MATTHEW FORGOT HIS LUNCH.
SO, I HAVE JUST BEEN
DYING TO KNOW...
WHAT YOU THOUGHT
OF MY RISOTTO.
ACTUALLY, I WAS--
I WAS GOING TO CALL YOU.
REALLY?
THE OTHER EVENING,
WHEN I WAS ASKING YOU
THE QUESTIONS...
ABOUT WHERE
YOU USED TO LIVE--
I KNOW WHY
YOU WERE DODGING THEM.
DID-- DID I GIVE YOU
THAT IMPRESSION?
GAIL, I KNOW WHY
YOU AND MATTHEW
HAD TO MOVE HERE.
YOU CAN TRUST ME.
REALLY.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
HOW HARD IT'S BEEN,
KEEPING THIS A SECRET
AND LIVING THIS LIE.
I MEAN, I-I THOUGHT
THAT HE WAS A NICE GUY.
YOU KNOW, I HAD NO IDEA
ABOUT THE HIDDEN CAMERA.
I GUESS EVERYONE'S
GOT THE INTERNET THESE DAYS.
- AND-- AND BEFORE YOU KNEW IT--
- YOU NEVER LIVED IN WOODBURY?
THERE WAS NO TESTIMONY,
NO TRIAL?
TRIAL?
[ Sydney ]
HOW IS EDNA?
AS VACANT
AS THE BATES MOTEL.
EDNA? DO YOU REMEMBER ME?
WE WERE COLLEAGUES
AT THE CENTRE,
- MANY, MANY YEARS AGO.
- SYDNEY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU DO REMEMBER.
EDNA? EDNA, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
FORGET IT, SYD.
SHE'S BEEN CLAP-ON,
CLAP-OFF ALL AFTERNOON.
TWENTY YEARS OF SEDATION
MUST HAVE TAKEN A DAMAGING
TOLL ON HER BRAIN.
BUT SOMETHING
BROUGHT HER HERE--
SOMETHING BROUGHT HER HERE
LOOKING FOR MY MOTHER.
- WHAT?
- LET'S TRY AND FIND OUT.
WELL, THERE'S ONLY
ONE REASON THE CENTRE
WOULD HAVE GONE TO...
SUCH LENGTHS TO KEEP HER QUIET.
SHE KNOWS THEIR
DIRTY LITTLE SECRETS.
I WANT TO KNOW THEM TOO.
EVEN IF EDNA WERE LUCID,
SHE MAY NOT HAVE
THE CAPACITY TO TELL YOU.
WELL, THIS DIG ISN'T OVER.
TAKES ONE TO KNOW ONE, RIGHT?
MAYBE WE SHOULD
PASS THE SHOVEL TO ANGELO,
AND SEE WHAT HE
CAN FIND IN THERE.
[ Eric ]
TOUGH DAY, HUH?
I'M AFRAID SO, ERIC.
DID YOU JUST GET
SOME BAD NEWS?
YEAH.
WOW.
THAT'S SOME
PRETTY SOPHISTICATED
SPY EQUIPMENT YOU GOT THERE.
WHAT'S THAT THING?
HEY, LOOK AT THIS--
AN OPERATIVE'S COMMUNICATOR.
- YOU KNOW, SO MY SUPERIORS
CAN CONTACT ME.
- WHEN YOU'RE ON A MISSION.
ERIC, JOEL WAS KIND
OF A JERK YESTERDAY,
THE WAY HE WAS MAKING FUN OF YOU
IN FRONT OF EVERYBODY
LIKE THAT.
I TRY NOT TO LET HIM
GET TO ME.
I DON'T REALLY CARE
WHAT HE OR ANY OF THE OTHER
NON-OPERATIVES THINK.
EXCEPT FOR MOLLY, RIGHT?
I SEE THE WAY
YOU LOOK AT HER.
THAT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
TOP SECRET.
AGAIN, STUPID JOEL
COMPROMISED EVERYTHING.
CHECK THIS OUT.
I KEEP ALL MY SECRETS
IN HERE.
YOU DON'T EXACTLY HAVE
THE PROPER CLEARANCE,
BUT, UH, I'LL MAKE
AN EXCEPTION.
WHOA.
- A SURVEILLANCE PHOTO.
NICE GOING.
- SHE PROBABLY HATES ME.
NAH. NO, YOU GOT THAT
DASHING SPY-THING GOING ON.
GIRLS LOVE THAT.
STILL, WHAT DO I DO?
WELL, IF I WERE YOU,
I WOULD JUST...
FACE IT HEAD ON
AND TELL HER HOW YOU FEEL.
NO WAY. SUICIDE MISSION.
WHEN YOU CARE ABOUT SOMEBODY,
YOU'VE GOTTA TELL THEM...
WHILE YOU'VE GOT THE CHANCE.
I WOULDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
HERE.
PRACTICE INTO THIS THING,
AND WHEN YOU GET IT RIGHT,
TELL HER.
[ Bell Ringing ]
MR. BRODIE?
THANKS.
YOU'RE THE FIRST FRIEND
I'VE MADE SINCE I CAME HERE.
[ Eric's Voice ]
YOU'RE THE FIRST FRIEND I MADE
SINCE I CAME HERE.
[ Jarod's Voice ]
HOW MANY OF YOU SPENT
YOUR WHOLE LIFE IN BOLTON?
[ Eric ]
I KEEP ALL MY SECRETS IN HERE.
[ Thinking ]
WOODBURY.
ERIC IS THE WITNESS.
MRS. WARNER,
HAVE YOU SEEN ERIC GANTRY?
HE WAS TALKING TO THE JANITOR
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
THEN I SAW HIM WALKING HOME.
DAMN IT.
MR. BRODIE!
THIS IS AGENT X-4
CHECKING IN.
ERIC! ERIC!
[ Tires Screeching ]
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHERE'S ERIC?
I WAS TRYING
TO HELP THE KID.
YOU'RE A U.S. MARSHAL.
THERE'S A LEAK INSIDE
WITNESS PROTECTION.
I WAS JUST ABOUT
TO PULL ERIC IN.
THEY'RE GONNA KILL HIM
IF YOU DON'T STOP THEM.
WHO?
- WHO SHOT YOU?
- DIDN'T SEE HIM.
GOTTA BE ESPOSITO'S
INSIDE MAN.
YOU HANG ON.
I'M GOING TO GET SOME HELP.
SAVE ERIC.
THE KILLER KNOWS
WHERE HE LIVES.
DON'T LET HIM
GO HOME, JAROD.
DON'T LET HIM GO HOME.
OPERATIVE'S COMMUNICATOR.
SO MY SUPERIORS
CAN CONTACT ME.
[ Beeping ]
[ Muffled Cries ]
SHH, SHH. IT'S ME.
COME ON.
BACK TO MY HOUSE.
LET'S GET YOUR MOM.
WHEN I HEARD THAT ANIMAL
GOT OUT, I WAS, UH--
I WAS SO SCARED.
BUT THEN
WITNESS PROTECTION CALLED
AND THEY SAID NOT TO WORRY,
THAT THEY WERE
SENDING SOMEONE OUT
TO KEEP AN EYE ON US.
THE JANITOR.
ESPOSITO'S MAN
ALREADY GOT TO HIM.
MY GOD.
THEY GAVE ME A NUMBER TO CALL
IN CASE OF AN EMERGENCY.
YOU CAN'T.
THERE'S A LEAK
INSIDE THE AGENCY.
IT'S NOT SAFE.
OKAY. OKAY,
SO WHAT DO WE DO?
WE CALL THE POLICE?
MY GUT SAYS THAT WE STAY
UNDER EVERYBODY'S RADAR--
AT LEAST FOR TONIGHT.
SIT DOWN AND TRY TO RELAX.
MR. BRODIE,
I AM SO, SO SORRY...
THAT I LIED IN CLASS
WHEN YOU ASKED WHO'S
LIVED HERE A LONG TIME.
I MEAN, THEY TOLD ME
THAT SOMETIMES I HAD
TO LIE.
IT'S NOT LIKE I WANTED TO.
ERIC--
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING.
MOM, I'M DONE.
OKAY, HONEY.
HEY. THERE'S EIGHT
CARTONS OF ICE CREAM
IN THE FREEZER.
AFTER YOUR HOMEWORK.
- HE'S A TERRIFIC KID.
- YEAH.
YOU TWO HAVE BEEN
THROUGH A LOT.
YEAH, BUT HE'S JUST A BOY,
AND HE DESERVES A CHILDHOOD...
SURROUNDED BY FAMILY
AND FRIENDS,
AND INSTEAD HE WAS HUSTLED AWAY
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT,
TAKEN AWAY FROM EVERYTHING.
IT'S NOT FAIR.
I KNOW.
AT LEAST HE HAS HIS MOTHER
TO TAKE CARE OF HIM.
MY LITTLE MAN.
I DON'T DESERVE HIM.
I REALLY DON'T.
SAW THE MURDER--
HIS CLASS WAS GOING
ON A FIELD TRIP,
AND ERIC WOKE UP
WITH SOME SNIFFLES
AND A FEVER COMING ON,
AND I REALLY SHOULD HAVE
KEPT HIM HOME,
BUT I DIDN'T.
SEE, I HAD MADE PLANS
THAT DAY.
WHAT HAPPENED WASN'T YOUR FAULT.
I AM HIS MOTHER.
I'M SUPPOSED TO KEEP HIM
SAFE AND HAPPY,
AND HE'S NEITHER.
AND THE WORST PART IS...
THAT ONCE THE NEW TRIAL STARTS,
IT'S GONNA START
ALL OVER AGAIN.
[ Sydney ]
QUIETLY, ANGELO.
I'M TAKING YOU TO SEE
A FRIEND OF MINE--
EDNA.
SYDNEY'S FRIEND DEAD.
NO, SHE'S VERY MUCH ALIVE.
NO. DEAD INSIDE.
THAT IS WHY I NEED
YOUR HELP, ANGELO.
GOT IT?
- WORKING LATE, SYDNEY?
- ISN'T IT PAST BONZO'S BEDTIME?
I HAVE THIS IDEA...
THAT ANGELO MIGHT
BE ABLE TO EMPATH...
- JAROD'S NEXT MOVE.
- YOUR IDEA WILL HAVE TO WAIT.
ANGELO'S SKILLS ARE REQUIRED
IN ANOTHER PURSUIT
AT THE MOMENT.
THAT A PROBLEM?
NO, OF COURSE NOT.
COME ON, MONKEY BOY.
[ Eric ]
MOM, WHAT'S
GONNA HAPPEN TO US?
I DON'T KNOW, KIDDO.
WE MAY HAVE TO PLAY IT
FAST AND LOOSE AGAIN.
MOM, I CAN'T LEAVE.
NOT YET.
HONEY, I DON'T KNOW
THAT WE HAVE A CHOICE.
- MOM, PLEASE. THERE'S
SOMETHING I HAVE TO DO.
- BABY, I'M SO SORRY.
THIS NEVER SHOULD HAVE
HAPPENED TO YOU.
NOW TRY AND GET
SOME SLEEP. OKAY?
SO WHAT NOW?
THE MARSHAL SAID
THAT ESPOSITO'S MAN
IS SOMEONE INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
I FIND HIM
BEFORE HE FINDS US.
[ Beeping ]
MRS. RAINES,
THAT MONSTER...
YOU'RE MARRIED TO
HAS KEPT YOU DOPED UP
FOR THE LAST 20 YEARS.
WHY? WHAT DID YOU KNOW?
SO GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
CATHERINE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'M CATHERINE, YOUR FRIEND.
I'M HERE TO HELP YOU,
BUT YOU NEED TO HELP ME TOO.
SO GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
CATHERINE.
AND I KNOW YOU CAME HERE
TO SEE ME FOR A REASON.
PLEASE... TELL ME
WHAT IT IS.
SO GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
CATHERINE.
LOOK. I'M NOT CATHERINE.
ALL RIGHT?
CATHERINE'S BEEN DEAD
A VERY LONG TIME.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
[ Groans ]
I'M NOT MY MOTHER.
HOW ARE YOUR MUMPS,
LITTLE MISS PARKER?
YOU REMEMBER.
EDNA, PLEASE--
TELL ME WHY
YOU CAME HERE TO SEE ME.
MIRAGE.
"MIRAGE."
WHAT IS MIRAGE?
WHAT YOUR MOTHER STARTED.
WORK SHE HOPED YOU'D FINISH.
WHAT KIND OF WORK?
EDNA? EDNA?
EDNA, STAY WITH ME.
RACHEL.
"RACHEL DALY.
CHICAGO FIELD OFFICE.
"FEDERAL MARSHAL,
WITNESS PROTECTION DIVISION.
CURRENT ASSIGNMENT:
ON LEAVE."
[ Beeping ]
RACHEL DALY.
RACHEL DALY,
THE SCHOOL COUNSELOR?
SHE'S A WITNESS PROTECTION
AGENT FROM OUT OF STATE.
BUT WHY WOULD SHE DO THAT?
MONEY. ERIC'S TESTIMONY...
IS THE ONLY THING
THAT COULD PUT ESPOSITO
BACK IN PRISON.
WHERE IS HE?
UH, HE'S STILL SLEEPING.
I DIDN'T WANT TO WAKE HIM
TILL I HAD TO.
WE HAVE TO GET
YOU TWO OUT OF TOWN.
I'LL DEAL WITH RACHEL LATER.
OH, MY GOD, THEY GOT HIM.
ERIC!
NO. THIS WASN'T FORCED OPEN.
IT WAS UNLOCKED FROM THE INSIDE.
BUT WHY? WHERE WOULD HE GO?
- [ School Bell Ringing ]
- [ Chattering ]
♪♪ [ Pop On P.A. ]
HEY. HI.
UH, MOLLY,
CAN I TALK TO YOU
FOR A SEC?
THERE'S SOMEWHERE
I HAVE TO GO.
YOU KNOW,
IT'S A SECRET MISSION,
BUT I DIDN'T WANT TO LEAVE
BEFORE I TOLD YOU SOMETHING.
YEAH? WHAT?
ALL YEAR LONG, I--
NO. NO, I'M SORRY.
THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEANT.
HERE.
UH, CAN YOU JUST
LISTEN TO THIS?
- PLEASE?
- SURE.
SORRY TO INTERRUPT
YOUR LOVE CONNECTION,
BUT YOU ALREADY GOT A DATE--
WITH MY FIST.
ERIC.
JUST THE YOUNG MAN
I WAS LOOKING FOR.
WHY DON'T YOU COME WITH ME?
THERE'S SOMEONE HERE
TO SEE YOU.
HEY THERE, BUDDY.
REMEMBER ME?
ERIC! ERIC!
[ Jarod ]
MOLLY.
- HAVE YOU SEEN ERIC GANTRY?
- THAT JERK JOEL
CHASED HIM THAT WAY.
ERIC! ERIC!
OH, MY GOD. SHE HAS HIM.
JAROD, WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO?
WHERE COULD THEY
HAVE TAKEN HIM?
WAIT A MINUTE.
SMART BOY, ERIC.
[ Tape Rewinding ]
[ Eric On Tape ]
LEAVE ME ALONE.
[ Esposito ] SHUT UP.
MY GOD.
WHERE ARE YOU TAKING ME?
DON'T WORRY, KID.
IT'S A SHORT WALK.
SORRY I DIDN'T BRING
A HARD HAT.
[ Daly ] COME ON, ERIC.
LET ME GO!
CALL THE POLICE.
[ Eric ]
COME ON!
I SWEAR TO GOD,
I WILL NOT TESTIFY
AGAINST YOU.
PLEASE LET ME GO!
SORRY, KID, BUT AS LONG
AS YOU'RE ALIVE,
YOU STAND TO SERIOUSLY
FOUL UP MY LIFE.
GET IN THE HOLE.
NO!
BE A GOOD BOY, ERIC,
AND DO AS HE SAYS.
BOTH OF YOU.
WHY DON'T YOU
FILL IT YOURSELF?
THANK GOD, JAROD.
- I SAW HIM DRAGGING ERIC HERE
AND I DIDN'T--
- I KNOW, I KNOW.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
I DON'T THINK THIS HOLE
IS FULL ENOUGH.
OH!
YOU OKAY?
UH, YEAH.
GOOD. YOU GO TAKE CARE
OF YOUR MOM NOW. GO.
OKAY.
IT'S KIND OF FITTING,
DON'T YOU THINK?
YOU'VE GOTTEN YOURSELVES
INTO A HOLE...
YOU CAN'T GET OUT OF.
JAROD, COME ON.
COME ON. WE WERE JUST
TALKING TO THAT KID.
OH, YES, LIKE THE WAY
SHE WAS JUST TALKING...
TO THAT FEDERAL MARSHAL--
WHEN SHE MURDERED HIM,
OR THE WAY YOU WERE JUST
TALKING TO THE SHOP OWNER...
TWO YEARS AGO
WHEN HE WAS BLUDGEONED
TO DEATH.
OH. WHOA, WHOA.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
JAROD?
JAROD, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
HE'S CRAZY.
ERIC WAS JUST A BOY.
ALL HE WANTED
WAS HIS CHILDHOOD--
TO BE WITH HIS FAMILY,
TO PLAY WITH HIS FRIENDS.
BUT YOU TOOK
ALL THAT AWAY FROM HIM.
IN AN INSTANT,
EVERYTHING HE KNEW
WAS JUST TAKEN AWAY.
WELL, NOW IT'S YOUR TURN
TO DISAPPEAR,
AND NO ONE
WILL EVER MISS YOU.
OKAY, I DID SELL ERIC OUT,
AND I DID SHOOT THE MARSHAL,
BUT I CAN HELP YOU OUT.
I CAN TESTIFY
AGAINST ESPOSITO.
SHUT UP!
I DON'T KNOW.
WHY DON'T YOU OFFER HER
SOME MORE MONEY, ESPOSITO?
- YOU'RE INSANE.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
- WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
I'M JUST A GUY
WHO'S DIGGING YOUR GRAVE.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT--
YOU TWO ALREADY DUG IT.
I'M JUST FILLING IT IN.
YOU BETTER TALK QUICK.
THIS STUFF DRIES FAST.
ALL RIGHT!
ALL RIGHT, I DID IT!
I SAID I DID IT.
- COME AGAIN?
- I KILLED THE SHOP OWNER.
I HIRED HER TO KILL THE KID.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT TO HEAR?
YES. AS A MATTER
OF FACT, IT IS.
[ Tape Rewinding ]
[ Esposito On Tape ]
I KILLED THE SHOP OWNER
AND I HIRED HER TO KILL THE KID.
IS THAT WHAT
YOU WANT TO HEAR?
YOU'RE STILL
GOING TO DISAPPEAR--
BOTH OF YOU.
[ Daly ] WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
[ Esposito ]
I GAVE YOU WHAT YOU WANTED.
[ Daly, Esposito Shouting ]
JAROD! YOU CAN'T JUST
LEAVE US IN HERE.
WAIT! WAIT!
JAROD!
WHAT ABOUT MIRAGE?
ANYTHING YET?
UH--
[ Clears Throat ]
WELL, I'VE, UH--
I'VE SCANNED THE D.S.A.
FILE DIRECTORY, AND--
THE HEADLINES, BROOTS.
NOT THE FINE PRINT.
NO. NOTHING ON MIRAGE.
MAYBE IT'S JUST NONSENSE.
I MEAN, THIS LADY IS
A LITTLE WHACKED-OUT.
MOST OF THE TIME, YEAH,
BUT NOT WHEN SHE
SAID MIRAGE.
I KNOW IT.
SO--
IT'S BACK
TO THE SALT MINES FOR ME.
[ Bell Ringing ]
COME ON, JOEL.
WHAT DID YOU BRING
FOR ME TODAY, FREAK?
WHAT'S THIS? BROWNIES?
OH.
DON'T, JOEL.
YOU'LL BE SORRY.
OH, I HAVEN'T
BEEN SORRY YET.
[ Snickers ]
MMM!
MMM! THAT'S GOOD.
TOO BAD YOUR MOTHER
DIDN'T MAKE YOU ANY, FREAK.
PATIENCE.
IT WON'T BE LONG,
WITH THE AMOUNT...
OF PRUNE EXTRACT
WE PUT IN 'EM.
I WOULD SAY RIGHT...
ABOUT...
NOW.
[ Rumbling ]
I WONDER WHAT
CAME OVER HIM.
SOMETHING HE ATE, MAYBE?
HMM.
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
NO!
WELL, AGENT GANTRY,
MISSION ACCOMPLISHED.
[ Bell Ringing ]
EXCUSE ME.
SEEN THE PAPER
THIS MORNING?
NOW, I CAN'T UNDERSTAND...
HOW THEY GOT THE STORY,
AND YET THERE'S NOT
ONE MENTION ABOUT THE GUY...
WHO MADE IT ALL HAPPEN.
TEACHING CAN BE SUCH
A THANKLESS PROFESSION.
NOT ENTIRELY.
- THANK YOU, JAROD.
- THANKS, MR. BRODIE.
ERIC, CAN I TALK
TO YOU FOR A SEC?
I LISTENED TO YOUR TAPE.
IT WAS SWEET.
I'M REALLY GLAD
YOU GAVE IT TO ME.
- REALLY?
- MM-HMM.
SO I WAS WONDERING--
DO YOU WANT TO GO
TO THE SADIE HAWKINS DANCE
WITH ME TOMORROW NIGHT?
YEAH! I-I MEAN--
- OF COURSE I DO.
- GOOD.
I'LL... SEE YOU IN CLASS.
MOM, WE DON'T HAVE
TO LEAVE TONIGHT, DO WE?
DOES A CERTAIN SECRET AGENT
HAVE ONE LAST RENDEZVOUS?
YEAH.
[ Miss Parker ]
SHE OKAY, SAM?
SHE WENT AND LAID DOWN.
I HAVEN'T HEARD
A WORD FROM HER.
MRS. RAINES? EDNA?
[ Whispering ]
OH, MAN.
NOW WE'RE LEFT
EMPTY-HANDED.
NOT EXACTLY.
I STILL HAVE MIRAGE.
♪ KRI KRA TOAD'S FOOT ♪
♪ GEESE WALK BAREFOOT ♪
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
♪ KRI KRA TOAD'S FOOT-- ♪
[ Edna ]
♪ KRI KRA TOAD'S FOOT ♪
♪ GEESE WALK BAREFOOT ♪♪