[ Broots ] JAROD SENT THESE.
FROM WHAT I CAN TELL, ALL TAKEN
WITHIN THE LAST FEW WEEKS.
THERE'S PORTLAND,
HOUSTON, LEXINGTON.
SOMEONE'S
BEEN TRACKING US?
NOT US--
YOU. LOOK.
FEELS LIKE THE HUNTER'S
BECOMING THE HUNTED.
[ Ringing ]
- WHAT?
- SOMEONE HAS EYES FOR YOU.
THE QUESTION IS, WHO?
[ Jarod ]
SOMETIMES THE ANSWER
IS THE QUESTION.
DON'T GET KWAI CHANG
ON ME, JAROD.
OOH, I LOVE THAT GUY,
WANDERING THE EARTH,
HELPING PEOPLE.
LIKE I'M TRYING TO HELP YOU
AND YOUR FATHER.
MY FATHER? JAROD.
[ Dial Tone ]
WHAT DID HE MEAN,
HELP YOUR FATHER?
DAMN IT.
WHAT IS IT, PARKER?
MY FATHER IS
STILL IN HIDING,
BUT I RECEIVED A CRYPTIC E-MAIL
FROM HIM THIS MORNING.
DADDY TOLD ME
NOT TO TRUST ANYONE.
THERE'S A CENTRE CONTRACT
OUT ON MY FATHER.
WELL, THEN WHY-WHY
DID HE FOLLOW YOU?
THEY PROBABLY THINK
I'LL EVENTUALLY LEAD THEM
TO THE REAL TARGET.
[ Barking ]
[ Chattering ]
DON'T ANYBODY TOUCH MY CARDS,
OR IT'LL GET UGLY!
YEAH, HUH.
AND HARRY CHEATS.
YEAH, YEAH.
[ Barking Continues ]
DAMN RACCOONS.
[ Footsteps Running ]
[ Barking Continues ]
[ Growling ]
[ Mumbling ]
I GOT SOMETHING
FOR YOUR GARBAGE-EATIN'
LITTLE ASS.
- [ Barking, Whining ]
- [ Screaming ]
THE FISH IS SWIMMING
ALONG HAPPILY IN
ITS NATURAL ENVIRONMENT.
YOU DROP THE HOOK IN,
YOU YANK IT OUT,
YOU CATCH HIM.
-AND THEN AFTER ALL THAT,
YOU RELEASE HIM?
-IT'S REALLY NOT THAT CONFUSING.
[ Siren Wailing ]
TELL THAT TO THE FISH.
HEY, BOY.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
HUNTERS CAUGHT SOMETHING FREAKY
UP IN THE MOUNTAINS.
[ Chattering ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Screams ]
- [ Man ]
IS THAT A BOY OR A GIRL?
- [ Gasps ]
- GET AWAY FROM THE WINDOW.
- [ Man ]
LOOK.
WHAT KIND OF CREATURE
IS THAT ANYWAY?
[ Grunting ]
COME ON NOW. COME ON.
[ Woman ] I THINK IT'S A GIRL.
DON'T MAKE IT ANY HARDER
THAN IT HAS TO BE.
[ Groaning ]
[ Woman ]
OH, THAT POOR THING.
- COME ON.
GET IN THE CAR.
- [ Whimpering ]
I'LL TAKE THAT.
YOU EVER SEE ANYTHING
LIKE THAT BEFORE?
[ Mumbling ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE DEFENDS THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
[ Mumbling ]
[ Man ] LOCATE DR. BENNETT
RIGHT AWAY.
GET A LAB CREW, LINGUIST,
PEDIATRICIAN.
- I VOTE FOR A VETERINARIAN.
- THE STATE IS SENDING ONE
OF THEIR PEOPLE TO OBSERVE.
[ Man ]
A SOCIAL WORKER?
PSYCHIATRIST.
- WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
- [ Gasps ]
- OH! DAMN IT!
- OH, STOP HER!
GO! GO!
SOMEBODY STOP HER!
[ Groans, Hits Ground ]
[ Man ]
IT'S LIKE SHE'S NEVER
SEEN A WINDOW BEFORE.
IT'S OKAY.
EVERYTHING IS GOING TO BE OKAY.
IT'S OKAY. I'M NOT
GONNA HURT YOU, HONEY.
I'M JUST GONNA
CLEAN THIS UP.
[ Whimpers ]
HOW YOU FEELING? HMM?
ALL RIGHT.
I'M ALMOST DONE.
YOU'RE MAKING A BIG MISTAKE
DEALING WITH HER LIKE THIS.
SHE'S AFRAID TO BE TOUCHED.
WE'LL INSTRUCT OUR OWN STAFF,
IF YOU DON'T MIND, DOCTOR--
BELL. JAROD BELL.
THE STATE SHRINK FROM PROVO.
YOUR OFFICE CONTACTED US
ABOUT YOUR ARRIVAL.
THIS IS DOCTOR BENNETT.
HOW DO YOU DO?
HELLO.
I'M DR. WOLVERTON.
I READ YOUR BOOK, THE EFFECTS
OF ISOLATION AND DEPRIVATION
ON THE HUMAN PSYCHE.
YOUR THEORIES PROMPTED
A GREAT DEAL OF DEBATE WITHIN
THE PSYCHIATRIC COMMUNITY.
MY WRITINGS ARE CONTROVERSIAL
BECAUSE THEY PUSH THE ENVELOPE
OF PSYCHOSOCIAL MEDICINE.
WELL, IT'S ALWAYS DIFFICULT
TO BREAK FROM THE PACK.
GIVEN HER PHYSICAL
APPEARANCE AND HER LACK
OF VERBAL SKILLS,
SHE MUST HAVE BEEN ISOLATED
AT A VERY YOUNG AGE.
THE QUESTION IS,
WHAT MADE HER SUDDENLY
DECIDE TO MAKE CONTACT.
- EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE OKAY.
- [ Whimpers ]
WE SHOW HER KINDNESS,
WE ESTABLISH SOME KIND
OF TRUST,
AND SHE'LL BEGIN TO COMMUNICATE
IN HER OWN WAY.
WE DON'T HAVE THAT KIND OF TIME.
WITH NO LEGAL GUARDIAN,
WE LOSE HER TO SOCIAL SERVICES
IN 36 HOURS.
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO FIND ANY FAMILY?
NO, THE POLICE ARE RUNNING
HER PICTURE ON THE NET.
UNTIL THEN,
I SUGGEST WE TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF THE TIME WE HAVE LEFT WITH
OUR ONE-OF-A-KIND SPECIMEN.
BRING HER OUT.
WE WERE LOOKING FOR YOU.
GOOD NEWS, I HOPE.
WELL-- [ Clears Throat ]
THE NUMBERS ON THESE PHOTOGRAPHS
ARE LEVEL ONE ENCRYPTION CODES,
USED EXCLUSIVELY FOR
TRIUMVIRATE COMMUNIQUÉS.
MUTUMBO?
THE ASSASSIN
UPLOADED THEM THROUGH
OUR SATELLITES TO AFRICA.
I WAS ABLE TO ISOLATE
THE KILLER'S DESIGNATION.
HE CALLS HIMSELF "THE OWL."
AND ACCORDING TO
PERSONNEL FILES,
THAT DESIGNATION
IS USED BY MR. COX.
THE GRIM REAPER.
YOU CAN'T SAY JAROD
DIDN'T WARN US.
[ Laughs ] BROOTS,
I WANNA KNOW EVERYTHING ABOUT
OUR PICTURE-TAKING FREAK.
UH, MISS PARKER, I RAN
MR. COX THROUGH THE DATABASE.
HE CAME UP EMPTY.
THE GUY IS
A BLANK SLATE.
THE ONLY PROOF THAT WE HAVE
THAT HE EXISTS IS THE FACT
THAT WE'RE LOOKING AT HIM.
SWEEP HIS OFFICE.
HE DOESN'T HAVE ONE.
BUT GET THIS.
I-I TALKED TO MY FRIEND RORY
IN PURCHASING.
THE FELLOW WITH
THE ARTIFICIAL LEG?
NO, THAT'S RUDY
IN PUBLIC INFORMATION.
RORY'S THE ONE WITH THE
BIRTHMARK ON HIS HEAD SHAPED--
[ Stomps ]
LIKE GUMBY.
OKAY. ANYWAY, RORY TOLD ME THAT
MR. COX HAS BEEN MAIL ORDERING
SURGICAL SUPPLIES...
AND HAVING THEM DELIVERED
AT THE CENTRE.
TRACK THE DELIVERIES.
I'M ON IT.
WHAT IF MR. COX REALLY
IS THE GRIM REAPER?
ALL THE MORE REASON TO MAKE SURE
HE DOESN'T FIND MY FATHER.
HMM.
[ Banging ]
MAKE SURE TO KEEP
HER ROOM WARM.
YES, MA'AM.
THANK YOU.
I HATE TO SEE HER
KEPT IN THIS PLACE.
I'M DR. SULVANE-- ANNE.
DR. JAROD BELL.
I'M THE STATE PSYCH.
SHE NEEDS FAMILIAR SURROUNDINGS.
PLANTS, GRASS, SUNSHINE.
MM-HMM.
I'M SORRY. I'M AFRAID
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
WE HAVE TO KEEP
HER ENVIRONMENT STERILE.
IF SHE'S BEEN ISOLATED HER
ENTIRE LIFE, WE DON'T KNOW WHAT
HER IMMUNE SYSTEM CAN HANDLE.
WELL, HER VITAL SIGNS
ARE OFF THE CHART. B.P. IS
200 OVER 120, PULSE IS 150.
- AT LEAST LET ME GIVE HER
A MILD SEDATIVE.
- NO MEDS.
AND I WANT MINIMAL INTERACTION.
WE'RE ONLY HERE TO OBSERVE.
HOW DO YOU EXPECT TO FIND OUT
WHO SHE IS IF YOU DON'T TRY
TO COMMUNICATE WITH HER?
SHE'S UNABLE
TO COMMUNICATE, DOCTOR.
AND THE HARD TRUTH IS,
SHE'S NOT GOING TO LEARN
FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
I AGREE WITH DR. WOLVERTON.
WE HAVE A ONCE-IN-A-LIFETIME
OPPORTUNITY TO STUDY THE VERY
CORE OF THE HUMAN ANIMAL.
SPECIMEN, ANIMAL.
HOW ABOUT HUMAN BEING?
[ Banging Continues ]
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE US,
WE'VE GOT TO GO MEET
WITH THE PRESS.
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Sighs ]
ARE YOU OKAY?
[ Anne ]
I JUST CAN'T GET PAST
HER EYES--
HOW SAD THEY LOOK,
HOW LOST.
YOU KNOW, IT ONLY TAKES
ONE PERSON TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
CARDINAL RULE OF TRAUMATIZED
PATIENTS, DR. BELL:
DO NOT INVEST EMOTIONALLY.
HOW COME I DON'T THINK
YOU REALLY BELIEVE THAT?
[ Banging Continues ]
WHERE DID YOU COME FROM,
LITTLE GIRL?
[ Chattering ]
DOCTOR! DOCTOR!
IS THE LITTLE GIRL
ABLE TO SPEAK?
DOES SHE UNDERSTAND ANYTHING?
HOW LONG HAS SHE BEEN
IN THE WILDERNESS?
FIRST OF ALL,
WE DON'T HAVE ANY ANSWERS
AS OF YET.
BUT THIS IS THE FINEST
PRIVATE RESEARCH FACILITY
IN THE STATE.
AND WE'VE ASSEMBLED
A TEAM OF SPECIALISTS WHO ARE
THE BEST IN THEIR FIELDS.
- WAS THERE ANY SIGN OF ABUSE?
- HOW IS SHE HOLDING UP
EMOTIONALLY?
[ Wolverton ] AS DR. BENNETT
SAID, WE HAVE AN EXPERT TEAM
WORKING ON THE SITUATION.
NOW, WE'LL KEEP YOU UPDATED
AS THE SITUATION WARRANTS.
NO MORE QUESTIONS.
THANK YOU.
[ Chattering ]
NO MORE QUESTIONS.
THANK YOU.
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Man ]
GIVE US THE ANSWER TO
A SIMPLE QUESTION, DOCTOR.
SHE'S PRETTY.
- ARE YOU ON DR. BENNETT'S TEAM?
- NOT EXACTLY.
DR. JAROD BELL.
LESLIE TWAIN.
I'M WITH
THE SALT LAKE CHRONICLE.
IF YOU COULD JUST LET ME GET
A COUPLE OF PICTURES, A BRIEF
INTERVIEW FOR MY PAPER,
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO HELP YOU
FIGURE OUT WHO SHE IS.
MY STORY WOULD BE SYNDICATED
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY AND--
DR. BELL IS NOT AT LIBERTY
TO GIVE INTERVIEWS.
REST ASSURED, EVERYTHING
IS UNDER CONTROL.
[ Glass Shatters ]
I'M SORRY, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO GO JOIN THE OTHERS
RIGHT NOW.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHERE THE HELL
DID SHE GO? WHERE?
DID YOU CHECK
THE MAIN BUILDING?
TOP TO BOTTOM.
SHE HAS TO BE SOMEWHERE
ON THE GROUNDS.
WHAT ABOUT THE PRESS?
WE MOVED THEM
IN THE COMMISSARY.
WAIT A MINUTE. WHAT ARE YOU
PLANNING ON DOING WITH THAT?
IT'S FOR HER OWN SAFETY.
THAT WEAPON WAS NOT MEANT
TO BE USED ON HUMANS.
THE SUBJECT IS IN
A TOTAL STATE OF--
THE SUBJECT...
IS A LITTLE GIRL WHO
IS SCARED OUT OF HER MIND.
PLEASE, DOCTOR.
LET US DO OUR WORK.
[ Chattering ]
[ Woman On P.A. ]
DR. WILSON, CALL EXTENSION 11.
DR. WILSON, EXTENSION 11.
WHAT NOW?
WE FIND HER FIRST.
COME ON.
- HERE WE GO.
TAKE MY COAT.
- OKAY.
- [ Gasps, Whimpers ]
- IT'S OKAY.
IT'S OKAY.
I'M NOT GOING TO HURT YOU.
HERE.
GO AHEAD.
TAKE HER.
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Laughs ]
YOU THINK THAT'S FUNNY?
- I GUESS THAT IS PRETTY FUNNY.
[ Laughs ]
- [ Laughs ]
[ Sighs ]
SHE SEEMS TO BE REACTING TO
THE CHANGE IN HER ENVIRONMENT.
HMM.
HER VITALS ARE STABLE.
SHE'S BREATHING EASIER.
SO WHAT DID YOU SAY TO HER
UP IN THAT TREE?
NOTHING.
WE JUST LAUGHED.
WHAT ARE THOSE PLANTS
DOING IN THERE?
THAT ROOM WAS
TO BE KEPT STERILE.
THEY CAN'T HARM HER.
[ Wolverton ]
THIS IS TOO MUCH INTERACTION.
THE SUBJECT IS TOO IMPORTANT.
THE SUBJECT? WHY DON'T
WE GIVE HER A NAME?
ASSIGNING HER A NAME IS
ASSIGNING HER A PERSONALITY.
IT COULD PREJUDICE THE RESULTS
OF THE CASE STUDY.
VIOLET.
VIOLET. I LIKE IT.
- [ Babbles ]
- SHE SPOKE.
[ Babbling Continues ]
- WH-WHAT IS SHE SAYING?
- IT'S MIMICRY.
RANDOM PHONETICS.
NO. SHE'S TRYING
TO TELL US SOMETHING.
[ Babbling Continues ]
- [ Anne ]
WHAT'S HAPPENING TO HER?
- SHE'S GOING INTO SEIZURE.
HELP ME HOLD HER DOWN.
[ Groaning ]
MY GOD, SHE'S BURNING UP.
DR. BENNETT,
I NEED MY MEDICAL BAG.
GET MY BAG NOW!
[ Gasps ]
[ Woman On P.A. ]
SOCIAL SERVICES,
PLEASE CALL 571.
HEY. YOU SHOULD GO HOME
AND GET SOME SLEEP.
LATER.
THE RESULTS OF THE TESTS
CAME BACK.
IT WAS A COMMON FLU STRAIN.
IT WENT RIGHT THROUGH
HER DEFENSES.
WELL, SHE RESPONDED
TO THE MEDICATION.
IT WAS SCARY TO SEE HER
SO HELPLESS.
ARE YOU INVESTING
EMOTIONALLY, DOCTOR?
[ Laughs ]
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT.
HER ROOM WAS STERILE,
THE PLANTS WERE INDIGENOUS,
AND NONE OF US
EXHIBITED SYMPTOMS
OF BEING SICK.
- I DON'T KNOW WHERE
THE VIRUS CAME FROM.
- [ Grunting ]
OH, SHE WANTS HER DOLL.
IT'S THE ONLY THING
THAT CALMS HER.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THIS IS A COCKTAIL
OF COLD AND FLU STRAINS.
THERE MUST BE AT LEAST
10 SEPARATE VIRUSES HERE.
OR 12.
YOU THINK SOMEONE PURPOSELY
INFECTED THIS DOLL?
UNLESS YOU BELIEVE THAT
A DOZEN INFECTIOUS VIRUSES...
MAGICALLY INFESTED
THE SAME SQUARE INCH
OF MATERIAL.
WELL, I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHY?
SOMEONE CLOSE TO THE SITUATION
IS AFRAID THAT VIOLET IS
GOING TO BEGIN TO COMMUNICATE.
WHAT YOU'RE IMPLYING
IS CRAZY.
THESE MEN ARE THE TOP
IN THEIR FIELDS.
WOLVERTON'S RESEARCH
HAS SAVED THOUSANDS,
AND BENNETT'S WORK WITH P.O.W.'s
IN ISOLATION IS GROUNDBREAKING.
I KNOW THE RECORD.
I DON'T KNOW THE MEN.
WE HAVE TO GET THAT
LITTLE GIRL OUT OF HERE.
I CAN'T BE A PART OF THIS.
I SEE THE WAY YOU LOOK AT HER.
IT'S NOT JUST A DOCTOR-PATIENT
RELATIONSHIP.
WHAT ARE YOU SO AFRAID OF,
ANNE?
I HAD A SON-- MATTHEW.
HE WAS A LITTLE YOUNGER
THAN VIOLET WHEN HE GOT SICK.
I TOOK HIM TO THE BEST CLINICS
IN THE COUNTRY,
THE BEST DOCTORS.
- BUT I COULDN'T SAVE HIM.
- I'M SORRY.
LOSING HIM NEARLY KILLED ME.
I CANNOT GO THROUGH
THOSE FEELINGS AGAIN.
NOT AGAIN.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Bennett ]
DR. BELL. DR. BELL!
DR. BENNETT.
I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU'VE LOCATED
THE SOURCE OF THE ILLNESS.
YES, AS MATTER OF FACT, I DID.
I WAS GOING TO SHOW IT
TO YOU IN THE MORNING.
IT SEEMS THAT THE INFECTION
CAME FROM HER DOLL.
THIS IS VERY DISTURBING.
[ Clattering ]
WHAT WAS THAT?
DR. BENNETT.
SHE'S NOT IN HER ROOM.
WHAT?
THE LITTLE GIRL IS GONE.
DAMN IT. DAMN IT!
VIOLET. VIOLET,
WHERE ARE YOU?
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
IT'S OKAY. IT'S MY CAR.
IT'S OKAY, HONEY. IT'S OKAY.
YOU OKAY?
WAIT, WAIT. STOP, STOP.
I'D LIKE A SECOND CHANCE
TO HELP, IF YOU'LL LET ME.
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME COX
HAS PULLED OVER. WHAT THE HELL
IS HE LOOKING FOR?
I NEVER PICTURED COX AS
THE PICKUP TRUCK KIND OF GUY.
[ Sighs ]
[ Miss Parker ]
YEAH, WELL, HE'S A BLANK SLATE,
REMEMBER?
OH, WHICH REMINDS ME,
I TALKED TO RORY IN PURCHASING.
HE SAID HE DIDN'T KNOW
WHERE COX HAD THE SURGICAL
TOOLS DELIVERED.
- WE'RE GOING IN CIRCLES.
- WAIT A MINUTE.
- WHAT'S HE DOING
WITH THE SHOVEL?
- OH, CRIMINY.
THAT'S A DEAD SOMETHING.
HE'S TAKING PICTURES
OF ROADKILL, JUST LIKE HE DID
WHEN HE WAS TRACKING YOU.
FLATTERING COMPARISON.
THANK YOU.
TELL ME HE DIDN'T
JUST SCOOP THAT WORM BANQUET
INTO THE TRUCK.
EW. WHAT NOW?
STAY WITH HIM. IF THAT PSYCHO
GETS TO MY FATHER,
WE'RE ALL ROADKILL.
WHAT MAKES YOU SO SURE
THAT THIS IS WHERE
SHE CAME FROM?
THE WINTERS IN THE REGION
ARE FAR TOO BRUTAL...
FOR ANYONE TO SURVIVE
WITHOUT SOME KIND
OF HEAT SOURCE.
ACCORDING TO THIS MAP, THERE'S
JUST ONE HOT SPRING IN THE AREA.
[ Airplane Passing Overhead ]
[ Babbles ]
COME ON.
THE WATER'S WARM.
HER HOME MUST BE CLOSE.
[ Laughs ]
[ Jingling ]
HMM.
INTERESTING.
WHERE DID SHE GET THE GLASS?
OR THIS?
WHAT IS IT, JAROD?
I THINK IT MIGHT BE VIOLET
WITH HER PARENTS.
GOD. COULD IT BE POSSIBLE?
[ Babbles ]
[ Babbling Continues ]
WHERE IS SHE GOING NOW?
[ Anne ]
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S A WRECKED PLANE.
JAROD, IT'S HER PARENTS.
DA.
MA.
DA, MA.
- WHAT IS IT?
- LOOKS LIKE SOME KIND
OF VIDEO CABLE.
[ Clock Chiming ]
HOW'S SHE DOING?
RESTING.
[ Sighs ] COULD SOMEONE
HAVE KNOWN ABOUT HER BEING
OUT THERE AND DONE NOTHING?
YES. FROM THE LOOKS
OF THESE PHOTOS, IT'S BEEN
GOING ON FOR OVER 10 YEARS.
THIS IS PERSONAL TO YOU,
ISN'T IT?
YES. IT'S PERSONAL.
YOU WANNA TALK ABOUT IT?
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE ME
IF I TOLD YOU.
TRY ME.
- SOME OTHER TIME, MAYBE.
- OH, WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO FIND OUT WHO DID THIS.
DID SOMEONE DIE?
YES.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
YOU REALLY WERE
AT A FUNERAL.
IN DOVER.
MR. COX, HE SPENT
THE NIGHT THERE. HE'S PRETTY
CHUMMY WITH THE OWNER.
THE OLD GUY?
I'M RUNNING HIM DOWN,
BUT I DON'T THINK...
HE HAS ANY CONNECTION
TO THE CENTRE.
WEIRD THING THOUGH,
MR. COX ONLY CAME AND WENT
THROUGH THE BACK DOOR.
WITH HEFTY BAGS.
YEAH, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S IN THEM.
WHAT COMES OUT THE BACK DOOR
OF A MORTUARY?
BODY PARTS.
WELL, WHATEVER WAS IN THEM,
HE HAD SENT TO
THE EAST WING OF SL 6.
EAST WING.
THAT WAS THE INFIRMARY
WHEN I WAS A KID.
I GOT MY TONSILS
TAKEN OUT THERE.
WELL, I DON'T THINK
HE'S HANDING OUT LOLLIPOPS
TO LITTLE GIRLS.
- NOT LIVE ONES, ANYWAY.
- EW.
I THINK IT'S TIME WE PAID
THE GRIM REAPER A VISIT.
[ Clears Throat ]
GIVE ME THE PHOTOS.
WHAT ARE WE DOING HERE?
I'M GONNA LEAVE THESE
FOR COX.
LET HIM KNOW
HE'S BEING WATCHED TOO.
[ Clinks ]
DID YOU LOSE SOMETHING,
MR. BROOTS?
[ Electricity Humming,
Crackling ]
LOVE WHAT YOU'VE DONE
WITH THE PLACE.
[ Sniffs ]
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU HAD YOUR TONSILS
REMOVED HERE, DIDN'T YOU?
WELL, I HAD TO CLEAN OUT
THE OLD FILE CABINETS.
OUT WITH THE FILES,
IN WITH THE BODY PARTS?
HANGIN' AT THE MORTUARY.
MYSTERIOUS BAGS
OF GOD KNOWS WHAT.
SCOOPING ROADKILL.
- YOU FOLLOWED ME?
- YOU TAKE SURVEILLANCE PHOTOS
OF ME,
YOU BETTER BE PREPARED
FOR A LITTLE RETALIATION.
WHO'S THE GRAY HAIR?
HIS NAME IS CARL.
HE'S MY FATHER.
YOUR-YOUR FATHER'S
THE MORTICIAN?
MMM.
WE USED TO HAVE LONG TALKS
ABOUT LIFE...
WHILE HE WAS EMBALMING
THE CORPSES.
NOW WE JUST EXCHANGE
TRICKS OF THE TRADE
FOR MY HOBBY.
MY FATHER GAVE ME
AN ERECTOR SET ONCE.
- HOBBY?
- MMM.
TAXIDERMY.
WELL, IT'S A SECOND CHANCE
AT LIFE AS A PART
OF MY COLLECTION.
THE EYES HAVE TO BE REPLACED
WITH GLASS ORBS.
YOU KNOW, IN SOME CULTURES
I'M STEALING ITS ABILITY...
TO SEE ITS WAY
INTO THE AFTERLIFE.
WELL, THAT'S DAD'S THEORY,
ANYWAY.
DADDIES CAN BE SO MUCH FUN.
SPEAKING OF WHICH.
HOW IS YOUR FATHER
THESE DAYS?
WOULDN'T YOU LOVE TO KNOW?
OH, MISS PARKER.
THOSE PICTURES OF YOU--
I DIDN'T TAKE THEM.
[ Electricity Humming,
Crackling ]
BUT...
I WILL BE KEEPING
AN EYE ON YOU.
THIS IS ONE FROM THE EARLIER
SURVEILLANCE TAPES.
THE FOOTAGE WAS TAKEN
NEAR THE CRASH SITE.
THESE SHOTS WERE TAKEN
THREE YEARS LATER.
[ Anne ]
I CAN'T BELIEVE SHE SURVIVED
ALL THOSE YEARS ALONE.
[ Jarod ]
SHE WAS LIVING
ON PURE INSTINCT.
THIS WHERE SHE GOT THE WOUND
ON HER ANKLE.
[ Screams ]
THAT'S SOME KIND
OF ANIMAL TRAP.
[ Screaming ]
HOW LONG WAS SHE CAUGHT
IN THAT THING?
ACCORDING TO THE LOGBOOK,
THREE DAYS.
- WHO COULD'VE DONE
SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
- WATCH.
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
MY GOD,
IT'S DR. WOLVERTON.
I'LL BE DAMNED.
NO.
BUT HE WILL BE.
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
COX IS TELLING THE TRUTH?
[ Clears Throat ]
I WAS DIGGING AROUND,
AND I FOUND THIS--
LYLE'S EXPENSE ACCOUNT.
THREE WEEKS AGO,
LYLE BOUGHT A VERY EXPENSIVE
LEICA CAMERA.
WELL, WHAT KIND OF CAMERA
DO YOU THINK TOOK THOSE SHOTS?
AND THEN THERE'S THIS.
A CENTRE MEMO.
LYLE NOT ONLY BROUGHT
MR. COX TO THE CENTRE,
BUT HE CREATED HIS POSITION.
MY BROTHER IS BEHIND THE HIT.
HE'S TRYING TO KILL DADDY?
YOU HAVE LOST YOUR MIND.
YOU TOOK THESE PHOTOS.
COX IS A CENTRE ASSASSIN,
AND HE WORKS FOR YOU.
YOU'RE SUGGESTING THAT
I WOULD HAVE MY FATHER--
OUR FATHER-- KILLED?
STOP TRYING TO MAKE YOURSELF
A PART OF THIS FAMILY.
IF YOU LOOKED--
REALLY LOOKED--
YOU WOULD SEE THAT
I'M JUST TRYING TO HELP HIM,
THE SAME WAY YOU ARE.
YEAH, I GOT AN E-MAIL
FROM DAD TOO.
SCARED THE HELL OUT OF ME.
HE'S ON THE EDGE OF
SOMETHING TERRIFYING.
HE TOLD ME TO TAKE
THE PHOTOS AND LEAK THEM
TO THE TRIUMVIRATE...
TO START ESTABLISHING A PATTERN
FOR YOUR ALIBI.
- ALIBI FOR WHAT?
- I DON'T KNOW.
HE SUGGESTED I START
A PAPER TRAIL FOR MYSELF TOO.
SOMETHING BIG
IS GOING DOWN.
SO BIG, MUTUMBO'S
COMING TO TOWN.
MUTUMBO'S COMING HERE?
ACCORDING TO DAD,
TO MEET WITH COX.
I SHOULDN'T BE TELLING YOU THIS.
HE TOLD ME NOT TO TRUST ANYONE.
HE TOLD ME THE SAME THING.
SO WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
WE WAIT, AND WE PRAY.
[ Bell Tolling ]
[ Shudders ]
[ Grumbles ]
DON'T BE AFRAID.
HERE'S YOUR DOLL.
I'VE BEEN WATCHING YOU
FOR A LONG TIME.
I WAS AN OBSERVER.
I NEVER INTERFERED.
I NEVER HARMED YOU.
GOD KNOWS THAT,
AND SO DO YOU.
[ Mutters ]
YOUR FATE WAS DETERMINED
BY THE LAWS OF NATURE,
NOT MAN, NOT ME.
HERE.
I'M SORRY I HAVE TO DO THIS,
BUT I CAN'T LET ANYBODY
FIND OUT.
[ Groaning ]
SO WHO'S THE ANIMAL NOW,
DOCTOR?
[ Whistling ]
HUH? OH. OH.
WHAT THE--
WHERE AM I?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
[ Jarod ]
DISORIENTING, ISN'T IT?
IMAGINE HOW IT MUST HAVE FELT
FOR A FOUR-YEAR-OLD LITTLE GIRL.
GIVE ME MY CLOTHES.
OW!
[ Groans ]
MY SHOES!
I'D LIKE TO, BUT I WOULDN'T
WANNA CONTAMINATE THE INTEGRITY
OF MY CASE STUDY.
BESIDES, VIOLET HAD NOTHING
WHEN YOU FOUND HER.
IT WOULD'VE BEEN NO DIFFERENT
IF I HADN'T FOUND HER.
I WAS JUST AN OBSERVER!
IT WAS A SCIENTIFIC STUDY.
OH, AND IT PAID OFF
FOR YOU, DIDN'T IT?
BOOKS, RESEARCH GRANTS,
CELEBRITY STATUS.
OH.
ONLY YOUR DATA WASN'T BASED
ON SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH.
IT WAS BASED ON THE TERROR
OF AN ORPHANED CHILD!
[ Groans ]
HOW LONG DID SHE STARVE
ALONE IN THE WILDERNESS
FOR YOUR STUDY, DOCTOR?
HELP ME!
NO CAN DO.
WHAT WITH THE COLD,
THE SLEEP DEPRIVATION,
THE HUNGER--
YOU'RE GONNA BE QUITE A SPECIMEN
WHEN THEY DRAG YOU OUT OF THERE.
OH, THIS IS CRAZY.
I COULD DIE DOWN HERE!
YES, QUITE POSSIBLY,
YOU COULD.
WE'LL JUST LEAVE THAT
UP TO THE LAWS OF NATURE.
UNLESS YOU CARE TO CONFESS.
NO? OH, WELL.
HAVE FUN.
ALL RIGHT!
I LEFT HER OUT HERE!
I-- I LEFT HER OUT HERE.
[ Sobbing ]
GOD FORGIVE ME.
WHAT HAVE I DONE?
[ Sobbing ]
HEY, DOC.
WELL, HERE'S SOMETHING
TO KEEP YOU COMPANY
IF YOU GET LONELY.
OH.
[ Sobbing Continues ]
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO THANK YOU, JAROD.
I'M THE ONE THAT
SHOULD BE THANKING YOU.
IT TOOK A LOT OF COURAGE TO SIGN
THOSE COURT PAPERS TO BECOME
VIOLET'S LEGAL GUARDIAN.
I GUESS YOU COULD SAY
I GOT A MESSAGE.
A MESSAGE?
AH, YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE ME
IF I TOLD YOU.
TRY ME.
[ Laughs ]
I HAD A DREAM LAST NIGHT.
MY SON CAME TO ME, AND HE SAID
IT WOULD BE ALL RIGHT.
HE SAID HE DIDN'T WANT ME
TO BE ALONE ANYMORE.
DOES THAT SOUND CRAZY?
IT SOUNDS PERFECT.
[ Laughing ]
IS THAT FOR ME?
MMM. THANK YOU.
AND I HAVE SOMETHING
FOR YOU TOO.
[ Gasps, Sighs ]
JAH-ROD.
HAVE A BEAUTIFUL LIFE, OKAY?
BYE.
YOU GOT A NEW DOLL.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Vehicle Departs ]