[ TV: Man ]
GOOD MORNING, WASHINGTON.
IT'S A SUNNY NEW DAY
HERE IN THE NATION'S CAPITAL,
BUT DON'T PUT AWAY
THOSE UMBRELLAS JUST YET,
AS THERE'S A STORM
MOVING UP THE SEABOARD.
THE FIVE-DAY FORECAST
WILL FOLLOW TODAY'S
WASHINGTON REPORT.
[ TV: Woman ]
WE'RE AT SECRET SERVICE
HEADQUARTERS...
FOR TODAY'S
WASHINGTON REPORT,
WHERE OFFICIALS ARE TRYING
TO PIECE TOGETHER THE FINAL
HOURS OF TODD BAXTER,
A YOUNG AGENT WHOSE BODY WAS
RECOVERED FROM THE POTOMAC RIVER
JUST LAST NIGHT.
TODD.
[ Panting ]
[ Panting Continues ]
[ Man Shouting ]
JAROD! JAROD!
MIKE! THROUGH HERE!
- STOP!
- [ Shouting, Indistinct ]
THERE HE IS! GET HIM!
STOP! WAIT! WAIT!
WILL YOU HELP ME, PLEASE?
MY CAR IS BROKEN DOWN
AND I NEED A RIDE.
- PLEASE?
- ALL RIGHT. HOP IN.
[ Beeps ]
GET ME MR. PARKER.
THE PRETENDER HAS ESCAPED.
I'M FREE.
I'M TODD-- BAXTER.
JAROD.
GOT A LAST NAME?
JUST JAROD.
JUST JAROD, HUH?
HOW ABOUT THEM APPLES.
[ Chuckles ]
APPLES?
I, UH-- I DON'T KNOW
HOW I CAN EVER THANK YOU.
OH, JUST SOMEDAY DOWN THE ROAD
DO SOMETHIN' NICE FOR SOMEBODY.
THE SECRET SERVICE
IS BAFFLED BY
THE APPARENT SUICIDE.
AFTER JUST
THREE-AND-A-HALF SHORT YEARS
AS AN AGENT,
HOW DID SUCH
A PROMISING YOUNG MAN
END UP DEAD IN THE POTOMAC?
A QUESTION
THAT MAY NEVER BE ANSWERED.
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
- [ Miss Parker ] HE DEFENDS
THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
- [ Jarod ] LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
[ TV: Woman ]
MORE DETAILS EMERGING
IN THE APPARENT SUICIDE...
OF YOUNG SECRET SERVICE AGENT
TODD BAXTER,
WHO SPENT THE FINAL HOURS
OF HIS LIFE AT THIS D.C. HOTEL,
THE RIVER GLEN.
SOURCES SAY HE JUMPED
TO HIS DEATH IN THE POTOMAC...
AFTER A NIGHT OF DRUGS
AND DEPRESSION.
HOWEVER, FRIENDS AND FAMILY
WE SPOKE WITH SAY THIS IS NOT
THE TODD BAXTER THEY KNEW.
I'M GONNA
MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
DOES THAT SOUND HOKEY?
HOKEY?
IS THAT A SPORTING EVENT?
[ Laughs ]
YEAH.
ANYHOW, ALL MY LIFE
I'VE KNOWN THAT, UH,
D.C.'S
WHERE THINGS GET DONE.
IT'S A TOUGH TOWN
AND ALL THAT,
BUT WITH SMARTS
AND HARD WORK,
A GUY CAN--
CHANGE THE WORLD.
BUT WHAT CHANGED
TODD BAXTER?
WAS IT THE PRESSURE OF LIFE
INSIDE THE BELTWAY,
THE DEMANDING YEARS
IN THE SECRET SERVICE?
THE ANSWERS
ARE THROUGH THOSE DOORS.
[ Radio:
Dispatcher, Indistinct ]
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
AGENT HOLDER?
YEAH?
- SPECIAL AGENT WILKES.
- OH, RIGHT, RIGHT, RIGHT.
THE BEHAVIORAL SCIENCE GUY.
YES, I JUST GOT IN
FROM THE AIRPORT.
I BET YOU DIDN'T HAVE
LUNCH, EITHER, DID YOU?
HERE. YOU HUNGRY?
"CUP O' SOUP.
A MEAL IN A MINUTE." THAT'S
A RATHER CLEVER IDEA, ISN'T IT?
IDEA? ARE YOU FROM
THE SEATTLE OFFICE OR MARS?
SOMEWHERE IN BETWEEN.
WELL, I BET THE BOSS
WANTS TO SEE YA. TALBOT.
HE'S GOT THE PLACE BUZZING
OVER THE BAXTER THING.
YOU KNEW TODD?
YEAH. CAN'T BELIEVE HE'D
DO SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
NEITHER CAN I.
- WILKES. ELLIS TALBOT.
- SIR.
SEATTLE FAXED ME
YOUR PAPERS THIS MORNING.
I COULD USE A MAN
WITH YOUR EXPERTISE
ABOUT NOW. FOLLOW ME.
THE MAID CALLED
THE D.C. COPS THIS MORNING
AND THEY CALLED THE BUREAU.
F.B.I.'S RUNNING THINGS.
HOOVER BOYS ARE LOOKIN'
AT BAXTER'S BODY NOW.
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND,
HE'D BEEN IN THE POTOMAC
ABOUT A WEEK.
HE PUT A "DO NOT DISTURB"
SIGN ON THE DOOR,
WHICH IS WHY IT TOOK
THE HOTEL PEOPLE SO LONG
TO FINALLY GET CURIOUS.
[ Holder ]
WHICH FITS WITH
THE REST OF THE STORY.
THE NIGHT TODD
CHECKED IN HERE,
WITNESSES DOWNSTAIRS SAY...
THAT HE MET UP WITH AN OLD
GIRLFRIEND IN THE BAR, THEY
CAME HERE FOR A LITTLE SEX...
AND A LOT OF HEROIN.
HAS ANYONE QUESTIONED
THE GIRLFRIEND?
THE FEDS ARE STILL
LOOKING FOR HER,
BUT INDICATIONS ARE
SHE WAS LONG GONE BEFORE
TODD WENT ON HIS BENDER.
AND JUMPED.
[ Talbot ] DEMONS LIKE HIS,
I SOMETIMES WONDER IF I EVER
KNEW THE REAL TODD BAXTER.
SURE YOU WANT
TO GET OUT HERE?
YES.
THIS WILL BE FINE.
ALL RIGHT.
YOUR CAR DIDN'T REALLY
BREAK DOWN, DID IT?
NO.
WHY DID YOU HELP ME?
MY GUT TOLD ME
TO TRUST YOU.
WAIT A SECOND.
THERE YOU GO.
OH, NO. I-I COULDN'T POSSIBLY.
YOU'VE HELPED ME
TOO MUCH ALREADY.
FORGET IT.
HAVE AN ICE CREAM CONE
ON ME.
ICE CREAM?
IS IT GOOD?
[ Chuckles ]
YEAH, IT'S VERY GOOD.
LOOK, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT CAVE YOU'VE BEEN
LIVIN' IN, JAROD, BUT...
YOU'RE EVER IN D.C.,
LOOK ME UP.
I WILL.
THANK YOU.
JAROD?
YOU TWO WORK WITH THE FEDS
IF YOU HAVE TO,
BUT REPORT ONLY TO ME.
SO WHAT IS IT
YOU'RE NOT TELLING ME?
F.B.I.'S FLOATING A THEORY
THAT THIS WAS A HOMICIDE.
THAT'S WHERE YOU COME IN.
BAXTER'S SUICIDE'S EMBARRASSING
ENOUGH WITHOUT FAR-FETCHED
SPECULATION IT WAS A MURDER.
YOU'RE THE
BEHAVIORAL SCIENCE EXPERT.
GET THEM TO SEE THE TRUTH
ABOUT TODD'S
PSYCHOLOGICAL TROUBLES.
THE TRUTH
IS ALL ANY OF US WANT.
- AGENT TED HOLDER.
- HI.
THIS IS SPECIAL AGENT
JAROD WILKES.
BAILEY MALONE,
VIOLENT CRIMES TASK FORCE.
V.C.T.F.
THE BUREAU'S FINEST.
I BROUGHT THE BAXTER
AUTOPSY FILES.
YOU BOYS HAVE
SOME CATCHING UP TO DO.
[ Muttering ]
DADDY?
I JUST HEARD.
OH, THERE'S NOTHIN' TO FEAR.
THE DOCTORS JUST WANT THE BABY
FOR OBSERVATION.
YOUR LITTLE BROTHER'S
GONNA BE JUST FINE.
AFTER ALL, YOU HELPED
MY NEW SON INTO THIS WORLD,
GOT ME BACK TO MY OLD DESK.
I'VE NEVER BEEN MORE PROUD
TO BE YOUR FATHER.
OH, YOU GOT THAT LOOK
IN YOUR EYE.
WHAT LIE HAS JAROD
BEEN TELLIN' YOU NOW?
IT'S NOT JAROD.
IT'S ME.
I DON'T KNOW, IT JUST--
[ Sighs ]
SO MUCH HAS HAPPENED
IN THE LAST FEW WEEKS.
BRIDGET DYING,
YOU COMING HOME, THE NEW BABY.
AH, I UNDERSTAND. YEAH.
YOU WANT THINGS TO BE DIFFERENT.
LISTEN, COME HERE.
COME HERE.
YOU MUST NEVER LOSE YOUR DESIRE
TO GET JAROD BACK.
THE NEW CHILD IS THE FUTURE
OF THE FAMILY, BUT JAROD
IS THE FUTURE OF THE CENTRE.
WHY?
HE'S OUR GREATEST ACHIEVEMENT,
OUR BIGGEST ASSET.
HOWEVER, CONSIDER YOUR LIFE
OFFICIALLY CHANGED.
IT'S A BRAND-NEW DAY
AT THE CENTRE.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Kiss ]
MY ATTEMPTS AT CROSS-POLLINATION
APPEAR TO BE SUCCESSFUL.
VERY GOOD.
LIES! DAMN LIES!
LIES!
[ Jarod ]
THEY FINISHED
THE AUTOPSY ALREADY?
YES, IT'S ALL THERE
IN THE REPORT.
OH, AND GET THIS--
MALONE TELLS ME THEY'RE NOT
JUST THINKING MURDER. THEY'RE
THINKING SIGNATURE KILLER.
A SIGNATURE KILLER?
YEAH.
WELL, APPARENTLY
THEIR PROFILER HAS A THEORY.
PROFILER?
[ Woman ]
THAT'S ME.
[ Knocking ]
- WERE YOU EXPECTING
SOMEONE ELSE?
- CALL IT DÉJÀ VU.
WITH A TWIST ENDING.
JAROD WILKES.
RACHEL BURKE.
- AGENT TED HOLDER.
- NICE TO MEET YOU.
NOT TO BE RUDE, BUT ISN'T
YOUR SIGNATURE KILLER THEORY
A BIT PRESUMPTUOUS?
WELL, IT'S JUST THAT.
IT'S A THEORY. BUT THERE'S
EVIDENCE TO SUPPORT IT.
- LIKE?
- LIKE OUR AUTOPSY.
IT CONFIRMS THAT TODD BAXTER
DID NOT DIE FROM A JUMP.
HE WAS STRANGLED TO DEATH.
PROBABLY A PIANO WIRE.
AND DESPITE A WEEK
IN THE POTOMAC,
WE FOUND THESE.
- LIGATURE MARKS.
- ON BOTH WRISTS.
NOT EXACTLY
CONSISTENT WITH SUICIDE.
NOT TO BE RUDE.
AND HE WAS DRUGGED,
AND THERE IS EVIDENCE
OF SEXUAL ACTIVITY.
HE MAY HAVE A SEXUAL NEED
TO BE TIED UP,
MAYBE EVEN ASPHYXIATED.
[ Phone Rings ]
OR SOMEONE ELSE TIED HIM UP.
YOUR SIGNATURE KILLER?
- YEAH. IT'S JUST, UH--
- INSTINCT.
SOMETHIN' LIKE THAT.
THEY'VE LOCATED
TODD'S GIRLFRIEND,
AN EMILY SADLER.
I'D LIKE TO
QUESTION HER MYSELF.
- I'LL KEEP YOU IN THE LOOP.
- I LOOK FORWARD TO THAT.
[ Woman ]
TODD AND I
MET AT COLUMBIA.
I STUDIED JOURNALISM,
AND HE WAS
A CRIMINOLOGY MAJOR.
WHAT THEY SAY
ABOUT TODD IS TRUE.
HE WAS A REALLY GOOD GUY.
BUT HE HAD DEMONS.
WHAT KIND OF DEMONS?
THE KIND
HE COULDN'T BEAT.
AND THIS TOWN
MADE IT WORSE.
I'D NEVER SEEN HIM
THAT WRECKED.
-HE WAS IN
A BAD PLACE THAT NIGHT.
-HE HAD A DRUG HABIT, DIDN'T HE?
YES.
IT HAUNTED HIM.
DID YOU TRY TO HELP HIM?
WELL, WHAT DO YOU THINK
I WAS DOING THAT NIGHT?
THAT'S WHY I WENT UPSTAIRS.
I WAS ALWAYS TRYIN'
TO HELP HIM.
BUT THEN HE
PULLED OUT THE DRUGS,
AND HE STARTED DRINKING.
AND WE STARTED FIGHTING.
SOME THINGS WERE SAID,
SO I LEFT.
SO YOU JUST... WALKED OUT.
NOW THAT'S MY DEMON.
SO, IN YOUR MIND,
TODD BAXTER
WAS PERFECTLY CAPABLE...
OF JUMPING OFF THAT BALCONY?
YEAH.
HE WAS ALWAYS
GOING TOO FAR.
THAT'S THE WAY HE WAS.
UNLESS YOU KNOW
SOMETHING I DON'T.
[ Miss Parker ]
THIS CAN'T BE RIGHT.
SYDNEY WOULDN'T
HAVE TRASHED THESE.
THEY'RE LIKE THERAPY FOR HIM.
HO-HO. HELLO.
[ Computer: Sydney ]
DAMN LIES!
ALWAYS KNEW
HE WAS A MAD SCIENTIST.
- THE CENTRE DOES THAT TO YOU.
- GO BACK TO
BEFORE HE FREAKS OUT.
OH.
[ Miss Parker ]
ANGELO.
- ZOOM IN AND FREEZE IT.
- [ Broots ] IT'S A WATCH
IN A CENTRE BAG.
ANGELO MUST HAVE DUG IT OUT
OF THE CENTRE ARCHIVES.
AND BEING AN EMPATH,
HE HAD TO KNOW THE EFFECT
IT WOULD HAVE ON SYD.
I HATE SEEING HIM LIKE THIS.
[ Exhales ]
HOW MANY BLACK HOLES
HAS SYDNEY HELPED ME OUT OF?
WHY DIDN'T YOU COME TO ME?
[ Talbot ]
YOU GOT 48 HOURS
TO FIND THE TRUTH.
THE F.B.I. WANTS TO
CHASE THEORIES, THEY CAN DO IT
TILL THEIR BADGES FALL OFF.
BUT I CAN TELL YOU, I WILL NOT
HAVE MY DIVISION WASTING
RESOURCES ON AGENT BAXTER.
TELL JERRY
WE'RE IN, PLEASE.
SIR, HE IS ONE OF OUR OWN.
THAT'S NOT THE ISSUE.
THIS WHOLE MESS
HAS PUT A SPOTLIGHT ON US,
AND IT'S A BAD ONE.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THAT THE F.B.I. IS LYING?
NO. I'M SAYING
AGENT BAXTER WAS LYING.
FOR ALL WE KNOW,
A HEROIN DEALER KILLED HIM.
IT'S BAD ENOUGH
THAT THIS DIDN'T SHOW UP
ON A BACKGROUND CHECK.
NOW WE HAVE TO FIND OUT THE KID
HAD A MILLION SICK HABITS.
A MILLION AND ONE.
JERRY LINDEN,
OFFICE OF COMMUNICATIONS.
SPECIAL AGENT WILKES.
PLEASURE.
IF A REPORTER CALLS YOU,
SEND HIM TO JERRY.
THANK YOU, SIR.
DO NOT LEAK THIS.
IT'S NOT GOOD.
AGENT BAXTER WAS ARRESTED
IN COLLEGE-- POSSESSION
OF HEROIN, INTENT TO SELL.
WELL, I GUESS WE'D BETTER
JUST DROP THE CASE RIGHT NOW.
CASE? YOU SOUND LIKE THE FEDS.
YOU GOT YOUR 48 HOURS.
THEN YOU'RE
BACK IN SEATTLE.
MAY I HAVE THIS?
YOU'VE GOT IT ALL ON FILE.
WE DON'T NEED
THIS STUFF ABOUT TODD
FLOATIN' AROUND.
COME ON IN.
THE SHREDDERS IN SEATTLE
ARE SMALLER.
SECRETS IN D.C.
ARE BIGGER.
YOU SHOULD SEE THE SIZE
OF THE JANITOR'S CART THEY HAUL
THIS STUFF AWAY IN EVERY FRIDAY.
- DID TALBOT PUT HIS PERSONALITY
THROUGH THAT THING?
- [ Chuckling ]
HAVE A SEAT.
LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHIN' ABOUT TALBOT.
YOU KNOW ALL THAT CRAP ABOUT
BOY SCOUTS WHO RUN ALONGSIDE
THE PRESIDENT'S LIMO?
HE DOESN'T JUST BUY IT.
HE LIVED IT FOR 25 YEARS.
TODD BAXTER WOULD HAVE TOO.
TELL ME SOMETHING.
IF THEY WERE SUCH GOOD FRIENDS,
WHY DID SHE WALK OUT
OF THAT HOTEL ROOM?
I DON'T KNOW.
HE HAD AN ADDICTION.
SOMETIMES WALKING'S
THE ONLY OPTION.
[ Screaming ]
EMILY!
[ Yelling, Groaning ]
DAMN!
[ Groans ]
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
THEY SAID MUGGINGS WERE UP,
BUT I HAD NO IDEA.
THANKS.
I'M GLAD
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
THAT WASN'T A MUGGING.
I THINK YOU KNOW THAT.
WHY DID YOU LEAVE TODD
AT THE HOTEL THAT NIGHT?
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
HE WAS MY FRIEND. IT'S NOT
MY FAULT HE COULDN'T SEE THAT.
HE WAS MURDERED,
AND SOMEONE IS TRYING TO DESTROY
WHAT'S LEFT OF HIS NAME.
I DON'T THINK YOU WANT THAT.
WHY ARE YOU LYING?
[ Sighs ]
I CAME TO THIS TOWN
TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
YOU SOUND LIKE TODD.
- YOU KNEW HIM?
- HE SAVED MY LIFE ONCE.
[ Sobs ]
GOD, I MISS HIM.
THEN HELP ME.
HELP ME
PROTECT HIS MEMORY.
[ Sighs ]
TODD SAID HE WAS MEETING
SOMEONE AT THE HOTEL,
BUT HE STILL HAD TIME
TO HELP ME WITH A PROBLEM
I HAD AT WORK.
THAT WAS TODD.
WE HAD DINNER AND I LEFT.
I HADN'T HEARD FROM HIM
IN A WEEK, AND THEN...
I SEE THE NEWS.
WHEN THEY FOUND HIS BODY.
I GET THIS PHONE CALL.
THE MAN ON THE OTHER END
KNOWS WHERE I LIVE.
HE KNOWS WHERE I WALK MY DOG,
EVERYTHING.
HE ASKED YOU TO LIE.
HE HAD THE LIE WORKED OUT.
IT WAS SCARY.
I HAD TO SAY THAT
IT WAS SEX AND HEROIN.
TODD AND I WERE BEST FRIENDS.
JUST FRIENDS.
WE WERE NEVER TOGETHER
IN HIS ROOM THAT NIGHT,
AND HE NEVER DID DRUGS.
THEY SAID HE WAS ARRESTED
FOR POSSESSION IN COLLEGE.
A TOTAL LIE.
THE MAN ON THE PHONE
THREATENED TO END MY CAREER.
I DIDN'T CARE.
TODD WAS MY FRIEND.
I TOLD HIM I WAS GONNA
CALL THE PAPERS.
AND THEN HE TOLD ME
TO CHECK MY MAILBOX.
THAT'S MY FATHER.
THEY MADE ME CHOOSE
BETWEEN TODD'S MEMORY
AND MY FATHER'S LIFE.
I--
[ Exhales ]
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING.
YOU DID
THE RIGHT THING.
DID TODD TELL YOU
WHO HE WAS MEETING
THAT NIGHT?
NO. UH--
[ Emily ]
ALL HE SAID WAS, "I'M GONNA
BE IN THE PAPER SOON."
AND THEN HE TAPPED
HIS BRIEFCASE.
LIKE THERE WAS
SOMETHING IMPORTANT IN IT.
I WANT YOU TO
STAY AT MY PLACE.
YOU'LL BE SAFE THERE.
THERE'S NO SAFE PLACE
FROM THE MONSTERS.
TODD SAID D.C. WAS LIKE
A BIG MASQUERADE BALL,
ONLY THE PEOPLE IN DISGUISE
WERE MONSTERS.
IF YOU WANT TO MAKE
A DIFFERENCE, YOU GOTTA
PULL OFF A FEW MASKS.
THAT'S WHY HE'S DEAD, JAROD.
[ Angelo ]
NO HOPE.
WHAT IS "HOPE,"
ANGELO?
SYDNEY LOST HOPE.
- WHAT DOES IT HAVE TO DO
WITH THAT WATCH?
- CENTRE TAKES HOPE.
WHAT DID THEY TAKE,
ANGELO?
CHECK SYD'S FILE.
IT'S A LONG SHOT, BUT SEE IF
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT "HOPE."
OKAY.
MR. PARKER TAKES HOPE
FROM SYDNEY.
WHAT DOES MY FATHER
HAVE TO DO WITH THIS?
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
HEY, HOW ABOUT
I COOK YOU LUNCH?
NO, THANKS. I'LL PASS.
YOU HAVE YOUR VEGETABLE,
YOUR CHICKEN NOODLE,
YOUR SHRIMP GUMBO.
SHRIMP ALMOST TASTES REAL.
MMM.
TEMPTING, BUT NO.
THIS BETTER BE GOOD.
TODD BAXTER TELLS HIS FRIEND,
EMILY SADLER,
THAT HIS NAME IS ABOUT TO BE
PUT INTO THE PAPER,
THAT HE HAS SOMETHING
IMPORTANT IN HIS BRIEFCASE.
THREE DAYS LATER, BILL RADCLIFF,
REPORTER, COVERS SECRET SERVICE
FOR THE WASHINGTON JOURNAL--
DIES IN A CAR ACCIDENT.
AN ACCIDENT
WITH ONE INCONGRUOUS DETAIL.
LIGATURE MARKS,
LIKE THOSE FOUND ON TODD BAXTER.
I BELIEVE BAXTER WAS GOING
TO MEET THIS REPORTER TO EXPOSE
SOMETHING THAT HE DISCOVERED.
AND THAT "SOMETHING"
WAS IN HIS BRIEFCASE.
ALL WE FOUND
WAS OFFICE PAPERWORK.
WHAT MAKES YOU SO DAMN SURE?
LET'S JUST SAY THAT
I'VE GOTTEN INTO THE MIND
OF THE KILLER.
YOU'VE WHAT?
THINK ABOUT IT.
THE KILLER WANTS TO COVER UP
WHAT TODD HAS DISCOVERED.
THAT'S WHY HE HAD TO
KILL THE REPORTER TOO.
I DON'T THINK SO.
THE KILLER'S INTO THE ACT--
THE POWER HE EXHIBITS
OVER THE HELPLESS VICTIM.
THERE'S A PURITY
IN THAT VIOLENCE.
IT SATISFIES HIM.
I MEAN, IF THERE IS
A COVER-UP, SOMEONE ELSE
IS CALLING THE SHOTS.
- SOMEONE ELSE?
- YES.
- AND THIS THEORY
IS BASED UPON WHAT?
- HOLD ON A SECOND. HOLD ON.
THERE ARE
TWO SUSPECTS?
YOU TWO MIGHT WANT
TO GET ON THE SAME PAGE.
YOU'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
HOLDER,
COME INTO MY OFFICE.
YOU AND I,
WE HAVE TO TALK.
TALBOT COULD SHUT US DOWN.
NOT ME.
HE COULD SEAL THE EVIDENCE.
IT WOULD TAKE MONTHS TO REOPEN
THE CASE, EVEN FOR THE F.B.I.
YOU AND ME,
WE HAVE TO WORK TOGETHER.
YES, BUT NOT BLINDLY.
- BUT YOU CAN MAKE THESE LEAPS
OF LOGIC? HOW DOES THAT WORK?
- IT'S COMPLICATED.
WELL, THAT ISN'T GOOD ENOUGH.
THERE'S EVIDENCE OF A COVER-UP.
- NOT BY THIS KILLER.
- THEN BY WHO?
TODD BAXTER
WAS AT THAT HOTEL ROOM
TO MEET THE REPORTER...
SO HE COULD
EXPOSE THE KILLER.
- HAS IT EVER OCCURRED TO YOU
THAT MAYBE HE NEEDS TO KILL?
- "NEEDS TO KILL." NO.
MAYBE YOU OUGHT
TO GET INTO HIS MIND AGAIN.
HOW DOES THAT WORK?
IT'S COMPLICATED.
[ Exhales ]
YOU KNOW, JAROD, I THINK THAT
UNDER DIFFERENT CIRCUMSTANCES
YOU AND I--
YES?
STILL WOULDN'T HAVE
GOTTEN ALONG.
IS THAT SO?
WELL, FOR STARTERS,
YOU DRINK PROCESSED POWDER
AND HOT WATER.
YOU NEVER KNOW HOW TASTY
SOMETHING'S GOING TO BE
UNLESS YOU TRY IT FOR YOURSELF.
WELL, IF WE EVER MAKE IT
OUT OF HERE, I'M GONNA SHOW YOU
WHAT REAL FOOD IS LIKE.
- I MAKE
AN AMAZING BOUILLABAISSE.
- REALLY?
MM-HMM.
- CAN YOU DRINK IT OUT OF A MUG?
- YOU CAN DRINK IT
OUT OF WHATEVER YOU LIKE.
[ Chuckles ]
YOU'RE LOOKIN'
FOR YOUR FAMILY?
YES. THEY'RE OUT HERE
SOMEWHERE.
I LOST MY DAD
WHEN I WAS 10.
IT'S A TOUGH AGE
TO BECOME MAN OF THE HOUSE.
YOU GREW UP FAST.
VERY.
BUT IT TAUGHT ME RESPONSIBILITY,
TO ALWAYS DO THE RIGHT THING.
AND MAKE SURE
OTHERS DO TOO.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Todd ]
MAKE SURE OTHERS DO TOO.
[ Emily ] ALL HE SAID WAS,
"I'M GONNA BE
IN THE PAPER SOON."
AND THEN
HE TAPPED HIS BRIEFCASE.
[ Jarod ]
LIKE THERE WAS SOMETHING
IMPORTANT IN IT.
DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
YOU KNOW, THE THING
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND
ABOUT THESE PAPERS, JAROD?
WHY KILL TODD OVER THESE?
THEY'RE ALL RANDOM,
NOT CONNECTED.
NOT EVEN BY A SPECIFIC CASE.
IT'S LIKE SOMEBODY
JUST GRABBED THEM.
TO REPLACE THE ONES
THAT WERE ORIGINALLY
IN HIS BRIEFCASE.
IF SOMEBODY DID SWITCH 'EM,
THEN TODD DEFINITELY
HAD THE GOODS ON HIM.
THE QUESTION IS, WHO.
HANG IN THERE, MAN.
WE'LL GET HIM.
[ Phone Rings ]
AGENT WILKES.
IT'S MALONE.
LISTEN, I WENT OVER
THOSE PAPERS YOU SENT
FROM BAXTER'S BRIEFCASE.
NOTHING.
HOWEVER,
I FOUND SOMETHING INTERESTING.
WHAT?
THAT HEROIN CHARGE
AGAINST BAXTER
FROM HIS COLLEGE DAYS?
IT'S A FAKE.
YEAH.
THE CAMPUS COP
WHO ARRESTED BAXTER
DOESN'T EXIST.
- SOMEONE'S TRYING
TO SMEAR HIS PAST.
- I'LL HAVE TO CALL YOU BACK.
[ Dial Tone ]
LET'S TAKE A WALK.
LET ME SHARE SOMETHING
WITH YOU, AGENT.
I'M UNDER REVIEW,
AND I'M NOT INCLINED TO
BELIEVE IN A CONSPIRACY,
BUT I KNOW WHAT CITY
I'M IN.
IF THIS BAXTER THING
KEEPS GOIN' SOUTH,
WE'RE GONNA
RUFFLE SOME FEATHERS,
AND WE'RE GONNA GET CLIPPED.
WHAT ABOUT TODD BAXTER?
WHOSE FEATHERS DID HE RUFFLE?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THERE WAS SOMETHING
IN HIS BRIEFCASE THAT
SOMEONE DIDN'T WANT EXPOSED.
HE ALSO HAD HEROIN, BARBITURATES
AND SOME FUZZY HANDCUFFS.
THE KID WAS MESSED UP,
JAROD.
I HIRED BAXTER.
YOU THINK I WANT
TO BELIEVE THIS?
HE WAS CONVICTED OF POSSESSION
IN COLLEGE. WE SHOULD TRACK DOWN
THE ARRESTING OFFICER.
HE ALREADY DID.
YOU TALKED TO THE OFFICER
THAT ARRESTED HIM?
YES. I WOULD HAVE RATHER NOT.
TRUST ME.
JERRY'S SEEN THE TRUTH
ON THIS THING
FROM THE BEGINNING.
AND I'M BEGINNING
TO SEE IT MYSELF.
[ Emily ]
LINDEN SWITCHED THE FILES?
NICE THEORY.
BUT YOU GOT NO PROOF UNLESS YOU
FIND THE ORIGINALS, AND THEY'RE
PROBABLY LONG SHREDDED BY NOW.
WELL, THEN IT'S TIME TO
GO DIGGING THROUGH SOME TRASH.
[ Glass Shattering ]
- TYPICAL SHRINK.
JUST FLAT NUTS.
- LIES!
IT WAS IN
A CENTRE EVIDENCE BAG.
- WHO DID THE WATCH BELONG TO?
- I DON'T WANT TO RELIVE THAT.
RELIVE WHAT?
WE HELPED HIM.
IT WAS AWFUL.
THEN GET IT OUT IN THE OPEN.
IT'S A BRAND-NEW DAY
AT THE CENTRE. REMEMBER?
ALL RIGHT. YEARS AGO,
SYDNEY KILLED A WOMAN.
[ Malone ] AGENT WILKES.
JUST THE MAN
I'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR.
WHAT?
NICE WORKING WITH YOU AGAIN.
A YEAR AGO, YOU WORKED WITH US
ON A KIDNAPPING IN ATLANTA.
YOU USED A DIFFERENT NAME.
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
WHO ARE YOU WORKING
UNDERCOVER FOR?
CONGRESS.
I WORK FOR
AN OVERSIGHT COMMITTEE...
THAT KEEPS TABS ON LOCAL
AND FEDERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT.
THAT EXPLAINS
YOUR BADGE IN ATLANTA.
WHAT BROUGHT YOU TO THE SERVICE?
THE COMMITTEE SMELLED A RAT
IN THE BAXTER CASE.
THEY SENT ME DOWN.
STILL DOESN'T ANSWER
ALL MY QUESTIONS.
I'LL ANSWER ANY QUESTION
YOU WANT.
BUT RIGHT NOW,
I FOUND TODD BAXTER'S KILLER,
AND I NEED YOUR HELP TO GET HIM.
SYD KILLED A WOMAN?
IN A CAR ACCIDENT.
IT HAPPENED DURING THE EARLY
STAGES OF THE JAROD PROJECT.
SYD HIRED A COLLEGE INTERN
FROM FRANCE, A YOUNG GIRL.
[ Broots Exhales ]
SHE WAS PRETTY.
APPARENTLY,
THEY WERE HAVING AN AFFAIR.
THEY'D GONE TO DINNER AND WERE
DRIVING BACK WHEN SYDNEY LOST
CONTROL AND BROADSIDED A TREE.
SHE DIED TWO HOURS LATER
IN THE HOSPITAL.
- HER NAME WAS HOPE?
- CLAUDIA.
WHEN ANGELO SAID SYDNEY
LOST HOPE, HE MEANT IT.
NOW, THESE ARE
THE CENTRE RECORDS
OF THE ACCIDENT.
I'M HOPING THAT'LL
HELP US FIND SYD.
PROVENCE RESTAURANT.
THIS MUST BE WHERE
THEY DINED BEFORE--
WORTH A TRY.
YEAH.
DID YOU GLUE THIS
TOGETHER?
YEAH.
IT'S ALL 6,422 STRIPS.
AFTER THAT, I GOT BORED.
MMM. YEAH, WELL,
BAXTER CERTAINLY WASN'T.
BETWEEN THESE ARTICLES AND
THOSE CONFIDENTIAL MEMOS
YOU PIECED TOGETHER,
BAXTER CONNECTED LINDEN TO
NUMEROUS ILLEGAL OPERATIONS
AND OTHER SO-CALLED SUICIDES.
TODD WAS DEFINITELY
TRYING TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
- HOW ABOUT THOSE APPLES?
- THEM APPLES.
- HMM?
- IT'S "HOW ABOUT THEM APPLES?"
OH. I KNEW IT WAS
SOMETHING ABOUT APPLES.
BAILEY TOLD ME
WHO YOU WORKED FOR.
THEY THE ONES WHO
SHOWED YOU HOW TO GET INTO
A KILLER'S MIND?
NO. THAT WAS
MORE HOME SCHOOLING.
THAT'S SOME HOME.
YOU DON'T WANT TO KNOW.
WELL,
I DECIDED NOT TO WAIT.
TRY THIS.
IS THIS
YOUR BOUILLABAISSE?
MM-HMM.
MMM.
MMM!
HOW DO YOU HAVE TIME TO
TRACK A KILLER AND MAKE
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS?
WELL,
WE ALL HAVE OUR SECRETS.
DON'T WE, JAROD?
IT ONLY HELPS
UNTIL THE NEXT MORNING.
AND, UH,
I'LL BE BACK THEN.
WE KNOW ABOUT
THE ACCIDENT, SYD.
LOOK, I'M HERE WITH
SOME OF MY FAVORITE GHOSTS.
CAN'T YOU SEE?
SO LEAVE ME ALONE.
YOU WOULDN'T
LET US OFF THAT EASY,
SO FORGET IT, SYDNEY.
IT WASN'T YOUR FAULT.
YOU HAVE TO LET CLAUDIA GO.
I CAN'T.
WE'RE CELEBRATING.
WHY?
BECAUSE.
BECAUSE THEY USED HER
AGAINST ME.
SYD,
THE CENTRE HELPED YOU.
THE CENTRE SURE HELPED.
THEY WERE THERE
RIGHT AFTER THE ACCIDENT.
CENTRE SWEEPERS YELLING,
"OH, WE'LL GIVE CLAUDIA
THE BEST CARE."
AND THEN...
TWO HOURS LATER...
I GOT THE NEWS.
I GAVE HER THIS WATCH
FOR HER BIRTHDAY.
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN
YESTERDAY.
HOW DID ANGELO KNOW
ABOUT--
[ Chuckles ]
ANGELO.
HOW DOES ANGELO
KNOW ABOUT ANYTHING?
HE KNEW THAT YOU NEED TO
DEAL WITH THIS PAIN, SYD,
THAT YOU WERE
IN LOVE WITH HER.
THAT WASN'T ANGELO.
- THEY TOLD YOU THAT.
- THAT'S WHAT MY FATHER SAID.
THAT'S WHAT THE FILE SAID.
CENTRE LIES!
CAREFUL, SYDNEY.
OH, NO, MUCH LATER,
WHEN I FOUND OUT WHAT THE CENTRE
WAS DOING WITH JAROD'S WORK,
AND I ROSE UP IN PROTEST--
THEY USED THE ACCIDENT
AGAINST YOU?
I DID LOVE HER.
LIKE MY DAUGHTER.
SHE WAS MY STUDENT.
BUT THE CENTRE
FABRICATED SOME STORY
OF AN AFFAIR BETWEEN US.
THEY THREATENED ME
WITH JAIL.
THEY THREATENED--
TO SEPARATE YOU
FROM JAROD.
YES.
THEY USED IT TO FORCE ME
TO DO THEIR BIDDING.
NOT ONLY WAS CLAUDIA DEAD,
BUT THEY TRIED TO DESTROY
THE VERY MEMORY OF HER.
MY FATHER
DID THIS TO YOU?
NOT DIRECTLY, OF COURSE.
BUT, YES, MR. PARKER
WAS RUNNING THE CENTRE.
NOW HAVE A SHOT.
[ Jarod ]
TODD BAXTER KNEW TOO MUCH.
HE CONNECTED LINDEN
TO SEVERAL MAJOR
ILLEGAL OPERATIONS--
CHARACTER ASSASSINATIONS,
EXTORTION,
AMONG OTHER
CLANDESTINE THINGS.
YOUR DIRECTOR OF COMMUNICATIONS
HAS HAD SIX WASHINGTON JOBS
IN THE LAST SEVEN YEARS.
YEAH. TRAVEL OFFICE,
D.O.J. COVER-UP, FRAMED
A D.O.E. WHISTLE BLOWER.
WATERGATE PLUMBERS
GOT NOTHIN' ON THIS GUY.
HASN'T PAID THIS WELL SINCE
G. GORDON LIDDY. HIS OFFSHORE
ACCOUNTS ARE PACKED.
AGENT BAXTER FOUND OUT,
AND THAT CRAFTY
SON OF A BITCH KILLED HIM.
MADE IT LOOK LIKE
A DRUG OVERDOSE
SO I'D SHUT DOWN THE CASE.
HE PLAYED ME.
EXCEPT LINDEN ISN'T
THE KILLER, IS HE, RACHEL?
ARE YOU TWO READING
EACH OTHER'S MINDS NOW?
MURDER IS NOT
IN LINDEN'S PROFILE.
HE LIKES TO CONTROL THE TRUTH,
BUT ONLY FROM THE BACKGROUND.
HE WAS NEVER IN THAT HOTEL.
THINK HE HAD SOMEONE
DO HIS DIRTY WORK FOR HIM?
MM-HMM.
ALL RIGHT.
WHEN DO WE MOVE?
[ Both ] WE DON'T.
THERE'S A KILLER OUT THERE,
AND LINDEN IS GOING TO
LEAD US RIGHT TO HIM.
DADDY, THE CENTRE DID THIS.
YOU DID THIS.
YOU FORGOT.
THE TRIUMVIRATE GAVE THE ORDERS.
I CARRIED THEM OUT.
- I KNEW YOU WOULD SAY THAT.
- I DON'T LIKE YOUR ATTITUDE.
DADDY, PLEASE.
I JUST WANT SYDNEY
TO HAVE SOME CLOSURE.
[ Sighs ]
IT CAN BE ARRANGED.
- [ Intercom Beeps ]
- MR. MORGENSTERN.
[ Gasps ]
CLAUDIA.
[ Speaking French ]
[ French ]
OH, SYDNEY.
[ French Continues ]
WHEN YOU TOLD ME WHAT
SYDNEY WAS GOING THROUGH,
I HAD HER FLOWN IN.
SHE'S A GROUNDBREAKING
PSYCHIATRIST AT A TEACHING
HOSPITAL OUTSIDE OF PARIS.
A HOSPITAL FUNDED
BY THE CENTRE.
AFTER THE ACCIDENT,
SHE HEALED UP QUICKLY.
WE GAVE HER A FUTURE, A CAREER.
AND TOLD HER THAT
SYDNEY WAS DEAD.
WELL, THAT'S ONE ORDER
I WISH I'D NEVER TAKEN.
ANGEL, A NEW LIFE
CHANGES EVERYTHING.
I TOLD YOU.
IT'S A BRAND-NEW DAY.
[ Rings ]
COMMUNICATIONS.
LINDEN.
[ Jarod ]
I'M WATCHING YOU.
WHO THE HELL IS THIS?
I'M THE MAN YOU HIRED
TO THROW TODD BAXTER
OUT THE WINDOW.
BAXTER COMMITTED SUICIDE.
NO.
YOU HIRED ME TO KILL HIM,
DIDN'T YOU?
I'LL TAKE THAT
AS A "NO COMMENT."
IF YOU CARE
TO EXPLAIN YOURSELF,
OFF THE RECORD,
MEET ME AT
THE RIVER GLEN HOTEL,
ROOM 814.
HELLO?
ANYONE HERE?
YOU DON'T THINK
I'D BE FOOLISH ENOUGH
TO BE ARMED, DO YOU?
I'M ABOUT TO FIND OUT
HOW BIG A FOOL YOU ARE.
AGENT WILKES.
SO WHAT IS THIS?
IT'S THE RIVER GLEN HOTEL.
NOT EXACTLY THE WATERGATE,
BUT SCANDALS CAN BE
MADE HERE AS WELL.
WELL, I SURE HOPE YOU BROUGHT
YOUR WALLET SO YOU CAN BUY
YOUR FREEDOM.
INNOCENT MEN
DON'T NEED TO.
[ Jarod ]
THESE DOCUMENTS THAT
I STOLE FROM YOUR OFFICE--
THEY SEEM
TO SAY OTHERWISE.
WELL, AREN'T YOU
INDUSTRIOUS.
FABRICATIONS DESIGNED
TO DESTROY AN HONEST MAN.
LIKE THE ONES
YOU CREATE?
THAT TODD BAXTER
DISCOVERED?
YOU MAKE A FORTUNE
CREATING SCANDALS
THAT RUIN PEOPLE'S LIVES,
EVEN END THEM.
JAROD, IF YOU'RE TRYING
TO GET ME TO MAKE
A VERBAL ADMISSION...
FOR SOMETHING
I KNOW NOTHING ABOUT,
FOR YOU OR...
WHOEVER ELSE IS WATCHING--
DAMN IT.
I'M AFRAID YOU GOT
THE WRONG FOOL.
[ Sighs ]
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I AM A FOOL FOR EVER
BELIEVING YOU COULD POSSIBLY
JUST TELL THE TRUTH.
- WE'RE DONE HERE.
- OH, WE ARE JUST...
GETTING STARTED.
WE'D BETTER
GET IN THERE.
NO, JUST GIVE HIM A MINUTE.
- I WOULDN'T WANT YOU
TO MISS IT.
- MISS WHAT?
YOUR SUICIDE.
[ Gasps ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Sighs ]
♪♪ [ Whistling ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M SETTING THE SCENE,
JUST LIKE THE MAN YOU HIRED
TO KILL TODD BAXTER DID.
[ Groans ]
I'M GONNA MAKE IT SEEM
LIKE YOU HAD AN EVENING
OF... DRUGS.
THEN YOU TOOK A SWAN DIVE
OUT THE WINDOW.
HOPE THEY FIND
YOUR BODY SOONER.
NO, WAIT. WAIT! NO!
MMM. NO WAITING.
NO! NO!
[ Grunts ]
WHO DID IT? YOU TELL ME
WHO KILLED TODD BAXTER,
OR THEY'LL BE FISHING YOUR BODY
OUT OF THE POTOMAC--
WHAT'S LEFT OF IT.
I CAN PAY YOU.
JUST FORGET ABOUT BAXTER.
MONEY?
YEAH.
TODD BAXTER
SAVED MY LIFE!
YOU KILLED HIM.
I'M GONNA EVEN THE SCORE!
NO! YOU'RE CRAZY.
PLAN "B." PLAN "B."
GO TO PLAN "B"!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU WARNING YOUR ACCOMPLICE?
YOU TELL ME WHO KILLED HIM,
OR I WILL DROP YOU
OUT OF THIS WINDOW!
HOLDER. AGENT HOLDER.
WHERE IS HE?
HE'S IN THE SERVICE ELEVATOR
AT THE END OF THE HALL.
GET UP!
NO! NO! NO!
GOOD LUCK.
YEAH, YOU TOO.
IS THIS
MORE BOUILLABAISSE?
NO, I ONLY HAD 30 SECONDS.
IT'S CHICKEN NOODLE.
[ Laughs ]
THE CHICKEN
ALMOST TASTES REAL.
MMM.
THAT'S WHY
YOU'RE UNDERCOVER.
YOU'RE ALONE
IN THIS WORLD.
WE ALL HAVE SECRETS.
NO FAMILY?
NO ONE TO GET CLOSE TO?
NOT YET.
I SHOULD GET BACK
TO THE OFFICE.
JAROD. THIS-- THIS WAS MORE
THAN JUST A CASE FOR YOU.
WHY?
LET'S JUST SAY
I WAS HELPING OUT...
AN OLD FRIEND.
WELL, IF YOU EVER
NEED A NEW FRIEND,
YOU CAN CALL ME.