I AM SORRY.
UH, PARDON ME. UH--
YOU'RE NAKED.
AND YOU'RE NOT.
UH-UH. NO, I--
SO, EITHER YOU
TAKE YOURS OFF,
OR I'LL PUT MINE ON.
THESE PEOPLE ARE CHASING--
I, UH-- I GOTTA GO.
EASY THERE,
MR. MAINTENANCE MAN.
I WAS JUST RECHARGING MY CORE.
IT'S LIKE TIME TRAVEL
IN THE TERMINATOR.
YOU'VE GOTTA BE IN THE SKIN.
IT'S GREAT FOR YOUR KARMA.
KARMA? WHAT'S KARMA?
UM, EVERY GOOD DEED COMES BACK
TO YOU. LIKE A BOOMERANG,
ONLY YOU DON'T THROW IT.
GOD, YOUR LIFELINE--
IT SAYS YOU'VE BEEN ALONE.
BUT THERE ARE THESE FAMILIES
COMING TOGETHER.
FAMILIES?
WHAT?
THEY'RE LOOKING FOR YOU.
AND WHILE YOU SEARCH FOR THEM,
YOU BRING OTHER
FAMILIES TOGETHER.
KEEP DOING WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
THE GOOD WILL COME BACK.
OH, THANK YOU.
NOW I REALLY HAVE TO GO.
WAIT, YOUR LIFELINE, IT SAID
SOMETHING ELSE. YOU ARE GONNA
MEET SOMEBODY JUST LIKE YOU.
A KINDRED SPIRIT.
A KINDRED SPIRIT. HMM.
UM, MISS,
YOU DROPPED YOUR BAG.
DAMN!
"JENNA."
[ Naked Woman's Voice ]
YOU BRING OTHER FAMILIES
TOGETHER.
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE DEFENDS THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
HOW WAS YOUR BREAKFAST,
MR. PRITCHARD?
SAM, YOU MISSED
SOME KILLER PANCAKES.
MY GIRL HERE IS
A BUDDING CHEF.
[ Chuckles ]
WELL, DON'T THANK ME.
THANK BISQUICK.
CHUCK, YOU'RE IN
THE BACK TODAY.
IF ANYBODY NEEDS ME,
I'LL BE PUTTING OUT FIRES.
HERE WE GO. ANOTHER DAY,
ANOTHER DOLLAR.
[ Car Alarm Blaring ]
SOUNDS LIKE THE BUICK.
YEAH, WELL, DOES
NUMB NUTS KNOW?
[ Coughing ]
SECONDHAND SMOKE.
IT'S A KILLER.
[ Ringing ]
YEAH, BABE?
YOU BETTER GET IN HERE.
CHUCK! CHUCK?
[ Chuck ]
SAM! I'M IN THE TRUNK!
GET ME OUTTA THE TRUNK!
SON OF A BITCH!
SAM! HURRY UP!
I'M IN THE TRUNK!
- SAM, MEET JAROD GRAY.
- YOU'RE LATE.
- WHAT IS THIS?
- IT'S A TEST. JAROD'S
WITH OUR SECURITY COMPANY.
THE SAME ONE WE'RE PAYING
FOR FOUR-STAR PROTECTION.
THE KIND WE'RE NOT GETTING.
HOW'D YOU BEAT THE CAMERAS?
IT WAS VERY DIFFICULT.
SORRY ABOUT ALL THE BELLS
AND WHISTLES,
BUT THE COMPANY LIKES
TO KEEP OUR MEN FROSTY.
SPEAKING OF WHICH, YOU MIGHT
WANT TO GET YOUR HEAD OF
SECURITY OUT OF THE TRUNK.
IT'S GETTING A LITTLE
CHILLY OUT THERE.
TELL CHUCK, NOW HE'S THE
NIGHT WATCHMAN, AND JAROD'S
THE NEW HEAD OF SECURITY.
GET HIM AN ADVANCE.
ROLAND, THIS ISN'T SMART
RIGHT NOW. WE GOT THAT THING
IN NEW BRUNSWICK.
YOU WANNA BE
THE NIGHT WATCHMAN?
WELCOME ABOARD.
JAROD, DO YOU KNOW JENNA?
YOU LOOK... SO FAMILIAR.
I HAVE ONE OF THOSE FACES.
[ Miss Parker ]
IS MY LITTLE BROTHER
GONNA BE OKAY?
WELL, HIS LUNGS
WERE UNDERDEVELOPED,
BUT THE OXYGEN SHOULD HELP.
THAT'S MY BOY.
GOD'S GREATEST MIRACLE.
[ Speaking Gibberish ]
THE REAL MIRACLE
WOULD BE FOR YOU AND ME...
IN THE SHADOW OF NEW LIFE
TO START ANEW.
THE GOOD BOOK SAYS
"TURN THE OTHER CHEEK."
I ALSO REMEMBER SOMETHING
ABOUT "EYE FOR AN EYE."
OH, JAROD SENT A GIFT.
"CORINTHIANS, 15:25.
EVEN A CHILD
IS KNOWN BY HIS DOINGS."
RING A BELL THERE,
JOHNNY DOGMA?
GOD BLESS YOU ALL.
WILLIE, OUR WORK HERE
IS DONE.
[ Sydney ]
IT'S WRONG?
IT'S NOT CORINTHIANS.
IT'S PROVERBS.
OF COURSE RAINES
HAD NO CLUE.
WELL, HOW DID YOU KNOW?
CORINTHIANS, 15:25.
"FOR HE MUST REIGN TILL
HE HATH PUT ALL ENEMIES
UNDER HIS FEET."
THE OPERATIVE TERM
BEING "REIGN."
- WHAT DO YOU THINK
JAROD'S TRYING TO TELL US?
- RAINES IS NO CONVERT.
HE ACTUALLY ASKED ME
TO FORGIVE HIM.
MAYBE RAINES HAS FOUND GOD.
MAYBE HE SHOULD HAVE
THOUGHT OF THAT BEFORE
HE KILLED MY MOTHER.
FIND OUT WHAT THAT
SON OF A BITCH IS UP TO.
OKAY.
[ Sam ]
HEY, LOOK AT THE
NEW GUY HARD AT WORK.
I CALLED THE COMPANY
ABOUT YOU.
I THOUGHT ONLY CUSTOMERS
GOT A BACKGROUND CHECK.
SO, WHAT DID OLD RUDY
HAVE TO SAY?
AH, YOU'RE FROM BALTIMORE,
AN EX-COP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SIX YEARS HOMICIDE.
I GOT TIRED
OF LOSIN' MY COLLARS
TO THE COURTS.
THAT'S WHERE WE GOTTA
CHANGE THE BOOKS.
2,200 GUN LAWS, MORE THAN
WE CAN ENFORCE, AND I'M
THE BAD GUY? I'M A SALESMAN.
WHY WOULD A COP LEAVE
A FAT PENSION TO TAKE
A BULLET FOR SOMEBODY?
WHY DOES A SALESMAN
NEED TWO BODYGUARDS?
WELL, WE ALL
GOT ENEMIES, JAROD.
WELL, MAYBE YOU SHOULD SPREAD
SOME BETTER KARMA AROUND.
KARMA?
YEAH. IT'S LIKE
A BOOMERANG,
ONLY YOU DON'T THROW IT.
- LONG DAY, MRS. PRITCHARD?
- OH, I'M NOT
MRS. PRITCHARD YET.
ROLAND'S GOT ME ON LAYAWAY.
WE START MAKIN' WEDDING
PLANS AFTER SATURDAY.
- THE TRIP TO NEW BRUNSWICK.
- YEAH. GOTTA SEE A FRIEND.
I'M GONNA WANT THE BUICK SWEPT
AND SECURED TOMORROW MORNING.
GOTTA PROTECT
MY INVESTMENT.
YOU TALKIN' ABOUT ME
OR THE ROCK?
AIN'T I LUCKY?
ALL THIS AND
A SENSE OF HUMOR.
SHE MEANS EVERYTHING TO ME.
YOU TAKE A BULLET FOR HER...
BEFORE YOU EVEN THINK
ABOUT TAKIN' ONE FOR ME.
WELL, I CERTAINLY HOPE
IT DOESN'T COME TO THAT.
[ Car Approaching ]
SHE'S MY DAUGHTER, DENNIS.
I HAVE TO SEE HER.
SHE'S AT ST. CHARLES.
- NO, I'M LEAVING. I'M LEAVING.
- NOT WITHOUT ME, I HOPE.
JAROD.
IT'S ONLY GOING TO GET WORSE
AFTER YOU'RE MARRIED.
HE'S GONNA WANT YOU WATCHED
ALL THE TIME. THEN WHEN
YOU HAVE THE LITTLE ONES--
OH, WE WON'T BE
HAVING CHILDREN.
ROLAND'S CHOICE.
- HE'S A GOOD MAN.
- I NEVER SAID HE WASN'T.
YOU THOUGHT IT, THOUGH.
EVERYONE DOES.
IT'S THIS BUSINESS.
BUT ROLAND'S MADE
A GOOD LIFE FOR US.
IT'S LIKE A... HAPPY ENDING.
YOU DO BELIEVE IN
HAPPY ENDINGS, DON'T YOU?
[ Car Approaching ]
GET DOWN!
YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
[ Policeman ]
MAKE A LIST OF ALL
THOSE EMPLOYEES THAT--
I'M SUPPOSED TO KNOW
WHEN YOU LEAVE THE BUILDING.
THANK YOU.
- [ Camera Shutter Clicking ]
- DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO DID THIS?
I'D RATHER KNOW HOW
THEY GOT SO CLOSE.
- IT WAS MY FAULT.
I JUST-- I WAS--
- NO, IT WAS MY FAULT.
I WENT TO GET THE CAR.
I-- I LET MY GUARD DOWN.
YOU SAVED HER LIFE.
THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
SHE'S GONNA HAVE
MY KIDS SOMEDAY.
[ Camera Shutter Clicking ]
LET'S GO.
[ Jenna's Voice ]
SHE'S MY DAUGHTER, DENNIS.
I HAVE TO SEE HER.
SHE'S AT ST. CHARLES.
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU, PAL?
THE BODY OF CHRIST.
AMEN.
[ Door Opens ]
THE BODY OF CHRIST.
MR. McGANN, YOUR DAUGHTER
AND I HAVE A DEAL.
SHE'D BETTER HONOR IT
IF SHE KNOWS WHAT'S GOOD
FOR YOU AND THE KID.
THE BODY OF CHRIST.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Gunfire ]
UH--
SORRY TO INTERRUPT.
I CAN COME BACK ANOTHER TIME.
NO, UH, I GOT WORK TO DO.
GREAT.
- KEEP AN EYE
ON THE PRIZE, WILL YA?
- OH. SURE, NO PROBLEM.
SO, UH, THANKS AGAIN...
FOR THIS MORNING.
WE'RE REALLY GETTIN'
OUR MONEY'S WORTH.
YOU'RE RIGHT. WE HAVE MET.
AT MY HOUSE.
AGENT DENNIS ALONZO.
HE FOLLOWED ME TO YOUR
DAUGHTER'S FIRST COMMUNION
REHEARSAL AT ST. CHARLES.
HE SEEMS TO BE STRONG-ARMING
YOUR FATHER. WHY?
IS HE TRYING
TO GET YOU TO TESTIFY AGAINST
YOUR FIANCÉ OR SOMETHING?
LOOK, I CAN PROTECT YOU.
AND I CAN HELP YOU
GET YOUR FAMILY BACK.
BUT YOU'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO TRUST ME.
YOU'RE WRONG, MR. GRAY.
I CAN'T TRUST ANYONE.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE GETTING INTO.
"OPERATION FAT CAT.
OBJECTIVE: SECURE EVIDENCE
ON ROLAND PRITCHARD.
OWNS 10 TRISTATE
GUN SHOPS, MONEY LAUNDERING,
ILLEGAL FILES AND--"
- WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
- I'M AN EX-COP.
AND I'M SOMEONE
WHO CAN HELP YOU
GET YOUR DAUGHTER BACK.
TELL ME SHE'S OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, I'M GONNA FINISH
THIS ASSIGNMENT.
- JUST TELL ME THAT SHE'S OKAY.
- ASSIGNMENT?
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE A.T.F.
OH, MY GOD. HOW LONG
HAVE YOU BEEN UNDERCOVER?
TWELVE MONTHS, 13 DAYS.
TWELVE MONTHS?
YOU'VE BEEN APART FROM YOUR
DAUGHTER FOR OVER A YEAR?
I MISS MY LITTLE GIRL.
♪♪ [ Rap ]
[ Police Siren Wailing ]
THIS BETTER BE GOOD.
OKAY.
THE CARD JAROD
SENT WITH THE GIFT--
THE CHAPTER AND THE
VERSE NUMBERS WERE A CODE
FOR RAINES'S COMPUTER.
EVERY DAY FOR THE LAST
SIX MONTHS, RAINES HAS BEEN
MEETING WITH THAT GUY.
OH, MY GOD.
GIUSEPPE.
YOU KNOW HIM?
JUNIOR YEAR
OF HIGH SCHOOL. ROME.
LOOK AT HIM.
YOU GUYS WERE LIKE
A THING OR SOMETHING?
HE WAS MY DATE
FOR THE SPRING FORMAL.
HE TRIED TO GET TO THIRD BASE
IN THE FRONT SEAT
OF HIS FATHER'S FERRARI.
I BROKE HIS FINGER.
BOY, HE IS
STILL A BISCUIT.
YOU MEAN BISCOTTI,
DON'T YOU?
[ Man ]
LOOK UP! LOOK UP! LOOK UP!
SHOOT!
♪♪ [ Rap ]
PARKER, IS THAT YOU?
GIUSEPPE.
YOU'RE LOOKING VERY WELL.
YOU TOO. VERY WELL.
GIVE ME A MOMENT,
WILL YA?
HOW'S THE FINGER?
OH, IT'S-- IT'S STILL BENT.
YEAH, I FEEL BAD
ABOUT THAT.
WELL, I HAVE, UH,
CHANGED A LOT SINCE THEN.
YES, YOU HAVE.
THIS ALL STARTED
WHEN WE TRACED SOME GUNS BACK
TO ONE OF ROLAND'S SHOPS.
THEY'D BEEN USED
IN A SCHOOL SHOOTING.
THE OPERATION WAS SUPPOSED
TO TAKE THREE MONTHS, TOPS.
THAT SNOWBALLED INTO A YEAR.
I STARTED OUT AS,
UH, ROLAND'S ASSISTANT.
AND THEN ONE DAY
HE ASKED ME OUT.
A.T.F. SAID,
"COULDN'T HURT."
A CUP OF COFFEE
TURNS INTO AN EVENING.
[ Sighs ]
ALONZO FORCED ME
TO GO WITH IT.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW,
I'M WEARING AN ENGAGEMENT RING.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
UNDERCOVER, JAROD?
ONCE OR TWICE.
SHE HAS YOUR EYES.
YOU'VE SEEN HER?
YES. HER AND
YOUR FATHER.
THEY BOTH LOOK WELL,
CONSIDERING.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN
SINCE YOU SAW THEM?
TWO MONTHS.
I USED TO GO EVERY WEEK,
BUT, UH, ALONZO PUT
A STOP TO THAT.
SAID ROLAND
WAS GETTING TOO CLOSE.
AND WHAT ABOUT YOU?
WERE YOU GETTING TOO CLOSE?
[ Shouting ]
YOU THINK I'M ENJOYING THIS?
LOOK, I KNOW CASSIE NEEDS ME,
BUT I CAN'T WALK!
AND WHAT IF ROLAND
FINDS OUT ABOUT HER?
HER FATHER'S GONE.
SHE CAN'T LOSE
ANOTHER PARENT.
JENNA, JUST KEEP
YOUR VOICE DOWN.
I UNDERSTAND.
THEY'VE MOVED CASS
AND MY DAD, AND ALONZO
WON'T LET ME SEE THEM.
WHATEVER IT TAKES
TO GET THE FAT CAT.
DON'T YOU HAVE ENOUGH
ON PRITCHARD TO PUT HIM AWAY?
ROLAND'S NOT THE TARGET.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW WHO
ALL THIS MONEY WASHING'S FOR.
[ Sighs ]
- WE MEET HIM IN TWO DAYS.
- THE OLD FRIEND
IN NEW BRUNSWICK.
DO ME A FAVOR.
KEEP THIS. IT BELONGED
TO MY MOTHER.
I WANT CASSIE TO HAVE
THAT... IF, UH,
THINGS DON'T WORK OUT.
EVERYTHING WILL WORK OUT.
AND THEN WHAT?
I DON'T KNOW WHO
I AM ANYMORE, JAROD.
PEOPLE CHANGE. WE USED
TO CALL YOU "SHIFTY G."
IT'S NO WONDER THAT
YOU'RE RAINES'S PRIEST.
THIS IS ABOUT WILLIAM?
OF COURSE.
JAROD SAID YOU'D COME.
YOU KNOW JAROD?
FATHER JAROD IS THE
BISHOP'S FAVORITE ENVOY.
AND MR. RAINES IS STUDYING
TO BE A DEACON.
THAT'S WHY
HE'S MEETING WITH YOU.
NO. DAILY CONFESSION.
WILLIAM LIVES WITH MANY DEMONS.
BUT HE IS ALSO
A CHILD OF GOD.
HE WILL BE GRANTED ABSOLUTION...
NO MATTER WHAT HIS SINS.
INCLUDING MURDER?
HE FEELS VERY BADLY
ABOUT CATHERINE'S DEATH,
AND REGRETS PROFOUNDLY
THE PAIN IT CAUSED
HER DAUGHTER.
WHAT OTHER LIES
DID HE TELL YOU?
I CAN'T BETRAY WHAT
HE TOLD ME IN CONFESSION.
HOWEVER, JAROD WAS CURIOUS
ABOUT SOMETHING...
MR. RAINES
TOLD HIS ASSOCIATE
IN THE PARKING LOT.
SOMETHING ABOUT
THE... VERITAS PROJECT.
VERITAS. TRUTH.
OVERHEARD IN THE PARKING LOT.
IS THAT YOUR WAY
OF BETRAYING A CONFESSION?
I WAS WRONG ABOUT YOU.
YOU'RE WORSE THAN RAINES.
SO FULL OF ANGER.
THAT'S MY RELIGION.
[ Camera Shutter Clicking ]
UH, I'LL BE RIGHT UP.
I'M GONNA MAKE A PHONE CALL.
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
THIS IS ALONZO.
SO,
HOW DO I LOOK?
SO YOU'RE AN EX-COP,
DETECTIVE JAROD GRAY.
SIX YEARS BALTIMORE P.D.
THAT GIVE YOU SOME RIGHT
TO JEOPARDIZE MY OPERATION?
YOU'RE DOIN' A FINE JOB.
I OVERHEARD JENNA YELLING
AT YOU ON YOUR CELL PHONE.
- YOU'RE LUCKY IT WAS ME THAT
OVERHEARD AND NOT PRITCHARD.
- JEN'S A LITTLE FRAYED NOW.
WHO WOULDN'T BE?
YOU'VE TAKEN HER FAMILY, YOU'RE
PRACTICALLY BLACKMAILING HER.
WHY DON'T YOU ADMIT IT?
YOU'RE IN OVER YOUR HEAD.
YOU THINK I WANTED THIS?
THESE ATTACKS ON PRITCHARD
ARE GETTIN' WORSE.
- I'VE NOTICED.
WHO'S TRYIN' TO KILL HIM?
- YOU TELL ME.
OBVIOUSLY YOU'VE READ MY FILE.
YOU KNOW THAT I WAS A GOOD COP
AND I'M HERE TO HELP.
NOW, WHO IS TRYIN' TO KILL HIM?
THE BEST WE CAN FIGURE
IT'S A CLIENT.
PRITCHARD'S SKIMMING
FROM THE PEOPLE
HE'S LAUNDERING MONEY FOR.
- SO HE'S MORE DANGEROUS
THAN I THOUGHT HE WAS.
- YOU HAVE NO IDEA.
- WHAT'S THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
- WHO THE HELL ARE YOU, ANYWAY?
I'M SOMEBODY WHO'S TRYING TO
MAKE SURE THAT AGENT McGANN
DOESN'T END UP DEAD.
ABOUT A YEAR AGO,
RIGHT AFTER JEN STARTED
WORKIN' UNDERCOVER HERE,
WE FOUND ONE OF PRITCHARD'S
GUN SUPPLIERS DEAD IN THE
WOODS, DOUBLE TAP AT THE CHEST.
NOW, WORD WAS HE CROSSED
PRITCHARD, BUT WE NEVER FOUND
A WEAPON TO MATCH BALLISTICS.
SO, YOU WEREN'T ABLE TO PIN
THE MURDER ON PRITCHARD.
- NO.
- AND NOW YOU'RE HOLDING
AGENT McGANN'S DAUGHTER?
WE'RE NOT HOLDING HER.
WE'RE PROTECTING HER.
BY MAKING HER MOTHER STAY
WITH A KILLER?
JEN MAY BE IN DEEP,
BUT SHE'S THE BEST AGENT I KNOW.
- THREE MORE DAYS,
SHE'LL GET US WHAT WE NEED.
- US... OR YOU?
EXCUSE ME, MR. McGANN?
AGENT JAROD GRAY,
A.T.F.
I CAME DOWN HERE
TO TELL YOU THAT YOUR DAUGHTER
WILL BE HOME SOON.
JUST IN TIME FOR CASSIE'S
FIRST COMMUNION, RIGHT?
I DON'T BELIEVE
A.T.F. LIES ANYMORE.
THAT'S NOT A LIE, SIR.
IT'S A PROMISE.
CASSIE. MR. GRAY HERE WORKS
WITH YOUR MOTHER.
MY MOMMY CATCHES BAD GUYS.
YES, CASSIE, SHE DOES.
SHE ASKED ME TO
COME DOWN HERE...
TO TELL YOU THAT
SHE MISSES YOU VERY MUCH,
AND SHE'LL SEE YOU SOON.
I SEE HER AT NIGHT,
IN MY DREAMS.
BUT IT'S NOT THE SAME.
CASSIE, YOUR MOM ASKED ME
TO GIVE YOU THIS.
SHE WANTS YOU TO
TAKE VERY GOOD CARE OF IT.
LOOK AT THAT, KIDDO.
THAT WAS YOUR GRANDMA'S RING.
MOMMY HASN'T COME
IN A LONG TIME.
DOES SHE NOT WANNA
SEE US?
OF COURSE SHE DOES, CASSIE.
I TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU SAVE A SEAT FOR HER
AT YOUR COMMUNION.
THAT'S A MIGHTY BIG PROMISE
YOU'RE MAKING.
[ Jarod ]
SHE'LL BE HERE.
[ Gunfire ]
JENNA, PRITCHARD, GET DOWN!
[ Gunshot ]
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
STRIKE ME DOWN NOW, LORD.
WILLIE.
MISS PARKER.
THIS SAINTLY ROUTINE
IS WEARIN' KIND OF THIN,
DON'T YOU THINK, DEACON?
YOU'VE BEEN TALKING
TO MY PRIEST.
PLEASE. SIT.
WE'VE BEEN DOWN
A DARK ROAD, YOU AND I.
OUR FOOTPRINTS SIDE-BY-SIDE.
BUT AT TIMES...
THERE WAS ONLY ONE SET.
THAT WAS WHEN I CARRIED YOU.
REALLY?
I THOUGHT THAT WAS WHEN
YOU WERE OFF KILLING MY MOTHER.
BELIEVE WHAT YOU MUST BELIEVE,
MISS PARKER.
BUT FIND IT IN YOUR HEART
TO FORGIVE ME. IT WILL
GIVE YOU INNER PEACE.
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
WHAT?
- WHERE ARE YOU?
- YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE ME
IF I TOLD YOU.
THIS VERITAS THING
RAINES AND WILLIE
WERE TALKING ABOUT.
IT'S AN EXPERIMENTAL
AIRBORNE TOXIN...
DEVELOPED BY THE CENTRE
AND SHELVED IN THE '80s.
- RAINES IS RESURRECTING IT.
- SOME PEOPLE CAN'T RESIST
TEMPTATION.
YOU KNOW THE ONE ABOUT
"THOU SHALL NOT COVET"?
OF COURSE.
THAT'S ONE COMMANDMENT
YOU DON'T WANT TO BREAK.
THANKING YOU IS GETTIN'
TO BE A HABIT.
JUST DOING MY JOB.
- WHAT'S THE WORD ON THE GUNMAN?
- MURETTA AND I GOTTA
TALK TO THE COPS.
YOU OKAY?
THAT LOOK IN YOUR EYES,
IT'S GENUINE CONCERN FOR HIM.
EMOTIONAL ASSIMILATION.
THE PSYCHOLOGICAL
SIDE EFFECT OF PROLONGED
UNDERCOVER WORK.
YOU ARE AN EXPERT.
JUST DON'T FORGET THAT THE MAN
YOU'RE ENGAGED TO IS A KILLER.
ROLAND'S DONE A LOT
OF TERRIBLE THINGS,
BUT HE'S NO KILLER.
- ALONZO DIDN'T TELL YOU,
DID HE?
- TELL ME WHAT?
HE'S UNBELIEVABLE.
JAROD?
ALONZO HAS LEFT OUT
A SMALL DETAIL.
SINCE HE PUT THAT RING
ON YOUR FINGER, PRITCHARD
KILLED A GUN SUPPLIER.
WHAT?
STAY FOCUSED OR GET OUT.
OKAY, UH--
LET'S JUST SAY
THAT HE IS A KILLER.
THAT'S ALL THE MORE REASON
FOR ME TO STAY UNDER.
I DON'T WANT ANYTHING TO
HAPPEN TO MY LITTLE GIRL.
IT'S JUST...
ONE MORE NIGHT,
UNLESS, OF COURSE,
YOU KNOW...
WHERE THE MEETING IS
IN NEW BRUNSWICK.
YOUR FIANCÉ KEEPS THAT
A SECRET.
THEN AGAIN, I KNOW
WHERE HE KEEPS THOSE.
[ Beeps ]
[ Beeping ]
LOOKS LIKE
YOUR COVER'S BLOWN,
AGENT McGANN.
THIS IS WHAT RAINES
WAS UP TO.
VERITAS WAS TESTED HERE
IN THE EARLY '80s.
IF THIS IS A DEAD END, I'M GONNA
TRACK DOWN FATHER GIUSEPPE
AND BREAK HIS OTHER NINE DIGITS.
IT MIGHT BE KIND OF FUN,
ACTUALLY.
MORE OF THAT FORBIDDEN
PRIEST THING, HUH?
[ Chuckles ] JUST OPEN THE DOOR.
THE DOOR SEEMS TO BE
PRESSURIZED OR SOMETHING.
I GOT IT.
[ Coughs ]
THERE'S SOME KIND OF GAS!
BROOTS! BROOTS!
OH, MY GOD!
[ Coughs ]
CANARY. CANARY IN
A COAL MINE. CANARY.
CANARY IN A COAL MINE?
[ Coughing Continues ]
BROOTS, I WANT YOU TO FIND OUT
ANYTHING ELSE YOU CAN ABOUT HOW
THIS GAS COULD POSSIBLY BE USED.
I'M GONNA GO FIND
FATHER GIUSEPPE.
HAVE SYDNEY TAKE A LOOK AT YOU.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL HER?
CERTAIN DETAILS ARE KEPT
FROM AN AGENT.
STOP MAKING EXCUSES.
YOU CROSSED THE LINE.
THE MAN IS A KILLER!
THE AGENT
COULD BE COMPROMISED!
THE AGENT WAS COMPROMISED!
WHAT?
I FOUND JENNA'S PERSONNEL FILE
IN PRITCHARD'S GUN SAFE.
LISTEN TO ME.
WE DON'T MAKE A MOVE UNTIL
PRITCHARD MAKES A MOVE.
WHAT IF HE MAKES A MOVE ON
JENNA? YOU PREPARED TO DREDGE
YOUR AGENT UP FROM THE HUDSON?
SHE KNOWS THE RISKS.
WHAT DID YOU JUST SAY?
IT'S THE JOB!
IS MAKING HER DAUGHTER AN ORPHAN
PART OF THE JOB TOO?
WE'LL WATCH PRITCHARD.
HE WON'T TAKE A DUMP WITHOUT US
KNOWING. HE WON'T DO ANYTHING.
YOU'D BETTER PRAY
THAT HE DOESN'T.
YOU'RE THE BODYGUARD!
PROTECT HER!
THOSE MANDATORY TRIGGER LOCKS,
THEY'RE A BITCH,
AREN'T THEY?
THEY'RE NOT MANDATORY YET.
I GOT NO ILLUSIONS
ABOUT WHAT I DO, JAROD.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
WHEN SOME PISSED-OFF
DAY TRADER...
DECIDES TO TAKE AN A.K.
TO HIS BROKERAGE FIRM,
I'M NOT STANDIN' THERE
HANDIN' HIM BULLETS
EITHER.
BUT WHAT IF HE NEEDS
SOME MONEY LAUNDERED?
COME AGAIN?
I LIKE TO KNOW
WHO I'M PROTECTING.
SOMETIMES KNOWLEDGE
IS NOT POWER.
WELL, IN MY CASE, IT IS.
JENNA ISN'T EXACTLY
WHO SHE SAYS SHE IS.
SHE'S A.T.F.
WHO HAVE YOU TOLD
ABOUT THIS?
NOBODY.
LOOKS LIKE NOW YOU'RE GONNA
NEED SOME HELP CALLING OFF
YOUR ENGAGEMENT.
LET'S JUST SAY
I HAVE SOME EXPERIENCE
IN THIS ARENA.
NO. I MEANT WHAT
I SAID. YOU TAKE
A BULLET FOR HER.
- JEN IS MY FUTURE.
- ARE YOU TELLIN' ME
YOU'RE IN LOVE WITH HER?
LET'S JUST SAY I'M IN LOVE
WITH WHAT SHE CAN GIVE ME--
A GET-OUT-OF-JAIL-FREE CARD.
SO, TONIGHT, WHEN WE'RE SAFE,
JENNA RADIOS HER BOSS
AND I GIVE THEM THE FAT CAT...
AND WE GET A LITTLE
BEACH HOUSE IN A SEXY,
NON-EXTRADITION COUNTRY.
- IF SHE FOLLOWS THE PLAN.
- SHE WILL.
A COLT 1911 "A."
IT CAN BE VERY CONVINCING.
BUT I GOT SOMETHIN'
BETTER THAN THAT.
JEN'S DAUGHTER.
CUTE KID, HUH?
LIKE I SAID, JAROD,
I GOT NO ILLUSIONS
ABOUT WHAT I DO.
[ Giuseppe ]
YOU KNOW HOW I STAND ON THIS.
[ Miss Parker ]
RAINES TOLD ME WHAT HE'S
DOING WITH THE VERITAS GAS.
HE CONFESSED!
HE SAID NOTHING ABOUT THAT.
HE'S A PSYCHOTIC KILLER.
AND HE'S UP
TO SOMETHING HORRIFIC.
DO YOU DEFINE ALL MEN
BY THEIR SINS?
ONLY THE BAD ONES.
ONLY THE ONES THAT TAKE
A GIRL IN THE BASILICA
DE ROMA AND COP A FEEL.
THAT'S NOT TRUE AND YOU KNOW IT.
THIS ISN'T ABOUT TWO TEENAGERS
GROPING IN A BASILICA.
BESIDES, IT WAS YOU
WHO CAME ON TO ME.
[ Scoffs ]
I REJECTED YOU. THE PAIN OF THAT
REJECTION LIVES INSIDE YOU.
NOT TRUE.
IT IS TRUE, PARKER.
YOU'VE REWRITTEN HISTORY.
CREATE AN ENEMY IN YOUR MIND
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT
YOU NEEDED TO SURVIVE.
ANGER IS YOUR RELIGION.
AND YOU NEED ENEMIES LIKE ME
AND MR. RAINES TO FUEL
THAT DISTORTED FAITH.
IF THY BROTHER TRESPASS
AGAINST YOU, REBUKE HIM.
AND IF HE REPENT,
FORGIVE HIM.
- HE KILLED MY MOTHER.
- IF HE TRESPASSED
AGAINST THEE...
- HE HAS PRESIDED OVER EVERY
MOMENT OF PAIN IN MY LIFE.
- SEVEN TIMES IN A DAY,
HE'S A MONSTER!
THOU SHALT FORGIVE HIM!
AND YOU ARE NOT HIS PRIEST.
YOU'RE HIS COCONSPIRATOR!
FORGIVE YOURSELF, PARKER.
IF YOU DON'T, YOU'LL SURELY
BE DAMMED TO A LIFE
OF ETERNAL SUFFERING.
GOD FORGIVES.
I DON'T.
[ Bell Tolling ]
[ Jarod ]
YOU CAN'T PUT YOUR FAITH
IN HIM.
HE WOULDN'T HURT HER.
YOU CAN'T TAKE THAT CHANCE.
I DON'T HAVE A CHOICE!
I HAVE TO GO WITH HIM TONIGHT.
JEN, LISTEN TO--
NO. I HAVE TO
FINISH THIS...
AND KNOW
THAT SON OF A BITCH
IS BEHIND BARS.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY THAT
CASSIE CAN BE SAFE.
YOU CAN'T TALK ME
OUT OF THIS.
WHERE'S JAROD?
I SENT HIM HOME.
WHY?
ROLL, BABY.
I GOT A CONFESSION
TO MAKE.
JEN! YOU HAVE TO TRUST ME.
DON'T DO THIS.
ALL RIGHT, SOMEBODY TELL ME
WHAT THE HELL IS GOIN' ON.
- I KNOW YOU KNOW WHO I AM.
- DON'T TELL HIM ANYTHING!
STOP! I'LL DO WHAT YOU ASK.
I'LL HELP YOU OUT
OF THE COUNTRY.
JUST DON'T HURT MY DAUGHTER.
- DON'T GO WITH HIM.
- SHUT UP! YOU BACK OFF.
NO MATTER WHAT HE SAYS, YOU
CAN'T BELIEVE HIM! HE'S STILL
GOING TO KILL YOUR DAUGHTER!
I WOULD NEVER KILL
A LITTLE GIRL.
[ Gasping ]
[ Groaning ]
JAROD, I'M SORRY.
GET IN THE CAR.
YOU KNOW WHAT.
IT'S FUNNY.
BUT I ACTUALLY DID
FALL IN LOVE WITH YOU,
IN A STRANGE WAY.
THEN YOU HAD TO
TEAR MY HEART OUT.
BUT I GUESS YOU MADE
THE RIGHT CHOICE.
OH, SHE DID.
YOU MISSED ME!
YOU KNOW, I HEARD THIS SONG ONCE
THAT HAPPINESS WAS A WARM GUN.
YES, IT IS.
YOU NEED
A COOLING-DOWN PERIOD.
[ Grunting ]
SHOOTING AN EX-COP.
NOT A VERY SMART IDEA.
ESPECIALLY WHEN HE'S PUT
BLANKS IN YOUR CLIP.
YOU SEE,
THERE'S THIS OPEN CASE
OVER AT THE A.T.F.
SOMETHING ABOUT A GUN SUPPLIER
FOUND SHOT TO DEATH
IN THE WOODS.
THEY NEVER COULD MAKE
A BALLISTICS MATCH.
OR FIND THE KILLER.
NOW THEY WILL.
[ Jenna ]
WANT TO KNOW
SOMETHING FUNNY?
I HAD FEELINGS FOR YOU.
BUT YOU HAD TO GO...
AND THREATEN MY LITTLE GIRL.
BAD DECISION.
KARMA. AIN'T IT A BITCH?
THIS IS ALONZO. OVER.
[ Jarod Over Radio ]
ALONZO.
JAROD, YOU BASTARD,
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE WITH JENNA?
SHE'S SAFE AND SOUND.
NOW, DID YOU EVER
GET THE FAT CAT?
WE GOT HIM.
- BUT NO PRITCHARD.
- CHECK THE THIRD ALLEY
OFF OF 18th STREET.
OH, AND, UH, I LEFT
A LITTLE PRESENT FOR YOU
UNDER YOUR SEAT.
[ Broots ] WE TRACKED DOWN SOME
OF THE PROPERTIES OF THE GAS
THAT RAINES WAS DEVELOPING.
VERITAS RELAXES THE LUNGS
TO THE POINT WHERE THEY CAN
NO LONGER TAKE IN OXYGEN.
IN SMALL DOSES,
IT'S NOT EVEN LETHAL.
I'M SURE RAINES
SKIPPED THAT PART.
WEAK LUNGS IS ONE OF
THE THEORIES BEHIND SUDDEN
INFANT DEATH SYNDROME.
OH, MY GOD. THE BABY.
[ Speaking Gibberish ]
STOP!
GET AWAY FROM HIM!
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE UP TO
WITH THE VERITAS.
I DON'T THINK YOU DO. A DILUTED
VERSION OF VERITAS GAS HELPED ME
LOOSEN BABY PARKER'S LUNGS.
[ Fussing ]
HE'S FREE OF
THIS BALL AND CHAIN.
I WISH I COULD SAY
THE SAME FOR MYSELF.
I SAW THE TESTING ROOM.
THERE ARE MANY VILLAINS
IN THE CENTRE, MISS PARKER.
I KNOW YOU NEED THEM
TO SURVIVE.
BUT I CAN'T BE
YOUR ENEMY ANYMORE.
[ Priest ] THIS IS THE LAMB
OF GOD WHO TAKES AWAY
THE SINS OF THE WORLD.
HAPPY ARE WE WHO ARE CALLED
TO THE LORD'S SUPPER.
THE BODY OF CHRIST.
[ Girl ]
AMEN.
THE BODY OF CHRIST.
[ Girl #2 ]
AMEN.
THE BODY OF CHRIST.
[ Girl #3 ]
AMEN.
- THE BODY OF CHRIST.
- AMEN.
THE BODY OF CHRIST.
[ Girl #4 ]
AMEN.
MAY ALMIGHTY GOD BLESS YOU,
THE FATHER,
THE SON,
AND THE HOLY SPIRIT.
THE MASS HAS ENDED. LET US GO
IN PEACE TO ALWAYS LOVE
AND SERVE THE LORD.
LOOK AT YOUR MOTHER.
YOU GOT THE BAD GUY?
WE GOT HIM.
NOW LET'S GO HOME.