[ Broots ]
IT'S JAROD'S LAST LAIR.
WE KNOW THAT MUCH.
HOW LONG SINCE HE LEFT?
IT'S ABOUT 24 HOURS.
WE GOT A CLEAN-UP CREW
TAKIN' THE PLACE APART
AS WE SPEAK.
SAME OLD SONG AND DANCE.
YEAH.
[ Miss Parker ]
WHO'S THE EGGHEAD
IN THE GO-CART?
- THAT'S DR. GUCHI TUCHEN.
- THE NEW HEAD OF THE CENTRE'S
CLEAN-UP UNIT.
CREDENTIALS IMPECCABLE.
YEAH, HE'S FROM CALCUTTA.
REMIND ME TO CANCEL
THE FROZEN STEAKS FOR CHRISTMAS.
AH, DR. TUCHEN.
THIS IS--
THE INFAMOUS MISS PARKER.
- EXCUSE ME FOR NOT STANDING.
- NOT A PROBLEM.
SO, WHAT DID
OUR LITTLE GENIUS LEAVE US
TO CLEAN UP THIS TIME?
I'M AFRAID IT'S A BIT
DISTURBING IN NATURE.
HOW SO?
HERE.
- P.C.P.
- RIDICULOUS.
JAROD WOULDN'T USE DRUGS.
I'M AFRAID I WILL HAVE
TO DISAGREE.
WE RAN A SERIES OF FIELD TESTS
ON THE BLOOD RESIDUAL
OF THE SYRINGES,
AND IT MATCHED
JAROD'S PERFECTLY.
[ Sydney ]
WITH WHAT JAROD'S BEEN THROUGH,
ADDICTION IS
A DISTINCT POSSIBILITY.
- JAROD'S A JUNKIE?
- WE ALSO FOUND THIS.
IT'S JAROD'S WRITING.
[ Broots ]
WHAT, DO YOU THINK
HE LEFT IT HERE BY ACCIDENT?
MAYBE HE REALLY IS CAUGHT UP
IN SOME KIND OF DRUG HAZE.
[ Man Over Walkie-Talkie,
Indistinct ]
[ Chattering ]
WE GOT ONE OVER HERE
ALREADY IN THE BUILDING.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HE'S ON,
BUT YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO LOCK HIM DOWN.
- HOW'S YOUR PERSONAL
INJURY INSURANCE?
- PAID IN FULL.
NO ONE'S GONNA HURT YA.
WE JUST WANNA MAKE SURE
YOU'RE OKAY.
LET'S DO THIS EASY,
OKAY, PAL? COME ON.
EASY.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
NICE AND EASY.
[ Grunting ]
COME ON!
NO! NO!
MOMMY! NO! NO!
MOMMY!
DAD! NO!
GRAB HIS FEET!
MOMMY! DADDY!
DON'T LET THEM TAKE ME!
[ Yelling ]
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
- [ Miss Parker ] HE DEFENDS
THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
- [ Jarod ] LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
[ Siren Wails ]
[ Police Radio, Indistinct ]
[ Grunting ]
COME ON!
- WHO DO WE GOT?
- TROUBLE. YOU'D BETTER KEEP
BOTH EYES ON THIS ONE.
WELCOME TO VISTA HOUSE,
MR. JONES.
I'M DR. EARL.
I AM YOUR STAFF PSYCHOLOGIST.
I AM HERE TO HELP YOU
WITH YOUR RECOVERY.
UNDERSTAND THAT NO ONE
CAN STOP YOU FROM USING BUT YOU.
[ Muffled Laugh ]
CHECK HIS BAG.
NOW, MR. JONES,
I NEED YOU TO SIGN THIS.
[ Panting ]
WHAT IS IT?
IT IS A CONSENT FORM
EMPOWERING US TO
PLACE YOU IN LOCKDOWN.
LOCKDOWN? I DON'T LIKE
BEING LOCKED UP.
WE NEED TO TAKE CONTROL
DURING THE INITIAL PERIOD
OF YOUR WITHDRAWAL.
I KNOW THAT MAY SOUND EXTREME,
BUT I BELIEVE OUR SUCCESS RATE
SPEAKS FOR ITSELF.
THANK YOU.
WHAT DO YOU GOT, GARRETT?
GOT A CHANGE OF CLOTHES,
BATH ROBE, WALLET,
$48 CASH,
MM-HMM.
RED NOTEBOOK, BLANK.
I KEEP A JOURNAL.
[ Dr. Earl ]
EXCELLENT.
A BIG PART OF YOUR RECOVERY
WILL BE WRITING DOWN...
A SEARCHING AND FEARLESS
MORAL SELF-INVENTORY.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
HOLD ON, HOLD ON.
[ Grunting ]
WE HAVE A CODE OF ETHICS
AROUND HERE.
IT'S CALLED
THE CIRCLE OF TRUST.
YOU GAIN OUR TRUST,
IT COMES BACK TO YOU
IN THE WAY OF PRIVILEGES.
BETRAY THAT TRUST,
THE CIRCLE IS BROKEN.
CONSIDER THIS A WARNING.
[ Straining, Grunting ]
I-I DON'T FEEL SO GOOD.
GET HIM A BUCKET.
[ Miss Parker ]
"I'M SEARCHING
FOR A SPECIAL MAN.
"IF YOU ARE HANDSOME,
EMOTIONALLY SECURE...
"AND HAVE LEARNED SOME OF
LIFE'S HARDER LESSONS,
WE MIGHT HAVE
SOMETHING IN COMMON."
HOW DOES IT FEEL TO BE
THE MAYOR OF LOSERVILLE?
- I-I READ THAT
FOR ENTERTAINMENT.
- RIGHT.
WHAT DID YOU FIND OUT
ABOUT JAROD'S LATEST CLUE?
THE "101776" CLEARLY RELATES
TO OCTOBER 17, 1976.
THE A-22 PART
HAS ME STUMPED, THOUGH.
IT'S EITHER AUGUST OR APRIL 22,
AND IT COULD RELATE
TO SL 22.
MAYBE IF YOU STOPPED
READING THE WANT ADS AND--
I'LL BE DAMMED.
- WHAT? WHAT IS IT?
- MY LUCKY DAY, APPARENTLY.
"A-22."
SECTION "A," PAGE 22.
BROOTS, GO GET THE MICROFICHE
FROM THE BLUE COVE PAPER...
DATED OCTOBER 17, 1976.
MAYBE WE CAN FIND OUT WHY
JAROD IS HOPPED UP ON HEROIN.
SYDNEY, YOU ALL RIGHT?
[ Jarod ] OKAY, I'M CURED.
LET ME OUT OF HERE.
[ Man ] THIS IS HOW IT PLAYS.
THE DOCTORS ARE LIKE
THE GENERALS. THEY'RE SITTIN'
UP THERE ON THE HILL.
THEY'RE WATCHIN' THE BATTLE.
BUT I'M THE GRUNT.
I'M DOWN THERE IN THE FIELD.
I'M LOOKIN' OUT FOR MY BUDDIES.
YOU GONNA BE
MY BUDDY THERE, JAROD?
SURE. WHY NOT?
GOOD ANSWER.
OKAY, I BRING YOU YOUR MEALS,
I SUPERVISE YOUR DRUG TESTS.
I CLEAN YOUR CLOTHES.
I WILL EVEN MOP UP
YOUR PUKE, MAN.
THE ONLY THING I ASK IN RETURN
IS THAT YOU DON'T GIVE ME
ANY TROUBLE.
THIS AIN'T EASY WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA BE GOIN' THROUGH HERE,
BUT I CAN HELP MAKE IT...
A WHOLE LOT MORE PRODUCTIVE,
OKAY?
- SORRY, BABY. WHOA.
- RUSTY!
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY!
COME ON! I'M SICK!
I NEED SOMETHIN'!
SEE THAT GUY?
HE IS NOT MY BUDDY.
COME ON. WE GOTTA
MAKE A PIT STOP.
ALL RIGHT, HERE.
FILL IT UP, UNLEADED.
CAN I GET SOME PRIVACY?
YOU'RE HOLDIN' THE CUP,
AREN'T YA?
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
WELL, NOT EXACTLY
THE FOUR SEASONS.
BUT LET'S FACE IT.
YOU COULDN'T AFFORD
THE FOUR SEASONS.
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
[ Shivering ]
IT'S-IT'S SO COLD IN HERE.
YEAH, WELL, YOU WON'T THINK SO
ONCE THE HOT FLASHES KICK IN.
ALL RIGHT, YOU GOT A BUCKET
FOR WHATEVER COMES UP,
AND IT'LL COME UP. TRUST ME.
I DON'T THINK I CAN DO THIS.
I JUST, UH, NEED
A LITTLE SOMETHIN',
YOU KNOW,
TO CARRY ME THROUGH,
YOU UNDERSTAND?
JUST-JUST SOMETHIN'
FOR TONIGHT, PLEASE?
- GET YOUR HANDS OFF ME, MAN!
- COME ON.
DON'T LEAVE ME IN HERE!
YOU CAN'T LEAVE ME IN HERE!
DON'T LEAVE ME-- COME ON!
DON'T LEAVE ME--
[ Panting, Grunting ]
WELL, BOTTOMS UP.
[ Chattering ]
[ Jarod Vomiting ]
GREAT.
[ Vomiting Continues ]
[ Dr. Earl ]
WE HAVE A NEW MEMBER
OF OUR GROUP.
THIS IS JAROD.
WELCOME TO
HEROIN HILTON, JAROD.
THANK YOU, HUEY. JAROD,
WHY DON'T YOU TELL THE GROUP
WHAT BROUGHT YOU HERE?
A LARGE COP
WITH BAD BREATH.
VERY CLEVER.
PERHAPS YOU COULD BE
A LITTLE MORE SPECIFIC?
NO, MAN, THERE'S NOTHIN'
YOU CAN TELL US WE HAVEN'T
ALREADY HEARD OR SEEN.
LET'S JUST SAY THAT
I'M GOING THROUGH
A SLIGHT IDENTITY CRISIS.
OKAY.
TODAY, I WANT TO TALK
ABOUT RESPONSIBILITY,
ABOUT HOW WE REFUSE
TO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY
FOR OUR ADDICTION.
INSTEAD, WE BLAME
EVERYBODY AND EVERYTHING ELSE.
WELL, I'LL TELL YA THIS, DOC.
YOU KNOW, IF I FALL BACK
INTO MY HABIT,
I'M BLAMING JILL.
SHUT UP, HUEY.
CHICK'S DRIVIN' ME NUTS,
CRYIN' EVERY FIVE SECONDS,
YAMMERIN' ON ABOUT
HER SMACK BINGE LAST WEEK.
"I'M CLEAN. I DIDN'T USE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW IT HAPPENED!"
IT'S THE TRUTH.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW IT HAPPENED.
- THAT'S WHACK, BABY.
- I THOUGHT THIS WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE A SUPPORT GROUP?
SHE TESTED POSITIVE
FOR OPIATES, DUDE.
HER DENYIN' SHE EVEN USED
IS A LIE. YOU'RE A LIAR.
- I'M NOT A LIAR.
- LIAR, LIAR, LIAR.
- YOU DON'T KNOW THAT.
- OKAY, NEW MEAT.
MAYBE THE SMACK
JUST KIND OF FLOATED DOWN
FROM THE HEAVENS...
AND LANDED RIGHT
IN YOUR BLOODSTREAM.
I LOST CUSTODY
OF MY SON LAST WEEK!
WHY WOULD I JEOPARDIZE
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING
IN MY LIFE TO USE?
- BECAUSE YOU'RE A JUNKIE.
- I'M NOT A JUNKIE
ANYMORE, HUEY.
I DON'T WANT HIM SEEIN' ME
IN HERE LIKE THIS.
HAVE AN ATTITUDE
OF GRATITUDE, JILL, HMM?
YOU'RE BLESSED.
YOUR SON IS GOING
TO GET TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
CLEAN AND ALIVE.
WHAT HUEY IS SAYING IS THAT...
YOU NEED TO ACCEPT THE FACT THAT
YOU HAVE A PROBLEM.
I KNOW I HAVE A PROBLEM,
DR. EARL.
I LOST MY SON.
SECTION "A," PAGE 22
HAD FIVE OBITUARIES.
SO I RAN THE NAMES
THROUGH THE DATABASE,
AND ONE OF THEM,
A GUY NAMED DAVID ARNOLD,
USED TO WORK HERE.
[ Miss Parker ]
WHEN?
IT DOESN'T SAY.
AND THERE'S NO OTHER
INFORMATION ON HIM,
WHICH IS REALLY STRANGE,
BECAUSE YOU KNOW
HOW THIS PLACE IS
ABOUT BACKGROUND CHECKS.
WHICH MAKES YOUR PRESENCE HERE
EVEN MORE OF A MYSTERY.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS!
WHAT IF SOMETHING
HAPPENS TO JAROD...
WHILE WE'RE CHASING GHOSTS?
BROOTS, KEEP WORKING
THE NUMBER CODES, AND STAY
ON THIS DAVID ARNOLD LEAD.
SURE. NO PROBLEM.
AND, BROOTS?
YOU REPORT ONLY TO ME.
THAT'S A FINE-LOOKING
LITTLE BOY YOU HAVE THERE.
I NEVER ACTUALLY KNEW MY MOTHER,
BUT I ALWAYS IMAGINED HOW GREAT
OUR RELATIONSHIP WOULD BE.
LOOK-- JAROD, RIGHT?
I APPRECIATE YOU
DEFENDING ME IN HERE,
BUT, PLEASE,
LEAVE ME ALONE, OKAY?
SORRY, I CAN'T DO THAT.
YOU SEE,
THE REASON I'M IN HERE...
IS TO HELP YOU,
AS A FAVOR TO YOUR FATHER.
MY FATHER'S BEEN DEAD
FOR OVER 20 YEARS.
JILL, I KNOW.
JILL? YOUR LITTLE BOY'S HERE.
HE'S WAITIN' FOR YOU
IN THE VISITATION LOUNGE.
I CAN'T LET HIM
SEE ME LIKE THIS.
YOU'RE HIS MOTHER.
NOTHING CAN CHANGE THE WAY
HE FEELS ABOUT YOU.
[ Man On Speaker ]
HILARY AND I HAVE A LOT
TO DO WITH YOU TODAY, SPORT.
WE'VE GOTTA PICK UP YOUR TUX
FOR THE WEDDING. I'VE GOTTA
GET THE PLANE TICKETS.
SO YOU JUST SAY HI TO MOMMY,
AND THEN LET'S GET GOING, OKAY?
TODD, HONEY?
THE TUXEDO SHOP
IS OPEN LATE,
AND THE TRAVEL AGENT
CAN MESSENGER YOU THE TICKETS.
PLEASE, DADDY?
CHRIS, YOU SPEND
AS MUCH TIME WITH YOUR MOMMY
AS YOU WANT, OKAY?
OKAY.
GUESS WHO.
- MOMMY!
- HEY! LOOK AT YOU!
I'VE MISSED YOU SO MUCH!
I MISSED YOU TOO.
WHY ARE YOU SHAKING, MOMMY?
- MOMMY'S BEEN SICK, BABY.
- ARE YOU GONNA GET BETTER?
YES. AND GUESS WHAT.
IF DR. EARL SAYS IT'S OKAY,
I CAN COME HOME
IN A COUPLE OF DAYS.
[ Chris ]
DOES THAT MEAN I GET
TO LIVE WITH YOU?
WELL, HONEY, NO.
DON'T YOU LOVE ME ANYMORE?
YES, OF COURSE I DO.
I LOVE YOU WITH ALL MY HEART.
OH, GOD.
GARRETT!
CIRCLE OF TRUST, JAROD.
WHATEVER YOU'RE DOING IN HERE,
YOU JUST BROKE THE CIRCLE.
TAKE HIM BACK TO HIS ROOM.
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
COME ON.
YEAH.
[ Beeps, Buzzer Sounds ]
THESE ARE HIS ORDERS.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I JUST WANNA TALK TO YOU.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE THAT
WE CAN TALK UNMONITORED.
PLEASE TRUST ME.
JUST LEAVE ME ALONE.
I DON'T THINK
HE WOULD HAVE WANTED THAT.
WHERE'D YOU GET THIS?
YOUR FATHER GAVE IT TO ME.
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY
WHEN I WAS A BOY.
THAT PHOTOGRAPH WAS
YOUR FATHER'S WAY OF GIVING ME
A FAMILY WHEN I NEEDED ONE.
I REALIZE THAT
ALL THIS SOUNDS CRAZY,
BUT IT'S THE TRUTH.
YOU DON'T BELONG IN HERE.
AND I KNOW...
YOU NEVER WOULD HAVE
DONE ANYTHING TO JEOPARDIZE
THE CUSTODY OF YOUR SON.
YOU KNOW, I REMEMBER
WHEN THIS PICTURE WAS TAKEN.
I WAS A JUNIOR
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
THAT WAS THE YEAR
EVERYTHING WENT CRAZY.
I MET THIS GREAT GUY.
A DEALER.
GOD, I GOT STRUNG OUT
SO FAST.
AND YOUR FATHER GOT YOU CLEAN.
NO GUILT TRIPS.
JUST UNCONDITIONAL LOVE.
THEN HE DIED.
I STAYED CLEAN
THROUGH THE WHOLE THING.
I WAS CLEAN FOR A LONG TIME.
THAT'S WHEN I MET TODD.
WE GOT MARRIED, HAD CHRIS.
IT WAS SUCH A GOOD LIFE.
AND THEN YOU STARTED
USING AGAIN.
YEAH.
I DON'T HAVE AN EXCUSE FOR IT.
I SCREWED UP.
BY THE TIME
I REALIZED WHAT I HAD DONE,
TODD HAD LEFT,
AND HE TOOK CHRIS.
THEN TODD MET HILARY.
I KNEW IF I WAS EVER GONNA
GET MY BOY BACK,
I COULD NEVER USE DRUGS AGAIN.
SO I GOT CLEAN AGAIN.
I GOT MY TEACHING CREDENTIAL.
EVERYTHING WAS FINE.
THE COURT WAS GONNA
GIVE ME CUSTODY.
THEN THE DAY BEFORE
THE FINAL HEARING--
I SWEAR TO GOD
I DON'T REMEMBER USING.
SO I LOST ANY CHANCE
OF GETTING MY LITTLE BOY BACK.
THERE IS ALWAYS A CHANCE.
NOT FOR ME.
ONCE HILARY AND TODD
GET MARRIED,
SHE CAN LEGALLY ADOPT HIM,
AND THEN THAT'S THE END.
TELL ME ABOUT THIS DAY
THAT YOU SAID
YOU DON'T REMEMBER USING.
I REMEMBER THE MORNING.
I WAS CLEAN. I CAME HERE
FOR MY WEEKLY DRUG TEST.
I WOKE UP THREE DAYS LATER
STRUNG OUT IN THE PARK.
I WOULDN'T HAVE
THROWN IT ALL AWAY--
NOT MY LIFE, NOT MY FAMILY.
[ Beeps, Buzzer Sounds ]
HELLO, JILL.
HOW ARE WE FEELING TODAY?
OKAY.
GOOD.
NURSES TELL ME
YOU'VE BEEN HAVING
A LITTLE TROUBLE SLEEPING.
WOULD YOU LIKE
A CLONIDINE PATCH?
YES, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT.
THERE.
THAT SHOULD HELP YOU RELAX.
THANK YOU.
JILL, I JUST WANNA LET YOU KNOW,
IF ALL GOES WELL,
I THINK I CAN HAVE YOU
OUT OF HERE BY FRIDAY.
- REALLY?
- REALLY. WE JUST WANNA
MAKE SURE THAT YOU'RE READY...
AND THERE AREN'T GONNA BE
ANY SETBACKS, OKAY?
I'M READY. I PROMISE.
GOOD. YOU GET SOME SLEEP,
AND I WILL CHECK IN
ON YOU LATER, OKAY?
OKAY.
[ Beeps, Buzzer Sounds ]
[ Broots ]
THE DELAWARE
CARTOGRAPHER'S OFFICE...
IS E-MAILING ME A MAP
CODED 101776.
- A-22 SHOULD BE THE COORDINATES
THAT LEAD US TO JAROD.
- GOOD WORK.
WILL YOU LET US KNOW
THE MINUTE IT COMES IN?
- OH, YEAH, YEAH.
- BROOTS, I WANNA REVIEW
YOUR G-4 REPORT WITH YOU.
ALL RIGHT. I'LL CATCH UP
WITH YOU, SYDNEY.
HMM.
- WHAT DO YOU GOT?
- OKAY.
YOU KNOW WINKEY, THE OLD GUY
WITH THE FACIAL TICKS THAT
WORKS DOWN IN THE INFIRMARY?
- WE HAVEN'T HAD THE PLEASURE.
- OKAY. ANYWAY,
HE REMEMBERS THIS DAVID ARNOLD
WHO USED TO WORK THERE
AS AN ORDERLY LIKE 20 YEARS AGO.
SO I CROSS-REFERENCED
ARNOLD'S NAME WITH
THE INFIRMARY'S D.S.A. DATABASE,
AND I CAME UP
WITH TWO MATCHES.
THE ONLY PROBLEM
IS THEY'RE MISSING
FROM WINKEY'S ARCHIVES.
SOMEBODY'S REALLY GONE
TO SOME TROUBLE...
ERASING THIS GUY FROM
THE HISTORY BOOKS AROUND HERE.
YOU'VE BEEN MAKING
UNAUTHORIZED ENTRIES INTO
THE INFIRMARY'S DATABASE.
IF IT'S DAVID ARNOLD
YOU WANT TO KNOW ABOUT,
I CAN TELL YOU HE WAS ONE OF
THE KINDEST, GENTLEST MEN I EVER
HAD THE PLEASURE OF KNOWING.
-WHAT'S HE DOING THESE DAYS?
-PUSHING UP DAISIES.
ARNOLD IS DEADER
THAN YOUR HAIR FOLLICLES.
[ Sighs ]
TELL ME THEN, MISS PARKER,
HOW DOES DAVID ARNOLD GET YOU
ANY CLOSER TO FINDING JAROD?
WE EXPLORE ALL AVENUES
IN PURSUIT OF JAROD,
EVEN THE DEAD ONES.
HE WOULDN'T BE BUGGING US
ABOUT A DATABASE HIT...
UNLESS HE HAD SOMETHING TO HIDE.
THE ANSWER LIES
IN THOSE MISSING D.S.A.s,
WHICH ARE MOSTLY LIKELY...
IN RAINES'S
PRIVATE COLLECTION.
♪♪ [ Dance ]
[ Woman ] GREAT. AND ONE,
AND TWO, AND THREE, AND FOUR.
KEEP IT GOING.
ALMOST FINISHED. BREATHE.
GOOD, AND ARMS.
AND ONE, AND TWO,
AND THREE, AND FOUR.
GOOD JOB.
HEY, NICE RIDE, DUDE.
WHAT ARE WE WAITIN' FOR?
LET'S GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
EVEN IF I COULD START IT,
THEY DON'T LET ME RIDE IT.
YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT MOTORCYCLE MAINTENANCE?
WELL, I READ A BOOK
ON IT ONCE.
NOTHIN' TO DO WITH MOTORCYCLES,
HOWEVER.
WHOA, WHOA. WHOA. GOD.
DOES IT FLOOD WHEN
YOU HIT THE THROTTLE?
YEAH.
THE TABS FROM YOUR FLOAT BOWL
ARE DISCONNECTED
FROM THE NEEDLE, SEE?
I'LL BE DAMMED.
HEY, THANKS.
COOL SHIRT.
WHAT'S "SKINT RABBIT"?
IT'S A ROCK-AND-ROLL BAND.
WE HAD A BIG HIT
IN THE '80s.
- "BLOODY LOVE BONES"?
- I WAS KINDA OUT OF IT
IN THE '80s.
AND THE '70s.
MOST OF THE '90s,
FOR THAT MATTER.
YEAH, WHO WASN'T?
BUT I WAS THEIR HEAD ROADIE.
WE WENT EVERYWHERE.
TOURED WITH THE BIGGEST.
STONES, ALLMAN BROTHERS.
THEN WE RELEASED
TWO LAME ALBUMS.
THE NEXT THING YOU KNOW,
WE ARE WARMIN' UP
HIGH SCHOOL GYMS FOR AIR SUPPLY.
WERE THEY HAVING TROUBLE
WITH THEIR VENTILATION SYSTEM?
EXACTLY.
HEY, LISTEN, BROTHER, UM,
I REALLY NEED TO SCORE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKIN' ABOUT.
COME ON. YOUR CLAMMY SKIN,
YOUR BEADY LITTLE PUPILS.
I THINK YOU KNOW
EXACTLY WHAT I MEAN.
COME ON.
HELP ME OUT.
GARRETT'S YOUR MAN.
[ Jarod ]
GARRETT?
UNLESS HE GOT BUSTED AGAIN.
AGAIN?
EARL NAILED HIM
A FEW WEEKS AGO DEALIN'
SMACK TO AN OUTPATIENT.
HOW DOES AN ORDERLY IN
A DRUG REHABILITATION CENTER
GET AWAY WITH THAT?
HEY, MAN, THERE'S STUFF
GOIN' ON AROUND HERE
NONE OF US WILL EVER KNOW ABOUT.
JILL?
JILL? JILL?
SOMEBODY GET IN HERE!
SHE'S O.D.'ING! JILL?
I WILL TAKE CARE OF THIS.
CHECK HER RESPIRATION.
I NEED AN AIRWAY
AND SOME O-2 STAT!
GET IN HERE! GET IN THERE!
GET IN THERE!
JILL? JILL?
JILL, HOW COULD YOU
DO THIS TO YOURSELF?
[ Broots ]
RAINES ALMOST CAUGHT ME.
I HAD TO HIDE UNDER HIS COUCH
FOR OVER AN HOUR.
THEN HIS MASSEUSE CAME IN
AND RUBBED HIM DOWN WITH OIL...
WHILE THEY WERE SINGING
"SHALL WE GATHER AT THE RIVER."
THE D.S.A.s?
YOU ARE NOT GONNA BELIEVE THIS.
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
JILL.
JAROD, I SWEAR I DON'T KNOW
HOW THIS HAPPENED.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
WHAT MATTERS NOW
IS GETTING YOU THROUGH THIS.
COME ON, COME ON.
LET'S GET YOU IN THE BED.
COME ON. COME ON.
I'M BEGINNING TO THINK MAYBE
I'M DOING THIS.
I CAN'T REMEMBER
WHAT'S HAPPENING TO ME ANYMORE.
OH, GOD.
I CAN'T GO THROUGH THIS AGAIN.
I DON'T HAVE THE STRENGTH.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO FIND THE STRENGTH
FOR YOUR SON.
- I'VE LOST HIM.
- NO, YOU HAVEN'T.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Vomiting ]
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
- I OWE YOUR FATHER.
- FOR WHAT?
[ Young Jarod ]
SOMEBODY HELP ME!
[ Grunting, Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
- SO HE HAD A BAD FLU.
- THIS ISN'T THE FLU,
MISS PARKER. WATCH.
[ Tape Rewinding ]
THE SELF-RIGHTEOUS
SON OF A BITCH
GOT JAROD HOOKED ON NARCOTICS.
HERE.
YOU HAVE TO DRINK
AND STAY HYDRATED.
ONE MORE. COME ON.
NO.
WHY WOULD THAT PLACE--
WHY WOULD THE CENTRE
GIVE A CHILD DRUGS?
BECAUSE TO THEM,
I WAS NEVER A CHILD.
YOU CALLED FOR ME, DOCTOR?
I NEED YOU
TO CLEAN UP THE ROOM.
THE BOY'S SICK.
YES, SIR.
HEY, KID.
I'M ONE OF THE ORDERLIES.
HELP ME, PLEASE.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
OH, MY GOD.
WHO DID THIS TO YOU?
PLEASE HELP ME.
JUST HANG IN THERE, BUDDY.
I'M GONNA HELP YOU
THROUGH THIS, OKAY?
EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE FINE.
[ Broots ]
THAT'S DAVID ARNOLD.
THERE'S THE CONNECTION
TO JAROD. ARNOLD HELPED HIM
GET THROUGH DETOX.
I'M SO HOT,
I FEEL LIKE I'M BURNING UP.
- JUST HANG TOUGH. IT'LL PASS.
- I HURT ALL OVER.
HANG TOUGH. IT'LL PASS.
[ Vomits ]
I DON'T THINK
I CAN DO THIS.
YES, YOU CAN.
JUST STAY FOCUSED ON ME.
COME ON. COME ON.
JUST A LITTLE BIT TO MAKE
THE PAIN GO AWAY.
I CAN'T DO THAT, JAROD.
I CAN'T DO THIS!
YOU'VE GOTTA GET ME SOMETHING.
PLEASE-PLEASE GET ME SOMETHING.
HOW ABOUT HIM?
IS HE ENOUGH?
I NEED MY-MY FAMILY
HERE TO HELP ME.
WHERE IS YOUR FAMILY?
I DON'T KNOW.
I CAN'T REMEMBER.
HERE. YOU HANG ONTO THAT.
LET MY DAUGHTER JILL AND I
BE YOUR FAMILY.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
I'M EVER GONNA REPAY YOU
FOR THIS.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
ONE DAY, YOU WILL.
WAIT. MISS PARKER,
YOU HAVE TO SEE THE NEXT D.S.A.
MR. ARNOLD?
YES, SIR?
YOU'RE TO BE COMMENDED.
THANK YOU.
I DON'T MEAN TO OVERSTEP
MY POSITION HERE,
BUT WHAT POSSIBLE REASON
COULD YOU HAVE TO GET
THIS KID HOOKED ON DRUGS?
THAT'S NOT YOUR CONCERN.
OH. I'M MAKING IT
MY CONCERN, SIR.
YOU'LL BE AMPLY REWARDED
FOR YOUR EFFORTS.
YOU KNOW,
YOU CAN KEEP YOUR MONEY.
I DON'T WANT ANYTHING
TO DO WITH THIS PLACE.
WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
[ Broots ]
THIS IS DATED OCTOBER 17,
THE DAY BEFORE DAVID ARNOLD...
ACCIDENTALLY DROWNED
IN HIS OWN SWIMMING POOL.
RAINES HAD HIM KILLED
TO KEEP HIM QUIET.
I CAN'T HELP WONDERING,
WHERE WAS SYDNEY
DURING ALL THIS?
HE WAS JAROD'S PROTECTOR.
HOW COULD HE LET THIS HAPPEN?
THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION.
I DESERVE TO LOSE HIM.
HILARY WILL MAKE
A MUCH BETTER MOTHER.
I JUST DON'T KNOW
HOW THIS HAPPENED.
WELL, IT'S ABOUT TIME
WE FOUND OUT.
GARRETT, YOU GOT
A PATIENT LOOSE.
[ Beeps, Buzzer Sounds ]
WHAT THE HELL WERE YOU DOIN'
OUT OF YOUR ROOM?
WERE YOU AFRAID I WAS GONNA
FIND YOUR DRUG STASH?
ALL RIGHT,
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
HOW COULD YOU DO THAT?
HOW COULD YOU GIVE DRUGS
TO A WOMAN WHO WAS TRYIN'
TO TURN HER LIFE AROUND?
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
I'M TALKING ABOUT JILL ARNOLD!
I'M TALKING ABOUT DOCTORING
HER CLONIDINE PATCH
WITH PURE HEROIN.
I DIDN'T!
YOU WANNA DEAL WITH ME,
OR SHOULD I CALL THE POLICE?
GO TO HELL.
YOU'RE THE DRUG SUPPLIER HERE.
WHY'D YOU DO IT?
I SWEAR! I SWEAR!
I DON'T EVEN HAVE ACCESS
TO THE CLONIDINE PATCHES.
ONLY DR. EARL COULD HAVE
LACED THEM WITH HEROIN.
HEROIN HE GOT FROM YOU!
[ Toilet Flushes ]
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
WHEN EARL CAUGHT ME
DEALIN' TO HUEY,
HE THREATENED...
TO HAVE ME ARRESTED
UNLESS I SCORED FOR HIM,
ALL RIGHT?
I HAD NO IDEA
HE WAS GONNA USE IT
ON A PATIENT.
WHY IS DR. EARL KEEPING
JILL ARNOLD ON DRUGS?
I DON'T KNOW!
I DON'T KNOW! I DON'T.
I SWEAR TO GOD, I DON'T.
BUT I CAN GET YOU
INTO HIS OFFICE.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
HELLO, HILARY.
I'M CALLING FOR DR. EARL.
IT SEEMS A SITUATION HAS COME UP
REGARDING JILL ARNOLD.
HE NEEDS YOU TO COME DOWN HERE
RIGHT AWAY.
[ Jarod ]
UH, HILARY, RIGHT?
DR. EARL SAID...
HE WAS RUNNING
JUST A LITTLE BIT LATE.
CAN I OFFER YOU
A GLASS OF WATER WHILE YOU WAIT?
[ Young Jarod Groaning ]
SOMEBODY HELP ME!
SYDNEY, HOW COULD YOU LET
THIS HAPPEN?
HE WAS JUST A BOY, SYD.
IN THOSE DAYS, THE CENTRE
WAS WORKING WITH PEOPLE...
WHO WERE TRYING TO PERFECT
A SYNTHESIZED NARCOTIC...
THAT MIGHT ENHANCE
MENTAL PERFORMANCE.
SO YOU LET THEM
EXPERIMENT ON JAROD?
IT WAS RAINES'S DECISION.
I GUESS THE IDEA OF
A GREAT MIND LIKE JAROD'S
BECOMING GREATER STILL...
WAS JUST TOO EXCITING
TO WALK AWAY FROM.
THE DRUG, OF COURSE,
IT TURNED OUT,
HAD PRETTY SERIOUS
SIDE EFFECTS.
RAPID ADDICTION
AND DEVASTATING WITHDRAWAL.
SO RAINES TURNS JAROD
INTO A JUNKIE LAB RAT,
AND YOU BURY YOUR HEAD
IN THE SAND?
SYDNEY, WHY?
[ Panting, Grunting ]
THEY TURNED SYDNEY
INTO AN ADDICT.
[ Dr. Earl Groaning ]
[ Both Gasp ]
- OH, MY GOD. WHERE AM I?
- WHAT'S HAPPENING TO ME?
I WOULD IMAGINE THAT JILL ARNOLD
MUST HAVE ASKED HERSELF
THE VERY SAME QUESTION.
-JAROD?
-I THINK WE SHOULD HAVE
A LITTLE GROUP THERAPY SESSION.
ONLY THIS TIME,
THE TWO OF YOU
GET TO BE THE PATIENTS.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- CIRCLE OF TRUST, DOC.
YOU GIVE JILL ARNOLD DRUGS
AGAINST HER WILL.
I DO THE VERY SAME THING
TO THE TWO OF YOU.
ONLY THIS TIME,
I USE A HYBRID NARCOTIC...
THAT CHEMICALLY TRICKS THE BRAIN
INTO THINKING YOU'VE BEEN
ADDICTED FOR YEARS.
WHAT YOU'RE EXPERIENCING NOW,
PHYSICALLY AND MENTALLY,
THAT'S WHAT'S KNOWN AS
"COLD TURKEY."
- GOBBLE, GOBBLE.
- YOU'RE SICK.
- YOU SON OF A BITCH.
NOW, THAT IS NOT EXPRESSING
AN ATTITUDE OF GRATITUDE, DOC.
BUT NOT TO WORRY.
I BROUGHT ALONG...
SOME CLONIDINE PATCHES
TO HELP TAKE THAT PAIN AWAY.
PLEASE, GIVE ME A PATCH.
FIRST, WE SHOULD TALK ABOUT...
INVESTIGATING OUR MORAL
SELF-INVENTORY TO DECIDE...
WHICH ONE OF YOU ACTUALLY
DESERVES A PATCH.
GIVE IT TO ME!
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
I'M SOMEBODY THAT CAN
HELP END YOUR TORMENT.
JUST TELL ME THE TRUTH.
COME ON.
I CAN'T TAKE THIS.
DON'T GIVE IT TO HER, JAROD!
GIVE IT TO ME!
JUST-JUST-JUST TALK TO ME.
I CAN'T.
MMM-- OKAY. OKAY.
PLEASE,
GIVE-GIVE ME A PATCH.
I GUESS YOU CAN LOOK FORWARD
TO THE NEXT EIGHT HOURS...
WITH YOUR HEAD IN A BUCKET.
[ Mimics Vomiting ]
GIVE ME A PATCH, PLEASE.
[ Hilary ]
PLEASE GIVE ME A PATCH.
ONE CLONIDINE PATCH DOWN.
[ Dr. Earl ]
JAROD, GIVE IT TO ME.
OKAY.
OKAY. HE DID IT.
- WHAT?
- HE NEEDED THE MONEY.
-SHUT UP, YOU STUPID BITCH!
-OH, PLEASE. COME ON.
YOU SAID NOBODY WOULD FIND OUT.
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO NEEDED
THAT STUPID KID.
YOU WANTED THE BOY!
- HEY!
- PLEASE, GIVE ME
ONE OF THE PATCHES.
LET ME GUESS.
IT WENT SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
TODD MOFFETT IS
A VERY RICH MAN.
SO RICH, IN FACT,
THAT IF YOU TWO
WERE TO GET DIVORCED,
YOU COULD STAND TO MAKE
ONE HELL OF A PAYDAY,
ESPECIALLY IF YOU WERE
TO ADOPT HIS SON.
AND WHAT BETTER WAY
TO INSURE CUSTODY...
THAN TO TURN
HIS BIOLOGICAL MOTHER
INTO A JUNKIE.
-AND WHO BETTER TO HELP YOU THAN
YOUR EX-COLLEGE SWEETHEART.
-HOW DID YOU KNOW THAT?
LET'S JUST SAY THAT
I TOOK A LITTLE PEEK...
INTO THE DOC'S
COLLEGE YEARBOOK.
YOU TWO MAKE
SUCH A CUTE LITTLE COUPLE.
IT SEEMS SO SAD...
THAT COLLEGE SWEETHEARTS
SUCH AS YOURSELF...
ARE GONNA HAVE TO EXPERIENCE
SUCH HORRIFIC PAIN.
I'VE HAD MY EXPERIENCE WITH
THAT LITTLE DEVIL YOU'RE ON.
AND LET ME TELL YOU--
SOMEBODY HELP ME!
IT'S A BITCH.
ONLY ONE
CLONIDINE PATCH LEFT.
IT WOULD BE A SHAME TO HAVE
TO WHITE-KNUCKLE IT
THROUGH SUCH A TERRIBLE DETOX.
OKAY!
I DID IT.
I DRUGGED JILL ARNOLD
SO SHE WOULD LOSE CUSTODY
OF HER SON.
- NOW CAN I HAVE
THAT PATCH, PLEASE?
- NO, HE DID IT.
PLEASE GIVE ME
THE PATCH.
LIKE YOU SAY, DOC,
RECOVERY STARTS
WHEN AN INDIVIDUAL ADMITS
THAT HE OR SHE HAS A PROBLEM.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT, TODD?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- OH, GOD.
LET ME TELL YOU, THE TWO OF YOU
HAVE ONE HELL OF A PROBLEM.
LISTEN, SPORT,
WE'RE GONNA SEE MOMMY
IN JUST A FEW MINUTES.
OKAY.
SO JILL WAS TELLIN'
THE WHOLE TRUTH AFTER ALL.
I FEEL LIKE A REAL PUNK
LAYIN' INTO HER THE WAY I DID.
HEY, YOU LIVE
AND YOU LEARN.
YEAH, BUT I'VE DECIDED,
YOU KNOW, I'M GONNA FINISH
UP MY TIME HERE THE RIGHT WAY.
I'VE JUST BEEN KIND OF
GOIN' THROUGH THE MOTIONS.
I GOTTA START THINKIN'
ABOUT MY FUTURE.
GOOD FOR YOU.
THANKS A LOT, JAROD.
SOMETHIN' FOR YOU.
HEY, WHAT'S THIS?
SKINT RABBIT.
OH, WOW.
"BLOODY LOVE BONES." BUT
DON'T LISTEN TO IT BACKWARDS.
YOU'LL END UP HERE FOR REAL.
THANKS FOR EVERYTHING.
I-I HOPE I CAN
MAKE THIS UP TO JILL.
NOW'S YOUR CHANCE.
MOMMY!
MOMMY, ARE WE GOING HOME NOW?
WE ARE GONNA GO HOME
IN TWO SECONDS, OKAY?
YOU LOOK GOOD.
I'M STARTIN' TO FEEL GOOD.
SO WHAT NOW?
ONE DAY AT A TIME.
JAROD, I DON'T KNOW
HOW I COULD EVER REPAY YOU
FOR EVERYTHING YOU'VE DONE.
THE DEBT'S
ALREADY BEEN PAID.
THANK YOU.
[ Phone Ringing ]
SYDNEY.
I DIDN'T THINK
YOU'D STILL BE WORKING.
GOOD OF YOU TO CALL.
I WAS GETTING REALLY WORRIED.
'CAUSE YOU THOUGHT
I MIGHT HAVE SLIPPED BACK INTO
MY CHILDHOOD DRUG ADDICTION?
JUST TELL ME WHY.
WHY DID YOU LET THEM
DO THAT TO ME?
JAROD--
YOU'RE THE ONLY PERSON
THAT I TRUSTED.
YOU WERE LIKE A--
YOU SHOULD'VE STOPPED THEM,
SYDNEY.
JAROD, I COULDN'T.
WHY NOT?
BECAUSE I WAS
A TEST SUBJECT MYSELF.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
I ASKED RAINES--
RATHER, I DEMANDED...
THAT YOU BE
LEFT OUT OF THE DRUG TESTING
AND THAT THEY USE ME INSTEAD.
AND RAINES AGREED.
IT WAS ONLY WHEN I CAME OUT
OF DETOX THAT I REALIZED
WHAT HAD HAPPENED--
THAT HE'D LIED.
SO YOU SACRIFICED YOURSELF
TO PROTECT ME.
WHY DIDN'T YOU EVER
TELL ME THAT?
I NEVER WANTED YOU
TO FEEL OBLIGATED...
TO STAY HERE
AT THE CENTRE...
IF YOU HAD A CHANCE
TO GET AWAY.
I'M SORRY, JAROD.
I'M REALLY SORRY.