[ Clucking ]
[ Broots ]
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
STOP, STOP!
RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS IT.
NICE JOB, BROOTS.
CAN YOU EVEN SPELL "MAP"?
NO, WE'RE NOT LOST,
MISS PARKER. THE G.P.S.
COORDINATES JAROD GAVE US...
SAY IT'S RIGHT AROUND HERE.
ABOUT, UH, 25 YARDS...
THAT WAY!
THIS SHOULD BE IT.
THIS-- THIS SHOULD BE IT,
RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS IT!
ALL RIGHT!
I'M WAY PAST THE POINT
OF LOSING PATIENCE
WITH JAROD'S LITTLE GAMES.
THIS IS A WASTE
OF TIME.
IF HE BROUGHT US HERE,
THERE MUST BE A REASON.
YEAH. TO MAKE US FEEL
LIKE ASSES TRAIPSING
AROUND KANSAS ALL DAY.
WELL, UH, ACTUALLY,
MISS PARKER, I DON'T THINK
WE'RE IN KANSAS ANYMORE.
- WHAT'D YOU SAY?
- WELL, BASED ON THIS MAP,
WE JUST CROSSED THE STATE LINE
RIGHT THERE.
NO. EXACTLY WHAT
DID YOU JUST SAY?
I SAID, "I DON'T THINK
WE'RE IN KANSAS ANYMORE."
WHAT'S THAT THERE?
A BRICK.
A YELLOW BRICK...
WITH AN ADDRESS ON IT.
- I GET IT.
FOLLOW THE YELLOW BRICK ROAD.
- VERY GOOD, BROOTS.
I LOVE THAT STORY.
EITHER OF YOU MUNCHKINS...
BREAK INTO SONG,
I'LL DROP A HOUSE ON YA.
LET'S GO FIND OUT WHAT OUR
LITTLE FLYING MONKEY IS UP TO.
WELL, I SEE THAT
THE SLOP ON A SHINGLE...
SEEMED TO WORK OUT ALL RIGHT
AFTER ALL.
I AM SORRY ABOUT
THE MISUNDERSTANDING.
BUT WITH THE NAME AND ALL, WELL,
I THOUGHT IT HAD SOMETHING TO DO
WITH THE BIOLOGICAL FUNCTION
OF A PIG.
I'M JUST KINDA GLAD
THAT I DIDN'T SUGGEST
THE RED-EYED GRAVY.
[ Laughing ]
OH. OH.
- DO YOU HAVE A RESTROOM?
- FOR CUSTOMERS ONLY.
I'LL TAKE A DOUGHNUT.
EXCUSE ME.
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
YEAH. PEACHY.
- I MEAN, IF THERE'S
SOMETHING I CAN DO?
- DAMN IT!
THANKS.
-IT WAS JUST A KISS, SWEETHEART.
-MAYBE I CAN HELP YOU.
- GETTING OUT OF THE WAY
WOULD BE A START.
- THAT GUY DIDN'T SEEM FRIENDLY.
YOU'RE A GREAT KISSER,
BUT IF YOU DON'T SHUT THE DOOR,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO HURT YOU.
SHUT THE DOOR!
THERE. IT'S SHUT.
[ Sighs ]
NOT WHAT I HAD IN MIND,
BUT WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TO GO WITH IT.
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Horn Honking ]
HE'S WEARING A BADGE.
YOU'RE ON THE RUN
FROM THE POLICE?
NAH, WE'RE ON THE RUN
FROM THE POLICE. HOW'S IT FEEL
TO BE A WANTED MAN?
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE DEFENDS THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
YOU COULD HAVE TOLD ME YOU WERE
ON THE RUN FROM THE POLICE.
I DON'T REMEMBER BEGGIN' YOU
TO GET IN THE CAR.
I THOUGHT YOU NEEDED HELP.
I APPRECIATE THE WHOLE DUDLEY
DO-RIGHT THING, BUT YOU'RE
A LITTLE OUT OF YOUR LEAGUE.
WHAT ARE YOU?
INSURANCE, BANKER, WHAT?
STOCK ANALYST.
AT LEAST I WAS.
UH-HUH.
FAMILY MAN, TOO, I BET.
A COUPLE OF KIDS,
A PRETTY LITTLE WIFE.
DRIVE 'EM TO SOCCER PRACTICE
IN THE S.U.V.
THE BEST THING YOU CAN DO
IS TURN YOURSELF IN.
LOOK, YOU CAN RELAX, ALL RIGHT?
I'M NOT ON THE RUN
FROM THE COPS.
I'M ON THE RUN FROM A COP.
SINGULAR.
THAT CHARMING GUY
BACK AT THE DINER WAS VINCE,
MY EX-BOYFRIEND.
HE'S NOT TAKIN' THE BREAKUP
REAL WELL.
YOU'RE TRYING TO TELL ME THAT
THAT COP WAS IN LOVE WITH YOU?
WHAT CAN I SAY?
I'M A HELL OF A CATCH.
WHERE ARE YOU HEADED?
NOWHERE. ANYWHERE.
SOMEWHERE'S RIGHT UP THE ROAD.
DROP YOU OFF?
I SUPPOSE WE'D PROBABLY
WIG OUT THE WIFE IF I
DROVE UP TO YOUR FRONT DOOR.
WELL, I DON'T HAVE A WIFE.
A HOME EITHER, FOR THAT MATTER.
WHERE YOU HEADED?
NOWHERE.
ANYWHERE.
I ALREADY BEEN SOMEWHERE.
WELL, I'M GOING EAST,
SO I GUESS THAT'S
WHERE WE'RE HEADED.
YOU CAN RIDE IF YOU WANT TO.
IT MIGHT BE NICE IF I
KNEW YOUR NAME, THOUGH.
JAROD.
NICE TO MEET YOU, JAROD.
I'M ZOE.
YOU'RE SURE THIS IS THE PLACE,
BROOTS?
WELL, THE ADDRESS
MATCHES THE BRICK.
IS IT ME, OR HAS OZ
BEEN SERIOUSLY REZONED?
[ Distant Train Horn Blaring ]
- YEAH?
- HI. WE'RE LOOKING FOR...
WHO THE HELL KNOWS.
- JAROD SENT US.
- OH. YOU MUST BE DOROTHY.
- HOLD ON A MINUTE.
- IF SHE'S DOROTHY,
THAT MAKES US, WHAT,
THE LION AND THE TIN MAN?
YOU'RE TOTO AT BEST, BROOTS.
- HELLO?
- DOWN HERE.
- DON'T TELL ME. YOU REPRESENT--
- YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
JUST GET INSIDE
BEFORE I AIR-CONDITION
THE WHOLE DAMN WORLD.
I GUESS THE WIZARD FORGOT
TO PAY THE LIGHT BILL.
HERE. HERE.
YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO.
FOLLOW, FOLLOW, FOLLOW, FOLLOW.
- IT JUST KEEPS GETTING BETTER.
- [ Lock Clicking ]
- HEY! OPEN UP THE DOOR!
- NOT WITHOUT THE MAGIC WORDS!
PARKER, I'M SURE
WE'LL GET OUT OF HERE
WHEN JAROD INTENDS US TO.
[ Sighs ]
IF I ONLY HAD A BRAIN.
COME ON.
[ Kids Chattering ]
- LEMONADE, 50 CENTS.
- [ Zoe ] CHECK IT OUT.
- GOD, HOW MANY TIMES DID WE
DO THAT WHEN WE WERE KIDS?
- LEMONADE, 50 CENTS.
- THEY'RE AWFULLY YOUNG
TO BE RUNNING A BUSINESS.
- IT'S A LEMONADE STAND.
ARE YOU TELLING ME YOU
AND YOUR FRIENDS NEVER DID THAT?
EVERY KID DOES THAT.
NOT EVERY KID.
LEMONADE.
- HEY, GUYS. HOW'S BUSINESS?
- NOT SO GOOD.
MAYBE YOUR LUCK IS CHANGING.
MY FRIEND AND I HAVE BEEN
DRIVING FOR A WHILE,
AND WE'RE REALLY THIRSTY.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT, JAROD?
OH, YEAH.
WE'RE PARCHED.
HOW MUCH?
FIFTY CENTS A GLASS.
OH, WE'RE A LOT THIRSTIER
THAN THAT.
WE MIGHT NEED
THE WHOLE PITCHER.
MM-HMM.
YOU THINK THAT'LL COVER IT?
[ Girls ]
MOM!
- MOTHER! MOM!
- TWO HUNDRED DOLLARS?
I JUST REMEMBER WHEN MY
SISTER KATIE AND I
USED TO DO THIS.
WE'D START OUT DREAMIN' WE'D
MAKE A TON OF MONEY, AND, OF
COURSE, THAT WOULD NEVER HAPPEN.
I GUESS I
JUST WANTED TO SEE WHAT
A DREAM COME TRUE LOOKS LIKE.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU HAD
A GOOD CHILDHOOD.
YEAH.
ABOUT A MILLION YEARS AGO.
CHEERS.
[ Coughs ]
OF COURSE, WHEN WE MADE IT,
WE ACTUALLY PUT SUGAR IN IT.
MMM.
I THINK IT'S PERFECT.
JAROD, YOU SCARE ME.
- YOU COMIN'?
- YES.
♪ BUT IF YOU FEEL
LIKE LOVIN' ME ♪
♪ AND YOU GOT THE NOTION ♪
[ Singing Along With Radio ]
♪ I SECOND THAT EMOTION ♪
SING IT!
♪ SO, IF YOU FEEL
LIKE GIVIN' ME ♪♪
I DON'T KNOW IT.
HEY, THERE'S A TAPE CASE
IN THE BACK.
♪♪ [ Off ]
GRAB SOMETHIN' THAT LOOKS GOOD.
YOU DON'T KNOW IT?
[ Laughs ]
♪ IF YOU FEEL LIKE LOVIN' ♪
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
THIS LOOKS INTERESTING.
YOU WANT TO TELL ME ABOUT IT?
WHAT'S TO TELL?
I DON'T LIKE WRITIN' OUT CHECKS.
THAT'S NOT A CRIME, IS IT?
COME ON.
A BOX FULL OF CASH?
THAT COP BACK AT THE DINER?
I ALREADY TOLD YOU
ABOUT HIM.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME THE TRUTH?
WHAT'D YOU DO, ROB A BANK?
YOU KNOW, SCREW YOU, JAROD.
THE ONLY THING I'M GUILTY OF...
IS STAYING TOO LONG
IN A LOUSY RELATIONSHIP.
OH, WITH THE COP, RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
EXCEPT VINCE DIDN'T KNOW HOW
TO LEAVE THE AUTHORITY FIGURE
THING AT HOME,
SO FOR TWO YEARS,
I PUT UP WITH HIM
BEATIN' THE CRAP OUT OF ME.
IT MIGHT BE TWO YEARS TOO LATE,
BUT AT LEAST I FINALLY
WALKED OUT.
THIS IS EVERY BIT
OF SAVINGS I HAD.
[ Sighs ]
SO THERE.
THAT'S MY HAPPY LITTLE TALE.
I'M 30 YEARS OLD,
AND MY WHOLE LIFE
IS TWO SUITCASES,
$27,000 AND A '62 FORD.
I KINDA MISSED OUT
ON HAPPILY EVER AFTER.
ZOE, I'M SORRY.
YOU KNOW, WHATEVER.
LOOK, IT'S BEEN REAL FUN,
BUT WHEN WE
REACH THE NEXT TOWN,
I'LL DROP YOU OFF
WHERE YOU CAN CATCH A BUS.
[ Bell Dings ]
FILL HER UP?
YES, PLEASE.
CAN I HELP YOU?
YES.
WHEN DOES THE NEXT BUS
COME THROUGH HERE?
OH, UH, HOLD ON A SECOND.
I GOT A SCHEDULE HERE SOMEPLACE.
TWENTY-ONE TO DISPATCH.
POSSIBLE ON FEMALE A.P.B.
OUT OF WARRINGTON.
PENNSYLVANIA PLATES.
EDWARD-BAKER-DAVID-6233.
[ Woman On Radio ]
ROGER, 21. SUSPECT WANTED
FOR ASSAULT AND ARMED ROBBERY.
APPREHEND WITH CAUTION.
HOWDY, MA'AM.
LICENSE AND REGISTRATION,
PLEASE.
[ Zoe ]
YEAH.
WELL, YOU'VE EITHER GOT
REAL GOOD LUCK OR REAL BAD.
- THE NEXT WESTBOUND DOESN'T GET
HERE TILL 7:45 TONIGHT.
- [ Zoe, Indistinct ]
BUT IF YOU'RE HEADED EASTBOUND,
WELL, HERE COMES
THE 1:30 RIGHT NOW.
[ Man ]
PRETTY LITTLE THING. I WONDER
WHAT SHE DID TO DESERVE THAT.
- ME TOO.
- [ Car Door Closes ]
SO, AM I GONNA
SELL YOU A TICKET?
[ Engine Starts ]
NO. MY PLANS HAVE CHANGED.
[ Sighs ]
COME ON.
YOU'RE BEING JERKED AROUND.
I DIDN'T STEAL ANYTHING
FROM ANYONE.
MA'AM, WE GOT AN A.P.B.
ON THE POLICE WIRE.
IF IT'S A MISTAKE,
YOU CAN CLEAR IT UP
BACK IN WARRINGTON.
I WON'T GET BACK TO WARRINGTON.
HAVEN'T YOU HEARD ANYTHING
I'VE JUST SAID?
- YOUR RIDE SHOULD BE HERE
ANY MINUTE.
- IT'S, UH, HERE NOW.
JAROD MALLOY, WARRINGTON P.D.
OH, I SEE YOU GOT MY PERP HERE.
MALLOY?
I WAS TOLD AN OFFICER HUDONO
WAS COMIN' TO GET HER.
OH, YEAH. VINCE.
HE SMACKED INTO...
THE CHIEF'S BRAND NEW LEXUS
ON THE WAY OUT
OF THE PARKING LOT.
OW.
HE'S GONNA BE PATCHIN' UP
HIS BUTT FOR A WHILE,
SO I'M, UH--
I'M COVERIN' FOR HIM.
I JUST WANT TO GO HOME.
YOU GOT YOUR PP-3 FORM?
UH-- UH-- UH--
DAMN IT! NO, I MUST HAVE
LEFT IT IN VINCE'S CAR.
WE REALLY CAN'T RELEASE HER
WITHOUT IT.
[ Tires Screeching ]
CAN YOU HELP ME OUT HERE?
IT'S MY DAUGHTER'S 10th
BIRTHDAY PARTY TONIGHT.
I REALLY WANT
TO GET BACK IN TIME FOR IT.
WHY DON'T YOU LET ME TAKE MY
PERP, AND THEN I'LL FAX YOU
BACK THE PP-3 FORM?
[ Car Door Closes ]
YEAH, WELL, ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO MISS
YOUR DAUGHTER'S PARTY.
THANKS.
I OWE YOU ONE.
- HEY, WHERE YOU GOIN'?
- I PARKED OUT BACK.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
THAT IS ABSOLUTELY
THE MOST INCREDIBLE THING
ANYONE'S EVER DONE FOR ME.
VINCE IS COMING THROUGH
THE FRONT DOOR.
GET IN THE CAR.
YOU HAVE MY CAR, MY MONEY.
YOU COULD HAVE TAKEN EVERYTHING
AND DISAPPEARED.
HOW DID YOU KNOW I WAS TELLING
THE TRUTH ABOUT VINCE?
I COULD'VE MADE THAT STUFF UP.
JAROD!
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
BECAUSE YOU TOLD ME.
YOU'RE A FUGITIVE NOW.
DRIVE, COWBOY!
HEY! HEY, ZOE!
JAROD, I THINK IT'S TIME
YOU TELL ME THE TRUTH.
- THE TRUTH ABOUT WHAT?
- YOU'RE OBVIOUSLY
NOT A STOCK ANALYST.
YOU MAKE
A PRETTY CONVINCING COP,
BUT THAT'S NOT IT EITHER.
SO, WHO ARE YOU REALLY?
I'M JUST SOMEONE
WHO'S LOOKING FOR A LITTLE
HAPPILY EVER AFTER MYSELF.
I'M SEARCHING FOR MY FAMILY.
I GOT SEPARATED FROM THEM
WHEN I WAS A KID.
I'M SEPARATED FROM
MY FAMILY TOO. BY CHOICE.
I RAN AWAY WHEN I WAS 16.
I CAN'T IMAGINE
HAVING A FAMILY AND NOT
WANTING TO BE WITH THEM.
- DON'T YOU MISS THEM?
- MY GRANDMOTHER, I DO A LOT.
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE WHO
EVER REALLY UNDERSTOOD ME.
BUT THE OTHERS?
I DON'T REALLY THINK ABOUT THEM.
EXCEPT, OF COURSE,
MY SISTER KATIE.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING
ABOUT IDENTICAL TWINS.
THEY'RE NOT.
KATIE GOT ALL THE BRAINS,
THE TALENT,
THE SENSE OF HUMOR.
NO ONE EVER HAD ANY TROUBLE
TELLING US APART.
THERE.
THAT SHOULD KEEP VINCE
OFF OUR BACKS.
THE STATE LINE IS ABOUT
AN HOUR EAST OF HERE.
AFTER THAT,
YOU'LL BE FREE AND CLEAR.
WE'RE NOT GONNA GO EAST ANYMORE.
A NEW PLAN.
WE'RE GOIN' NORTH.
TO WHERE?
I'M GONNA TEACH YOU...
ABOUT ANOTHER CHILDHOOD STAPLE
I'M PRETTY SURE
YOU MISSED OUT ON.
THE ROAD TRIP.
THE ROAD TRIP?
YEAH. DISTILLED TO
ITS MOST BASIC ESSENCE,
IT IS LOADING UP ON JUNK FOOD,
CRANKIN' THE RADIO AND...
JUST DRIVIN'.
♪ YOU GOT A SMILE SO BRIGHT ♪
♪ YOU KNOW YOU COULD'VE
BEEN A CANDLE ♪
♪ I'M HOLDING YOU SO TIGHT ♪
♪ YOU KNOW YOU COULD'VE
BEEN A HANDLE ♪
♪ THE WAY YOU SWEPT ME
OFF MY FEET ♪
♪ YOU KNOW YOU COULD'VE
BEEN A BROOM ♪
♪ THE WAY YOU SMELL SO SWEET ♪
♪ YOU KNOW YOU COULD'VE
BEEN SOME PERFUME ♪
♪ WELL, YOU COULD'VE BEEN
ANYTHING THAT YOU WANTED TO ♪
♪ AND I CAN TELL ♪
♪ THE WAY YOU DO
THE THINGS YOU DO ♪
♪ OH, YEAH ♪♪
[ Miss Parker ]
OKAY, JOKE'S OVER.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE WE SUPPOSED
TO BE FINDING?
MAYBE JAROD WANTS US TO RUN
LIKE RATS IN A MAZE.
OH, YEAH.
OR A FUN HOUSE.
THAT WOULD IMPLY HAVING FUN.
WHAT'S THAT LIGHT DOWN THERE?
GREAT. WE GO ON
THE YELLOW BRICK ROAD
DEATH MARCH,
AND ALL WE FIND IS
THIS GOODWILL REJECT?
HEY, THAT'S G.I. JOE.
ONE OF YOUR "DON'T ASK,
DON'T TELL" BUDDIES?
I HAD ONE JUST LIKE THIS
WHEN I WAS A KID.
HE HAD THE SAME JUNGLE FATIGUES,
THE SAME FAKE SCAR.
OH.
[ Sydney ]
WHAT IS IT?
THERE'S A LETTER "B"
CARVED IN THE BOOT.
BUT MINE HAD A "B."
I CARVED IT WITH
KENNY GOLLETTI'S POCKET KNIFE.
- [ Sydney ] YOU'RE SAYING
THIS IS YOUR DOLL?
- IT COULDN'T BE.
- COULD IT?
- WE HAVE ENTERED
THE JAROD ZONE.
G.I. JOE
WAS MY BEST FRIEND.
WHEN I WAS 12,
I GOT THE MEASLES.
I SPENT ALL SUMMER
IN THE HOSPITAL.
I ALMOST DIED.
YOU KNOW, NONE OF MY FRIENDS
COULD VISIT ME.
AND THEN MY BROTHER,
HE SNUCK ME IN MY G.I. JOE.
AND IT REMINDED ME OF HOME,
OF MY ROOM,
WHERE EVERYTHING
WAS SO MUCH BETTER.
YEAH, I KNOW IT SOUNDS CRAZY,
BUT THIS LITTLE GUY
SAVED MY LIFE THAT SUMMER.
YOU NEVER MENTIONED THIS STORY
BEFORE, BROOTS.
WELL, I NEVER EVEN
THOUGHT OF IT BEFORE.
- UNTIL--
- TILL JAROD REMINDED YOU.
[ Sighs ]
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
TOO ICK?
NOT ICK AT ALL.
YOU LOOK BEAUTIFUL.
WHY THE CHANGE?
MMM.
WOULD, UH, YOU BE WILLING
TO PRETEND FOR ME AGAIN?
OKAY, OKAY.
ANYTIME YOU WANT TO FILL ME IN
ON WHAT'S GOING ON HERE--
ZOE! OH,
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT'S YOU!
HI, GRANDMA.
OH, SWEETIE,
IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE YOU!
I CAN'T TELL YOU THE TIME I'VE
SPENT WORRYING THAT SOMETHIN'
MIGHT HAVE HAPPENED TO YOU.
SOMETHING HAS HAPPENED TO ME.
THERE'S SOMEONE
I WANT YOU TO MEET.
THIS IS JAROD.
HI.
MY HUSBAND.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE HIM, GRANDMA.
[ Laughing ]
HE'S SWEET AND KIND
AND SPOILS ME ALMOST AS MUCH
AS YOU USED TO.
OH, WELL,
YOU PICKED A PERFECT
TIME TO SURPRISE ME.
YOUR SISTER LINDA
AND HER HUSBAND ARE HERE.
COME ON IN
AND SHARE THE GOOD NEWS.
LET'S GO SHARE
THE GOOD NEWS, HONEY.
LINDA, YOU'LL NEVER GUESS
WHO'S HERE.
YOUR BABY SISTER,
AND SHE'S A NEWLYWED.
- HEY, LINDA.
- WOW. WELL, THAT'S... GREAT.
UM, CONGRATULATIONS.
UH-- UH,
LINDA IS MY SISTER.
AND, UH, THIS IS--
THAT'S MY HUSBAND, GREG.
ZOE SHOULD KNOW THAT,
BUT SINCE SHE
COULDN'T BE BOTHERED...
TO COME TO OUR WEDDING,
THEY'VE NEVER MET.
[ Mouths Word ]
WHO WANTS COFFEE?
[ Linda ]
I'M NOT SURE IF YOU CARE,
BUT MOM'S STILL CHAIRING
THE LADIES' GROUP AT THE CLUB,
AND, UH, MARK AND HIS WIFE
JUST HAD THEIR
SECOND BOY IN JUNE.
MARK'S OUR BROTHER.
I SWEAR, HE HASN'T HAD
A MINUTE TO REST.
HE'S TAKEN OVER
THE FIRM FROM DAD.
IT'S BEEN SUCH A SUCCESS.
THEY MUST HAVE
20 PARTNERS NOW.
- SO, WHAT DO YOU DO, JAROD?
- HMM?
UH, A LITTLE BIT OF THIS,
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT.
OH, DON'T BE SO MODEST, HONEY.
JAROD'S AN AEROSPACE ENGINEER.
HE DESIGNS COMMERCIAL JETLINERS.
SMALL WORLD.
I RUN THE F.A.A.'S...
PROPULSION RESEARCH FACILITY
IN RED VALLEY.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE
OF THESE NEW 6250s
COMIN' OUT OF NORTHUM?
WELL, THEY'LL LOOK A LOT BETTER
AFTER THEY SORT OUT THEIR
PREIGNITION WIRE BUS PROBLEMS.
THE S.Q. GYRO PLATFORMS
TEND TO SHIMMY AT HIGH R.P.M.s,
WHICH COULD THROW OFF
THE WHOLE TELEMETRY.
- REALLY?
- MM-HMM.
I HADN'T HEARD
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
- HE'S REALLY SOMETHING.
- YEAH, HE SURE IS.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A JERK,
AND THIS PROVES IT.
I'M TELLIN' YOU RIGHT NOW,
IF THAT THING STARTS PLAYING...
"SOMEWHERE OVER THE RAINBOW,"
I'M GONNA BLOW IT
INTO A MILLION PIECES.
NOW, DON'T. WAIT.
[ Chuckles ]
IT'S A FRENCH SONG
FROM THE EARLY '40s.
- "LES MOTS D'AMOUR."
- "THE LANGUAGE OF LOVE."
IT WAS YOURS, HUH, SYD?
♪♪ [ Record ]
WHEN THE ALLIES
LIBERATED OUR CAMP,
MY BROTHER JACOB AND I
HAD TO MAKE OUR WAY
BACK HOME TO LYON.
WHEN WE GOT HOME, THE HOUSE
MY FATHER BUILT BY HAND...
♪♪ [ Woman Singing In French ]
WAS REDUCED TO MERE RUBBLE.
BUT IN THE DEBRIS,
WE FOUND THIS RECORD.
IT WAS MY MOTHER'S
FAVORITE SONG.
SHE WOULD PUT IT ON AND MAKE
MY FATHER DANCE WITH HER.
AND MY BROTHER JACOB AND I
WOULD HAVE TO WATCH THEM.
I THOUGHT I HAD
LOST IT YEARS AGO.
SYDNEY, WHAT DO YOU THINK JAROD
IS TRYING TO TELL US
WITH ALL OF THIS?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT I'M GLAD HE IS.
♪♪ [ Continues ]
FOUR CHILDREN, 12 GRANDCHILDREN
AND 10 GREAT-GRANDKIDS.
I'D SAY I'M BLESSED,
WOULDN'T YOU?
I'D SAY.
IS THIS ZOE WITH KATIE?
OH, THIS IS ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
AND THIS WAS TAKEN
JUST A FEW WEEKS
BEFORE, UH, KATIE DIED.
IT WAS ALMOST LIKE THEY BOTH
DIED ON THE SAME DAY.
YOU KNOW, IT HIT
EVERYBODY PRETTY HARD.
BUT ZOE, SHE WAS DEVASTATED.
I CAN IMAGINE.
HER TWIN SISTER.
IN TIME, THE REST OF
THE FAMILY MANAGED TO GO ON.
BUT I THINK SHE RESENTED THEM,
LIKE THEY WERE FORGETTING
ABOUT KATIE.
ZOE JUST SORT OF SPIRALED
AFTER THAT, PULLIN' AWAY
FROM THE FAMILY.
- THAT'S WHEN ZOE RAN AWAY.
- MMM.
I HAVE A FEELING
NOW I CAN WORRY LESS.
WHAT ARE YOU TWO
GOSSIPING ABOUT?
OH, NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS. SHH.
YOU SLEEP TIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT.
AND I'LL SEE YOU
IN THE MORNING.
[ Chuckles ]
WE DID IT!
WE PULLED IT OFF!
[ Laughs ]
OH, AND, JAROD,
THAT WHOLE AIRLINE ENGINE THING?
PERFECT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WHY IS IT SO IMPORTANT
THAT THEY THINK YOUR LIFE
IS SOMETHING THAT IT'S NOT?
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I HAVE ALWAYS BEEN
THE FAMILY SCREWUP.
NO DIRECTION,
NO DECENT JOB.
LOUSY RELATIONSHIPS.
LOOK AT MY BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
ALL SUCCESS STORIES.
WELL, WHO CARES
WHAT THEY THINK?
I DON'T.
BUT MY GRANDMOTHER--
I WANT HER TO THINK THAT...
I'VE TURNED MY LIFE AROUND--
THAT I'M HAPPY.
EVEN IF IT IS A LIE.
IT'LL BE EASIER FOR HER
THAT WAY.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY THAT?
NOTHING.
HEY, I KNOW HOW WE CAN REALLY
CONVINCE THEM THAT
WE'RE NEWLYWEDS.
[ Meows ]
STICK AROUND.
- WHAT IS IT?
- HOW LONG HAVE YOU KNOWN
YOU WERE SICK?
- HOW'D YOU KNOW I WAS SICK?
- THESE PRESCRIPTIONS...
ARE ALL PRECURSORS
FOR CHEMOTHERAPY.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU KNOWN?
I DON'T KNOW.
THREE WEEKS.
AND YOU HAVEN'T FILLED
THE PRESCRIPTIONS YET. ZOE--
- I HAVEN'T GOTTEN AROUND TO IT.
- THIS IS SERIOUS.
YOUR CAREFREE ATTITUDE
WON'T MAKE IT GO AWAY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME,
SOME SCENE OUT OF LOVE STORY?
SORRY.
DRAMA QUEEN'S NOT MY STYLE.
I'M GOING TO
THE DRUGSTORE TOMORROW.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THAT.
I WANT TO.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO.
JAROD, I'VE SEEN PEOPLE FIGHT
THIS TYPE OF CANCER BEFORE.
ALL THE AGONY AND SICKNESS.
THE CURE'S WORSE
THAN THE DISEASE.
- BESIDES, MOST OF THEM
DIE ANYWAY.
- THERE ARE NEW TREATMENTS--
ADVANCEMENTS THAT COULD
GIVE YOU A REAL CHANCE.
- SO NOW YOU'RE A DOCTOR TOO?
- I'M JUST SAYING IT DOESN'T
HAVE TO BE A FATAL CONDITION.
LIFE IS A FATAL CONDITION.
YOU GET OFF THE BUS,
SUCK ALL THE JUICE OUT
OF THE YEARS YOU HAVE,
AND IT'S...
GOOD NIGHT, CLEVELAND.
YOU'VE BEEN A BEAUTIFUL CROWD.
THOSE ARE THE RULES.
ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
I GET IT.
AND I'M NOT GONNA CRY AND PLEAD
FOR SPECIAL TREATMENT
JUST AS THE CURTAIN'S CLOSING.
YOU KNOW, IT'S WEIRD,
BUT IN SOME WAYS,
IT'S BEEN A GOOD THING.
IT MADE ME REALIZE I HAD TO
GET AWAY FROM VINCE.
BROUGHT ME HERE TO SEE
MY GRANDMOTHER AGAIN.
EVEN BROUGHT ME TO YOU.
YOU CAN'T GIVE UP
WITHOUT A FIGHT.
YES, I CAN.
JAROD, DON'T SAY ANYTHING...
ABOUT THIS TO ANYONE,
ESPECIALLY MY GRANDMOTHER.
ZOE--
PROMISE ME?
- [ Scoffs ]
I CAN'T ACCEPT THIS.
- YOU HAVE TO. THIS IS MY LIFE.
THESE ARE MY DECISIONS.
BESIDES, MAYBE I DESERVE IT.
JAROD?
I VOTE WE GO BACK
TO THE MUNCHKIN AND SHOOT
OUR WAY OUT OF THIS MADHOUSE.
THIS JOURNEY ISN'T OVER
TILL WE FIND WHAT JAROD
LEFT FOR YOU, MISS PARKER.
AND I THINK
WE JUST FOUND IT.
THIS LOOKS LIKE THE BASKET
THAT DOROTHY CARRIED TOTO IN.
WELL, IF JAROD RUSTLED UP
MY OLD DOG MR. SHECKLE,
IT AIN'T GONNA BE PRETTY.
- A THIMBLE?
- [ Broots ] MISS PARKER?
MY FAMILY...
DIDN'T SPEND A LOT OF TIME
TOGETHER WHEN I WAS GROWING UP.
MY FATHER WAS ALWAYS
AT THE CENTRE.
IF HE WAS AROUND,
MY MOTHER WAS OFF
IN AN ORPHANAGE SOMEWHERE.
BUT ONE DAY,
THERE HAD BEEN A BIG STORM.
BUT THE ROADS WERE ALL CLOSED.
EVERYTHING WAS SHUT DOWN.
[ Chuckles ]
DADDY, OF COURSE, WAS ANNOYED.
BUT I WAS ELATED,
BECAUSE IT WAS
JUST THE THREE OF US...
TRAPPED TOGETHER
IN THE HOUSE.
SO, YOU ALL JUST
SEWED SOMETHING.
[ Chuckling ]
- WE PLAYED MONOPOLY.
- OH.
WE PLAYED MONOPOLY ALL DAY
AND INTO THE NIGHT.
DADDY WAS THE SHOE,
MY MOTHER WAS THE CAR,
AND I WAS...
THE THIMBLE.
[ Clears Throat ]
SO, WHY DO YOU SUPPOSE
JAROD IS DOING THIS?
I MEAN, WHAT DO YOU--
WHAT DO YOU THINK
HE'S TRYING TO SAY?
- THERE'S NO PLACE LIKE HOME.
WHICH IS HOW WE GET
THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
- THERE'S NO PLACE--
- WE'VE SAID IT
THREE TIMES ALREADY!
I KNOW, BUT I GOTTA HEAR IT
WITH THE SHOES CLICKING.
YOU'RE GONNA HEAR IT
WITH THE CLICKING
OF MY .9 MILLIMETER...
IF YOU DON'T OPEN
THE DAMN DOOR!
[ Lock Clicking ]
HEY, NICE ATTITUDE!
DON'T FORGET TO COME BACK...
AND SEE ME NEXT TIME
YOU'RE IN THE EMERALD CITY, HUH?
- I REALLY WISH YOU
WEREN'T LEAVIN' SO SOON.
- SO DO I.
BUT JAROD'S SPEAKING AT
A BIG CONFERENCE UP NORTH.
AND IF WE DON'T LEAVE NOW,
WELL, HE'S GONNA BE LATE.
WELL, DON'T YOU KEEP
MY LITTLE GIRL
AWAY TOO LONG, JAROD.
I WANT TO SEE HER
BACK HERE SOON.
OH, SHE'LL BE BACK
BEFORE YOU KNOW IT.
OH, ONE MORE THING, GRAM.
I HAVE SOMETHING FOR YOU.
A, UH-- A SURPRISE
BIRTHDAY PRESENT.
- BUT MY BIRTHDAY
ISN'T FOR TWO MONTHS.
- THAT'S WHY IT'S A SURPRISE.
BUT DON'T OPEN IT
UNTIL AFTER WE LEAVE.
I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU, ZOE.
OH, I LOVE YOU.
[ Grunts ]
BYE.
THANK YOU, JAROD,
FOR KEEPING YOUR PROMISE.
I STILL THINK
YOU SHOULD TELL HER.
BETTER SHE REMEMBER ME
LIKE THIS.
DRIVING AWAY ONE LAST TIME?
NO. HAPPY.
AND I'D REALLY APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU'D BE HAPPY TOO.
YOU KNOW,
ENOUGH OF THIS MOROSE CRAP.
I PLAN ON MAKING THE MOST
OF MY TIME THAT'S LEFT.
[ Man On Radio ]
AND BY THE WAY, IF YOU'RE
OUT NEAR FREEBURG TODAY,
THE LOCAL "Y"
IS PUTTING ON A CARNIVAL.
THEY'RE GONNA HAVE GAMES, RIDES.
BRING THE WHOLE FAMILY DOWN.
COME ON, JAROD.
SHOW ME A GOOD TIME.
[ Radio ]
YOU'LL HAVE LOTS OF FUN--
[ Door Opening ]
IT'S NOT HOME,
BUT IT'LL DO.
[ Sydney ]
LOOKS LIKE THE NEXT PIECE OF
JAROD'S PUZZLE'S ALREADY HERE.
[ Broots ]
THE WICKED WITCH OF THE WEST.
HEY, DOESN'T IT KIND OF
LOOK A LITTLE... LIKE--
I'LL TAKE THAT AS A COMPLIMENT.
THERE MUST BE MORE THAN
THE OBVIOUS INTERPRETATION.
MAYBE SOME DEEPER MEANING?
HMM?
[ Evil Laughter,
Sizzling ]
[ Laughter Continues ]
[ Warped Laughter ]
[ Laughter Stops ]
HEY, LOOK.
BROOTS, CALL THE AIRSTRIP.
TELL THEM TO GET
MY BROOMSTICK FIRED UP.
WE'RE GOIN' BACK TO KANSAS.
[ Zoe ] THE MANAGER SAID
OUR ROOM IS AROUND HERE.
YOU'RE AMAZING, JAROD.
I'VE NEVER SEEN SOMEONE...
WIN ONE GAME
AFTER ANOTHER LIKE THAT.
IT'S REALLY VERY SIMPLE.
IT'S ALL A MATTER OF GEOMETRY
AND PHYSICS.
RIGHT.
OKAY, I WORKED A STINT
AS A CARNY A WHILE BACK.
I KNOW ALL THEIR SECRETS.
NOW, WHY DOESN'T THAT
SURPRISE ME?
[ Both Chuckling ]
HE GAVE US
LUCKY NUMBER SEVEN.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING NOW?
ZOE?
IT'S MAGICAL, JAROD.
DON'T YOU FEEL
LIKE TAKIN' A DIP?
COME ON.
ZOE, NO.
JAROD, YES.
LOOK AT IT.
IT'S CALLING US.
I DON'T HAVE
A BATHING SUIT.
NEITHER DO I.
I DON'T KNOW.
HEY, I PAID FOR THE ROOM.
THE LEAST YOU CAN DO
IS SWIM WITH ME.
[ Sighs ]
YOU'VE NEVER SKINNY-DIPPED
BEFORE, HAVE YOU?
IS-- IS THAT
WHAT THEY CALL IT?
YEAH. JUMP IN
AND I'LL SHOW YOU WHY.
- YOU'RE CRAZY, YOU KNOW THAT?
- AND YOU'RE STALLING.
JUST WHAT DOES A NAKED WOMAN
HAVE TO DO TO GET YOU IN HERE?
[ Splashing ]
IT'S NOT SO BAD, IS IT?
NICE.
IT'S PRETTY GOOD.
HI.
MMM. ZOE?
- [ Chuckles ]
OKAY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- LAST NIGHT WAS AMAZING.
- MMM.
- THE LAST 48 HOURS
HAVE BEEN AMAZING.
FALLING IN LOVE
WASN'T PART OF THE PLAN.
- WHAT PLAN?
- THE ONE THAT SAYS I HAVE TO GO
NOW, AND IT HAS TO BE ALONE.
WHAT? WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THIS ISN'T FUNNY.
UNLOCK THESE CUFFS.
- UNLOCK THE CUFFS!
GIVE ME THE KEY!
- I CAN'T.
LOOK, YOU'RE GOING
TO GET WELL.
YOU'LL BEAT THIS!
NO, I WON'T!
I'M SURE OF THAT.
I NEED TO END THINGS MY WAY.
GO OUT WITH A BANG, RIGHT?
- ZOE, DON'T DO THIS.
- JAROD, YOU'RE GOOD
AT PRETENDING.
- JUST PRETEND YOU NEVER MET ME.
- ZOE! ZOE--
- ZOE!
- [ Door Closes ]
[ Grunting ]
HI, HONEY.
GOIN' SOMEWHERE?
- THE GAME'S OVER.
IT'S TIME TO GO HOME.
- THAT'S NOT MY HOME ANYMORE.
I TOLD YOU, YOU AND I ARE OVER.
IF YOU DIDN'T WANT ME
TO FIND YOU,
THEN YOU WOULDN'T HAVE
USED YOUR CREDIT CARD
TO RENT THE ROOM.
YOU HAVEN'T BLOWN
ALL THAT MONEY?
THE MONEY WAS MINE!
IT WAS OURS!
FINE. YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU CAN HAVE IT,
BUT YOU CAN'T HAVE ME!
YOU REALLY WANNA TAKE ME ON?
DO YOU?
I WILL IF I HAVE TO.
WHAT THE HELL?
YOU'RE WITH THIS GUY?
COME ON, ZOE. IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HEY!
LOOK, SHE DOESN'T WANNA
BE WITH YOU.
WHY CAN'T YOU GET THAT
THROUGH YOUR HEAD?
THAT'S NOT HER DECISION.
AND IT'S NOT YOURS EITHER.
LET'S GO.
OH, MY GOD, VINCE, NO!
YOU MUST'VE HAD SOME FUN
LAST NIGHT, HUH?
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
NOT LIKE THE FUN YOU AND I
ARE GONNA HAVE TONIGHT.
[ Grunting ]
VINCE, DON'T!
SON OF A BITCH!
YOU GOT SOME BRASS ONES!
I'LL GIVE YOU THAT!
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
ZOE! ZOE!
ZOE?
HOW'D YOU KNOW?
I CALLED YOUR GRANDMOTHER.
SHE SAID THIS IS WHERE
YOUR SISTER DIED.
- PLEASE, I WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
- OH, NO, YOU DON'T.
YOU WANT TO STOP ME
FROM FINISHING MY JOURNEY.
ZOE, WHAT HAPPENED WAS TERRIBLE,
AND IT WAS VERY SAD,
BUT IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
YOU HAVE TO STOP
BLAMING YOURSELF FOR IT.
I'M THE ONE WHO TOLD HER
TO CLIMB UP HERE.
I ONLY MEANT IT AS A JOKE,
BUT KATIE,
SHE NEVER TURNED DOWN A DARE.
SHE WAS RIGHT ABOUT HERE
WHEN SHE SLIPPED.
KATIE SHOULD HAVE BEEN
THE ONE THAT LIVED.
SHE WAS SMARTER, FUNNIER.
SO YOU THINK
YOU DESERVE TO DIE.
IS THAT IT?
IT'S NOT LIKE I'VE BEEN
A BIG SUCCESS IN LIFE.
LOOK AT WHAT I'VE DONE TO MINE.
I'VE MADE A MESS OF IT.
BECAUSE YOU'VE BEEN PUNISHING
YOURSELF FOR WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR SISTER,
AND THAT'S WHY YOU'RE
NOT FIGHTING THE CANCER.
THIS ISN'T ABOUT LIVING LIFE
TO THE FULLEST...
OR GOING OUT WITH A BANG.
YOU'RE NOT FIGHTING IT
BECAUSE YOU DON'T THINK
YOU DESERVE TO BEAT IT.
GOD, JAROD.
I'M JUST SO SCARED.
I KNOW YOU ARE.
AND I'M GOING TO HELP YOU.
BUT THERE'S ONLY
ONE PLACE TO DO IT,
AND THAT'S WITH
THE PEOPLE YOU LOVE.
WHY WOULD JAROD BRING US
ALL THE WAY BACK HERE...
WHEN NOTHING HAS CHANGED?
WELL, NOTHING EXCEPT THIS.
IT'S NOT EXACTLY RUBY SLIPPERS.
I THINK JAROD FELL ASLEEP
IN THE MAGICAL POPPIES
A LITTLE TOO LONG.
[ Broots ]
A NOTE FROM JAROD, SYDNEY?
WHAT DOES IT SAY?
"THERE'S NO PLACE LIKE HOME."
IN CASE WE DIDN'T
GET IT BEFORE?
"EVERYONE DESERVES ONE.
SO WHY DON'T YOU...
LEAVE ME ALONE
AND LET ME FIND MINE?"
[ Kid Laughing, Chattering ]
HEY-HEY-HEY!
[ Chattering, Indistinct ]
ARE YOU SURE ABOUT THIS?
YEAH, I'M SURE.
YOU GOT A LONG FIGHT
AHEAD OF YOU.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO HAVE TO
GO THROUGH IT ALONE.
I'M NOT ALONE.
I'VE GOT THEM.
AND I'VE GOT YOU.
IN HERE.
I WANT TO STAY WITH YOU.
I KNOW.
BUT YOU CAN'T STAY, CAN YOU?
I CAN SEE IT IN YOUR EYES.
THANK YOU...
FOR HELPING ME
FIND MY WAY BACK HOME.
GOOD-BYE.
YOU EVER SAY THAT WORD AGAIN,
I'LL KICK YOUR BUTT.
OKAY.
GO.