I WOULD LIKE
A DOUBLE-DIP VANILLA
WITH GRANOLA SPRINKLES, PLEASE.
- TRUCK AIN'T OPEN.
- UH, I HAVE CASH MONEY.
IT'S 7:30
IN THE FREAKIN' MORNING.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY
THE WAFFLE HOUSE?
CONSIDERING THE IRON,
CALCIUM AND LACTOSE
IN THE ICE CREAM,
THE CARBOHYDRATE VALUE OF
THE CONE AND THE FIBER CONTENT
OF THE GRANOLA,
ONE COULD, IN REALITY, RECEIVE
MORE NUTRITIOUS INGREDIENTS
IN ONE TASTY SURPRISE...
THAN IN AN ENTIRE
BACON AND EGG BREAKFAST.
- ARE YOU SOME KIND OF NUT?
- NO. I JUST LIKE ICE CREAM.
YEAH.
- TAXI!
- [ Man ] I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THE POLICE LOOKED THROUGH MY
DAUGHTER'S ROOM ONCE ALREADY.
WHAT DID YOU SAY
YOUR NAME WAS?
WAXMAN. DETECTIVE JAROD WAXMAN.
THE OTHER OFFICER SAID
A TEENAGER MISSING
LESS THAN 48 HOURS...
WASN'T GONNA BE
A HIGH PRIORITY CASE.
WE RECONSIDERED
THE SITUATION.
WAS THERE ANYTHING
OUT OF ORDINARY GOING ON...
IN YOUR DAUGHTER'S LIFE
BEFORE SHE DISAPPEARED?
SOMETHING BOTHERING HER?
[ Man ]
MY WIFE PASSED AWAY
THREE YEARS AGO.
- CANCER.
- I'M SORRY.
AND IT'S BEEN HARD FOR ME,
BUT NOT LIKE IT'S BEEN
FOR JESSE.
SHE JUST BARELY TURNED 15.
SHE WAS AT AN AGE WHERE A GIRL
REALLY NEEDS HER MOTHER.
AND I GUESS I JUST DIDN'T HAVE
THE ANSWERS THAT SHE NEEDED.
MAYBE SHE WENT AWAY
WITH A FRIEND,
SOMEONE FROM SCHOOL?
JESSE'S SHY.
SHE DOESN'T HAVE
MUCH OF A SOCIAL LIFE.
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S LIKE SHE JUST
VANISHED INTO THIN AIR.
SHE SEEMED TO HAVE
A SPECIAL INTEREST IN ANGELS.
YEAH. WHEN HER MOTHER
PASSED AWAY,
JESSE STARTED COLLECTING THEM,
READING BOOKS ABOUT THEM.
THAT ONE'S HER FAVORITE.
- HAVE YOU SEEN THIS BEFORE?
- NO, NEVER.
"GATES OF HELL."
THAT'S JESSE'S HANDWRITING.
YOU'VE GOT TO HELP ME.
MY DAUGHTER'S LIFE
IS IN YOUR HANDS, DETECTIVE.
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
- [ Miss Parker ] HE DEFENDS
THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
- [ Jarod ] LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
A MAN WITH NO FACE?
IT REMINDS ME OF A YOUNG MAN
I RECENTLY HIRED...
TO HELP RESTORE
A BROKEN-DOWN OLD WAX MUSEUM.
MR. KLEINMAN,
I DIDN'T EVEN HEAR YOU COME IN.
[ Chuckling ]
OH, A GIFT FOR A FRIEND?
MORE LIKE... A MESSAGE.
AH. I BROUGHT YOU A SNACK.
OOH, I HOPE IT'S ICE CREAM.
BETTER. A DELICACY.
ALCATRAZ OYSTERS.
THESE LITTLE BEAUTIES YOU CAN
FIND ONLY IN SAN FRANCISCO BAY.
GO AHEAD. EAT.
ENJOY. YEAH.
- EH?
- MMM.
THEY'RE VERY GOOD.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Sniffs ]
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THIS JUST MIGHT DO THE TRICK.
YOU ARE A VERY STRANGE
YOUNG MAN, JAROD.
NOT HALF AS STRANGE
AS THE PEOPLE
I'M SENDING THIS TO.
JAROD, ARE YOU SURE YOU WOULDN'T
WANT TO STAY UPSTAIRS?
ACTUALLY, I SPEND
A LOT OF TIME ALONE.
IT'S SORT OF NICE
TO HAVE THE COMPANY.
-AH.
-MR. KLEINMAN, HAVE YOU EVER
SEEN ANYTHING LIKE THIS BEFORE?
[ Gasps ]
MY GOD!
WHERE DID YOU GET THIS?
A MAN I KNOW IS SEARCHING
FOR HIS DAUGHTER.
- YOU HAVE SEEN IT.
- YEAH.
- I HAVE SEEN IT.
- YOU'RE A HOLOCAUST SURVIVOR.
MEMBERS OF THE S.S.
WORE SIMILAR SYMBOLS...
ON THEIR UNIFORMS.
DEVILS. DEMONS.
THIS MAN--
HE'S WORRIED
FOR HIS DAUGHTER'S SAFETY.
OH, HE SHOULD BE.
HE SHOULD BE SCARED
TO DEATH.
♪♪ [ Techno, Man Singing,
Indistinct ]
♪♪ [ Man Screaming ]
♪♪ [ Singing Resumes ]
DIDN'T YOUR MOTHER EVER TELL YOU
IT'S RUDE TO STARE?
I HARDLY KNEW MY MOTHER.
SEE SOMETHING YOU LIKE?
I'M CONFUSED.
DOESN'T ALL THAT... HURT?
THAT'S THE IDEA, SLICK.
SO YOU ENJOY...
SELF-INFLICTED PAIN?
YOU'RE SCREWIN'
WITH MY HEAD, RIGHT?
ACTUALLY,
I'M LOOKING FOR SOMEONE.
A YOUNG MAN. A MAGICIAN.
THROW A ROCK, BABY CAKES.
YEAH, I'VE SEEN HAWK
HANDING THESE OUT
TO A SELECT FEW.
HE'S HOLDING COURT
IN THE BACK ROOM.
YOU CAN'T MISS HIM.
THANK YOU.
AND WHEN YOU'RE FINISHED
PLAYING GAMES WITH
THE BIRD MAN, COME BACK.
I'LL SHOW YOU A REAL MAGIC SHOW.
THAT WOULD BE ENJOYABLE.
THANK YOU.
♪♪ [ Screaming ]
♪♪ [ Singing Resumes ]
MOST PEOPLE CAN'T COMPREHEND
THE VERY WORLD THEY INHABIT.
THEY EXIST,
BUT THEY DON'T EXPERIENCE.
THEY LOOK, BUT THEY NEVER SEE.
I BELIEVE THAT THEY'RE PORTALS--
WINDOWS TO THE BODY,
THE MIND AND THE SPIRIT.
GIVEN THE PERFECT EXCHANGE
OF ENERGIES,
THESE WINDOWS CAN BE OPENED.
PASS BEYOND.
I LOOK AT YOU.
I LOOK INTO YOU,
AND I SEE TREMENDOUS SORROW,
EMPTINESS.
I WANT YOU TO THINK ABOUT
WHAT WAS TAKEN FROM YOU.
IMAGINE IN YOUR MIND'S EYE
THE CAUSE OF YOUR SUFFERING.
I-- I DON'T--
SHH. TRUST ME.
I WANT YOU TO THINK
ABOUT THE OBJECT OF YOUR PAIN.
CAN YOU SEE IT?
YES.
I OFFER YOU THIS GIFT...
WITH ALL MY LOVE.
[ Gasps ]
OH, MY GOD!
HOW COULD YOU--
WHO IS CLARE?
SH-SHE'S MY-- MY TWIN SISTER.
[ Murmuring ]
AND WHERE IS SHE?
SHE WAS KILLED...
IN A CAR ACCIDENT
WHEN WE WERE TWO.
[ Sobbing ]
BUT HOW COULD YOU KNOW THAT?
SIMPLE.
YOUR HEART TOLD ME.
TELL US AGAIN ABOUT
THE ANGEL'S FLIGHT.
WHAT'S ANGEL'S FLIGHT?
IT WAS A DREAM THE GREAT HOUDINI
HAD REPEATEDLY
THROUGHOUT HIS LIFE.
OR NIGHTMARES, SOME BELIEVE.
HOUDINI FELT,
GIVEN THE POWER OF ANGELS,
HE COULD BREAK FREE...
FROM THE BOUNDARIES OF EARTH
AND SOAR IN THE HEAVENS
LIKE A GOD.
BUT, UNFORTUNATELY, HE WASN'T.
AND WHEN HE DIED,
HIS DREAM DIED WITH HIM.
HAWK SAYS THE ANGEL'S FLIGHT
IS ATTAINABLE.
CLOSE ENOUGH TO TOUCH.
I SUGGEST WE ASSEMBLE AGAIN
AT MIDNIGHT
FOR A READING SESSION.
GO WITH THE ANGELS.
[ Girl ]
THIS IS TOO HEAVY FOR ME.
[ Boy ] THIS GUY IS AWESOME.
THEY SEEM TO BE VERY... LOYAL.
I OFFER THEM
SOMETHING THEY NEED.
SOMETHING THEIR WORLDS
HAVE DENIED THEM.
♪♪ [ Techno, Woman Singing ]
MAGIC.
LOVE.
MY NAME IS JAROD.
I HEAR YOU HAVE A GREAT GIFT--
THE ABILITY TO TOUCH PEOPLE.
AND YOU DESIRE THIS GIFT.
I WISH TO LEARN
FROM THE BEST.
AND WHY SHOULD I OPEN MYSELF
TO A STRANGER?
♪ I CAN'T SLEEP
NO MATTER HOW I TRY ♪
♪♪ [ Continues, Indistinct ]
[ Blowing ]
THE PERFECT EXCHANGE OF ENERGY.
KESSLER WILL SHOW YOU THE WAY.
♪ AWAKE AT NIGHT ♪
MIDNIGHT.
YOU DON'T SEEM TO SHARE HAWK'S
BELIEF IN THE POWER OF ANGELS.
- EXCUSE ME?
- WHEN THE SUBJECT
OF ANGEL'S FLIGHT CAME UP,
YOU SEEMED RATHER UNCOMFORTABLE.
♪ AWAKE AT NIGHT ♪
MIDNIGHT.
♪ I CAN'T SLEEP
NO MATTER HOW I TRY ♪♪
WHERE ARE YOU, FALLEN ANGEL?
WHERE ARE YOU?
DON'T EVEN TALK TO ME
UNLESS IT'S GOOD NEWS. BROOTS?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA BE HAPPY.
IT'S NOT GOOD NEWS.
- ANY SIGN OF JAROD?
- IT'S LIKE HE VANISHED
INTO A BLACK HOLE.
KIND OF LIKE
YOUR PERSONAL LIFE?
TELL ME ABOUT IT.
[ Sydney ]
THAT'S ODD, ISN'T IT?
[ Miss Parker ] WHAT, THE GIRL?
CIGAR.
LYLE DOESN'T SMOKE.
OH, YEAH,
THAT'S A GIFT.
JERRY, THE GUY WITH
THE GLASS EYE WHO WORKS
DOWN IN TRANSPORTATION--
WELL, HE TOLD ME
THAT MR. LYLE IS EXPECTING...
SOME CENTRE HOTSHOT
FROM THE WEST COAST.
-[ Miss Parker ] DID MARBLE-EYED
JERRY GIVE YOU A NAME?
-NOT THAT I CAN REMEMBER.
HMM. THAT MAKES HIM ABOUT
AS WORTHLESS AS THIS SHIRT THEN,
DOESN'T IT?
WHAT, DID DON HO
HAVE A GARAGE SALE?
DON WHO?
THE BOX. WHAT'S IN IT?
OH, YEAH. MISS PARKER,
THIS BOX IS FOR YOU.
WELL, THAT'S SOMETHING
YOU DON'T SEE EVERY DAY.
- "BEWARE OF STRANGERS
BEARING GIFTS."
- I BET IT'S FROM JAROD.
GEE, YOU THINK?
MAYBE HE'S TALKIN'
ABOUT LYLE.
UH-UH.
CIGARS AND CHAMPAGNE?
MAYBE.
WHAT ARE YOU
UP TO NOW, JAROD?
[ Door Knob Rattling ]
[ Hawk ]
WELCOME, MY FRIENDS,
TO THE MIDNIGHT SESSION.
LET US BEGIN.
PLEASE STAND.
COMMON, I KNOW.
READ THE DATE ON THIS COIN.
- 1994.
THAT HAS SPECIAL MEANING
FOR YOU, DOESN'T IT?
YES.
WHY?
BECAUSE THAT'S THE YEAR
MY MOTHER DIED.
TURN THE COIN OVER.
OH!
SHE-SHE USED TO CALL ME
HER PUPPY.
YES. SHE'S WITH YOU.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Whispering ]
SHE'LL ALWAYS BE WITH YOU.
THANK YOU.
[ Applause ]
I SEE YOU FOUND YOUR WAY.
- I WASN'T SURE
WHICH WAY TO GO.
- OBVIOUSLY NOT THAT WAY.
TIGHT SECURITY.
PROTECTING MAGIC SECRETS.
HAWK LIKES TO KEEP
HIS PERSONAL LIFE... PERSONAL.
I SUGGEST YOU
JOIN THE OTHERS.
THE READING'S ALREADY STARTED.
- CAN I ASK YOU SOMETHING?
- IF I SAID NO,
WOULD YOU WALK AWAY?
PROBABLY NOT.
- LOOK FAMILIAR?
- WHERE DID YOU GET THAT?
I LIKE TO KEEP
MY PERSONAL LIFE... PERSONAL.
YOU DON'T WANT TO MISS
THE SESSION.
OF COURSE NOT.
- [ Hawk ] YOUR NAME?
- UH, SCOTT.
STAND UP, SCOTT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I WON'T BITE.
[ People Chuckling ]
YOU CAN PUT THAT DOWN.
YOU'RE NEW HERE.
YES.
YOU'RE NERVOUS.
[ Chuckles ]
A LITTLE BIT.
YOU'RE ALSO BLEEDING.
BLEEDING?
INSIDE.
YOU WERE BETRAYED.
HURT BY SOMEONE YOU TRUSTED,
SOMEONE YOU LOVED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
YES, YOU DO.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WE LOVE YOU.
[ People, Softly ]
[ Gasps ]
YOU COULDN'T BELIEVE IT
WHEN IT STARTED.
YOU WANTED TO SCREAM,
BUT YOU WERE AFRAID.
CONFUSED.
PLEASE DON'T.
[ Hawk ]
YOU WERE SO YOUNG,
VULNERABLE.
IT WAS LIKE A NIGHTMARE
THE WAY HE CAME AT YOU.
SO MUCH ANGER.
I CAN'T DO THIS.
YOU THOUGHT IF
YOU CLOSED YOUR EYES,
IT WOULD STOP.
BUT IT DIDN'T STOP,
DID IT, SCOTT?
IT GOT MORE VIOLENT
AND ANGRY.
NO. NO.
[ Hawk ]
YOU WERE AFRAID TO TELL ANYONE.
AFRAID TO SAY THE NAME,
TERRIFIED THAT NO ONE
WOULD BELIEVE YOU.
I WAS AFRAID.
[ Sobbing ]
YOU WERE ONLY A BOY,
AND HE WAS SO POWERFUL,
SO TERRIFYING.
[ Scott ]
I WANTED HIM TO STOP HITTING ME.
I WANTED TO SAY HIS NAME.
I KNOW YOU DID.
AND NOW YOU CAN.
NOW YOU CAN SAY IT
FOR THE ENTIRE WORLD TO HEAR.
I CAN'T.
SAY IT.
SAY IT, SCOTT!
SAY IT AND END
THE NIGHTMARE FOREVER!
I CAN'T!
[ Sobbing Continues ]
I CAN'T.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SAY IT FOR YOU.
[ People Gasping ]
IT WAS YOUR FATHER.
IT WAS YOUR FATHER
WHO BEAT YOU, SCOTT.
I NEVER WANTED IT TO HAPPEN.
I KNOW YOU DIDN'T, SCOTT.
I KNOW YOU DIDN'T.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
BE AFRAID ANYMORE.
IT'S OKAY, SCOTT.
YOU SHOULD TRY THAT ON ME.
MAYBE I WILL.
YOU THINK YOU HELPED HIM?
EVERYONE HAS SECRETS,
DEMONS THEY KEEP HIDDEN.
AND SOMETIMES,
IF YOU DON'T STOP THEM,
THEY EAT YOU ALIVE
A PIECE AT A TIME.
WHAT ABOUT YOU, JAROD?
WHAT KIND OF DEMONS
ARE YOU HIDING INSIDE?
THAT'S ALL FOR TONIGHT.
MR. KESSLER WILL
COLLECT YOUR OFFERINGS.
ANOTHER RUSH DELIVERY
FROM JAROD?
YEAH, NUMBER THREE.
GREAT. NOW YOUR BOY'S YANKIN'
MY CRANK ON AN HOURLY BASIS.
JAROD NEVER PLAYS THESE GAMES
WITHOUT SUBSTANTIAL MOTIVATION.
IT'S A HEAD MADE OF STERNO.
WHAT IS IT THIS TIME?
WOW!
ANOTHER GIANT LEAP
INTO THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
YOU WERE SAYING SOMETHING
ABOUT MOTIVATION?
SUBSTANCE, PARKER.
AND THERE'S ANOTHER NOTE.
"SEE NO EVIL."
IN THE BOX WITH THE EARS,
THE NOTE WAS, "HEAR NO EVIL."
ANYTHING ELSE ON THE IDENTITY
OF LYLE'S MYSTERY ARRIVAL?
NOTHING ON THE GRAPEVINE.
WELL, AT LEAST WE HAVE
MR. POTATO HEAD.
COOL.
[ Beeps ]
I FINALLY FOUND YOU, JESSICA.
KILL THE SON OF A BITCH.
I WAS EXCITED
TO GET YOUR CALL,
EVEN IF IT WAS A BIT CRYPTIC.
FOUND SOMETHING OUT
ABOUT JESSICA?
I'M STILL WORKING ON THE CASE.
MR. BRACKEN, YOU TOLD ME
THAT YOUR WIFE...
PASSED AWAY FROM AN ILLNESS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S NOT WHAT
REALLY HAPPENED, IS IT?
I WANNA HELP YOU
FIND YOUR DAUGHTER,
BUT WE'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
IF I'M GOING TO HELP YOU,
YOU HAVE TO TELL ME THE TRUTH.
OKAY.
SARAH WAS... VIBRANT.
SHE WAS SO FULL OF LIFE.
THEN SHE GOT SICK.
ALL THAT LIFE JUST
SLOWLY DRAINED OUT OF HER.
SHE TRIED TO TAKE
THE TREATMENT,
BUT... IT WAS TOO LATE.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
SHE WENT OUT ON THAT ROOF.
I DON'T KNOW... WHAT SHE
WAS THINKING WHEN SHE JUMPED.
THE POLICE FOUND HER BODY
IN THE ALLEY THE NEXT MORNING.
SHE WAS STILL CLUTCHING
HER ANGEL PENDANT IN HER HAND.
AND THAT'S HOW JESSE
BECAME OBSESSED WITH ANGELS.
YEAH. I'M SORRY.
I SHOULD HAVE
TOLD YOU THE TRUTH.
I JUST, UH, DIDN'T THINK
THAT IT--
FIND MY LITTLE GIRL,
DETECTIVE, PLEASE.
SHE'S ALL I HAVE LEFT.
[ Broots ]
SPEAK NO EVIL.
ANYBODY RECOGNIZE HIM?
HE KINDA LOOKS
LIKE GILLIGAN.
GILLIGAN?
YEAH.
YOU KNOW, THE SKIPPER
AND THE PROFESSOR
AND MARY ANN AND-AND GINGER.
YOU GREW UP IN A TRAILER PARK,
DIDN'T YOU?
NO, I DID NOT.
IT WAS A MOBILE HOME.
IT'S OBVIOUS JAROD
IS TRYING TO KEEP US BUSY
CHASING MR. NO NAME'S IDENTITY,
WHILE HE SKIPS ALONG
FREE AS HE PLEASES.
- THE QUESTION IS,
WHY ALL THE EFFORT?
- WHAT ABOUT THE NOTES?
- JOKES WITHOUT PUNCH LINES.
- MAYBE A WARNING.
WHAT IS THAT?
IT LOOKS LIKE
A-A WATER STAIN.
[ Sniffs ]
EW!
- SMELLS LIKE LOW TIDE.
- [ Sniffs ] WOW!
THEY ALL SMELL THE SAME.
MAYBE JAROD'S JUST
DROPPING BREAD CRUMBS.
HAVE THESE CARDS ANALYZED.
OKAY.
WHO ARE YOU, PAL?
"A HISTORY OF FALLEN ANGELS."
FALLEN... ANGELS.
HAWK SAYS THE ANGEL'S FLIGHT
IS ATTAINABLE.
CLOSE ENOUGH TO TOUCH.
[ Echoing ]
I DON'T KNOW WHY
SHE WENT OUT ON THAT ROOF.
I DON'T KNOW...
WHAT SHE WAS THINKING
WHEN SHE JUMPED.
[ Squeaking ]
JESSICA.
[ Gun Cocks ]
I HOPED YOU WERE SMARTER.
WHY COULDN'T YOU JUST WALK AWAY
AND LET THIS THING FINISH?
THE SAME REASON
THAT YOU COULDN'T SIT
AT THAT TABLE WITH HAWK...
AND TALK ABOUT ANGEL'S FLIGHT.
HE DID THIS, DIDN'T HE?
WHAT HAPPENED?
JESSE BRACKEN
DIDN'T HAVE ENOUGH TO OFFER?
OR SHE FOUND THE COMPUTER FILES
THAT HAWK KEEPS ON THE OTHERS?
THE WEALTHY, DISENFRANCHISED,
YOUNG PEOPLE...
THAT WERE RECRUITED
OFF THE STREETS BY YOU.
THAT'S THE GAME, ISN'T IT?
DAZZLE THEM WITH MAGIC,
AND THEN TAKE THEM
FOR EVERY PENNY YOU CAN.
I TOLD HAWK THAT WE
SHOULD JUST CUT AND RUN,
BUT IT WAS NEVER ONLY
ABOUT THE MONEY FOR HIM.
ANGEL'S FLIGHT WAS JUST
THE LAST ACT OF THE PLAY.
I SWEAR, SOMETIMES,
THE GUY REALLY THINKS
HE'S GONNA FLY.
- WHAT HAPPENED TO HER?
- HAWK FLIPPED OUT
A COUPLE OF DAYS AGO,
AND JESSE OVERHEARD US
TALKIN' ABOUT THE SCAM.
I JUST THOUGHT HE WAS
GONNA TALK TO HER.
- WHAT?
- SHE'S STILL ALIVE.
- GIVE ME THE GUN AND HELP ME
GET HER OUT OF HERE.
- NO. HAWK--
IF YOU LET HER DIE,
THERE IS NO MAGIC IN THE WORLD
THAT'S GOING TO SAVE YOU.
- NOW GIVE ME THE GUN.
- ALL SHE WANTED...
WAS SOMEBODY
TO CARE ABOUT HER,
SOMEBODY TO WATCH OVER HER.
SOMEBODY DID.
NOW GIVE ME THE GUN.
♪ IT'S REVOLUTION ♪
♪ IN THE TOWN WATCHING IT GROW ♪
♪♪ [ Continues, Indistinct ]
♪ IT'S REVOLUTION ♪
♪ IT'S REVOLUTION ♪♪
MISS PARKER, NOT ONLY HAS JAROD
TOPPED OFF MR. POTATO HEAD
WITH A NICE HAIRPIECE,
I JUST FOUND OUT
THAT THE STAINS ON THE CARDS
WERE MADE BY OYSTERS.
[ Sydney ]
OYSTERS?
MM-HMM.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
JAROD WAS A SLOPPY EATER?
THE RESIDUE WAS LEFT
BY A VERY SPECIFIC SHELLFISH...
FOUND ONLY
IN THE SAN FRANCISCO BAY.
I THINK JAROD WANTED
US TO FIND HIM.
SAN FRANCISCO IS A BIG CITY.
WELL, I STARTED THINKING
ABOUT THE HEAD JAROD LEFT,
SO I SCRAPED SOME OF THE WAX,
AND I HAD IT ANALYZED.
IT IS USED ALMOST EXCLUSIVELY
FOR THE CONSTRUCTION
OF HUMAN REPLICATION.
WAX MUSEUM.
[ Broots ]
TOUCHÉ, SYD.
SO I CALLED THE FRISCO AREA
AND FOUND ONE DEFUNCT
WAX MUSEUM.
AND WHEN I CALLED,
THIS IS WHAT I GOT.
[ Jarod ]
HELLO, SYDNEY, BROOTS,
AND AS ALWAYS, MISS PARKER.
I ASSUME SINCE YOU'RE LISTENING
TO THIS RECORDING,
YOU FIGURED OUT
MY CURRENT LOCATION.
I REALIZE THINGS GOT
A LITTLE FISHY ALONG THE WAY,
BUT YOU REALIZE TIMING
IS EVERYTHING...
IN THE "RUN FOR YOUR LIFE"
BUSINESS.
I WON'T KEEP YOU
LONGER THAN NECESSARY.
I REALIZE YOU HAVE
A PLANE TO CATCH.
I JUST ASK TWO THINGS:
FIRST, BRING ALONG THE WAX HEAD.
I THINK YOU'LL
FIND IT ENLIGHTENING.
AND SECOND, DON'T FORGET
TO BUCKLE YOUR SEAT BELTS.
HAPPY LANDINGS.
- GOOD WORK, BROOTS.
- THANKS, SYDNEY.
LET'S NOT POLISH EACH OTHER'S
DOORKNOBS QUITE YET.
- GET THE JET FIRED UP.
WE'RE GOING TO CALIFORNIA.
- YES, MA'AM.
- BROOTS?
- YES, MA'AM?
- DON'T WEAR THAT SHIRT.
IT MAKES ME NAUSEOUS.
- YES, MA'AM.
IT DOES.
[ Boat Horn Blaring ]
- I HAVE TOLD YOU. HE IS GONE.
- SWEEP IT.
YES, MISS PARKER.
WAS THAT A GUN?
WHO ARE YOU PEOPLE?
YOU WERE SAYING THAT JAROD
HELPED YOU TO
REMODEL THE MUSEUM.
[ Mr. Kleinman ]
AN ARTIST HE IS,
SENT HERE BY THE ANGELS.
- SO I SEE.
- [ Mr. Kleinman ] HE REDESIGNED
THE MOVIE STAR EXHIBIT,
THE PRESIDENTIAL STUDY
AND MY ROSE ROBE.
AND HE EVEN ADDED
A NEW DISPLAY.
JAROD CALLS IT...
CENTRE OF SHAME.
SHOW ME.
I HAVE NO IDEA WHAT
IT IS SUPPOSED TO MEAN,
BUT SOMETHING TELLS ME
YOU WILL.
HEY, IT'S US!
[ Chuckling ]
INCREDIBLY LIFELIKE.
[ Miss Parker ]
IT JUST GETS WEIRDER
AND WEIRDER.
[ Broots ]
UH-OH. THIS CAN'T BE GOOD.
[ Echoing Laughter ]
- I'LL BE DAMNED!
- [ Broots ] WE JUST WITNESSED
OUR OWN EXECUTION.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[ Laughter Continues ]
[ Hawk ]
WELCOME TO THE ANGEL'S FLIGHT.
AS I LOOK AT YOU ALL TONIGHT,
I'M FILLED WITH DIVINE ENERGY.
THE BELIEF IN THE POSSIBILITY
OF THE IMPOSSIBLE.
THAT FAITH IS WHAT SEPARATES
THE LEADERS FROM THE FOLLOWERS,
THE ENLIGHTENED FROM THE BLIND,
THE GODS... FROM THE MORTALS.
WITH YOUR STRENGTH AND SPIRIT,
ALL THINGS ARE POSSIBLE.
[ Jarod ]
LOOKING FOR
YOUR SAFETY LINE, HAWK?
- JAROD.
- YOU SEEM SURPRISED TO SEE ME.
I SAW THE SHIRT.
KESSLER SHOT YOU.
AH-AH-AH.
THE FIRST RULE OF MAGIC:
NEVER BELIEVE WHAT YOU SEE.
HAWK, WHAT'S GOING ON?
IT SEEMS OUR FRIEND HAWK HERE
ISN'T EXACTLY THE MAGIC MAN
HE PRETENDS TO BE.
YOU WANT TO TELL THEM?
OR SHOULD I?
- GO TO HELL.
- YOU FIRST.
WHAT'S THAT?
IT'S YOU. AND YOU.
AND YOU.
IT'S ALL OF YOU.
GO AHEAD. TAKE A LOOK.
HAWK HAD A PERSONAL FILE
ON EACH AND EVERY ONE OF YOU.
HE KNEW WHO YOU WERE,
WHO YOU ARE,
WHERE YOU'RE FROM,
HOW MUCH YOU HAD TO...
OFFER.
HE KNEW YOUR DEEPEST FEARS,
YOUR DARKEST SECRETS.
HE KNEW YOU BETTER
THAN YOU KNEW YOURSELVES.
AND IN RETURN FOR HIS
AMAZING INSIGHTS, YOU GAVE HIM
WHATEVER YOU HAD OF VALUE.
AND WHY NOT?
HE SAW INTO YOUR SOULS, RIGHT?
- WHY?
- MONEY.
UNFORTUNATELY, NOT ALL OF YOU
WERE SO EASILY LED.
THAT'S WHY YOU
KILLED JESSE BRACKEN.
SHE STUMBLED
ONTO YOUR COMPUTER ROOM,
DISCOVERED YOUR LITTLE SCAM.
AND THAT'S IT.
SHE HAD TO GO.
SO YOU DRAGGED HER UP HERE
AND YOU THREW HER OFF THE ROOF.
- YOU CAN'T PROVE ANYTHING.
- CAN'T I?
NEXT TIME YOU TOSS SOMEONE
OFF A BUILDING,
YOU'D BETTER MAKE DAMN SURE
YOU CLEAN UP AFTER YOURSELF.
SO, YOU STILL THINK...
THAT YOU'RE WORTHY TO FLY
WITH THE ANGELS, HAWK?
OR IS THIS JUST
A PATHETIC CURTAIN CALL
OF A HALF-BAKED MAGIC SHOW?
WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
DIVINE INTERVENTION?
[ Hawk ]
MY FINAL GIFT TO YOU.
SON OF A BITCH!
YOU KILLED HIM!
[ Jarod ]
AH-AH-AH.
REMEMBER WHAT I TOLD YOU?
THE FIRST RULE OF MAGIC:
NEVER BELIEVE WHAT YOU SEE.
I HATE TO SAY IT,
BUT JAROD HAS ME STUMPED
THIS TIME.
THERE MUST BE SOMETHING
THAT WE'RE NOT SEEING.
[ Broots ]
EYES, NOSE, EARS, MOUTH.
IT ALL SEEMS TO BE THERE.
SEE NO EVIL, HEAR NO EVIL,
SPEAK NO EVIL.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT MEANS,
BUT IT GIVES ME A BAD FEELING.
- GOOD. YOU'RE ALL STILL HERE.
- WHERE ELSE?
AS YOU MAY OR MAY NOT KNOW,
THE TRIUMVIRATE HAS DECIDED...
TO BECOME MORE HANDS-ON
IN THE PURSUIT OF JAROD.
AND IN AN EFFORT TO PROTECT
THE INTEGRITY OF THEIR PURSUIT,
AN ELEMENT HAS BEEN ADDED
TO ACT AS A SAFEGUARD,
OR A SAFETY NET,
IF YOU WILL.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST SAY IT?
A NEW PLAYER.
YOU CAN THINK OF HIM
AS A ONE-MAN
INTERNAL AFFAIRS DIVISION.
MR. COX.
- COX?
- IT'S WITH AN "X."
[ Chuckles ]
I HOPE WE GET TO KNOW EACH OTHER
BETTER IN THE COMING DAYS.
- NO DOUBT.
- I HATE TO BE RUDE,
BUT WE REALLY HAVE TO LEAVE
IF WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THAT NEXT APPOINTMENT.
THAT ANSWERS THAT.
BRINGS US TO A BIGGER QUESTION.
WHO IS MR. COX?
JAROD ALREADY ANSWERED THAT.
HE'S THE GRIM REAPER.
- HI.
- HEY, DETECTIVE WAXMAN. I WAS
HOPING WE'D SEE YOU AGAIN.
I WAS ON MY WAY OUT OF TOWN,
AND I THOUGHT I WOULD
STOP BY AND SAY GOOD-BYE.
YOU LOOK GOOD.
THE DOCTOR SAID IT'S A MIRACLE
SHE WASN'T KILLED.
MY DAD SAYS
THAT YOU SAVED MY LIFE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO THANK YOU.
SEEING YOU SITTING THERE SMILING
IS THANKS ENOUGH.
THEY SAID THE MAN THAT DID THIS
CONFESSED TO RUNNING THE SCAM
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
IT'S GOOD TO KNOW HE WON'T BE
HURTING ANYBODY ELSE'S CHILDREN.
DETECTIVE,
I KNOW IT'S NOT THE SAME
AS SAVING YOUR LIFE,
BUT I THOUGHT MAYBE
YOU'D LIKE TO HAVE THIS.
IT HELPED KEEP ME SAFE.
I HOPE IT'LL DO
THE SAME FOR YOU.
I'LL KEEP IT CLOSE.
THANK YOU.
BYE.