AT LEAST JAROD COULD HAVE LED US
TO A PLACE NEAR THE STRIP,
THEN I COULD HAVE
HIT THE CRAPS TABLE.
[ Clears Throat ]
WELL, HIT THIS INSTEAD:
SINGLE MALT, LIKE YOU ASKED FOR.
AND YOU'RE FORGETTING SOMETHING.
JAROD DIDN'T LEAD US HERE.
HIS FRIEND TOLD HIM
TO STAY HERE IN AN E-MAIL
I INTERCEPTED.
HE'S BEEN COMPROMISED THIS TIME,
AND HE'S GONNA WALK RIGHT INTO
OUR HANDS.
MY HANDS.
NOW GO TO YOUR ROOM.
OH, THIS IS MY ROOM. OUR ROOM.
THIS IS THE HONEYMOON SUITE.
NOT EVEN AFTER FOUR OF THESE.
OH, NO, NO. MISS PARKER,
IT'S PERFECT.
WHY DO YOU THINK SYDNEY AND
LYLE ARE COMING TOMORROW?
IF JAROD CAME HERE...
AND HE SAW A WOMAN AND THREE MEN
ON THE REGISTER, WELL, HE'D--
HE'D KNOW WE'RE HERE.
THIS WAY, IF--
IF YOU AND I PRETEND...
TO BE THE HONEYMOON COUPLE,
WELL, HE'D BE NONE THE WISER.
- THIS WAS YOUR IDEA.
- YEAH.
I MEAN, IT'S A GOOD ONE,
ISN'T IT? NOBODY'D
BELIEVE YOU AND SYD.
HE'S-- HE'S MIDDLE-AGED,
AND HE'S FLEMISH.
AND YOU, YOU'RE YOUNG AND--
UNLESS YOU THINK THAT YOU'D
RATHER ROOM WITH LYLE.
CENTRE'S A SICK PLACE BUT--
BUT YOUR OWN BROTHER?
RELAX, ROMEO.
THAT'S AS FAR AS I GO.
TAKE FIRST WATCH. ANYBODY
PULLS INTO THAT PARKING LOT,
SEND UP A FLARE.
OKAY.
BROOTS?
FALL ASLEEP, IT'LL BE
A HELL OF A WEDDING NIGHT.
[ No Audible Music ]
[ Bird Chirping In Distance ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Murmurs,
Clears Throat ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Sighs ]
[ Jarod Narrating ]
WELCOME TO SIN CITY--
LAS VEGAS, NEVADA.
A PRETENDER COULD WIN BIG HERE--
SOME OTHER PRETENDER.
I'VE BEEN ROLLING NOTHING
BUT SNAKE EYES.
I SHOULD BE HAVING SOME FUN
IN THE SUN, AND ALL I GOT IS...
FROSTBITE.
THEY SAY LUCK IS A LADY.
THAT MUST BE GOOD LUCK.
[ Shivering ]
- BAD LUCK IS DEFINITELY A MAN,
AND HE DRESSES FUNNY.
- [ Teeth Chattering ]
ARGYLE TRIED
TO SELL ME TO THE CENTRE
A COUPLE OF YEARS BACK.
LAST YEAR HE ALMOST
GOT ME KILLED.
- [ Sneezes ]
- WHY SHOULD THIS YEAR
BE ANY DIFFERENT?
- [ Whimpers ]
- SOME DAYS IT DOESN'T PAY
TO ANSWER YOUR E-MAIL.
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
- [ Miss Parker ] HE DEFENDS
THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
- [ Jarod ] LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
[ Jarod Narrating ]
LOOK AT ME. SOME GENIUS.
I WISH I COULD PRETEND MYSELF
INTO SOME LONG JOHNS.
BUT IN MY OWN DEFENSE,
THIS ALL STARTED WHEN ARGYLE
DECIDED TO BECOME A PRETENDER.
AS USUAL, HIS MOUTH
WAS WRITING CHECKS
HIS BRAIN COULDN'T CASH.
HELLO?
HA! PREPARE TO DIE,
YOU MAMALUKE. OW! OOH!
AH! HEY! HEY!
[ Grunts ]
- J-MAN! YOU MADE IT.
- ARGYLE, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M SORRY, J-DOG.
YOU SAW THE DOOR.
THIS IS A DANGEROUS BUSINESS.
AND WHEN YOU'RE THE MAC DADDY
OF PRIVATE DICKS,
THE FLYIN' MONKEYS--
ALL THEY WANNA DO IS PUT YOU ON
THE NIGHT TRAIN TO EMERALD CITY.
YOU'RE LUCKY YOU DIDN'T GET YOUR
TICKET PUNCHED, RICHARD DIXON,
PRIVATE INVESTIGATOR.
- OH, NO. I AIN'T DICK DIXON.
I'M HIS PARTNER.
- SO WHY DID YOU E-MAIL ME?
WHY DON'T YOU GET HIM
TO HELP YOU?
OH. WELL, YOU SEE,
THIS AIN'T DOUBLE "D'S"
KIND OF GIG.
THIS IS WHAT WE
IN THE INDUSTRY CALL
A "MULTIFACETAL" TYPE THING.
SEE, THERE'S A LOT
OF CROSS-PURPOSING ENTITIES,
MULTICULTURAL...
PURPOSES, YOU KNOW--
ALL OF THAT AND WHATNOT.
- GOOD-BYE, ARGYLE.
- NO, NO, NO! WAIT! J-DOG.
J-DOG. YOU CAN'T LEAVE ME.
YOU CAN'T LEAVE.
YOU'RE ALL I GOT, MAN.
I'M IN TROUBLE, JAROD. PLEASE.
[ Jarod Narrating ]
RAYMOND CHANDLER HAD A SECRET
FOR WRITING DETECTIVE STORIES.
"WHEN IN DOUBT," HE SAID,
"HAVE SOMEBODY ENTER THE ROOM
WITH A GUN."
OKAY, IT'S AN ICE-CREAM CONE.
BUT IT WAS PISTACHIO,
AND I'M ALLERGIC TO PISTACHIOS.
- YOU DICK DIXON?
- ME? NO. I'M HIS PARTNER.
THAT'S DICK DIXON.
- OH! OW!
- THINK THAT HURT?
TASTE THIS.
[ Jarod Narrating ]
LET'S CALL THIS STORY
"DEATH BY DOUBLE DIP."
NOW, OUR PISTACHIO-PACKING
FRIEND WILL HAVE TO WAIT,
SINCE THE PRETENDER
IS NOW DICK DIXON, PRIVATE EYE.
LET ME GIVE YOU THE SKINNY.
ARGYLE'S NEW JOB WAS ANOTHER
EPIC WORK OF FICTION.
DICK DIXON
ISN'T EVEN AROUND ANYMORE.
HE SKIPPED TOWN LAST YEAR
BURIED IN DEBT.
ARGYLE HAD ONLY BECOME
HIS PARTNER A WEEK EARLIER.
HE WAS WORKING THE BUILDING
AS A "HOSPITALITY TECHNICIAN."
AND THAT'S WHAT HE CALLED IT.
I CALL IT "JANITOR."
HE HAPPENED TO BE SCRUBBING
DICK DIXON'S ABANDONED OFFICE
WHEN... SHE WALKED IN.
I'M LOOKING FOR DICK?
EXCUSE ME?
- YOU KNOW-- DICK.
- DICK?
- DICK DIXON?
- OH. OH. DICK DIXON.
UH, YEAH.
UM, NO. HE'S GONE.
- GONE?
- YEAH. HE TOOK
THE SLOW BOAT TO CHINA.
WASTIN' AWAY IN MARGARITAVILLE--
THAT KIND OF THING.
- DO YOU WORK FOR HIM?
- DO I WORK FOR HIM?
- YEAH.
I AM HIS NOM DE PLUME.
I'M HIS COUP DE GRÂCE.
I AM HIS COMRADE-IN-ARMS,
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
- I AM HIS PARTNER,
FOR PETE'S SAKE.
- UM, YOU DO HIS DIRTY WORK?
THAT'S FUNNY.
THIS MOP-- YOU SEE--
I'M UNDERCOVER.
I'M WHAT WE IN THE INDUSTRY CALL
THE "CLANDESTINAL" PARTNER.
WHATEVER DICK WANTS,
ARGYLE GETS DICK.
"ARGYLE."
THAT'S AN INTERESTING NAME.
YEAH. MY PARENTS GAVE IT TO ME
ON ACCOUNT OF MY BIRTHMARK.
HEY, WOULD YOU LIKE
TO SEE MY BIRTHMARK?
- NO.
- OH, NO. I'M SORRY. I--
- [ Sobs ]
- I GET THAT A LOT. PLEASE DON'T
CRY. I HATE TO SEE A GIRL CRY.
HERE. TAKE THIS.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
- SAY, WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
- MONA.
- LIKE THE LISA?
- YEAH.
- THAT'S VERY BEAUTIFUL.
- [ Blows Nose Loudly ]
LISTEN, MONA.
I CAN HELP. TALK TO ME.
WELL, I'M A SHOWGIRL
DOWN AT THE CLUB ALI BAR,
AND MY BOSS IS IN TROUBLE.
TROUBLE?
WHAT'S YOUR BOSS'S NAME?
- DIRTY WILLY.
- HE DOESN'T BATHE?
NO. PEOPLE JUST CALL HIM THAT.
HE'S A GOOD MAN, TAKES CARE
OF US, AND ALL THE GIRLS
HAVE COMPREHENSIVE DENTAL.
- WOW. THAT'S KEY.
- AND THIS BUCKET OF QUARTERS
IS ALL HE'S GOT LEFT.
AND HE TOLD ME
TO GIVE THIS TO MR. DIXON.
OKAY.
I WILL GET THIS
TO MR. DIXON.
WILLY KNOWS THINGS,
MR. ARGYLE--
OH, YEAH?
THINGS THAT HE SHOULDN'T KNOW.
HE NEEDS PROTECTION.
CONSIDER IT DONE,
MS. LISA.
ARGYLE IS ON THE CASE.
[ Giggles ]
[ Jarod Narrating ]
"ARGYLE IS ON THE CASE"--
FIVE WORDS TO SEND A CHILL
DOWN YOUR SPINE.
ARGYLE EMBRACED THE CLICHÉ,
CASTING HIMSELF IN
THE STARRING ROLE...
OF A BIG-TIME PRIVATE EYE
EXTRAORDINAIRE.
DETERMINED TO HELP MONA,
HE MADE HIS WAY BACK
INTO THE CLUB ALI BAR...
AND, LIKE A TRUE DETECTIVE,
WAS LOOKING FOR CLUES--
ANYTHING HE COULD FIND
THAT WOULD LEAD HIM TO WHERE
OR WHAT HAPPENED TO DIRTY WILLY.
BUT HE WASN'T READY
TO BE A STAR.
AS SOON AS THINGS GOT REAL,
ARGYLE WISHED HE'D TAKEN
A BIT PART.
[ Argyle Gasps ]
DIRTY WILLY.
HE'D DONE THE JOB,
SOLVED THE CASE.
HE HAD THE KILLER CORNERED.
- SO ARGYLE DID
WHAT ARGYLE DOES BEST.
- [ Gasps ]
- HE NEVER SAW THE HIT MAN.
WHO COULD AT THAT SPEED?
- WOAH!
HE WAS PRETTY SURE
THE KILLER DIDN'T SEE HIM--
PRETTY SURE.
WHICH BRINGS US BACK
TO OUR PISTACHIO-PACKIN' PORKER.
HE WAS WONDERING
THE SAME THING AS ME.
- WHERE THE HELL IS MONA?
- WELL, I-I-I DON'T KNOW.
SHE TOLD ME SHE WAS COMIN'
TO SEE YOU, DIXON.
AND NOW SHE'S GONE?
- DID SHE SAY
WHERE SHE WAS GOIN'?
- SHE HASN'T TOLD ME ANYTHING.
- DID SHE LEAVE ANYTHING?
- LOOK. NORMALLY, I DON'T TALK
TO GUN-WIELDING THUGS.
YEAH. YOUR MAMA MUST BE
REAL PROUD OF YOU NOW,
EH, BIG BOY?
NO. SHE'D PROBABLY
GIVE ME A LICKIN'.
MY MAMA'S DEAD.
TRUTH IS, I'M NOT A THUG.
MY NAME IS MIKE.
I'M MONA'S BROTHER.
- OH. HI, MIKE.
- HI.
[ Sighs ] IT JUST AIN'T LIKE HER
NOT TO CHECK IN. OUR PARENTS
DIED WHEN WE WERE REAL LITTLE,
AND I MADE A PROMISE TO MOM
THAT I'D TAKE CARE OF MONA.
- I JUST GOTTA KNOW
IF SHE'S OKAY.
- [ Sighs ]
YOU WILL. JUST AS SOON
AS WE FIND OUT ANYTHING,
YOU'LL BE THE FIRST TO KNOW.
I PROMISE.
RIGHT, PARTNER?
YEAH.
DICK DIXON IS ON THE CASE,
KICKIN' TAIL AND TAKIN' NAMES.
YOU ARE MR. POSITIVI-TIVITY,
THE SHAH OF "I CAN."
HEY, NOW. SWELL RIDE.
LIKE I ALWAYS SAY,
PRIVATE DICK'S GOTTA
HAVE A RAGTOP.
- YOU ARE NOT GOING.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
I AM NOT A DETECTIVE. YOU ARE
NOT MY PARTNER. IF I'M GOING
TO HELP, YOU STAY OUTTA MY WAY.
THAT WAS
EXTREMELY HOSTILE.
I CAN'T KEEP SAVING YOUR LIFE
IF YOU KEEP LYING YOURSELF
INTO A CORNER.
YOU HAVE TO THINK.
[ Engine Starts ]
HEY!
[ Engine Stops ]
I'VE BEEN THINKIN'.
I WAS UPSIDE, INSIDE OUT,
LIVIN' LA VIDA LOCA
TILL I MET YOU.
NOW AFTER YOU HELPED ME
AND POP LAST YEAR, I'M MENDIN'
MY WICKED WAYS, YOU KNOW.
I AIN'T HAD NOTHIN'
BUT HONEST JOBS SINCE.
ONLY THING MISSIN'
IS THE LOVE OF MY LIFE.
AND I MET HER LAST WEEK.
- MONA'S THE ONE.
- YOU SPENT SIX MINUTES
WITH HER.
360 GLORIOUS SECONDS,
J-MAN. SOMETHIN' HAPPENED
BETWEEN US, I'M TELLIN' YA.
IT WAS LIKE "ELECTRONICAL"
CHEMICALS OR SOMETHING.
PHEROMONES, BABY,
I'M TELLIN' YA.
AND NOW MY FUTURE
BROTHER-IN-LAW'S WEEPIN'
IN HIS PISTACHIO.
YOU GOTTA LET ME
COME WITH YOU, J-STER.
YOU GOTTA LET ME HELP HER.
J-MAN. J-DOG.
PLEASE, I'M BEGGIN' YA.
PLEASE, PLEASE, PLEASE,
PLEASE, PLEASE.
THERE ARE CERTAIN TIMES IN LIFE
WHEN YOU NEED TO THINK WITH
YOUR HEART, NOT YOUR HEAD.
THIS WASN'T ONE OF THOSE TIMES,
BUT I THOUGHT IT WAS,
SO I MADE THE FOLLOWING MISTAKE.
PLEASE?
GET IN.
YEAH, YEAH.
[ Engine Starts ]
ARGYLE IS ON THE CASE.
COME ON!
HOW DID I GET IN THIS NIGHTMARE?
WELL, I-I REMEMBER
I WAS WATCHING OUT
FOR JAROD,
AND YOU LOOKED AT ME WITH
BEDROOM EYES, LIKE YOU WANTED
TO DO THE LATE-NIGHT CREEP.
I DID NOT. WE DID NOT.
WELL, HOW CAN YOU BE SURE,
MISS PARKER?
FOR STARTERS,
PIGS AREN'T FLYING,
HELL HASN'T FROZEN OVER,
AND YOU'RE NOT
THE LAST MAN ON EARTH.
[ Rings ]
- WHAT?
- HOW'S THE STAKEOUT GOING?
SYDNEY, HOW ARE YOU?
I... AM FINE.
SWEEPER TEAM SAYS
YOU HAVEN'T REPORTED IN.
HUH. SOMETHING CAME UP.
I... OVERSLEPT, BUT--
BUT I WAS JUST GETTING DRESSED.
I'LL BE THERE TOMORROW
WITH LYLE AND RAINES.
PARKER, IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
I AM ROLLING NOTHING BUT SEVENS.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Quietly ]
YOU SO MUCH AS HINT AT THIS
WHEN THEY ARRIVE,
I WILL AMPUTATE YOUR HEAD.
- WELL, WHAT ABOUT THIS?
- THERE IS NO "THIS."
NOTHING HAPPENED,
BROOTS.
LIKE I SAID, IT WAS A NIGHTMARE,
AND I'M GLAD I WOKE UP.
WHEN YOU SAY THINGS LIKE THAT,
DO YOU EVEN CONSIDER
MY FEELINGS?
WHAT IS IT ABOUT ME
THAT YOU FIND SO REPULSIVE?
YOU REALLY WANT TO KNOW?
YES. I REALLY
WANT TO KNOW.
OKAY.
NOW YOU SHUT UP
AND LISTEN.
WHAT I FIND SO UTTERLY
UNINSPIRING ABOUT YOU...
IS YOUR IDEA OF RISK
IS TO GO WITHOUT DEODORANT.
WHEN THE BULLETS STOP FLYING,
YOU'RE ALWAYS THE ONE
SHAKING IN THE CORNER.
THAT, IN THE GAME OF LIFE,
IS SECOND STRING.
AND I DON'T WANT
NO SCRUBS.
HEY. STOP, AND LET ME TELL
YOU SOMETHING, AND YOU--
YOU SHUT UP AND LISTEN.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I HAVE NEVER TAKEN A RISK.
BECAUSE THE WHOLE TIME
I'VE KNOWN YOU, I'VE ONLY
WANTED TO TAKE JUST ONE.
WHICH ONE WOULD THAT BE?
YOU'RE IN YOUR OFFICE.
IT'S LATE, AND I SNEAK IN.
IN ONE HAND I HAVE GARDENIAS,
AND IN THE OTHER I HAVE
A BOTTLE OF SINGLE MALT--
TWO OF YOUR FAVORITE THINGS
IN THE WORLD.
AND I FIND THAT LITTLE SPOT
ON THE NAPE OF YOUR NECK,
AND I JUST...
RUB IT THE RIGHT WAY...
TO GET RID OF THAT MIGRAINE
YOU ALWAYS GET ABOUT
6:20 EVERY NIGHT--
THE ONE YOU NEVER TELL
ANYONE ABOUT.
THE TRUTH IS,
IF I HAD JUST ONE SHOT,
YOU KNOW WHAT I'D DO?
I WOULD TAKE YOUR PAIN AWAY.
TRUTH IS, YOU'D BE LUCKY
TO GET A SCRUB LIKE ME.
- DO YOU HEAR THAT, BROOTS?
- WHAT?
PIGS ARE FLYING.
[ Man Singing Slow Jazz ]
♪ SO BABY, SAY YOU WILL ♪
♪ NO NEED TO TELL ♪
♪ NO REASON TO DENY IT ♪♪
[ Both Moaning ]
[ Miss Parker Squeals, Giggles ]
[ Jarod Narrating ]
LIFE IS STRANGE.
ONE HOUR IN THE NEVADA SUN, AND
I HAD MORE UNANSWERED QUESTIONS
THAN THE WARREN COMMISSION.
♪♪ [ Continues ]
THERE WAS DIRTY WILLY'S
MURDER TO SOLVE...
AND MONA,
THE MISSING SHOWGIRL,
TO TRACK DOWN.
BUT ARGYLE HAD TO SEE
HIS FATHER, BENNY.
THE OLD MAN USED TO BE OBSESSED
WITH THE POPE. I WAS ABOUT
TO FIND OUT HE CONVERTED.
WAYNE NEWTON IS MORE
THAN A HOLY MAN.
HE IS THE SHAMAN OF THE STRIP.
HE'S THE DUKE OF DOWNTOWN.
- WAYNE NEWTON
IS LAS VEGAS.
- IF YOU SAY SO.
YOU KNOW, I MET HIM ONCE,
SORT OF?
MY ADELLA AND I, UH,
SAW HIM IN VEGAS LONG AGO.
WHO'D HAVE THOUGHT
I'D BE BACK HERE IN VEGAS
WITH ARGYLE...
LIVIN' IN THIS
EXQUISITE GOLF VILLA?
[ Man, In Distance ]
FORE!
DRIVING RANGE IS OPEN.
[ Man ]
SORRY.
YEAH. THE ONLY ONE MISSIN'
IS MY ADELLA.
THIS WEEK WOULD'VE BEEN
OUR 50th ANNIVERSARY.
SHE WAS MY INSPIRATION, JAROD.
SHE'S THE REASON I'M WRITIN'
A SONG FOR WAYNE.
- HEY, POP, WE--
WE DON'T HAVE TIME FOR THAT.
- OH, SURE WE DO.
THE BIG "W,"
HE CHANGED OUR LIVES,
SO MY ADELLA SUGGESTED THAT
I SHOULD WRITE HIM A SONG,
SORT OF A COMPANION PIECE
TO "DANKE SCHOEN."
SHE SAID,
"CALL IT 'AUF WIEDERSEHEN,'"
AND HERE GOES NOTHING.
♪♪ [ Introduction ]
♪♪ [ Ends ]
- WHERE'S THE SONG?
- IT'S STILL A WORK IN PROGRESS.
IT'LL BE READY BY TOMORROW.
- WHAT'S HAPPENING TOMORROW?
- UH, WAYNE IS PLAYIN'
IN A CHARITY TOURNAMENT,
AND HE WILL BE
RIGHT THERE PUTTING,
AND I WILL BE
RIGHT HERE STANDING--
♪ WHEN I HIT HIM
WITH THE RAZZAMATAZZ ♪
YOU KNOW, I'VE NEVER
ACTUALLY PLAYED GOLF, BUT, UM,
WON'T THAT DISTURB HIS GAME?
OH, YEAH.
WELL, YEAH, BUT IT'S WORTH IT
FOR MY ADELLA'S LAST WISH,
ISN'T IT?
IT'S MORE THAN WORTH IT.
YEAH. GOOD.
AND THE BIG "W"
WILL LOVE IT, POP,
BUT WE GOTTA GET OUT OF HERE.
WE GOTTA CATCH OURSELVES
A KILLER.
I GOT ME A SONG
TO WRITE.
CATCH YOU LATER, POP.
[ Jarod Narrating ]
IT WAS NICE TO SEE BENNY AGAIN,
BUT ARGYLE WAS RIGHT.
WE DID HAVE A KILLER
TO CATCH. SO WE WENT BACK
TO THE SCENE OF THE CRIME.
OKAY.
UH, DIRTY WILLY BOUGHT IT
RIGHT ABOUT HERE,
AND I SAW THE KILLER
STANDING RIGHT OVER THERE.
HEY, FUNNY FACE,
THIS AREA'S OFF LIMITS,
ALL RIGHT?
I GOT TOP-NOTCH TALENT
MAKIN' THEIR WAY THROUGH HERE...
TO THE MOST GLORIOUS STAGE
IN LAS VEGAS,
AND I CAN'T HAVE YOU
OR THAT THING YOU CALL A SUIT
IN THE WAY.
-LET ME EXPLAIN.
-NO. THERE'S NO EXPLAININ'
THAT, AND WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
- MY NAME IS DICK DIXON.
- YOU'RE DICK DIXON?
- OH!
- YOU SLEPT WITH MY WIFE,
YOU SCUMBALL!
- I DON'T EVEN KNOW YOUR WIFE.
- THRIFTY SUITES, NUMBER 38.
RING A BELL, PUMPKIN?
HEY, HEY, HEY, HALF-PINT,
THIS AIN'T ABOUT YOUR OLD LADY
GIVIN' ROOM SERVICE, ALL RIGHT?
WE'RE TRYIN' TO FIND
MONA JEFFRIES.
YEAH, WELL, I AIN'T SEEN HER.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
ABOUT IT, TOUGH GUY?
[ Yelps ]
YOU SEE THAT?
THERE GOES MY CHIVAS.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN
HOW TO DO THAT?
I RAN A DOJO ONCE.
NOW TELL US WHAT YOU KNOW.
OKAY. I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I TOLD THE COPS, ALL RIGHT?
MONA AIN'T YOUR TYPICAL
SHOWGIRL, ALL RIGHT? SHE--
SHE WON'T SHOW HER CONES,
AND SHE SAVES HER DOUGH.
[ Yelps ]
- SHE BOUGHT A CONDO
OUTSIDE OF TOWN.
- WHERE?
[ Yelps ]
OKAY! GOD!
I'LL TELL YA! GEEZ!
I GOT YOUR BACK, J-MAN.
OH, THAT'S VERY COMFORTING.
EITHER MY MONA'S REAL MESSY,
J-MAN, OR SOMETHIN' REAL BAD
HAPPENED TO HER.
YOU CAN STOP RIGHT THERE.
LET'S SEE SOME I.D.
- THE I.D.'S OUT IN THE CAR.
MY NAME IS DICK DIXON.
- YOU'RE DICK DIXON?
- YES.
- YOU SLEPT WITH ONE
OF OUR DEPUTIES.
SHE LEFT THE FORCE
'CAUSE OF YOU.
I SEEM TO HAVE
THAT EFFECT ON PEOPLE.
- WHAT HAPPENED HERE?
- BEEN A WHILE SINCE YOU CRACKED
YOUR DETECTIVE HANDBOOK, HUH?
WE GOT A REPORT OF
A DISTURBANCE. DOOR WAS JIMMIED,
PLACE HAD BEEN TRASHED,
BUT HER CAR KEYS, PURSE
AND VALUABLES ARE STILL HERE.
- MONA WAS LEAVING?
- NO. SHE WAS KIDNAPPED.
[ Knocking ]
- YOU GONNA GET THAT?
- [ Knocking Continues ]
THOSE ARE
THE LATE-NIGHT CREEPERS.
IT IS THE HONEYMOON SUITE.
[ Knocking ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Faucet Turns, Water Running ]
[ Martial Arts Grunts ]
[ Imitating Elvis ]
OH, YEAH.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
OH, SYD. YOU'RE HERE EARLY.
[ Clears Throat ]
I THOUGHT SOMETHING WAS WRONG.
[ Water Running Continues ]
OH, NO. NO.
NO. AS A MATTER OF FACT,
THINGS ARE GONNA BE DIFFERENT
FROM NOW ON.
[ Water Stops ]
BROOTS, YOU ARE GONNA PAY FOR...
USING ALL THE HOT WATER,
YOU MORON!
YOU WERE SAYING, BROOTS?
SYD, PLEASE TELL ME
YOU'RE HERE TO RELIEVE ME.
BEING COOPED UP
WITH FELIX UNGAR HERE MAKES ME
GLAD TO SEE YOUR SORRY MUG.
LYLE AND I
ARE REGISTERED
AT CAESARS.
SEPARATE ROOMS?
WELL, SEPARATE SUITES.
[ Scoffs ]
[ Sydney ]
LYLE WILL BE HERE LATER.
PERHAPS WE CAN TAKE OVER.
HOPEFULLY, I WON'T HAVE
PLUGGED BROOTS BEFORE THEN.
CALL ME WHEN HE GETS HERE.
- WHAT?
- I THOUGHT THINGS WERE GONNA
BE DIFFERENT BETWEEN US.
THERE IS NO "US."
AT LEAST...
NOT THAT THEY KNOW OF.
COULD YOU IMAGINE
WHAT THEY WOULD DO
IF THEY KNEW?
RIGHT. RIGHT. WE DON'T--
WE DON'T WANNA GIVE THEM
ANY AMMUNITION, NOW DO WE?
SPEAKING OF WHICH,
MY CLIP IS EMPTY.
OH, YEAH.
I GET IT, BABY.
BUT IF WE'RE GONNA DO THIS--
[ Whispering ]
WE GOTTA DO IT RIGHT.
I'VE ALWAYS HAD A LITTLE FANTASY
I WANT TO LIVE OUT WITH YOU.
BUT FIRST I WANT YOU
TO CALL ME...
"PUFF DADDY."
SAY IT.
PUFF--
[ Inhales ]
DADDY.
OH!
[ Sighs ]
- ♪♪ [ Soul, Slow ]
WELCOME TO STATION WEFUNK--
- [ Lip-synching ]
[ Continues Lip-synching ]
BETTER KNOWN AS "WE-FUNK,"
OR DEEPER STILL,
"THE MOTHER SHIP CONNECTION,"
HOME OF THE EXTRATERRESTRIAL
BROTHERS,
DEALERS OF FUNKY MUSIC,
"P" FUNK,
UNCUT FUNK, THE BOMB.
♪ MAKE MY FUNK
THE "P" FUNK ♪
♪ I WANT THE FUNK UNCUT ♪
♪ OH, MAKE MY FUNK
THE "P" FUNK ♪
♪ I WANTS TO GET FUNKED UP ♪
♪ HIM, I WANT THE BOMB
I WANT THE "P" FUNK, Y'ALL ♪
♪ DON'T WANT MY FUNK
STEPPED ON ♪
♪ MAKE MY FUNK THE "P" FUNK ♪
HOME OF
THE EXTRATERRESTRIAL BROTHERS.
♪ BEFORE I TAKE IT HOME ♪♪
♪♪ [ Saxophone ]
GETTIN' DEEP.
♪♪ [ Saxophone Continues ]
ONCE UPON A TIME
CALLED "RIGHT NOW."
[ Jarod Narrating ]
THEY SAY THAT LIFE
IS STRANGER THAN FICTION.
MINE CERTAINLY HAS BEEN,
AND THIS WAS NO EXCEPTION.
MONA WAS KIDNAPPED,
BUT BY WHOM?
WHATEVER TROUBLE HER BOSS,
DIRTY WILLY, FOUND,
IT HAD CERTAINLY FOUND HER,
AND IT WAS ONLY A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE IT FOUND US.
I DID WHAT SYNDEY
ALWAYS TAUGHT ME: WHEN IN DOUBT,
GO BACK TO THE EVIDENCE.
A COUPLE OF THINGS
JUST DON'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
ACCORDING TO THE AUTOPSY REPORT,
WHAT KILLED DIRTY WILLY
WAS LOW LEVELS OF OXYGEN
IN HIS TISSUES...
DUE TO HYPOTHERMIA--
EXTREME COLD.
HE FROZE TO DEATH.
IN VEGAS?
AND HE HAD SEVERAL
ICE PICK HOLES IN HIS HANDS.
I'M THINKIN' TORTURE.
WAIT A SECOND, J-MAN.
YOU DON'T THINK
WHO'S EVER DOIN' THIS
MIGHT, YOU KNOW,
POKE MONA LIKE THAT?
LET'S HOPE NOT.
ACCORDING TO THIS FILE,
HE IS THE NUMBER ONE SUSPECT:
CONSTANTIN FALZONE--
AN EXTORTIONIST
FOR THE POSAVAC CRIME FAMILY.
WHAT OTHER PART
OF YOUR TWO-PLUS-TWO CASE
DON'T ADD UP TO FOUR?
[ Jarod ]
DIRTY WILLY WEIGHED
OVER 300 POUNDS.
FROZEN OR NOT,
THAT'S A LOT OF WILLY
FOR ONE MAN TO CARRY AROUND.
- WAIT.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYIN', "J"?
- THERE WERE TWO KILLERS...
WHO TORTURED DIRTY WILLY
AND FROZE HIM TO DEATH.
QUESTION IS,
WHAT DID THEY WANT OUT OF HIM?
[ Exhales ]
THAT'S EASY, BABY--
CASH, DO-RE-MI, J-MAN.
EVERYBODY KNOWS FALZONE
COLLECTS AROUND TOWN,
SO MAYBE DIRTY WILLY
COULDN'T COME UP
WITH THE GREEN,
AND THE TWINS
GET P.O.'d WITH HIM.
- TWINS?
- FALZONE'S GOT THESE
FRIGIDAIRES THAT WORK FOR HIM.
CALLS 'EM
HIS CADDIES.
CADDIES? WHY?
[ Jarod Narrating ]
FALZONE-- SIN CITY OLD-TIMER.
DOESN'T CARE ABOUT
SHOPPING MALLS, PIRATE SHIPS OR
THE EIFFEL TOWER IN THE DESERT.
HE'S ONLY INTERESTED IN CASH...
AND A THREE HANDICAP.
J-ROD, THOSE TWO GOONS
KILLED DIRTY WILLY
AND KIDNAPPED MY MONA.
I SAY WE WASTE 'EM
AND SNAG FALZONE.
NO. WE MEET FALZONE
OUT THERE ON HIS OWN TURF.
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW
HOW TO PLAY.
IT'S ALL GEOMETRY
AND PHYSICS.
HOW HARD COULD THAT BE?
[ Narrating ] SYDNEY ALWAYS
TAUGHT ME, THE MOST DIFFICULT
PRETENDS HAVE AN INNER SECRET.
ONCE YOU REVEAL THAT SECRET,
IT COMES NATURALLY.
[ Club Hits Bushes ]
[ Bird Squawking ]
[ Dog Barks ]
IN 56 MINUTES,
I FOUND THE SECRET
TO A PERFECT GOLF GAME.
I'LL SHARE IT WITH YOU SOMETIME.
THE TWINS WERE IMPRESSED,
JUST LIKE I SAID.
FALZONE WANTED TO TAKE ME ON.
THEN I TOLD THEM
I WAS DICK DIXON.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
GUESS WHICH ONE'S MARRIED.
THE TWINS PROMISED
TO GET US TO FALZONE,
WHICH THEY DID.
HOWEVER, IN TRUE CHANDLERESQUE
FASHION, WE FOUND OUT
IT WAS WITH A TWIST.
SOMEONE ELSE
HAD GOTTEN TO HIM FIRST.
AND TO THINK
I WASTED 56 MINUTES.
RAYMOND CHANDLER ALWAYS SAID,
"THE BEST WAY TO GET A READER'S
ATTENTION IS WITH A DEAD BODY."
BUT OF COURSE, CHANDLER
WASN'T WRITING THIS ONE.
[ Gasping ]
I GOT BALLS!
[ Splashing ]
I GOT BALLS.
UNBE-FRIGGIN-LIEVABLE.
PEOPLE ACTUALLY
THROW THESE AWAY.
AND THAT MAKES THEM YOURS.
POSSESSION IS 9/10ths.
YOU OUGHTA KNOW.
I HEAR DICK DIXON STEALS WIVES.
AND I HEAR YOU HANG
DIRTY WILLYS. AND NOW
YOU'VE KIDNAPPED MONA JEFFRIES.
HOW COME I GET THE FEELING
YOU CHEAT AT GOLF?
IF YOU'RE NOT CHEATING,
YOU'RE NOT PLAYING.
- HEY, WE WANT MONA BACK.
- WHO ARE YOU-- LITTLE DICK?
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SHOW YOU LITTLE,
YA BIG FREAK.
HEY. DIRTY WILLY NEVER
CAME UP SHORT, SO THERE'S
NO REASON TO KILL HIM.
AS FOR MONA,
A VIAGRA-POPPIN' MAN
SUCH AS MYSELF...
CAN ONLY PRAY TO ENJOY
A MUFFIN LIKE THAT
IN THE MORNING.
ALL RIGHT. THAT'S IT. YOU AND ME
GONNA THROW RIGHT NOW, PAISAN.
I HAD IT WITH THIS MOOK.
HEY. I GOT NO BEEF
WITH DIRTY WILLY.
I GOT NO BEEF WITH YOU, DIXON.
MONA ASKED ME FOR HELP.
SHE SAID THAT DIRTY WILLY
WAS GETTIN' SQUEEZED...
BY, UM, A COUPLE
OF GOONS BY THE NAME
OF THE FROST BROTHERS.
[ Together ]
THE FROST BROTHERS?
THE FROST BROTHERS.
NOW I GOT MY FINGER IN EVERY
CASINO IN THIS WHOLE TOWN.
I NEVER HEARD OF THESE GUYS.
OKAY? SO THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL I KNOW. ALL RIGHT?
ARE WE DONE? ARE WE DONE?
LET'S GO.
GIVE ME MY BALLS.
♪♪ [ Humming ]
ROOM SERVICE.
I WAS JUST TALKIN'
TO THE MANAGER. YOU WON'T
BELIEVE WHAT HE WAS TELLING ME.
- AND WHAT WOULD THAT BE,
MR. BROOTS?
- GLAD YOU COULD JOIN US.
[ Raines ]
CENTRE EMPLOYEES OF OPPOSITE
GENDERS DON'T ROOM TOGETHER.
JUST SHOW HIM.
TAKEN BY A SECURITY CAMERA AT
McCARRAN INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT.
IT'S OF JAROD
HEADING FOR THE RUNWAY.
HE SKIPPED TOWN.
YOUR THEORY ISN'T HOLDING.
IT'S TIME TO GO HOME.
NO, BUT THE-- THE E-MAIL
SAID THAT HE WAS GONNA BE HERE.
W-WE HAVE TO STAY.
- BROOTS, IT'S OVER.
- NO. I JUST TALKED
TO THE MANAGER.
HE TOOK A RESERVATION
LAST NIGHT UNDER THE NAME
OF "JAROD SIEGEL"--
AS IN "BUGSY SIEGEL,"
THE MAN WHO CREATED VEGAS.
A RESERVATION DOESN'T MEAN
HE'S GONNA SHOW.
- WE'RE LEAVING.
- WE'RE STAYING.
DID HE JUST IGNORE US?
YOU WANNA BARGE IN HERE
AND TRY AND SCARE ME?
YOU GO AHEAD.
BUT DON'T QUESTION MY SKILLS.
I'M NOT SECOND STRING ANYMORE.
I DO A JOB, AND I DO IT WELL.
AND IF YOUR PARANOID MINDS
CAN'T TAKE THAT, THEN YOU
CAN GO CHASE THAT PHOTO.
MISS PARKER AND I
WILL CATCH JAROD.
ENJOY YOUR BREAKFAST.
[ Wheels Squeaking ]
YOU BETTER HOPE
WE CATCH JAROD,
OR WE'RE THROUGH.
YOU MEAN US?
I MEAN OUR NECKS.
[ Jarod Narrating ]
AS ARGYLE AND I
DROVE BACK TO BENNY'S,
WE KNEW THAT WITHOUT
THE MYSTERIOUS FROST BROTHERS,
THERE WAS NO MONA...
AND NO DREAM FOR ARGYLE.
BUT ARGYLE'S DREAM
WASN'T THE ONLY ONE IN JEOPARDY.
- OH, THOSE BASTARDS.
BASTARDS, ALL OF THEM!
- BENNY, WHAT HAPPENED?
THERE I AM.
I AM STANDING THERE
IN THE BUNKER.
I AM HALFWAY
INTO MY "OVERATURE,"
AND THEY GRAB ME.
WAYNE'S BODYGUARDS.
OH, BITE YOUR TONGUE.
WAYNE'S PEOPLE...
WOULD NEVER DO THAT
WITH A RAKE.
AH, IT WAS THOSE LOWLIFES
THAT WORK FOR THE OTHER HALF
OF WAYNE'S THREESOME--
THOSE "MUGICIANS"
WITH THE BIG HAIR?
IT'S A GOOD THING
THEY DIDN'T BRING
THEIR TIGERS, BOY.
NO. AND I KNOW
HE WOULD'VE LOVED IT.
OF COURSE HE WOULD HAVE.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH HIM?
- WE HAVEN'T FOUND MONA YET.
OH, BOY. OH, BOY.
IT'S ALWAYS A GIRL,
ISN'T IT?
LET ME LET YOU IN
ON A LITTLE TINY SECRET.
HE'S JUST EXACTLY LIKE ME.
- NO.
- OH, YES. I WAS WILD.
I WAS UNCHECKED,
UNTIL MY ADELLA TAMED ME.
I STILL REMEMBER THAT TRIP
TO VEGAS. WE WANTED
TO GET AWAY FROM IT ALL.
DR. KANAPA HAD TOLD US
THAT WE WOULDN'T BE ABLE
TO HAVE A FAMILY,
AND I KNOW
IT WAS REALLY TOUGH
FOR HER.
BUT MY ADELLA--
GOD, SHE LOOKED SO BEAUTIFUL
THE NIGHT WE WENT TO SEE WAYNE.
YA NEVER SAW A POLKA DOT DRESS
LIKE THAT IN YOUR LIFE.
WELL, BIG WAYNE--
HE PICKS HER OUT
OF THE WHOLE CROWD,
AND HE SANG "DANKE SCHOEN"
RIGHT TO HER.
- IT WAS--
- LIKE A DREAM.
YEAH. THAT NIGHT,
ADELLA CAME BACK
TO THE MOTOR COURT...
ALL GIDDY
FROM WAYNE'S SHOW,
YOU KNOW?
AND WE DROVE THE CATTLE ACROSS
THE PRAIRIE ALL NIGHT LONG,
IF YOU CATCH MY MEANING,
AND... WE WERE BLESSED.
- YOU CONCEIVED ARGYLE.
- ROLLED A HARD EIGHT.
[ Chuckles ]
- [ Benny ] SO NOW, WHEN I SEE
HIM GOIN' THROUGH ALL THIS--
- [ Dog Whimpers ]
I THINK, "WHERE WOULD I BE TODAY
IF IT WEREN'T FOR MY ADELLA?"
SHE WAS YOUR MONA.
[ Sighs ]
JAROD,
YA GOTTA FIND
THAT GIRL FOR MY BOY.
[ Dog Whimpers ]
[ Jarod Narrating ]
IT SEEMS EVERYBODY WHO MET MONA
WANTED HER:
ARGYLE, HER BROTHER, FALZONE.
IT GOT MY DETECTIVE GEARS
SPINNING.
LOOK, BUDDY BOY. I FOLLOWED
HER HOME ONCE-- OKAY, TWICE.
NICK HAD KNOWN EVERYTHING
ABOUT MONA: WHERE SHE LIVED,
HOW SHE SAVED HER MONEY.
MAYBE HE KNEW
WHO THE FROST BROTHERS WERE.
BUT I SWEAR, I NEVER HEARD
OF THE FROST BROTHERS.
IT WAS ALMOST A DEAD END.
ALMOST.
DIXON.
DEPUTY WYATT HADN'T PUNCHED ME
THE FIRST TIME WE MET.
GUESS HE FIGURED I WAS DUE.
OH, THIS IS GETTIN' REALLY OLD.
YOU TRYIN' TO DESTROY THREE
MONTHS OF REAL POLICE WORK?
WE ALMOST GOT FALZONE
FOR EXTORTION.
SO GET HIM.
AFTER YOU TALKED TO HIM?
YOU OF ALL PEOPLE SHOULD KNOW,
THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY
TO DO THINGS IN THIS TOWN:
THE VEGAS WAY.
WHAT ABOUT
THE FROST BROTHERS WAY?
WHAT'S THAT PLACE GOT
TO DO WITH ANYTHING?
PLACE?
PLACE. IT'S AN ABANDONED
MEAT-PACKING PLANT
OUTSIDE TOWN. SO WHAT?
[ Dog Barking, Whimpers ]
MONA?
[ Whimpering, Barks ]
MONA! MONA!
MONA.
I DIDN'T THINK
YOU'D COME.
OH, YOU'RE SO COLD.
L-LET'S GET YOU OUT OF HERE.
ARGYLE, THESE TWO GUYS--
THEY HAD MASKS ON.
THEY GRABBED ME.
THEY'VE BEEN TRYING
TO GET ME TO TELL THEM
WHAT DIRTY WILLY TOLD ME.
BUT I CAN'T TELL THEM
THAT SECRET, 'CAUSE
I CAN'T DO THAT TO WILLY.
WELL, YOU COULD TELL US
THE SECRET, MONA.
TELL US LATER.
WE HAVE TO GET OUT OF HERE
RIGHT NOW.
YEAH. WE NEED TO GET YOU
BACK TO YOUR BROTHER.
BROTHER?
I DON'T HAVE A BROTHER.
- SURE YOU DO. TWO OF 'EM.
- [ Barks ]
- [ Dog Growling ]
- ARGYLE, SAY HELLO
TO THE FROST BROTHERS.
[ Continues Growling ]
[ Jarod Narrating ]
IT WAS A CASE TO MAKE
RAY CHANDLER PROUD.
LET'S REVIEW.
OUR TWO SHERIFF DEPUTIES,
WYATT AND MIKE,
THEY KILLED DIRTY WILLY--
TORTURED HIM, FROZE HIM,
HUNG HIM.
BUT WHAT DID THEY WANT
OUT OF HIM? MONEY? DO-RE-MI?
- YOU WON'T BE SURPRISED IF
I TELL YOU THE ANSWER IS NO.
- [ Whimpers ]
DIRTY WILLY HAD
ONE DIRTY LITTLE SECRET LEFT,
AND THESE GUYS WERE TRYING
TO GET IT OUT OF MONA...
AND US.
- IT'S BEEN EIGHT HOURS.
START TALKING.
- I GOT NOTHIN' TO SAY.
YOU JUST DON'T GET IT,
DO YOU, DIXON?
WE DO THINGS THE VEGAS WAY.
NOW, MONA'S BROTHER HERE IS
GONNA DRIVE HER INTO THE DESERT.
IF HE DOESN'T HEAR
FROM ME IN 30, SHE'S GONE,
AND I ICE THE TWO OF YOU.
- OH, AND I KEEP THE DOG.
- [ Growling Continues ]
DON'T GIVE 'EM ANYTHING, ARGYLE.
NOT ONE QUARTER!
- [ Barking ]
- AH, PUT A SOCK
IN IT, DOG.
THAT WAS
A STRANGE THING
TO SAY.
YEAH, RIGHT--
ESPECIALLY SINCE DOGS
DON'T WEAR SOCKS.
NOT DOG. MONA.
SHE SAID, "NOT A QUARTER."
"DON'T GIVE THEM ONE QUARTER."
WELL, J-MAN, MONA LEFT
A BUCKET FULL OF QUARTERS
IN DICK DIXON'S OFFICE.
DIRTY WILLY'S SECRET. WHATEVER
HE WAS TRYIN' TO PROTECT
MUST HAVE BEEN IN THAT BUCKET.
WYATT!
HEY, WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOIN'?
I'M GONNA GIVE HIM
WHAT HE WANTS. WYATT!
THERE IT IS.
[ Beeps ]
[ Wyatt On Tape ]
LOOK, WILLY.
IF YOU PAY US WHAT WE NEED,
WE WON'T NEED
TO GET ROUGH WITH YOU.
[ Beeps ]
FALZONE WASN'T EXTORTING MONEY
FROM WILLY AND HIS CLUB.
YOU WERE.
AND THE DIRTY FAT BOY
RECORDED ME DOIN' IT.
- ALL THE TIME YOU JUST WANTED
THAT TAPE, IT WAS RIGHT THERE.
- NICE WORK, DETECTIVES.
WILLY WAS JUST TRYIN'
TO GET THAT TAPE
TO DICK DIXON.
SO NOW YOU GOT IT.
CALL YOUR DEPUTY
AND LET MONA GO.
POOR WILLY DIDN'T EVEN KNOW THAT
DICK DIXON HAD SKIPPED TOWN.
WAIT A SECOND.
YOU'RE NOT DICK DIXON?
- NO.
- [ Slot Machine Bell Ringing ]
- [ Ice Pick
Tapping On Desk ]
- LOSER.
[ Tapping Continues ]
[ Groaning ]
OH, HI, THERE.
LET ME OUTTA THIS.
UH-UH.
- YOU KNOW, YOU SHOULD
BE PROTECTING PEOPLE--
- [ Slot Machine Clicking ]
NOT EXTORTING FROM THEM.
BUT I GUESS
THAT'S WHAT THEY CALL
THE "VEGAS WAY," RIGHT?
- OH, YEAH.
- WELL, WE'VE ALREADY
TRIED THAT.
LET'S TRY THE JAROD WAY.
NO! NO! NO!
- YOU'RE TOTALLY WHACKED.
- YOU DON'T KNOW THE HALF OF IT.
- YOU'RE GOING TO MAKE A CALL.
YOU'RE GOING TO LET MONA GO.
- I DON'T THINK SO.
- LOSER.
- [ Sighs ]
- [ Wyatt Yelps ]
- OH. OOH, THAT'S HARDER
THAN GOLF.
YOU'RE OUTTA YOUR MIND.
MAKE THE CALL.
- NO.
- UH, LOSER.
LAST CHANCE.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
- LOSER.
- OKAY.
- FORE!
- [ Jarod Narrating ]
WYATT FINALLY MADE THE CALL.
AND SO DID I-- TO THE F.B.I.
WHEN THEY ARRIVED
AT THE OFFICE, THEY FOUND
A KILLER WAITING FOR THEM...
ALONG WITH THE EVIDENCE
TO CONVICT HIM--
ALL COURTESY OF THE MYSTERIOUS
RICHARD W. DIXON.
BUT THE STORY ISN'T OVER.
I STILL HAVE
ONE MORE JOB TO DO.
ANYTHING?
NOTHING.
WHICH IS WHAT WE'RE GONNA BE
WHEN WE GET BACK TO THE CENTRE.
IT WAS FUN WHILE IT LASTED--
[ Whispering ]
PUFF DADDY.
[ Faucet Turns, Water Running ]
MISS--
HOO.
I GUESS I'M NOT
A SCRUB ANYMORE.
I HOPE YOU LIKE RENEWAL WING,
'CAUSE I'M GETTIN' YOU
A GIFT CERTIFICATE.
THE CENTRE REEDUCATORS CAN
WIPE THIS ENTIRE WEEKEND
FROM YOUR BRAIN.
[ Jarod ]
WELL, YOU BETTER TELL THEM
THAT BROOTS CAUGHT ME.
[ Chuckles ]
DON'T HAVE TO.
WE'RE A TEAM, AREN'T WE,
DR. FUNKENSTEIN?
WELL, THAT ALL DEPENDS
ON ONE THING, BABY.
AM I YOUR PUFF DADDY?
[ Sighs ]
OH, YEAH, BABY.
AND I WANNA GET FUNKED UP.
OH, I HAVE TO WATCH?
YOU GET TO WATCH.
[ Both Giggle ]
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT,
MR. FUNKADELIC.
IF WE'RE GONNA DO THIS,
LET'S DO IT RIGHT.
IT'S MY TURN
TO LIVE OUT A FANTASY.
- BALD MEN HAVE ALWAYS
DRIVEN ME CRAZY.
- [ Broots Chuckles ]
♪ MAKE MY FUNK THE "P" FUNK ♪
AND IT TAKES MORE THAN ONE
TO REALLY SATISFY ME.
- MR. WIGGLES, GET IN HERE!
- ♪♪ [ Continues ]
♪ I WANTS TO GET FUNKED UP ♪
[ Wheels Squeaking ]
♪ I WANT THE BOMB
I WANT THE "P" FUNK, Y'ALL ♪
♪ DON'T WANT MY FUNK
STEPPED ON ♪
♪♪ [ Continues ]
MAKE MY FUNK THE "P" FUNK.
[ Man On CD ]
HOME OF
THE EXTRATERRESTRIAL BROTHERS.
♪ MAKE MY FUNK THE "P" FUNK ♪
UNCUT FUNK!
♪ I WANT MY FUNK UNCUT ♪
"P" FUNK!
- NO.
- ♪♪ [ Continues ]
♪ I WANTS TO GET FUNKED UP ♪♪
MISS PARKER, WHAT ABOUT US?
I WANTS TO GET FUNKED UP.
NO.
♪♪ [ Continues ]
NO. NO.
NO!
WHAT THE-- AH! MR. WIGGLES.
[ Sputters ]
OW.
I TOLD YOU NOT TO FALL ASLEEP.
I WAS ASLEEP?
YEAH.
THE WHOLE TIME?
YES, RIP VAN WINKLE.
YOU WERE MAKIN'
SOME WEIRD NOISES TOO.
AND BY THE WAY, WHAT EXACTLY
IS A "PUFF DADDY"?
[ Jarod Narrating ]
LIKE I SAID,
I HAVE ONE MORE THING TO DO.
BUT IT ISN'T THIS... DREAM.
- IT'S SOMEBODY ELSE'S.
- [ Strains ]
- CAN I HELP YOU WITH THAT?
- WHY, I--
[ Chuckling ]
OH, GOD.
IF YOU KNEW, SIR, HOW MUCH
I'VE WANTED TO MEET--
THIS IS AN HONOR, SIR.
THIS IS AN HONOR.
LISTEN.
THIRD ROW, POLKA DOT DRESS.
SIR?
ADELLA.
SHE WAS WEARIN'
A POLKA DOT DRESS.
YOU ARE A GOD.
[ Chuckles ]
LISTEN. I UNDERSTAND THERE'S
SOMETHING YOU'D LIKE ME TO HEAR.
- WELL, AS A MATTER OF FACT, UH,
YOU PROBABLY WOULDN'T WANNA--
- ♪♪ [ Accordion: Stray Notes ]
YOU KNOW--
I'D LOVE TO.
YOU WOULD?
I WOULD.
YEAH?
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪ [ Stray Notes ]
OKAY. HERE WE GO.
♪♪ [ Swing Introduction ]
♪ AUF WIEDERSEHEN, BABY ♪
♪ AUF WIEDERSEHEN ♪
♪ IT MEANS GOOD-BYE
MY BABY ♪
♪ I DON'T KNOW WHY
I FEEL THIS PAIN ♪
♪ IT'S NOT MY GOITER ♪
♪ BUT LET'S RECONNOITER ♪
♪ SO EVEN THOUGH
I'M ON THAT FAR-OFF DESERT
IN MOROCCO ♪
- ♪ I'M FEELIN' ROCKO, BUT
I WANNA DO THIS REFRAIN ♪
- [ Howls ]
♪ AUF WIEDERSEHEN ♪
- ♪ AUF WIEDERSEHEN ♪♪
- ♪♪ [ Ends ]
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Jarod, Argyle ]
WHOO!
WELL, THAT WAS UNMISTAKABLY YOU.
THAT'S JUST THE FIRST VERSE.
THERE'S MORE TO COME.
I CANNOT WAIT.
UH, LISTEN.
I WANNA SEE YOU ALL
TONIGHT AT MY SHOW.
YOU'LL BE MY GUEST.
I'LL LEAVE YOUR NAMES
AT THE FRONT DOOR.
AND BY THE WAY,
I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT ADELLA
WAS MY INSPIRATION TOO.
OH, THANK YOU, SIR.
THANK YOU.
SEE YOU. SEE YOU TONIGHT.
[ Benny ]
WHAT A GUY.
THANK YOU.
MY PLEASURE.
THAT COULD BE
THE WORST SONG
I'VE EVER HEARD.
I KNOW. BUT TO HIM IT WAS
A DREAM COME TRUE.
[ Chuckles ]
GUESS THEY MEAN
A LOT TO YOU, HUH?
- HE LISTENED. HE LIKED IT.
- [ Argyle ]
STANDING ROOM ONLY, POP.
SPEAKING OF A LOT,
THANK YOU FOR THAT DONATION.
IT WAS FOR A GOOD CAUSE.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T THINK
I EVER GOT YOUR NAME.
WELL, EVERYONE IN TOWN
CALLS ME DICK DIXON.
YOU'RE DICK DIXON?
YES.
[ Impact ]
[ Body Hitting Ground ]