- PREVIOUSLY ON THE PRETENDER.
- HAVE WE MET?
THOMAS GATES.
FRIENDS CALL ME TOMMY.
I DON'T HAVE ANY FRIENDS.
EVERYTHING THAT
I'VE EVER DONE OR FELT,
IT WAS WASTED BECAUSE
YOU WEREN'T PART OF IT.
THOMAS?
- I FIND IT HARD TO BELIEVE...
- THOMAS?
THAT SOMEBODY BREAKS INTO
YOUR HOUSE, SHOOTS YOUR LOVER
POINT BLANK IN THE HEAD.
- OH, MY GOD.
- AT LEAST I KNOW HOW TO
PROTECT THE ONES I LOVE.
THE MAN THE POLICE THINK
KILLED THOMAS GATES DIED
OF A DRUG OVERDOSE IN HIS CELL.
DADDY, THIS MAN
WAS THE LAST LINK IN PROVING
WHO KILLED THOMAS.
I DON'T WANT ANY TRACE
OF CENTRE INVOLVEMENT.
THEY KILLED THEM ALL.
AND FOR WHAT?
- WHAT WILL YOU DO NOW?
- FIND OUT WHO DID THIS
AND MAKE THEM PAY.
[ Miss Parker ]
TELL ME ABOUT YOURSELF.
- WHAT DO YOU WANT TO KNOW?
- EVERYTHING.
[ Gates ]
BRIDGET SEEMS LIKE
A NICE PERSON.
IF IT'S MAKING YOU THIS
MISERABLE, MAYBE YOU SHOULD STOP
SPENDING TIME WITH THEM.
- THEY'RE MY FAMILY.
- MAYBE YOU SHOULD THINK
ABOUT STARTING A NEW ONE.
[ Miss Parker ]
THERE ARE PLACES IN ME, TOMMY.
DARK PLACES.
IF SOMETHING IS NOT RIGHT,
WE'LL DEAL WITH IT. TOGETHER.
I'M A FIX-IT MAN, REMEMBER?
[ Gates ]
I WILL MAKE YOU A DEAL.
WHEN I DIE,
I'LL LEAVE YOU ALL MY SHIRTS.
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
I'M NOT GOIN' ANYWHERE.
HMM?
[ Shower Water Running ]
PARKER?
TOMMY.
I LOVE YOU, PARKER.
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Line Ringing ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Beeps ]
MUST BE THE 10th TIME
I GOT HER PHONE MACHINE.
[ Sydney ]
YOU LEFT THE ADDRESS,
DIDN'T YOU?
MAYBE MISS PARKER
WILL MEET US HERE.
SYD, SHE HATES ANYONE
TO ENTER ONE OF JAROD'S LAIRS
BEFORE SHE DOES.
[ Sighs ]
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
SOMETHING'S UP.
THINK BACK ONE YEAR, BROOTS.
THOMAS?
TODAY? IT'S A YEAR TO THE DAY
THAT SHE FOUND THOMAS
MURDERED AT HER HOUSE?
I'M SUCH AN IDIOT.
I LEFT ALL THOSE PHONE MESSAGES
ON HER MACHINE LIKE IT WAS
JUST ANY OTHER DAY.
IT IS
SAME CLOWN.
DIFFERENT SIDE SHOW.
I'M SORRY,
MISS PARKER.
THANK YOU.
SO, WHAT'S UP
WITH JAROD THE JESTER?
WELL, SYD AND I HAVE BARELY
SCRATCHED THE SURFACE,
IF YOU WANT TO START DIGGIN' IN.
[ Clears Throat ]
HAVE CLEAN-UP
CRATE EVERYTHING.
IF WE CAN'T FIGURE OUT
WHAT JAROD'S UP TO,
WE CAN DONATE THIS STUFF
TO A TWO-RING CIRCUS
LOOKING TO ADD A THIRD.
WE DID FIND ONE THING.
THE CELEBRITY CLOWN
OF A LOCAL KIDDIE SHOW,
MARCO THE MAGNIFICENT,
WAS ARRESTED YESTERDAY
ON MOLESTATION CHARGES.
POLICE FOUND HIM
LOCKED IN A LION CAGE...
[ Chuckles ]
WITH RAW BEEF
STRAPPED TO HIS--
ANYWAY,
WELL, IT'S ALL IN THERE.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
BOYS AND GIRLS,
I GIVE YOU...
RINGMASTER JAROD.
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S--
IT'S JAROD'S
TWISTED LITTLE MODEL...
OF MY FIRST MEETING
WITH THOMAS.
- BASTARD.
- I'M SURE THERE'S AN INNOCENT
REASON JAROD LEFT IT.
RIGHT.
AND O.J. WAS
JUST CHIPPING GOLF BALLS.
ALL I'M SAYING IS--
IT'S BAD ENOUGH HE KNOWS
HOW THOMAS AND I MET, BUT...
THE FACT THAT HE LEFT IT FOR ME
ON THIS DAY IS NO MISTAKE.
FOR ONCE,
ADMIT HE'S TORMENTING ME
JUST TO TORMENT ME.
AND WHEREVER HE IS,
I JUST KNOW HE'S LAUGHING.
[ Nose Squeaks ]
HARDLY LAUGHING.
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE DEFENDS THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
[ Jarod ]
LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
TO HOUSES
SKILLFULLY TURNED INTO HOMES.
TO EMPTY HEARTS
FILLED UP AGAIN.
TO NEW BEGINNINGS
THAT MIGHT HAVE BEEN.
ALL LEFT WITH YOU, MY LOVE.
BEAUTIFUL WORDS.
WHAT, NO CONFETTI GONGS, JOY
BUZZERS, SQUIRTING FLOWERS?
NONE OF THIS
IS A LAUGHING MATTER.
YEAH.
NO, YOU REALLY CAUGHT ME
IN A MOOD TODAY.
I'M REAL TEMPTED
TO PUT A CAP IN YOU,
WIPE THE SLATE CLEAN ON MY LIFE
AND TAKE OFF WITHOUT EVER
LOOKING BACK.
YOUR GUN WON'T WORK.
I TOOK THE FIRING PIN OUT
LAST NIGHT.
I SLEEP WITH THIS
UNDER MY PILLOW.
AND YOU DROOL
OUT OF THE LEFT
CORNER OF YOUR MOUTH.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
DOING HERE, JAROD?
IT'S TIME TO TAKE CARE OF
SOME UNFINISHED BUSINESS,
TO FIND OUT WHO KILLED
THE MAN YOU LOVED AND WHY,
AND TO PAY RESPECTS
TO A MAN LIKE THOMAS GATES,
BECAUSE HE DESERVES IT.
JUST BECAUSE YOU'RE A GENIUS
DOESN'T MEAN YOU KNOW
WHAT HE DESERVES.
WHY ARE YOU TORMENTING ME,
JAROD?
WHY DO YOU EVEN C-CARE?
[ Sydney ]
RUMOR 5-8-2-5-9?
[ Broots ]
YEAH. STANDARD CENTRE
CODING LOGISTICS.
IN THIS CASE,
"RUMOR" WOULD BE THE CODE NAME
OF THE OPERATIVE IN CHARGE.
AS FAR AS THE NUMBERS,
I'LL HAVE TO TALK TO MANNY.
YOU KNOW THE MUTE GUY
DOWN IN COMMUNICATIONS?
HE, THE ONE WITHOUT A TONGUE?
YEAH. I GUESS IT'D BE PRETTY
POINTLESS TO PLAY SPIN THE
BOTTLE WITH A GUY LIKE THAT.
I MEAN,
IF I WAS A WOMAN.
ANYHOW, OFFHAND I'D SAY
THESE NUMBERS MIGHT BE A CODE...
FOR A CENTRE
AUDIO PHONE TAP FILE.
FIND OUT FROM MANNY
THE MARBLE MOUTH WHICH ONE.
WELL, GIVEN THE CLIMATE AROUND
HERE, MISS PARKER, I DON'T THINK
THAT'S GONNA BE TOO EASY.
- WHY?
- OH, YOU HAVEN'T HEARD?
MUTUMBO'S DEAD,
AS IN "DING-DONG,
THE WICKED WITCH IS."
DEAD.
TRIUMVIRATE'S CRAZY ZULU
APPEARS TO HAVE BEEN MURDERED.
[ Mr. Lyle ]
TWO SHOTS THROUGH THE HEART.
SMALL TARGET.
AND WHOEVER PUT
THE BULLETS IN MUTUMBO
ALSO GOUGED OUT HIS EYES.
LIKE HE SAW SOMETHING
HE WASN'T SUPPOSED TO.
SPEAKING OF WHICH,
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU LAID EYES ON YOUR FATHER?
WHEN IS THE LAST TIME
SOMEBODY CHECKED
FOR YOUR PULSE?
[ Giggling ]
[ Clears Throat ]
UM--
NOW, NOW.
I MERELY ASK BECAUSE FAMILY
IS THE MOST IMPORTANT THING
IN THE WORLD.
MY FAMILY.
YOUR FAMILY.
THE CENTRE FAMILY.
CARE TO TRANSLATE
FOR BARNEY THE DINOSAUR?
THE GUN THAT WAS USED
TO KILL MUTUMBO...
WAS TRACED TO THE HIGHEST LEVEL
OF THE CENTRE.
A LEVEL THAT INCLUDES YOU,
MR. LYLE, AND DEAR OLD DAD,
WHO JUST HAPPENS TO GAIN
THE MOST FROM MUTUMBO'S
SUDDEN... ERASURE.
YOU THINK
MY FATHER KILLED HIM?
ANYONE COULD HAVE.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN WE MISS THE ONES WE LOVE
AND SURVIVAL'S AT STAKE,
WE'RE CAPABLE OF ANYTHING.
TOMMY.
TALK TO ME, PARKER.
THERE'S SOMETHING ON YOUR MIND.
I CAN TELL.
YES. I--
I--
IT'S OKAY.
IN YOUR OWN TIME.
MISS PARKER.
THE SEARCH FOR YOUR FATHER
HAS AND WILL CONTINUE
TO INTENSIFY...
ON MY AUTHORITY.
HE WILL BE FOUND.
AND WHEN HE IS,
THOSE ALLIED WITH HIM...
COULD FIND THEMSELVES
ENDANGERED SPECIES.
HE WAS AS MUCH
AS ACCUSING YOU OF--
HELL, ACCUSING ME
OF PARTICIPATING IN A COUP.
THE LEAST YOU COULD DO
IS PRETEND TO LISTEN. PARKER?
CALL ME...
WHEN YOU'RE BACK
WITH THE LIVING.
[ Miss Parker ]
DO YOU BELIEVE
IN GHOSTS, SYD?
[ Sydney ]
I BELIEVE IN AN AFTERLIFE.
SECOND CHANCES.
I'M TALKING ABOUT THOMAS.
HIS... PRESENCE
IS ALL AROUND ME.
SOMETIMES I HEAR
MY MOTHER'S WHISPER
OF CONSOLATION,
MY FATHER'S LAUGHTER.
THOSE WE LOVE...
ARE WITH US ALWAYS,
IN LIFE AND DEATH.
IT'S MORE THAN THAT.
I SEE HIM.
ALMOST TOUCH HIM.
THE ANNIVERSARY
OF HIS DEATH.
YOUR FATHER'S DISAPPEARANCE.
NOW MUTUMBO'S ASSASSINATION.
UNDER STRESS, THE MIND
IS CAPABLE OF MANY THINGS.
IT'S NOT MY MIND
PLAYING TRICKS ON ME.
IT IS THOMAS.
HE'S--
HE'S IN THE ROOM WITH ME,
LIKE--
LIKE HE'S WAITING.
MAYBE HE IS.
MAYBE HE'S GIVING YOU
THAT SECOND CHANCE
TO COMPLETE SOMETHING...
LEFT UNFINISHED.
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Beeps ]
ANGEL.
DADDY?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
BETTER THAN ANYBODY,
NOW THAT MUTUMBO'S, YOU KNOW--
YOU?
ME KILL HIM?
IF I HAD, HE'D BE MISSIN'
MORE THAN HIS EYES.
DADDY,
THEY'RE LOOKING FOR YOU.
COX.
LET HIM.
MY COMEBACK PLAN'S WORKIN'.
ONE MORE PIECE,
AND EVERYTHING
WILL BE BACK TO NORMAL.
- YOU SOUND DIFFERENT.
- DAMN STRAIGHT.
I'M GONNA BE A FATHER AGAIN.
I HAVEN'T FELT LIKE THIS
SINCE YOU WERE BORN.
LISTEN,
WE NEED TO HOOK UP.
WHERE?
I HAVEN'T DECIDED.
JUST KEEP YOUR EYES OPEN AND
YOUR BACK COVERED. AND, ANGEL?
THIS TURMOIL?
IT'S ALMOST OVER.
THE SURVIVORS
WILL BE TOGETHER SOON.
[ Line Hangs Up ]
[ Scoffs ]
"SURVIVORS."
[ Broots ]
AS MANNY EXPLAINED TO ME,
THIS CODE--
YOU... HAD A CONVERSATION
WITH A TONGUELESS MUTE?
NO. [ Chuckles ]
NOT IN SO MANY WORDS.
BUT I--
BROOTS.
OKAY.
THE PHONE TAP...
WAS ON THOMAS'S PHONE.
ALL OF IT WAS ROUTED
TO AN OPERATIVE,
CODE NAME RUMOR.
I STILL HAVEN'T FIGURED OUT
WHO THAT IS YET, BUT I WAS ABLE
TO UNSCRAMBLE PART OF THE CALL.
AND I-I-I DOWNLOADED IT.
PLAY IT.
[ Gates ] YEAH. PARKER AND I
ARE GOIN' AWAY FOR THE WEEKEND,
SO WE'LL TALK WHEN I GET BACK.
[ Jarod ]
OKAY, BUDDY.
I'LL SEE YOU AGAIN SOON.
[ Gates ]
YOU TAKE CARE, JAROD.
[ Line Clicks ]
TOMMY AND JAROD...
WERE FRIENDS?
[ Gates ]
TALK TO ME.
[ Exhales ]
[ Shower Faucet Squeaks ]
[ Shower Water Running ]
TOMMY?
TOMMY.
[ Both Gasp ]
ANGEL.
OH, GEEZ.
I THOUGHT I WAS GONNA HAVE
A TUB BIRTH THERE FOR A SECOND.
YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
YOU LOOK LIKE
YOU JUST SAW A GHOST.
NO. I--
I'M SO GLAD
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT, DADDY.
I'M JUST FINE.
IT'S BRIGITTE
WE NEED TO WORRY ABOUT.
YEAH.
CARRYIN' A NEW LIFE.
IT'S GOD'S ULTIMATE CHALLENGE.
HOW DID YOU GET HERE?
I DIDN'T SEE YOUR CAR.
UH, WE, UH, HITCHED A RIDE,
CAME UP THE BACK PATH
AND USED THE KEY YOU GAVE US.
DID I?
I NEED A FAVOR.
ANYTHING.
I WANT TO HELP.
BOTH OF YOU.
YEAH, GOOD. WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TO HELP EACH OTHER.
I GOTTA HAVE YOUR CAR.
HE FOUND A SAFE PLACE
FOR THE BIRTH.
YEAH, WE GOTTA KEEP MOVIN'
FOR THE BABY.
AND A DOCTOR WE CAN TRUST
FOR THE DELIVERY.
DADDY.
HMM?
TELL ME WHERE YOU'RE GOING.
PLEASE? I JUST--
I NEED TO BE A PART
OF SOMETHING POSITIVE
RIGHT NOW.
I CAN'T.
IT'S NOT SAFE.
LISTEN, JUST BECAUSE
MUTUMBO'S DEAD DOESN'T MEAN
HIS ORDER TO KILL US IS.
YOU SEE, I THINK
THE HITTER'S REAL CLOSE.
I THINK IT'S COX.
WELL, IT'S A PRO,
THAT'S FOR DAMN SURE.
THAT'S WHY
YOU HAVE TO CARRY ON
BUSINESS AS USUAL.
NOW, IT WON'T BE LONG.
I'M JUST ONE PIECE AWAY
FROM BEIN' BACK...
RUNNIN' THE CENTRE.
I CAN GET YOU THAT PIECE
IF YOU JUST--
NO, NO. YOU CAN'T.
I'LL HAVE IT REAL SOON.
NOW, GIVE ME THE CAR KEYS.
COME ON.
THERE.
- YOU TAKE CARE OF THAT BROTHER
OR SISTER OF MINE.
- I WILL.
COME ON.
LET'S GO.
[ Door Opens ]
DADDY?
HMM?
WHAT IS RUMOR 5-8-2-5-9?
BEATS THE HELL OUT OF ME.
RUMOR IS A CODE NAME
FOR THE OPERATIVE
IN CHARGE OF THAT FILE.
THE REST SOUNDS LIKE
A DIGITAL PHONE TAP NUMBER.
YEAH. SEE?
WE GOTTA HELP EACH OTHER.
COME ON.
NOW REMEMBER,
BUSINESS AS USUAL.
[ Mr. Parker ]
REMEMBER, BUSINESS AS USUAL.
[ Brigitte ] RUMOR'S
A CODE NAME FOR THE OPERATIVE
IN CHARGE OF THAT FILE.
[ Gates ] TALK TO ME, PARKER.
THERE'S SOMETHING ON YOUR MIND,
I CAN TELL.
[ Jarod ] IT'S TIME TO FIND OUT
WHO KILLED THE MAN
YOU LOVED AND WHY.
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Rings ]
[ Click ]
- WHAT?
- LET'S HOPE THERE'S NOT
A DIGITAL TAP ON THIS PHONE.
IT DIDN'T STOP YOU AND TOMMY
FROM BECOMING FAST FRIENDS.
- AT LEAST YOU'VE DECIPHERED
SOME OF WHAT RUMOR MEANS.
- I'M JUST GETTING STARTED.
SO WHY NOT
SAVE ME SOME TIME...
AND JUST TELL ME
WHO KILLED HIM?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU LISTEN TO ME, JAROD.
THE RULES THAT YOU AND I
HAVE BEEN PLAYING BY--
MY INDENTURED SERVITUDE
TO THIS HOUSE OF HORRORS,
YOU SHAKING YOUR FAMILY TREE--
YOU JUST THROW THOSE
THE HELL OUT THE WINDOW
WHEN IT COMES TO THOMAS!
HE IS NOT A GAME!
I WOULD NEVER
TREAT HIM LIKE ONE.
DECEPTION WAS NEVER MY GOAL
WITH YOU AND THOMAS.
YOUR GOAL?
WHAT GOAL?
[ Sighs ]
LOVE.
PUTTING YOU TWO TOGETHER WAS
ONE OF THE MOST REWARDING THINGS
I'VE EVER DONE.
PUTTING US TOGETHER?
YOU'RE A LIAR.
WE HAD A CHANCE MEETING
IN BLUE COVE AT A GAS STAT--
YOU DIDN'T MEET HIM
AFTER I DID.
YOU KNEW HIM BEFORE?
THE WAY YOU FELT
ABOUT EACH OTHER
HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH ME.
I JUST--
I JUST LIT THE TORCH.
[ Sobs ]
MISS PARKER,
ARE YOU THERE?
[ Sighs ]
[ Sobs ]
TELL ME ABOUT
THE TOMMY YOU KNEW.
WE MET ABOUT A MONTH
BEFORE YOU DID.
I WAS WORKING CONSTRUCTION
FOR ONE OF HIS COMPETITORS--
A GREEDY CONTRACTOR
WHOSE SELFISHNESS
COST A YOUNG MAN BOTH HIS LEGS.
TOMMY HELPED YOU
TAKE HIM DOWN.
- THOMAS WAS BIG
ON DOING THE RIGHT THING.
- YEAH.
I... HAVE TO KNOW
WHO KILLED HIM, JAROD.
AS SOON AS I FIND OUT ANYTHING,
YOU'LL BE MY FIRST STOP.
BUT UNTIL THEN,
EVERYTHING INSIDE OF ME
SAYS RUMOR MURDERED THOMAS.
FOLLOW THAT LEAD.
AND, MISS PARKER,
BE CAREFUL.
RUMORS CAN KILL YOU.
[ Beeps ]
PARKER?
- TOMMY.
- TIME TO TRUST NOW, PARKER.
- BUT--
- NO. TRUST JAROD.
TRUST HIM.
[ Broots ]
THAT'S FUNNY.
"CENTRE VOTING BOOTH.
"USE HANDY LEVER
TO VOTE FOR MOST HATED.
"ONE FLUSH, MR. LYLE.
[ Laughing ]
[ Clears Throat ]
"TWO FLUSHES, MR. RAINES.
THREE FLUSHES, MR. COX."
HEY, I GUESS
IT'S ANYBODY'S ELECTION.
I'M FLATTERED.
BUT I'D HATE TO BE THE ONE
TO HAVE TO COUNT THE VOTES.
[ Urinal Flushes
Three Times ]
WOULDN'T YOU, MR. BROOTS?
THERE ARE RUMORS
GOING AROUND, MR. BROOTS.
RUMORS?
WELL, YOU ARE A WASHER,
I HOPE?
OH, YEAH. ALWAYS.
BEFORE AND AFTER.
[ Air Blowing ]
SO, UH-- [ Clears Throat ]
WHAT KIND OF RUMORS?
IT'S FUNNY-- THESE DRYERS
BRING BACK FOND MEMORIES
OF FATHER'S MORTUARY.
WE EMPLOYED SIMILAR DEVICES
IN THE PREPARATION PROCESS.
OH.
HE USED TO
LET ME HELP AFTER SCHOOL.
IF I WAS GOOD.
[ Chuckles ]
I GUESS EVEN THE DEAD
HAVE TO BE CLEAN.
OH, YES, BECAUSE...
CLEANLINESS IS TRUTH.
HERE. PLEASE.
[ Air Blowing ]
YOU BELIEVE IN TRUTH,
DON'T YOU, MR. BROOTS?
[ Clears Throat ]
SURE.
[ Sighs ]
SO, UH,
ABOUT THIS RUMOR THING,
I CAN EXPLAIN--
CLEANLINESS IS TRUTH.
BUT THAT--
THAT'S KINDA HOT.
[ Chuckles ]
JUST LIKE THE CREMATORIUM.
NOW, WHAT RUMORS ARE YOU
HEARING, MR. BROOTS?
OH! [ Groaning ]
OH, MY GOD!
[ Screaming ]
[ Sighs ]
OH, THAT FEELS GOOD.
SO, BROOTS,
WHAT DID YOU TELL COX?
I SCREAMED AND TOLD HIM
THAT MY HAND WAS FRYING.
ABOUT RUMOR!
WELL, AS IT TURNS OUT,
MR. COX WASN'T INTERESTED
IN THE RUMOR FILE AT ALL.
HE JUST KEPT COMING BACK
TO YOUR FATHER.
HIS PERSISTENT INTEREST
IN YOUR FATHER
POINTS TO ONE THING.
YES. THAT COX IS THE HITTER
HIRED BY MUTUMBO
TO KILL DADDY.
AND BRIGITTE, MAYBE,
AS WELL AS THE BABY.
I'M RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
SO IS DADDY.
ANYTHING FURTHER
ON RUMOR, BROOTS?
WELL, I WAS ABLE
TO REACH THE END
OF THE PHONE TAP ARCHIVE.
AND?
NOTHING BUT A TEXT MESSAGE
TELLING ME THE IDENTITY OF
RUMOR IS IN A HARD COPY FILE.
- LET'S FIND IT.
- NO, NO. I-I'M WORKING ON IT.
IT'S, UH--
THE FILE'S CALLED A Z3 FILE.
Z3?
YEAH.
DESIGNATES
CONTRACT KILLINGS FOR HIRE.
MAKES IT A LOCK.
THOMAS WAS MURDERED BY SOMEONE
INSIDE THE CENTRE.
[ Miss Parker ] THANKS FOR
LENDING ME YOUR CAR, BROOTS.
NO PROBLEM.
DO YOU WANT ME TO STICK AROUND
AND KEEP YOU COMPANY
FOR A WHILE, MISS PARKER?
MMM, THANKS,
BUT I DON'T FEEL ALONE.
IT MUST BE PRETTY
HARD STILL, THOUGH, HUH?
WHY DOES SOMEBODY HAVE TO DIE
FOR US TO REALIZE ALL THE THINGS
WE NEVER SAID TO THEM?
WELL,
I GUESS IT'S 'CAUSE
WE KINDA TREAT LIFE LIKE
A BUG ON THE SIDEWALK.
ALL WE SEE IS A BUG,
NOT A MIRACLE.
AND NO MATTER
HOW HARD WE TRY,
WE USUALLY END UP
STEPPIN' ON IT...
INSTEAD OF
TAKIN' IT INTO OUR HAND.
AND THE LIVING ARE...
LEFT WITH
ALL THE UNFINISHED BUSINESS.
UNTIL WE FINISH IT, YEAH.
YOU KNOW,
BETWEEN THOMAS...
AND EVERYTHING THAT'S
HAPPENING WITH YOUR FATHER,
I JUST WANT YOU
TO KNOW THAT...
I'M HERE FOR YOU,
MISS PARKER.
I-I MEAN,
IF YOU NEED SOMEONE.
I-I MEAN, A FRIEND.
MISS PARKER?
THE Z3 RUMOR FILE?
HOW DID IT GET IN HERE?
IT'S NOT HOW IT GOT HERE
THAT MATTERS. IT'S WHO IT SAYS
IS THOMAS'S KILLER.
WHO?
REVENGE? YOU SHOULD THINK
ABOUT THIS, MISS PARKER.
THINK ABOUT WHAT?
TOMMY WAS MURDERED.
AND HIS KILLER'S GONNA PAY.
THINKING COMPLETED.
MISS PARKER.
GOD HELP US ALL.
BE CAREFUL, PARKER.
TOMMY.
OPEN UP, BRIDGET!
[ Groans ]
ANGEL.
- IT'S 4:00 IN THE MORNING.
- WHERE'S BRIDGET?
- OH, GOD, NOW WHERE DID SHE GO?
- DON'T TRY TO COVER FOR HER!
WHERE THE HELL IS SHE?
SHE WAS HERE
WHEN I FELL ASLEEP.
WE HAD TO LEAVE
OUR LAST HIDING PLACE.
DECIDED TO SLEEP IN THE CAR.
- HOW DID YOU FIND US?
- THE CAR HAS A TRACKING SYSTEM.
DAMN IT.
SHE'S BEEN ACTIN' NUTS THE LAST
COUPLE OF WEEKS, DISAPPEARING
FOR HOURS AT A TIME.
OH, MY GOD, ANGEL.
SHE COULD BE
HAVIN' THE BABY.
ANGEL, WHAT'S HAPPENED?
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
THOMAS.
RUMOR 5-8-2-5-9.
OH, GOD.
BRIGITTE'S RUMOR.
YOU KNEW NOTHING
ABOUT THIS?
OF COURSE NOT!
SHE MUST HAVE BEEN
FOLLOWIN' MUTUMBO'S ORDERS.
SHE KILLED THOMAS.
I'M SO SORRY.
[ Groans ]
SHE'S CARRYING MY BABY.
DADDY, THINK.
WHERE WOULD SHE GO?
NOW THAT MUTUMBO'S DEAD,
SHE'S NOT SAFE ANYWHERE.
NO, EVERYBODY HAS A SAFE PLACE.
THINK.
WHAT?
WELL, THERE WAS A PLACE.
LET'S SEE, IT WAS
IN THE COUNTRY, I THINK.
I NEVER KNEW WHERE.
BUT SHE KEPT A SPARE KEY
IN HER DESK AT THE CENTRE.
I'LL FIND IT,
AND I'LL FIND HER.
THEN WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
THINK ABOUT MY BABY!
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Bell Dings ]
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
SEARCHING. WHY?
BECAUSE
YOU'RE NOT THE ONLY ONE.
WITH TRIUMVIRATE PRESSURE,
COX HAS CRANKED UP
HIS SEARCH FOR DAD.
AND IF THEY FIND
ANY LINK TO MUTUMBO'S DEATH,
PARKER WILL NOT
BE THE SAFEST SURNAME
TO HAVE AROUND HERE.
SO, WHEN DID YOUR BOY COX
TURN ON YOU?
LIKE I TRIED
TO TELL YOU BEFORE,
ANY LINK BETWEEN COX AND ME
IS A LIE.
I INTEND TO STAY OUT
OF HIS CROSSHAIRS.
AND I SUGGEST
YOU DO THE SAME.
[ Bell Dings ]
MISS PARKER?
BROOTS!
MR. COX AND A TEAM
OF SWEEPERS ARE--
I HEARD.
- I NEED YOU TO FIND
SOMETHING FOR ME. A KEY.
- A KEY?
YEAH. A PIECE OF METAL
WITH TEETH ON IT.
YOU KNOW, THOSE OF US THAT HAVE
EVOLVED BEYOND FIRE AND WHEELS
USE IT TO UNLOCK DOORS.
WHERE IS IT?
BRIDGET'S OFFICE.
BRIGITTE?
[ Phone Ringing ]
- WHAT?
- IT WAS YOUR EYES.
WHAT WAS?
WHERE THOMAS
FELT AT HOME.
- DID HE TELL YOU THAT?
- YES, HE DID.
DO YOU THINK HE EVER KNEW
WHAT I REALLY DID?
I DON'T KNOW.
AND TO HIM, THAT WAS LOVE.
HE SAID THE FIRST TIME HE EVER
EXPERIENCED THAT FEELING WAS
WHEN HE LOOKED INTO YOUR EYES.
[ Exhales ]
MISS PARKER?
THERE WERE SO MANY TIMES
I WANTED TO TELL HIM,
TO SAY IT TO HIM.
BUT I--
TELL HIM WHAT?
IT'S TOO LATE NOW ANYWAY,
JAROD.
NEVER UNDERESTIMATE
THE IMPORTANCE OF COMPLETING
UNFINISHED BUSINESS.
OH, DON'T YOU WORRY.
BRIDGET WILL KNOW THE IMPORTANCE
OF THAT REAL SOON.
SO, BRIGITTE IS THE ONE
THAT PULLED THE TRIGGER.
LIKE YOU DIDN'T READ
THE RUMOR FILE
YOU LEFT IN MY HOME.
MISS PARKER,
I DIDN'T LEAVE YOU ANY FILE.
WHETHER IT'S LOVE
OR REVENGE,
DON'T LET
UNFINISHED BUSINESS
FINISH YOU.
[ Beeps ]
[ Knocking ]
YOU FOUND IT!
YES. AND WHAT
IT OPENS, I THINK.
YOU SEE, I REALIZED
THAT IF BRIGITTE WAS
INTERCEPTING THOMAS'S CALLS,
SHE HAD TO HAVE
THEM FORWARDED SOMEWHERE.
SO I WENT TO SEE MANNY
TO SEE IF HE COULD
BACKTRACK THE CALLS.
HE OWES ME A FAVOR
'CAUSE I LOANED HIM
MY KARAOKE MACHINE.
FOLLOW THE BOUNCING BALL,
BROOTS.
WELL, ALL THE CALLS
WERE TRANSFERRED TO A CABIN
LESS THAN 20 MILES FROM HERE.
HERE'S THE ADDRESS.
BE SURE AND TELL MANNY THE MUTE
THAT I SAID...
[ Mouths Words ]
"THANK YOU."
[ Engine Off ]
[ Exhales ]
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
I'M HAVIN' THE BABY.
[ Exhales ]
I HEARD A LITTLE RUMOR
ABOUT YOU.
IT'S TRUE.
PULL THE TRIGGER
IF YOU WANT.
GOD KNOWS I DESERVE IT.
YOU... HAVE NO IDEA.
JUST ANSWER ONE QUESTION.
WHY DID YOU KILL TOMMY?
- ORDERS.
- WHO ORDERED IT?
- [ Grunts ]
- TELL ME WHO!
[ Groaning ]
OH, GOD!
HOW FAR APART
ARE YOUR CONTRACTIONS?
LET'S JUST SAY IT WON'T BE LONG
BEFORE YOU'RE A SISTER AGAIN.
DO WHAT YOU WANT
WITH ME.
JUST PLEASE
LET MY BABY LIVE.
OH, YOU'VE ALWAYS HAD A KNACK
FOR STATING THE OBVIOUS.
THE TRUTH IS,
IT DOESN'T REALLY
MATTER ANYWAY.
- THIS BABY WILL EVEN
THE SCORE FOR YOU.
- THE BABY?
I HAVE A DISORDER
CALLED PLACENTA PREVIA.
I'LL BLEED TO DEATH
AS THE BABY IS BORN.
[ Groaning, Inhaling ]
[ Groaning, Screaming ]
UH-UH.
I'LL GET HELP.
[ Dialing ]
[ Groans ]
THERE'S NO SIGNAL
OUT HERE.
[ Groaning Continues ]
HOLD ON!
I'LL GET HELP!
- THE LAND LINE WENT DEAD
AFTER I SPOKE TO YOUR FATHER.
- YOU SPOKE WITH DADDY?
HE SAID YOU'D FIND
THE DOCTOR AND BRING HIM.
WHY DID YOU RUN?
I KNEW IT WAS JUST
A MATTER OF TIME BEFORE
YOU FOUND OUT I WAS RUMOR.
AND WITH MUTUMBO'S
HITTER THERE, I RAN,
HOPING TO KEEP THE FOCUS
AWAY FROM YOUR FATHER.
DESPITE WHAT YOU THINK,
I LOVE HIM VERY MUCH.
[ Screaming ]
GOD!
[ Gasps ]
OH! OH!
OH!
THANK YOU.
THANK FOR NOT MAKING ME
DO THIS ALONE.
♪♪ [ Whistling ]
[ Gasps ]
PUTTING IN OVERTIME?
I'M SALARY.
SO IS YOUR FRIEND, MANNY.
THE TONGUELESS ONE?
THE POOR MAN DROOLS
WHEN HE SPEAKS.
SP-SPEAKS?
[ Clears Throat ]
ABOUT YOU, MR. BROOTS.
ME?
NOW, YOU HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY
TO TELL ME WHERE BRIGITTE WENT.
NOW, IF YOU CHOOSE NOT TO
ACCEPT THAT OPPORTUNITY,
YOU COULD FIND YOURSELF HAVING
MORE IN COMMON WITH MUTE MANNY
THAN JUST KARAOKE.
- [ Exhales ]
- SHALL I SING YOU
A TORCH SONG?
HMM?
[ Groaning,
Inhaling, Exhaling ]
STAY WITH ME, BRIDGET.
I'M HERE.
I'M SORRY...
FOR THOMAS.
FOR ALL THE PAIN
I CAUSED YOU.
YOU NEVER ANSWERED MY QUESTION.
I DON'T KNOW WHO.
BUT IT WASN'T
THE TRIUMVIRATE.
IT CAME FROM
INSIDE THE CENTRE.
THEY THOUGHT THAT
YOU WERE LOSING YOUR FOCUS.
OH, GOD!
SOMETHING'S
HAPPENING INSIDE!
WHERE'S DADDY WITH THE DOCTOR?
- STAY WITH ME NOW.
- I'M GONNA FAINT.
NO, YOU'RE NOT. NO--
OH, I CAN SEE THE HEAD.
YOU NEED TO PUSH.
THE HEAD IS BLUE.
I CAN'T.
YOU CAN. PUSH.
THE BABY NEEDS OXYGEN.
PUSH!
HOW BAD AM I?
UH--
UH, THERE'S A LOT OF BLOOD.
- I'M NOT GONNA MAKE IT.
- YES, YOU ARE, DAMN IT!
I CAME HERE TO KILL YOU!
I'LL BE THE ONE WHO DECIDES
WHETHER YOU LIVE OR DIE!
- NOW PUSH!
- [ Screaming ]
PUSH! HOLD ON! HELP'S HERE!
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Baby Crying ]
OH! OH!
[ Crying Continues ]
BRIGITTE?
BRIGITTE!
[ Sobbing ]
OH, GOD. OH.
[ Lock Rattling ]
- I SEE I'M TOO LATE
FOR THE LAMAZE.
- BUT NOT TOO LATE TO DIE.
NO, NO, ANGEL.
HE'S ON OUR SIDE.
UH, DR. COX
IS HERE FOR THE BABY.
- DOCTOR?
- OB-GYN, HARVARD '93.
[ Scoffs ]
MMM.
[ Coos ]
AHH.
OOH. AHA.
THIS SEALS IT.
THE LAST PIECE.
[ Chuckles ]
HERE YOU ARE, NURSE.
DON'T FORGET THE PLACENTA
AND CORD BLOOD.
DADDY, WHAT'S GOING ON?
MR. COX HAS BEEN
MY INSIDE MAN FOR MONTHS,
WATCHING OUT
WHILE I PLANNED MY RETURN.
THERE'S ONLY ONE REASON
FOR YOU BEING HERE, ANGEL.
DID SHE ADMIT TO EVERYTHING
IN THE RUMOR FILE?
DAMN LUCKY THING,
THAT FILE SHOWIN' UP.
- SHE'S GONE.
- MMM.
- DID YOU--
- KILL HER? NO.
SHE DIED IN CHILDBIRTH.
AREN'T YOU EVEN CONCERNED
ABOUT YOUR WIFE?
TILL DEATH DO US PART.
WHAT--
SHE WAS NOTHING MORE
THAN A VESSEL FOR THE BABY,
FOR YOUR LEGACY.
DID YOU LEAVE THE RUMOR FILE
IN MY HOUSE?
NOW, WHY WOULD I
DO A THING LIKE THAT?
LET ME GUESS.
THE GUN THAT KILLED MUTUMBO.
FOUND ON HER BODY.
JUST CLEARS EVERYONE
OF EVERYTHING.
SHE PLANTED IT IN MY STUFF!
IT WAS A SETUP.
RUMOR WAS TRYIN' TO
RUIN BOTH OF US.
WHEN ARE THEY GONNA LEARN
THEY CAN'T WHIP
A PARKER, HUH?
MAKE IT ALL GO AWAY.
- DADDY?
- WHAT?
DON'T YOU EVEN WANT TO KNOW?
KNOW WHAT?
IF IT'S A BOY OR A GIRL.
I THOUGHT THAT GETTING REVENGE
FOR TOMMY'S DEATH
WOULD SOMEHOW BRING ME PEACE.
BUT EVEN IF I HAD BEEN ABLE TO,
I KNOW NOW IT WOULDN'T HAVE.
[ Jarod ] THAT ISN'T
THE UNFINISHED BUSINESS
THAT NEEDS FINISHING.
YOU SAID THE OTHER DAY
THAT YOU WISH YOU HAD TOLD HIM.
TOLD HIM WHAT?
I NEVER--
I NEVER TOLD TOMMY
THAT I LOVED HIM.
AND NOW YOUR HEART
AND YOUR MIND ARE RAGING
A WAR AGAINST EACH OTHER.
I WOULD TRADE EVERYTHING
FOR ONE MINUTE WITH HIM.
JUST TO SAY THOSE WORDS
AND HAVE HIM HEAR THEM.
TELL HIM.
LET YOUR HEART
WIN THE WAR.
♪♪ [ Pop ]
[ Man ]
♪ I NEED TO REMEMBER THIS ♪
♪ SO, BABY
GIVE ME JUST ONE KISS ♪
♪ AND LET ME TAKE
A LONG LAST LOOK ♪
♪ BEFORE WE SAY GOOD-BYE ♪
♪ JUST LAY YOUR HEAD
BACK ON THE GROUND ♪
♪ LET YOUR HAIR
FALL ALL AROUND ME ♪
♪ OFFER UP YOUR BEST DEFENSE ♪
♪ THIS IS THE END ♪
I LOVE YOU, TOMMY.
AND I LOVE YOU, PARKER.
♪ OF THE INNOCENCE ♪
♪ OH, NO, NO ♪♪