PREVIOUSLY ON THE PRETENDER.
YOU PEOPLE ONLY UNDERSTAND
ONE THING-- POWER.
- DADDY, GET BACK!
- SHOOT HIM!
WELCOME BACK
TO THE CENTRE, JAROD.
SETTLE DOWN
OR I'LL BASH YOU AGAIN!
[ Sniffs, Sighs ]
HE STILL STINKS.
ON THE WAY TO THE SHOWER,
HE FREAKED. THOUGHT HE WAS
GONNA CHEW MY HEART OUT.
IT TOOK A LITTLE SWIPE
FROM THE MOTIVATOR
TO CALM HIM DOWN.
[ Grunts ]
IF YOU DON'T WANT
TO GO TO THE SHOWERS,
I'LL BRING THE SHOWERS TO YOU.
[ Spits ]
[ Grunting ]
ENOUGH!
WE DON'T WANT HIM DEAD,
JUST LESS ODIFEROUS.
CLEAN THE FILTH OFF YOURSELF,
THEN DO THE WALLS.
- YOU CLEAN IT.
- [ Chuckling ]
THE WORLD IS CHANGING.
MR. PARKER IS GONE.
MR. RAINES IS GONE.
MISS PARKER IS...
GOD ONLY KNOWS WHERE.
BUT YOU AND I ARE HERE,
AND I'M IN CHARGE.
[ Crackling ]
[ Gasping ]
LIKE I SAID,
THE WORLD'S CHANGING.
NO! NO! NO!
YOU BASTARDS!
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE DEFENDS THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
[ Jarod ]
LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
NO! NO!
YOU BASTARDS!
THAT WAS THREE WEEKS AGO.
SINCE THEN WE'VE BEEN WORKING
ON MAKING HIM MORE MANAGEABLE.
WHY HAVEN'T I BEEN ALLOWED
TO SEE HIM?
- LOOK AT HIM.
HE WAS OUT OF CONTROL.
- WAS?
THE WORLD IS CHANGING,
AND SO IS BOY WONDER.
[ Screaming ]
LISTEN TO ME, LYLE.
YOU'RE A SICK MAN.
I'M A PERSUASIVE MAN.
JAROD?
I HAVE A PROJECT THAT I'D
LIKE YOU TO DO FOR ME.
ANYTHING YOU WANT,
MR. LYLE.
[ Sydney ]
BRAINWASHING'S NOT POSSIBLE
WITH JAROD.
OH, WE ALL HAVE
AN ACHILLES' HEEL.
IN JAROD'S CASE,
IT'S FAMILY.
THE ONE HE SO DESPERATELY
WANTS BACK.
IF YOU WANNA HEAR
ABOUT MOMMY AND DADDY,
JUST TRUST ME.
[ Jarod Crying ]
- I LOVE THAT PART.
- LYLE, PLEASE LET ME GO TO HIM.
SYDNEY, IF IT WERE UP TO ME,
YOU TWO COULD GO ON
A FATHER-SON PICNIC,
BUT THE ISOLATION ORDERS
COME FROM THE TRIUMVIRATE--
BIG MUTUMBO.
I GOT HERE
AS QUICKLY AS I COULD.
SYDNEY,
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
WE HAVEN'T FINISHED
TALKING ABOUT JAROD!
JAROD IS NO LONGER THE MOST
IMPORTANT THING IN THE WORLD,
AND TOMORROW HE LEAVES FOREVER.
HE'S MUTUMBO'S PROPERTY,
AND I, FOR ONE, AM NOT GONNA
CROSS THAT CRAZY ZULU.
DID YOU SEE THE LOOK ON
HIS FACE WHEN HE TOOK RAINES
AND MY FATHER AWAY?
JUST, UH, TAKE IN A MOVIE.
GET A MASSAGE.
CHECK OUT THE AMPUTEE DWARVES
DOWN IN SL 6.
JUST FORGET ABOUT JAROD.
[ Broots ]
YOU STOLE A D.S.A.
FROM LYLE?
EVER SINCE MUTUMBO'S PUT THAT
THUMBLESS MANIAC IN CHARGE,
MORE BODIES HAVE BEEN
DROPPIN' AROUND HERE THAN
ST. VALENTINE'S DAY MASSACRE.
DID HE TELL YOU WHERE
MISS PARKER'S HOSPITALIZED?
NO. HE PLAYED DUMB
ON THAT TOO.
WHO'S THE ALBINO?
SOMEONE MORE IMPORTANT
THAN JAROD.
[ Broots ]
WHO COULD BE MORE IMPORTANT
THAN JAROD?
I DON'T KNOW. MAYBE THE WORLD
REALLY IS CHANGING.
[ Man Screaming ]
[ Man ]
STOP THE VOICES!
NURSE, UH, I'M LOOKING
FOR MY DAUGHTER.
AT THE END OF THE HALL.
OH! OH, MY!
OH, MY ANGEL!
[ Grunts ]
DADDY?
WHERE--
OH! OH, THANK YOU, LORD.
MY ANGEL, I AM SO SORRY.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
- IT WASN'T YOUR FAULT.
- IT IS ALL MY FAULT.
ARE YOU OKAY?
THEY KEPT ME DRUGGED
IN I.C.U. FOR THREE WEEKS.
YOU'RE THE FIRST VISITOR
I'VE SEEN.
YEAH. I NOTICED.
YEAH, IT'S A DAMN GOOD THING,
ANGEL, HUH?
THOSE BASTARDS
DON'T KNOW WHERE I AM.
THEY DON'T KNOW I'M HERE,
AND WE'RE GONNA KEEP IT
THAT WAY.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
EQUATORIAL AFRICA.
THE TRIUMVIRATE MUST BE HAPPY
THEY GOT JAROD BACK.
OH, YEAH,
YOU'D THINK SO.
INSTEAD, THEY THREW ONE
RIGHT NASTY SOIREE...
FOR ME
AND THAT WHEEZING
BASTARD RAINES.
I'M BEGINNING TO WONDER
ABOUT HIS LOYALTY.
BEGINNING TO--
THE BULLET IN MY BACK
WAS MEANT FOR YOU.
[ Chuckling ]
CAN'T KILL A PARKER.
NEVER.
I GOT BRIGITTE OUT ALREADY.
GOTTA KEEP THAT BABY.
GOTTA HAVE THAT BABY,
ESPECIALLY ALIVE.
DADDY, WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON?
SAME AS USUAL-- JAROD.
HE'S THE KEY TO OUR
SURVIVAL-- ALL OF US.
OH, CAN'T TALK.
NOT HERE. NOT NOW.
YOU'RE SCARING ME.
OH, WE CAN'T HAVE THAT.
I MEAN, THAT'S WHAT THEY WANT.
CAN'T HAVE THAT.
CAN'T GIVE THEM THE EDGE.
- [ Clears Throat ]
- SHE'S NOT SUPPOSED TO
HAVE VISITORS.
- I WAS JUST LEAVING.
- ME TOO.
I'M DISCHARGING MYSELF.
- ONLY YOUR PSYCHIATRIST
CAN DISCHARGE YOU.
- THE PSYCHIATRIST?
I WAS SHOT!
SINCE WHEN DO HEAD SHRINKERS
USE SCALPELS?
[ Man ]
I WANT MY MOMMY!
OH, SHE PROBABLY WENT
TO CALL SOMEBODY.
I HOPE I CAN TRUST YOU NOT
TO TELL ANYBODY I WAS HERE.
DADDY, DON'T LEAVE ME.
I'LL COME BACK
WHEN I CAN EXPLAIN. HUH?
OH, WHO WAS THAT,
UH, PLAYWRIGHT WITH
THE WHITE BEARD?
YOUR MOTHER USED TO
READ HIM ALL THE TIME--
WITH ALL THAT PUNCTUATION.
- SHAW?
- YEAH, WELL, WHATEVER.
LISTEN, THERE'S A QUOTE
I WANT YOU TO REMEMBER.
"A FAMILY IS A TYRANNY...
RULED OVER
BY ITS WEAKEST MEMBER."
ITS WEAKEST MEMBER.
DON'T FORGET THAT.
OH, DADDY.
DADDY. DADDY.
♪ KRI KRA TOAD'S FOOT ♪
♪ GEESE WALK BAREFOOT ♪♪
SO WHAT'S IN STORE TONIGHT?
ANOTHER DATE WITH MR. LYLE'S
JUMPER CABLE?
DIFFERENT GAME
THIS TIME, JAROD.
ARE WE TAKING ANOTHER TRIP?
THIS TIME IT'S NOT
SO DEPENDABLE.
VACCINES. HEPATITIS "A,"
MALARIA, TYPHOID.
- AFRICA.
- YOU ARE AS SMART
AS THEY SAY.
- LOT OF GOOD
IT'S DONE ME LATELY.
- ARM.
[ Grunts ]
♪ KRI KRA TOAD'S FOOT ♪
[ Sydney ]
TELL ME WHERE JAROD IS,
ANGELO.
FIND HIM FOR ME.
HEY. WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
I'M USING ANGELO'S EMPATHETIC
ABILITIES TO TRY AND DETERMINE
WHERE JAROD IS BEING KEPT.
HOW DOES THE, UH, FREAK
WITH THE FLOWBEE FIT IN?
IN CASE OF SUSPICIONS,
I WANTED THE LAB TO BE
BUSINESS AS USUAL.
AH. USUAL.
SYDNEY. SCARED.
YES, ANGELO.
SYDNEY IS SCARED THAT HE'LL
NEVER SEE JAROD AGAIN.
EMPATH JAROD.
TELL ME WHERE
THEY'RE HOLDING HIM.
- [ Broots ] ANY LUCK?
- NOT YET. YOU?
I FOUND SOME BREAD CRUMBS
THAT MAY LEAD US TO MISS PARKER.
A SHORT CALL COMES IN AT THE
EXACT SAME TIME FROM A HOSPITAL
50 MILES WEST OF HERE.
PATIENT UPDATE.
EXACTLY.
BEFORE I COULD TRACK WHERE
THE CALLS WENT TO, LYLE'S ALBINO
CAME BLUSTERING IN.
SOMETHING ABOUT
A PRIORITY COMMUNICATION.
SOMETHING CALLED
SI-- SILENCE.
SILENCE, HUH?
[ Angelo ]
ANGELO HAPPY. FIND JAROD.
IF YOU WANNA HEAR
ABOUT MOMMY AND DADDY,
JUST TRUST ME.
[ Whispering ]
JAROD. JAROD.
SYDNEY.
ARE YOU OKAY?
IS IT TRUE?
IS IT TRUE THAT THEY CAPTURED
MY FATHER AND THE BOY?
DID LYLE TELL YOU THAT?
HE SAID ONLY ONE OF THEM
SURVIVED, AND I'D FIND OUT
WHICH ONE IN AFRICA,
IF I COOPERATE.
YOU TRUST LYLE?
DON'T YOU?
[ Door Opens ]
WELL, DON'T YOU, SYDNEY?
I SEE EVEN YOU
FOUND THIS NEEDLE
IN OUR LITTLE HAYSTACK.
I WONDER HOW.
I NEVER LIKED YOU.
I'M NOT EVEN SURE
WHAT THE HELL YOU ARE.
COME ON, JAROD.
TIME TO GO.
NO INJECTIONS
THIS TIME, JAROD.
- [ Pills Rattling ]
- SEDATIVES.
- JAROD.
- IT'S OKAY, SYDNEY.
- I PREFER TO SLEEP
THROUGH THIS.
- JAROD, DON'T!
LYLE, I WON'T ALLOW THIS!
DENY IT AS SWEET SORROW
IF YOU WANT, SYDNEY,
BUT YOU TWO ARE PARTING,
SO BE A MAN.
SAY ADIOS.
GOOD-BYE, SYDNEY.
TONGUE?
THAT-A-BOY.
UH, SYDNEY?
PUT HIM AWAY.
JAROD'S SOUL IS CLOUDED.
HIS MIND IS STILL SHARP.
GOOD NIGHT, SWEET PRINCE.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
THE TOWER CALLED.
WE HAVE A PRIORITY PASSENGER
TO BE DROPPED OFF.
LEVEL "A" PROJECT
CALLED SILENCE.
UNTIL WE CROSS THE ATLANTIC,
WE'RE NOT STOPPIN'
ANYWHERE FOR ANYONE.
[ Man ]
MR. LYLE SAYS WE ARE.
I'LL TELL YOU WHERE WE'RE GOING
WHEN WE GET IN THE AIR.
YES, MR. LYLE.
I HAVE THE BLUEPRINTS
AND EVERYTHING I NEED.
TELL OUR CLIENTS AT RAYLOR
THAT AS SOON AS OUR INSIDE
PERSON GETS THE E.T.A.,
SILENCE WILL GO DOWN
FLAWLESSLY THIS TIME.
WELL, THE C-4 WILL CATALYZE
THE ON-SITE ACCELERANT
AND BURN WHITE HOT.
EVEN IF SOMEONE COULD DIG
THROUGH THE DEBRIS,
OUR CORPORATE CUSTOMERS
CAN REST ASSURED...
THERE'LL BE NO TRACE
OF EVEN THE TIMING DEVICE
THAT SURVIVES.
OH, I GUARANTEE YOU--
THERE'LL BE NO TRACE LEFT
OF THE NASH FAMILY...
ANY RESIDUAL FALLOUT WILL
JUST HELP TO MASK THE I.D.'s
OF OUR INTENDED TARGETS.
I'LL CONTACT YOU
WHEN I'M IN PLACE.
HAVEN'T YOU PEOPLE
DESTROYED ENOUGH LIVES?
WHAT THE HELL'S GOIN' ON?
IF A BULLET
PENETRATES THE JET'S SKIN,
IT CAN EXPLODE.
NOT IF SOMETHING
PLUGS THE HOLE.
[ Alarm Beeping ]
COME ON! COME ON!
- [ Gasps ]
- GOOD MORNING, SWEET PRINCE.
FORTUNATELY,
I WAS ABLE TO LAND THE PLANE
IN ALMOST ONE PIECE.
MY LUCKY DAY.
WHERE'S MR. WHITE?
HE DISAPPEARED.
ANY IDEA WHERE HE MIGHT
HAVE DISAPPEARED TO?
EVEN IF I KNEW,
I WOULDN'T TELL YOU.
[ Lyle ] YES, MUTUMBO,
I UNDERSTAND CLEARLY EVERY WORD
THAT YOU ARE SAYING,
AND I ASSURE YOU THAT
THE IRONY OF JAROD'S ESCAPE
IS NOT LOST ON ME EITHER.
[ Mutumbo On Phone ]
SIR, ARE YOU BEING FACETIOUS?
FACETIOUS? NO. NO.
OF COURSE I'M NOT BEING
FACETIOUS, SIR.
[ Mutumbo ]
YOU UNDERSTAND?
YES, I UNDERSTAND THE
IMPORTANCE OF REACQUIRING JAROD
AS IT RELATES TO SILENCE, SIR,
BUT, AS YOU KNOW,
WE HAVE AN INSIDE PERSON.
SO, OUR FRIENDS AT RAYLOR CAN
REST ASSURED THAT THE PROJECT
WILL NOT BE COMPROMISED.
- [ Mutumbo ] IT BETTER NOT BE.
- YES, SIR. YOU HAVE MY WORD.
ALL RIGHT.
IT SEEMS LIKE THE WORLD
HASN'T CHANGED SO MUCH.
OKAY, SYDNEY,
YOU WERE RIGHT,
AND I WAS WRONG.
BUT I WOULD RATHER
BE ALIVE AND WRONG
THAN DEAD RIGHT.
AND IF WE DON'T
GET JAROD BACK,
I'M NOT THE ONLY ONE MUTUMBO'S
GONNA PERSONALLY REEDUCATE.
- OH. OH, SORRY
FOR BURSTING IN.
- WHAT?
YOU WON'T BELIEVE
WHO I JUST SAW WALKIN' AROUND
THE HALLWAYS ALIVE AS DAY.
I MEAN, RUMOR HAS IT
HE'S SUPPOSED TO BE DEAD,
BUT HE'S, UH, NOT.
[ Wheezing ]
GLAD TO DISAPPOINT YOU.
HUH.
[ Gasps ]
IT'S GOOD TO BE BACK
IN THE BOSOM OF THE CENTRE.
GOD BLESS YOU ALL!
NOW, LET'S GO CATCH JAROD.
AMEN.
A PH.D. IN NUCLEAR PHYSICS
FROM M.I.T. AND A DOCTORATE IN
RADIOISOTOPIC DESIGN FROM USC.
THAT'S A PRETTY
IMPRESSIVE SHEEPSKIN.
YOU SEE WHAT THEY LOOK LIKE
ON THE INTERNET, PRESS PRINT,
AND YOU'RE SOMEBODY ELSE.
OH, UH, JEANIE,
THIS IS DR. JAROD HICKUM.
HELPED DESIGN
THE PROPULSION SYSTEM ON
THE CASSINI PROBE FOR NASA.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
WEREN'T THOSE
RUSSIAN-MADE REACTORS?
I BELIEVE
THAT YOU'RE THINKING
OF THE TOPAZ II.
THE CASSINI'S REACTORS WERE
CHANDON DESIGNED, WITH 72 POUNDS
OF 238 AT THE CORE.
WELL, I HOPE
YOUR EXPERTISE CAN HELP US
WITH THE NEPTUNE PROBE.
WE'RE, UM, THREE MONTHS
BEHIND SCHEDULE.
AND WE'VE LOST OUR TWO
BEST RESEARCHERS.
[ Jarod ]
WELL, I'M HERE
TO DO EVERYTHING I CAN.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
SYDNEY.
MISS PARKER.
MISS PARKER,
WE'VE BEEN SEARCHING
EVERYWHERE FOR YOU.
THANK GOD YOU'RE--
ALIVE? HARDLY.
AND THESE MORONS IN HERE
WON'T LET ME OUT.
OH, I GET MY STRENGTH BACK,
I SWEAR I'M GOING POSTAL.
THAT'S WHAT
THEY'RE AFRAID OF.
ACCORDING TO THIS CHART,
YOU WERE ADMITTED UNDER
A SUICIDE WATCH.
SUICIDE?
I WAS SHOT IN THE BACK!
- ONLY YOUR NEXT OF KIN
CAN OKAY YOUR DISCHARGE.
- NEXT OF KIN.
PARKER, HAVE YOU HEARD
FROM YOUR FATHER?
- NO.
- WELL, SOMEBODY SURE WANTS
TO KEEP YOU IN HERE.
- YEAH, THE WHEEZING
SACK OF BONES RAINES.
- I'M NOT CERTAIN THAT'S RIGHT.
RAINES MAY HAVE SPENT
SOME TIME ON MUTUMBO'S
SIDE OF THE STREET,
BUT HE'S ACTING
MORE LIKE HE'S BEEN IN
MISTER ROGERS' NEIGHBORHOOD.
HE FOUND RELIGION--
OR IT WAS GIVEN TO HIM.
I DON'T BUY IT.
THERE'S SOMETHIN'
GOIN' DOWN AT THE CENTRE,
AND THEY DON'T WANT ME AROUND.
LYLE KEEPS SAYING, "THE WORLD
IS CHANGING." BESIDES RAINES'S
REBIRTH, JAROD HAS ESCAPED.
LYLE HAS SOME ALBINO
RUNNING A PRIORITY PROJECT
CALLED SILENCE.
I GOTTA GET OUTTA HERE.
[ Groans ]
YOU STILL NEED REST.
AT LEAST ANOTHER 24 HOURS.
TWENTY-FOUR HOURS,
AND THEN I'M BLOWIN'
THIS CAT SCAN STAND.
I WANT YOU TO FIND OUT
EVERYTHING YOU CAN ABOUT
THE ALBINO AND SILENCE.
THEY MAY HAVE ME DOWN,
BUT I'LL BE DAMNED
IF I'M OUT. GO!
[ Chattering ]
- JAROD.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- JEANIE. HI.
I WAS TRYING TO GET A LEG UP
ON THINGS AND I THOUGHT I WOULD
GO STRAIGHT TO THE SOURCE.
WHAT PART OF THE PROJECT
WERE THE NASHES WORKING ON?
THEY WERE HEADING UP
THE RESEARCH FOR RAYLOR
CORPORATION'S PROPULSION SYSTEM.
THEY MADE
SOME INCREDIBLE DISCOVERIES
WITH MULTIPLE APPLICATIONS.
BUT MOST OF THEIR WORK
WAS SEALED AFTER THE ACCIDENT.
- ACCIDENT?
- YEAH, A FREAK THING.
THEIR SAILBOAT BLEW UP
WHILE IN PORT IN THE CARIBBEAN.
A GAS LEAK OR SOMETHING.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE THEY'RE DEAD.
- MAYBE THEY'RE NOT.
WHO SEALED THE DATA?
THE WORD WAS IT ALL WENT
TO THE DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY
OFFICE IN ALBANY.
[ Phone Ringing ]
THIS IS SYDNEY.
I HEAR SILENCE IS GOLDEN,
ESPECIALLY AT THE CENTRE.
THERE IS A PROJECT
CALLED SILENCE, BUT GOD
ONLY KNOWS WHAT IT IS.
- IS THAT MR. BROOTS I HEAR?
- YEAH. HOW'D YOU KNOW?
DEVIATED SEPTUM.
RIGHT NOSTRIL.
WELL, I DID GET BEANED
WITH AN ETCH A SKETCH
WHEN I WAS SEVEN--
WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME
ABOUT SILENCE?
JUST THAT LYLE AND
SOME WEIRD-LOOKING ALBINO GUY
WERE TALKIN' ABOUT IT.
[ Jarod ]
AH, YES. THE WHITE-HAIRED MAN.
HE AND I SHARED
SOME FREQUENT-FLYER MILES.
I CAN'T TALK TO YOU ABOUT THIS.
WE'RE-- WE'RE SUPPOSED TO
BE TRYIN' TO CATCH YOU.
I KNOW WHERE YOU LIVE,
MR. BROOTS.
EVEN IF WE DID
FIND SOMETHING OUT
ABOUT SILENCE--
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
GOING ON AROUND HERE.
I MEAN,
THEY TURNED MR. RAINES
INTO PAT ROBERTSON.
SILENCE IS ABOUT
THE CENTRE KILLING A MAN,
WOMAN AND THEIR CHILD.
NOW, LYLE AND THE ALBINO
HAVE AN INSIDE PERSON
HELPING THEM.
MY GUESS IS SOMEONE WITHIN
THE DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY.
- I NEED HELP FINDING OUT WHO.
- WE'LL DO OUR BEST.
WELL, YOU'D BETTER,
BECAUSE IF YOU DON'T,
AN INNOCENT FAMILY
IS GOING TO DIE.
[ Beeps ]
[ Siren Blaring ]
SO, WHO'S THIS NEW HOTSHOT
JOINING THE NASH DETAIL,
INSPECTOR?
HIS NAME IS JAROD WATTS,
BUT HE IS HARDLY A HOTSHOT.
BOTTOM THIRD IN COLLEGE,
BARELY SQUEAK-BY I.Q.
THIS GUY HAS BEEN BOUNCED
AROUND FROM ONE MEDIOCRE
ASSIGNMENT TO THE NEXT.
- BUT HE HAS ONE THING ON HIS
RÉSUMÉ THAT NONE OF US HAVE.
- [ Woman ] WHAT'S THAT?
- THE SAME LAST NAME
AS THE UNDERSECRETARY.
- SON?
- NEPHEW.
- OH.
I'M SORRY I'M, UH, LATE.
SO--
SORRY.
UH, JAROD WATTS.
THE REASON I'M LATE IS
I WAS DOING A LITTLE BONING UP
ON THAT NASH THING.
THE "NASH THING"
IS A P-1 WITNESS PROTECTION
TRANSFER, WATTS.
- PLEASE DON'T FORGET THAT.
- UH, YES, SIR.
NOW THEN--
[ Loud Clattering ]
AGENT TIMSON WILL CONTINUE
TO BE POINT ON THE CLARE NASH
PROTECTION TEAM...
UP UNTIL SHE IS REUNITED
WITH HUSBAND AND DAUGHTER.
I'LL BE MAINTAINING
A CODE 3 SECURITY STATUS
ON THE NASH WOMAN.
EXCUSE ME.
UH, ISN'T A CODE 3
A LITTLE BIT THIN?
THAT'S THE IDEA, WATTS.
YOU SEE, A CODE 3
PROVIDES PROTECTION WITHOUT
DRAWING UNDUE ATTENTION...
TO THE LOCATION
SAID WITNESS
IS BEING HELD.
- IT'S REALLY QUITE EFFECTIVE.
- YES, SIR. CODE 3.
[ Chuckling ]
AGENT CARLSON.
PLEASE, TRY TO BRING WATTS UP
TO SPEED ON THE "NASH THING."
I'LL TOLERATE
NO MISTAKES.
THAT'S LUNCH.
ANGEL, IT'S DADDY.
I LOOKED FOR YOU AT THE
HOSPITAL, BUT YOU'RE GONE.
YOU CAN'T KEEP A PARKER
UNDER WRAPS. NO, SIRREE.
UH, WHAT I NEED TO TELL YOU
HAS TO BE SAID FACE-TO-FACE.
I'LL BE AT YOUR PLACE
TONIGHT AT 9:00.
NOW, YOU BE ALONE.
ERASE THIS TAPE.
I WOULDN'T WANT
THE WRONG PEOPLE SHOWIN' UP.
WRONG PEOPLE. RAINES.
[ Carlson ]
THE NASHES' NUCLEAR RESEARCH
FOR THE RAYLOR CORPORATION...
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE
STRICTLY FOR SPACE
PROPULSION APPLICATIONS.
BUT WHEN THEY SUSPECTED RAYLOR
WAS SELLIN' THEIR WORK
FOR WEAPONS APPLICATIONS,
THEY DECIDED TO BLOW
THE WHISTLE TO THE D.O.E.
THAT'S WHEN SOMEONE TRIED
TO KILL THEM ON THE BOAT.
ARE THERE ANY LEADS?
NONE. COMPLETELY
PROFESSIONAL JOB.
IT TURNED OUT TO BE ALMOST
AS GOOD AS KILLING THEM.
HOW'S THAT?
WELL, THE NASHES
GOT SEPARATED IN THE MAYHEM,
AND IT DROVE THEM UNDERGROUND.
UNTIL THE D.O.E. FOUND
JASON NASH AND HIS DAUGHTER
LIVING IN THE CARIBBEAN.
THEY WERE PLACED
IN PROTECTIVE CUSTODY.
JASON NASH SAID HE'D TESTIFY
IF HIS WIFE WAS FOUND AND THEY
WERE REUNITED AS A FAMILY.
WE JUST RECENTLY
FOUND CLARE.
TOMORROW AT 3:00
WE BRING THEM ALL BACK TOGETHER
AT THE ATOMIC RESEARCH LAB.
FAMILY REUNITED,
FAMILY TALKS.
FAMILY TALKS,
FAMILY DIES.
MY WORK HERE IS MY LIFE.
I'VE SPENT YEARS HERE DOING
THE WORK OF THE LORD.
RAINES, IT'S TIME FOR YOU
TO PAY FOR KILLING MY MOTHER.
SAY YOUR PRAYERS,
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
MISS PARKER,
I'D LIKE TO INTRODUCE
FATHER CONNELLEY.
- HE WAS A FRIEND
OF YOUR MOTHER'S.
- HOW DO YOU DO?
I LOOK FORWARD TO YOU
CONTINUING WITH YOUR
GOOD WORK, MR. RAINES.
WHAT'S YOUR GOOD WORK?
FREE EXORCISMS
FOR THE WHACK JOBS
IN RENEWAL?
DO YOU BELIEVE IN MIRACLES,
MISS PARKER?
I BELIEVE
IN REVENGE.
NOW TELL ME, WHY DID YOU
TRY AND KILL DADDY?
A SELFISH, MISGUIDED ACT.
BUT IT CAME FROM ABOVE,
AS GOD IS MY WITNESS.
THIS KINDNESS CRAP
MAY SLAY 'EM
AT THE PARISH POTLUCK,
BUT IT AIN'T CUTTIN' IT
WITH ME.
THEN I'LL TURN
THE OTHER CHEEK.
MISS PARKER,
THOSE MIRACLES I MENTIONED--
THEY BEGIN WITH... LOVE.
WHEN I FIND OUT
WHAT YOU'RE UP TO,
IT'S GONNA TAKE A HELL
OF A LOT MORE THAN A PRAYER
TO SAVE YOUR SORRY ASS.
THANK YOU,
BUT I'M NOT HUNGRY.
MRS. NASH WON'T EAT?
- SHE'S A LITTLE FREAKED OUT.
- LET ME TRY.
I KNOW IT'S NOT GOURMET,
BUT YOU REALLY SHOULD EAT.
IT WILL HELP YOU
KEEP YOUR STRENGTH UP.
NO.
WHEN I WAS A KID,
IN THE PLACE I GREW UP IN,
I NEVER WANTED TO EAT EITHER.
WHY WAS THAT,
AGENT WATTS?
BECAUSE IT WASN'T MY BODY
THAT NEEDED NOURISHING.
IT WAS MY HEART.
THERE WASN'T
A MEAL SATISFYING ENOUGH
OR A ROOM SAFE ENOUGH...
TO HELP ME STOP MISSING
THE FAMILY THAT I WANTED
TO BE WITH SO BADLY.
WELL, WHERE'S
YOUR FAMILY NOW?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S THE NOT KNOWING,
THE WAITING, THAT'S
THE HARDEST PART.
BUT WHILE YOU WAIT,
MAYBE THIS CAN HELP.
C-COURTNEY GAVE ME THIS
FOR MOTHER'S DAY.
I THOUGHT I LOST IT FOREVER.
TOMORROW
YOU'LL BE BACK TOGETHER
WITH THE REAL THING.
I PROMISE YOU.
I MISS THE DAYS
WHEN THE PEOPLE
I COULDN'T TRUST...
WERE THE PEOPLE
I COULDN'T TRUST.
YOU'VE OBVIOUSLY MET
THE NEW MR. RAINES,
MISS PARKER.
NOW MEET MR. WHITE.
HE REPORTS TO LYLE.
SINCE WHEN DOES ANYBODY
REPORT TO MY BROTHER?
SINCE THE TRIUMVIRATE
GAVE HIM HIS OWN COVERT TEAM
A FEW YEARS AGO.
HIS LATEST PROJECT
IS CALLED SILENCE.
IT'S A CORPORATE-SPONSORED
CENTRE HIT ON A COUPLE
RESEARCH SCIENTISTS.
JAROD WAS ON THAT PLANE
WITH WHITE WHEN IT WENT DOWN.
HE KNOWS THOSE INNOCENT PEOPLE
WILL DIE IF HE DOESN'T STOP HIM.
YOU KNOW HE'LL TRY.
- IF JAROD'S GOING,
THEN SO AM I.
- HMM.
MISS PARKER'S
GONNA WANT TO OFF HERSELF
WHEN SHE HEARS THIS ONE.
CAN ANYBODY
SPARE A NOOSE?
MISS PARKER!
- IS YOUR NOSE WHISTLING?
- I HAVE A DEVIATED SEPTUM.
YOU KNOW, MR. PARKER
COULDN'T HAVE BEEN
THE NEXT OF KIN...
TO HAVE YOU COMMITTED
IN THAT HOSPITAL
ON THAT SUICIDE WATCH.
THE DATES DON'T SQUARE.
MUTUMBO HAD ALREADY
SIPHONED AWAY MR. PARKER.
SO, THE NEXT OF KIN
WOULD HAD TO HAVE BEEN--
LYLE.
LYLE TRAPPED ME THERE.
DADDY?
DADDY!
I'M SORRY I CAN'T BE THERE
TO TALK TO YOU FACE-TO-FACE,
BUT, UH, PLANS CHANGE, HUH?
AFTER ALL,
IT IS THE CENTRE, RIGHT?
NOW, I DON'T HAVE
A WHOLE HELL OF A LOT OF TIME,
SO PAY ATTENTION.
THE WORLD IS CHANGING.
THE CENTRE IS CHANGING.
I AM CHANGING.
AND YOU?
YOU HAVE TO RIDE ALL THIS
CRAZY STUFF OUT, SEE?
JUST, UH, RIDE HER OUT.
DON'T TRY TO FIND US.
AND ABOVE ALL ELSE, ANGEL,
WATCH OUT FOR YOURSELF.
DON'T FORGET--
"A FAMILY IS A TYRANNY"--
"RULED OVER
BY ITS WEAKEST MEMBER."
THANK GOD YOU'RE SAFE.
YOU HAD ME WORRIED.
ABOUT WHAT?
THAT SUICIDAL SIS MIGHT PLAY
A LITTLE GAME OF RAZOR ROULETTE?
THE SUICIDE WATCH WAS
FOR YOUR OWN PROTECTION.
OH.
NOT PERFECT, BUT IT WAS
ALL I COULD THINK OF.
THE MORE THE OTHERS THOUGHT
YOU WERE A NONFACTOR,
THE SAFER YOU'D BE.
OTHERS?
THE SAME ONES
THAT GOT TO RAINES,
THAT PUT THE SCARE
INTO OUR FATHER.
WHICH CONVENIENTLY
PUT YOU IN CHARGE.
MUTUMBO SNAPS, I JUMP.
GUILTY.
YOU AND YOUR TEAM--
I KNOW ALL ABOUT
YOUR COVERT DIVISION.
MR. WHITE. SILENCE.
GOOD, BECAUSE I
NEED YOUR HELP.
LOOK, I'M BEING
STRAIGHT HERE.
SILENCE IS
A LEVEL "A" CONTRACT.
THE LAST THING I NEEDED
WAS FOR JAROD TO ESCAPE
AND MAKE THIS HIS CAUSE.
CAREFUL.
YOU'RE SWEATING.
WELL, WITH JAROD HOVERING,
I'D BE STUPID NOT TO.
YOU BOTCH A LEVEL "A,"
AND YOU'LL NEED MY PRAYERS,
NOT MY HELP.
I NEED MY SISTER.
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN
A SURVIVOR, PARKER,
BUT IN THE PAST YEAR SINCE
I FOUND MY FATHER AND YOU,
I-- I'VE REALIZED IT'S NOT
JUST ME AGAINST THE WORLD.
I HEAR THE WORLD'S
CHANGING.
ONE LOOK INTO DAD'S EYES
CONFIRMS IT.
DESPITE THAT, THE CENTRE'S
ALWAYS BEEN ABOUT PARKERS.
AND LIKE IT OR NOT,
YOU AND I ARE IT.
LET'S FIGHT FOR IT,
FOR US--
FOR HIM.
[ Chiming ]
TIMSON.
TIMSON!
[ Grunts ]
WHERE IS SHE?
WHERE'S CLARE NOW?
JAROD! GONE. SHE'S
BEEN TAKEN OUT TO GO MEET
HER HUSBAND AND DAUGHTER.
YOU WEREN'T TOLD ABOUT
THE SCHEDULE CHANGE?
NO, I WASN'T.
OUT OF THE BLUE,
THE TRANSFER ORDERS
WERE MOVED UP TO NOON.
TIMSON.
YEAH.
THEY WERE HIS ORDERS.
WHEN I ASKED FOR DETAILS,
HE SAID IT WAS
"NEED TO KNOW ONLY."
GUESS TIMSON DOESN'T THINK
YOU AND I NEED TO.
GLAD TO SEE YOU'VE DECIDED
TO TAKE UP THE FIGHT.
I DIDN'T COME TO HELP YOU.
I CAME TO RECAPTURE JAROD.
[ Beeping ]
IT WON'T BE LONG NOW,
MRS. NASH.
THANK YOU.
[ Man On Radio ]
AGENT BLAINE.
- WE'RE IN POSITION.
- ROGER THAT.
- SIR, "B" TEAM HAS MR. NASH AND
THEIR LITTLE GIRL IN POSITION.
- VERY GOOD.
[ Door Opens ]
WELL, THIS IS AN HONOR.
MURDERERS HAVE NO HONOR.
NO, NO, NO.
MEETING YOU.
I MEAN, MY GOD,
YOU'RE JAROD.
DIDN'T HAVE MUCH CHANCE
TO TALK ON THE PLANE.
BY THE WAY, I OWE YOU
FOR SOME GREAT, GREAT FLYING.
THOUGHT I WAS TOAST.
WHERE'S THE BOMB?
YOU KNOW WHERE THE BOMB IS,
OTHERWISE YOU WOULDN'T BE HERE.
NOW, THAT SAID,
I'M LEAVING.
- I DON'T LIVE,
I DON'T GET PAID.
- YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
WAS IT GOOD
SEEING YOUR DAD AGAIN?
I MEAN,
YOU JUST BEAT ME TO HIM.
BUT, HEY, HE'S NOW
OUT THERE AGAIN,
AND IT KIND OF
KEEPS ME IN BUSINESS,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
BUSINESS?
I'M A FINDER.
MISSING FAMILIES
ARE KIND OF MY NICHE.
AND YOURS IS
A FULL-TIME JOB, BROTHER.
WHAT ARE YOU GETTING AT?
WELL, JUST THAT
OCCASIONALLY MR. LYLE...
WILL, UH, PAY ME
FOR SPECIAL PROJECTS.
TAKE YOUR SISTER, EMILY,
FOR EXAMPLE.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT MY SISTER?
THAT SHE ADORES YELLOW TULIPS,
SHE HATES CRUELTY TO ANIMALS,
SHE'S SMART, SHE'S FUNNY,
SHE'S TORTURED
BY THE TRAGEDIES
OF HER FAMILY...
AND THAT SHE HAS THE CUTEST
LITTLE TATTOO JUST ABOVE HER--
UH-UH-UH!
HER LAST KNOWN ADDRESS
IS IN HERE.
THERE MIGHT EVEN BE SOME TIDBITS
ABOUT DEAR OLD MOM TOO.
SHAME TO SEE IT ALL GO POOF.
THERE MAY BE TIME FOR YOU
TO SAVE THAT FAMILY UPSTAIRS,
MAYBE EVEN TIME FOR YOU
TO SAVE THIS FAMILY IN HERE.
BUT YOU DO NOT GET ME
IN THE PACKAGE.
I'LL SEE YOU
ON DOWN THE ROAD.
NO. NO!
[ Grunts ]
WE'LL HAVE A BETTER CHANCE
OF CATCHING JAROD
IF WE SPLIT UP.
YOU THREE TAKE THE INTERIOR,
AND I'LL COVER OUTSIDE.
FINE.
CAN I SEE MY HUSBAND
AND DAUGHTER NOW?
SOON. VERY SOON, MA'AM.
VERY SOON, MA'AM.
[ Rings ]
OH, EXCUSE ME.
THIS IS TIMSON.
YES, SIR.
ABSOLUTELY, SIR.
IF I'M NOT BACK IN,
UH, FIVE MINUTES,
GO AHEAD AND BRING IN
NASH AND THE GIRL.
- IT WON'T BE LONG NOW, MA'AM.
- THANKS.
- SURE.
- OH, THERE YOU ARE.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I JUST CAME FROM
INSPECTOR WOCHECK'S OFFICE.
HE SUSPECTS
THERE'S A CONTRACT OUT
ON MRS. NASH'S LIFE,
AND THEY THINK THE HITTER
MIGHT BE WITHIN THE D.O.E.
AH. UH, BLAINE,
YOU AND JAROD HERE
KEEP WATCH.
I'M GOING OUT
TO THE MOBILE UNIT
TO CONTACT THE INSPECTOR.
I CAN SAVE YOU
THAT TRIP, SIR.
NO, I GOTTA GO.
INSPECTOR WOCHECK IS GONNA
CALL ME ON THIS CELL PHONE
AT 12:00 SHARP.
THAT'S ONLY A FEW MINUTES AWAY.
I HAVE TO REVIEW THE PLACEMENT
OF MY AGENT PERIMETERS.
- YOU CAN USE MY WALKIE, SIR.
- I DON'T WANT TO USE
YOUR DAMN WALKIE!
SPEAK WHEN YOU'RE
SPOKEN TO, AGENT.
EXCUSE ME.
IS THERE SOMETHING
THE MATTER?
- NO.
- YOU SEEM LIKE YOU'RE IN
A HURRY TO GET SOMEWHERE.
- WHAT THE HELL'S WRONG
WITH THIS THING?
- NOTHING.
IT'S JUST, UH--
WELL, IT'S, UH--
IT'S LOCKED.
- OPEN IT.
- WHAT'S THE RUSH?
OPEN THE DAMN DOOR! NOW!
I-I DON'T UNDERSTAND. I--
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
THE PROBLEM IS,
IF YOU DON'T OPEN THE DOOR,
WE'RE GONNA BLOW UP, YOU IDIOT!
- OH, MY GOD.
- OH, YOU MEAN THIS THING
I FOUND IS A BOMB?
- [ Beeping ]
- DO SOMETHING!
- KABOOM!
- [ Screams ]
I FIND IT INTERESTING
THAT YOU KNEW THERE WAS
A BOMB IN THE BUILDING,
BUT YOU DIDN'T BOTHER
TO TELL ANYBODY.
YOU WERE GOING TO ALLOW
AN INNOCENT FAMILY TO DIE--
AND YOUR OWN MEN--
IN AN EXPLOSION.
AND FOR WHAT?
AGENT BLAINE?
GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
IT WOULD BE
MY PLEASURE, JAROD.
I THINK YOU'RE HERE
TO SEE SOME SPECIAL PEOPLE.
YEAH.
[ Gasps ]
OH, MY BABY!
[ Jarod ]
THERE'S A BROWN SEDAN
IN THE PARKING LOT.
HERE'S ALL THE INFORMATION
YOU NEED TO START YOUR NEW LIFE.
YOU'LL BE SAFE.
I PROMISE YOU.
BUT-- BUT WHO ARE YOU?
NO, IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WE CAN TRUST HIM.
OH, JAROD, I HOPE THAT ONE DAY
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY CAN FEEL
THIS MOMENT TOO.
[ Kisses,
Chuckles ]
GOOD LUCK.
BYE.
- PARKER.
- OUR WORK'S DONE HERE.
WHAT, HE GOT AWAY? HOW?
YOU SHOULDN'T
UNDERESTIMATE JAROD.
MM-MMM.
AND YOU SHOULD NEVER
UNDERESTIMATE ME.
AND THE NEXT TIME THAT
YOU SEND ME INTO A BUILDING
THAT'S GONNA EXPLODE,
IT HAD BETTER BLOW,
BECAUSE IF IT DOESN'T,
IT'S GONNA BE
YOUR GRAY MATTER...
THEY'LL BE MOPPING UP
WITH A TOOTHBRUSH.
BY THE WAY,
JAROD LEFT YOU SOMETHING.
[ Mr. Parker
On Answering Machine ]
OH, MY ANGEL.
GOD, I'M SORRY I MISSED YOU.
I WANTED TO HEAR YOUR VOICE.
NEEDED TO.
NOW, IF YOU DON'T HEAR FROM ME,
DON'T YOU WORRY.
BRIGITTE AND I ARE SAFE.
AT LEAST I THINK I AM.
IT'S ALWAYS WHEN YOU THINK
YOU ARE, THAT'S WHEN YOU'RE
THE MOST VULNERABLE.
NOW, DON'T YOU MAKE
THE SAME MISTAKE I DID.
NOW, DON'T EXPOSE
THE SOFT UNDERBELLY.
THEY TARGET THAT.
NO, NO, NO. YOU CATCH JAROD
AND NEVER, EVER LET HIM GO.
DAMN IT! HE'S THE KEY.
HE'S THE ONLY KEY.
ALWAYS HAS BEEN.
AND THERE'S ONE LAST THING--
[ Sighs ]
'CAUSE I KNOW YOU'RE TOUGH,
I'M NOT WORRIED.
YOU WATCH YOUR BACK
AT THE CENTRE.
NOBODY'S WHAT
THEY SEEM TO BE.
THERE'S NO SOUL IN THAT PLACE--
NOT ONE-- THAT YOU CAN TRUST,
WITH THE POSSIBLE EXCEPTION
OF YOUR BROTHER.
[ Chattering ]
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
MY NAME IS JAROD.
HAVE YOU SEEN THIS WOMAN?
LIKE I SAID,
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
I'M HER BROTHER.
DAMN. SHE'S GONNA
BE SORRY SHE MISSED YOU,
BUT SHE JUST LEFT TODAY.
SHE WOULDN'T SAY WHERE.
SORT OF LIKE SHE THOUGHT SOMEONE
WAS FOLLOWIN' HER. SWEET GIRL.
WAS SHE ALONE?
YEAH, BUT SHE
DIDN'T WANT TO BE.
SHE WAS SEARCHIN' FOR
HER FAMILY. SAID SHE WAS
DETERMINED TO FIND THEM.
LIKE I SAID,
SHE'D BE SORRY
IF SHE KNEW SHE MISSED YOU.
YEAH.
[ Electricity Crackling ]
[ Rings ]
WHAT?
AT LEAST WE PUT
ONE FAMILY BACK TOGETHER.
- WHILE MINE
GOT RIPPED APART AGAIN.
- I KNOW THE FEELING.
YOU KNOW, JAROD,
MAYBE LYLE'S RIGHT.
MAYBE THE WORLD IS CHANGING.
IT DOESN'T SEEM TO MATTER
HOW MUCH IT CHANGES.
IT'S STILL THE SAME FOR US.
WE'RE STILL ALONE IN IT.