[ Man ]
JAROD BOOKED OUT OF HERE
A COUPLE DAYS AGO.
I SURE MISS THAT OLD BOY.
TO KNOW HIM IS TO LOVE HIM.
AMEN, BROTHER.
I KIND OF TOOK HIM
UNDER MY WING, SO TO SPEAK.
YEAH, I KEPT MY EYE ON HIM.
I'M SURE THAT'S
JUST LIKE YOU, JUNIOR, ALWAYS
THINKING OF THE OTHER GUY.
I BELIEVE IN HELPIN' THOSE
LESS FORTUNATE.
"DARWIN TRANSPORT."
YEP, THIS IS IT.
- THIS IS WHAT?
JAROD STAYED IN THAT?
- YEP.
HE'D LOCK HIMSELF IN THERE
FOR THREE, FOUR DAYS AT A TIME.
PAID ME TO CHECK IN ON HIM
NOW AND AGAIN.
YOU KNOW,
BRING HIM A LITTLE BREAD,
SOME WATER, CHAIN HIM UP--
[ Together ]
CHAIN HIM UP?
LIVE AND LET LIVE.
THAT'S MY MOTTO, ESPECIALLY WHEN
THERE'S CASH COMIN' MY WAY.
HELL, HE'D EVEN ASK ME
TO ZAP HIM WITH A CAR BATTERY
NOW AND THEN.
WHATEVER TURNS YOU ON,
I GUESS.
- WHY, JAROD!
- JAROD!
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU WAS IN THERE!
I GOT YA, DIDN'T I?
[ Wheezy Laugh ]
BUY YOURSELF
A FIFTH OF HAPPINESS.
I COULDN'T GET
A SHOT OF JOY FOR THIS.
THERE'S NO PLACE LIKE HOME.
WELL, THEY SAY
THERE'S A FINE LINE
BETWEEN GENIUS AND INSANITY.
[ Miss Parker ]
JAROD'S LINE WAS ERASED
LONG AGO.
HUH. WHAT'S A HOME
WITHOUT TV?
THAT'S JAROD'S HANDWRITING.
SINCE WHEN DO WE FOLLOW
HIS DIRECTIONS?
THERE'S ALWAYS A METHOD
TO JAROD'S MADNESS.
SO IF IT SAYS DON'T TOUCH,
DON'T TOUCH.
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
[ Miss Parker ]
LYLE!
OH, NO.
IT WON'T BUDGE.
JUNIOR? JUNIOR!
[ Junior ]
SEE YOU LATER,
MISS PARKER, MR. LYLE!
OH, DAMN IT!
WE NEVER TOLD THAT
SCUM-TOOTHED IDIOT OUR NAMES!
JAROD SET THIS UP.
NOW WE'RE HIS PRISONERS.
[ Helicopter Passing Overhead ]
WORST HEAT WAVE
WE'VE HAD IN YEARS,
AND THIS ONE'S BEEN LOCKED
IN THE HOLE FOR THREE DAYS.
WE'RE GONNA NEED TO
SCRAPE HIM OUT WITH A SHOVEL.
[ Jarod ]
THANKS, BUT THAT
WON'T BE NECESSARY.
I COULD USE A SHOWER, THOUGH.
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE DEFENDS THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
[ Jarod ]
LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
♪♪ [ Jarod Whistling ]
GOOD MORNING, GENTLEMEN.
[ Groans ]
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
IF YOU DON'T MIND MY SAYING,
IT'S CREEPY THAT YOU JUST SPENT
THE LAST THREE DAYS IN THE SAME
HOLE OFFICER RION HUNG HIMSELF.
SOMETIMES, YOU GOTTA WALK
IN SOMEBODY ELSE'S SHOES...
TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT THEY'VE BEEN THROUGH.
CALL IT A... SIMULATION.
IS THAT SOMETHING
THEY TEACH YOU IN CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION TRAINING?
IT'S JUST SOMETHING
I PICKED UP AS A KID.
LIEUTENANT--
KIMBRALL. MOLLY KIMBRALL.
I'M WITH THE PROVOST
MARSHAL'S OFFICE.
JAROD STEVENS.
YEAH, I KNOW.
THE BASE'S GRAPEVINE
IS PRETTY MUCH SIZZLING...
WITH WORD THAT C.I.D.'S HERE
INVESTIGATING RION'S SUICIDE.
COLONEL DANCE ASSIGNED ME TO
ESCORT YOU AROUND. HE WANTS TO
SEE YOU IN HIS OFFICE A.S.A.P.
HE'S A LITTLE PISSED.
PISSED?
TICKED OFF.
- YOU KNOW, MAD?
- WHY SHOULD HE BE MAD?
I'VE ONLY KEPT HIM WAITING
72 HOURS AND 13 MINUTES.
[ Man ]
I AM HONORED YOU FINALLY DECIDED
TO PAY ME A VISIT,
EVEN IF IT DID TAKE YOU
THREE AND A HALF DAYS.
I WAS JUST DOING
A LITTLE RECON, TRYING
TO BE A GOOD SOLDIER.
THAT'S AN UNDERSTATEMENT.
TOP 10 IN YOUR CLASS
AT WEST POINT.
J.D. WITH HONORS.
GEORGETOWN LAW.
AND I SAW RAMBO 27 TIMES.
CAPTAIN SAUNDERS HERE
IS THE LEADER
OF RION'S TRAINING UNIT.
HE WAS THERE THE NIGHT HE DIED.
WE'LL BE DOING
SOME TALKING, CAPTAIN.
- MOST DEFINITELY.
- YOUR FILE TELLS ME DAMN NEAR
EVERYTHING EXCEPT YOUR RANK.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW IF YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO CALL ME "SIR."
WELL, THAT IS THE ARMY.
NOT ONLY DOES IT
PROMOTE THE INCOMPETENT,
BUT IT ALLOWS
C.I.D. OFFICERS LIKE MYSELF
TO KICK AROUND ANYONE...
FROM A PRIVATE TO A GENERAL
REGARDLESS OF RANK.
BUT IF IT MAKES YOU
FEEL ANY BETTER,
I'LL CALL YOU "SIR."
WOULD YOU EXCUSE US FOR NOW?
GLADLY, COLONEL.
LET ME KNOW IF THERE'S
ANYTHING I CAN DO TO HELP,
SIR.
AFTER YOU, LIEUTENANT.
OKAY, STEVENS, LET'S JUST STOP
ALL THIS NICE CRAP.
AGREED?
FAIR ENOUGH.
P.O.W. SURVIVAL TRAINING
IS ABOUT THE SYSTEMATIC
BREAKING DOWN...
OF A MAN'S PSYCHE,
HIS IDENTITY,
EVEN HIS WILL TO LIVE.
IT'S ABOUT SURVIVAL.
NOW, IT IS MY DUTY...
TO SEE WHO CAN AND CANNOT
PASS THAT TEST.
IF A MAN FAILS HERE,
HE GOES DOWN ALONE.
BUT IF HE FAILS THAT TEST
IN WAR, HE TAKES
HIS BROTHERS DOWN WITH HIM.
NOW, THAT'S ALL VERY NOBLE,
BUT LET ME TELL YOU
ABOUT MY DUTY, COLONEL.
YOUR DUTY IS AKIN
TO A SNAKE IN THE GRASS.
AROUND HERE, WE PROTECT
AND POLICE OUR OWN.
WE DON'T NEED SOME
PENTAGON COPPERHEAD
SLITHERING AROUND OUR FEET.
MAYBE THE LATE
WARRANT OFFICER RION DOES.
RION'S DEATH WAS
INVESTIGATED THOROUGHLY.
HE WAS IN THE HOLE
DURING P.O.W. TRAINING,
AND HE SNAPPED.
- AND MUTILATED
AND HUNG HIMSELF.
- HE SNAPPED!
NOW, ANY FURTHER INVESTIGATION
WILL BE A WASTE OF YOUR TIME...
AND, MORE IMPORTANTLY,
MINE.
RION'S PARENTS ARE CONVINCED
THAT THEIR SON'S DEATH
WAS NOT A SUICIDE.
THEY CAN'T ACCEPT THE FACT
THAT SCOTT KILLED HIMSELF.
NOW, IT AIN'T PRETTY,
BUT IT IS TRUE.
THE TRUTH IS EXACTLY
WHAT I INTEND TO FIND OUT,
SIR.
♪♪ [ Classical ]
[ Chuckles ]
WHOA.
YES, I'M STUDYING THE IMPACT
OF UNIQUE PHYSICAL
CHARACTERISTICS...
ON SENSORY PROCESSING.
I WOULD HAVE GUESSED THAT.
THERE'S SOMETHING WEIRD...
ABOUT THIS SHIPPING INVOICE
THAT JAROD LEFT
AT HIS LAST LAIR.
WEIRD HOW?
IT'S SUCH AN OBVIOUS CLUE.
IT'S LIKE JAROD WANTED MISS
PARKER AND MR. LYLE TO GO DOWN
TO TEXAS AND INVESTIGATE IT.
MAYBE HE DID.
WHAT ELSE DID JAROD LEAVE?
SOME ARMY STUFF--
MANUALS, BOOKS, EQUIPMENT.
A-- A WORN-OUT RAMBO VIDEO.
BUT THERE'S JUST SO MUCH STUFF,
I HAVEN'T HAD TIME
TO GO THROUGH IT ALL YET.
WE NEED TO ALERT
MISS PARKER AND LYLE,
AS THIS MAY BE RELEVANT
TO THEIR INVESTIGATION.
THAT'S THE OTHER WEIRD PART.
NO ONE'S HEARD FROM THEM YET.
IT'S LIKE THEY JUST VANISHED.
[ Miss Parker ]
I CAN'T GET A SIGNAL OUT
THROUGH THESE WALLS.
SCREW SIGNALS.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
POINT IT AT MY HEAD? HUH?
DON'T TEMPT ME.
WHAT THE HELL KIND OF GAME
IS JAROD PLAYING ANYWAY?
HMM. LET'S SEE.
HE LOCKS US
BOTH IN HERE TOGETHER
FOR GOD KNOWS HOW LONG...
WITH NOTHING BUT
A BUCKET OF STAGNANT WATER
AND A ROLL OF TOILET PAPER.
IT DOESN'T TAKE MUCH TIME
TO FIGURE OUT THIS ISN'T
JUST A GAME OF SURVIVAL.
THIS IS SURVIVAL
OF THE FITTEST.
[ Mr. Lyle ]
WELL, AT LEAST
HE'S NOT A COMPLETE JERK.
HE LEFT US SOME ARMY RATIONS.
- [ Monitor Beeps ]
- MISS PARKER. MR. LYLE.
WELCOME TO YOUR HOME
AWAY FROM HOME.
REVISE THAT LAST STATEMENT.
HE IS A COMPLETE JERK.
FOR ALL THE YEARS THAT I WAS
LOCKED AWAY AT THE CENTRE,
AND FOR THE THREE YEARS
I'VE BEEN OUT, THE KEY
TO MY LIFE HAS BEEN SURVIVAL.
A FUN LITTLE GAME.
NOW ASK YOURSELVES,
WHAT WOULD YOU DO TO SURVIVE?
I FOUND IT'S IMPORTANT
TO KNOW YOURSELF
AND TO KNOW YOUR FAMILY.
HAVE A GOOD TIME.
OH, BY THE WAY,
I'VE WHIPPED YOU UP
A YUMMY LITTLE MEAL.
HOPE YOU ENJOY IT.
MMM-MMM!
BARBECUED GRASSHOPPERS.
[ Chuckles ]
BON APPÉTIT.
ACTUALLY,
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
VERY HIGH IN PROTEIN.
TASTES LIKE LIQUORICE.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
WHAT ARE YOU WILLING TO DO
TO SURVIVE, MISS PARKER?
[ Gulps ]
MMM.
OH! OH!
[ Spits ]
[ Object Clatters ]
A KEY.
CLEVER.
ANOTHER LITTLE PIECE
TO WOLFGANG PUKE'S PUZZLE.
I THINK I CHIPPED MY TOOTH.
GREAT. WHAT NEXT?
[ Beeping ]
[ Jarod ]
SO YOU'VE BEEN HERE EVER SINCE
O.C.S. AND M.P. SCHOOL?
YOU READ MY FILE.
I'M C.I.D.
I'M SUPPOSED TO SNOOP.
YOU'RE A VERY CAPABLE OFFICER.
SHOULDN'T YOU HAVE
YOUR BARS BY NOW?
THE REASON I'M NOT A CAPTAIN YET
HAS LESS TO DO WITH ABILITY
THAN IT DOES WITH BIOLOGY.
IT'S NOT EASY TO BE A WOMAN
IN THIS MAN'S ARMY, HUH?
CHIEF RION
USED TO REMIND ME THAT.
- YOU KNEW RION PRETTY WELL?
- WE WERE FRIENDS.
HE TREATED ME WITH RESPECT,
NOT LIKE SOME OF
THESE GUNG-HO IDIOTS.
HE WAS NICE.
REALLY NICE.
IS IT TRUE HE CALLED
HIS PARENTS THE NIGHT BEFORE
HE STARTED P.O.W. TRAINING?
I'M THE ONE WHO'S SUPPOSED
TO SNOOP, REMEMBER?
SORRY. IT'S JUST RUMOR IS,
HE TOLD HIS FATHER THAT
SOMEONE ON BASE COMMITTED
A BREACH OF CONDUCT,
WHICH HE WAS GOING TO REPORT
WHEN HE GOT BACK FROM
THE P.O.W. ISOLATION TEST.
I GUESS HE NEVER GOT THE CHANCE
TO MAKE THAT REPORT, DID HE?
NO, SIR.
I GUESS NOT.
THE TRAINING AREA'S
JUST UP THE ROAD,
BUT I DOUBT YOU'LL FIND
SERGEANT REED ANY MORE HELPFUL
THAN COLONEL DANCE WAS.
SEALY, SEALY, SEALY.
SEALY!
IT'S HOT OUT HERE,
ISN'T IT, SEALY?
[ Sighs ]
THAT SURE HIT THE SPOT.
YOU WANT SOME?
WANT A SIP? HUH?
DAMN, I'VE BEEN
DOIN' THAT ALL DAY.
HANG TOUGH, AIRBORNE.
DON'T CRACK, SEALY!
ALL YOU GOTTA DO
IS QUIT, SEALY.
[ Car Door Closes ]
QUIT.
YOU CAN GO OVER THERE
AND DRINK AS MUCH AS YOU WANT.
WE'LL TAKE YOU BACK TO YOUR
NICE, AIR-CONDITIONED ROOM.
TAKE A NICE, LONG, COLD SHOWER.
AND AFTER THAT,
YOU GET TO CALL YOUR MOMMY,
TELL HER TO COME PICK YOU UP
AT THE AIRPORT
ON THE FIRST FLIGHT HOME!
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT,
SEALY?
I'M NOT GIVING UP, SERGEANT.
HANG TOUGH, SEALY.
DON'T CRACK!
MR. C.I.D.
STEP INTO MY OFFICE.
[ Man ]
DON'T GIVE UP!
I UNDERSTAND THAT
YOU WERE IN CHARGE OF TRAINING
THE NIGHT THAT CHIEF RION DIED.
NOT ONLY THAT,
BUT I'M THE ONE...
WHO OPENED UP THE HOLE
AND FOUND HIM
HANGING BY HIS BELT.
IT'S ALL IN THE REPORT.
YOU MUST AT LEAST
HAVE A THEORY
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
HE WENT IN THERE BY HIMSELF,
STAYED DOWN THERE ALL NIGHT
BY HIMSELF.
WE WERE ALL RIGHT OUTSIDE
THE WHOLE TIME.
BOY MUST'VE BEEN
SCARED OF THE DARK
ALL I CAN FIGURE.
LET HIS MIND
GET THE BEST OF HIM.
ENOUGH TO MUTILATE
AND HANG HIMSELF?
NEVER GOT A CHANCE TO ASK HIM.
YOU HERE TO ARREST ME?
NOT TODAY.
GOOD,
'CAUSE I GOT WORK TO DO.
SEE, THESE BOYS ARE STILL ALIVE.
IT'S MY JOB TO KEEP IT THAT WAY.
[ Rion's Voice ]
"DEAR MOM AND DAD,
WE'RE ALMOST FINISHED HERE.
"I CAN'T TELL YOU HOW MUCH
THIS OPPORTUNITY MEANS TO ME.
"EVER SINCE I WAS LITTLE,
I'VE WANTED TO BE ON
THE SPECIAL FORCES...
"JUST LIKE DAD WAS.
"OUR TALKS ABOUT HIS EXPERIENCE
AS A P.O.W. IN VIETNAM...
"PREPARED ME FOR WHAT
I HAD TO GO THROUGH
HERE IN TRAINING.
"AND LIKE HE ALWAYS SAID,
THE MOST IMPORTANT
SURVIVAL TOOL IS THE MIND.
"I MISS YOU BOTH VERY MUCH
AND LOOK FORWARD
TO US BEING TOGETHER SOON.
YOUR LOVING SON, SCOTT."
WE SHOULD'VE HEARD SOMETHING
BY NOW. THERE'S BEEN
NO WORD FROM MISS PARKER,
NO WORD FROM MR. LYLE,
NO ANSWER ON THEIR CELL PHONES.
- SYD, I'M GETTIN'
KIND OF FREAKED HERE.
- I'M CONCERNED AS WELL.
YOU THINK THEIR DISAPPEARANCE
HAS SOMETHING TO DO WITH JAROD?
ALL THOSE MILITARY MANUALS
WE FOUND IN HIS LAIR, DON'T THEY
ALL HAVE A SURVIVAL COMPONENT?
- YEAH.
- I'M GOING TO SEND ANOTHER
SWEEPER TEAM TO TEXAS.
BROOTS, DIG DEEPER INTO
THAT SHIPPING MANIFEST AND
ALL THE OTHER ITEMS WE FOUND.
OKAY, I'M ON IT
LIKE A CHEAP SUIT.
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO,
JAROD?
SOME P.O.W.s RETURNED FROM
THE BRUTALITY AND ISOLATION
OF PRISON CAMP INTACT,
OTHERS AS MERE SHADOWS
OF THE MAN THEY ONCE WERE.
[ Young Jarod ]
THEY SEEM HAUNTED.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
[ Young Sydney ]
STUDY THESE MEN, JAROD.
HELP US UNDERSTAND WHY
SOME SURVIVE AND SOME SHATTER.
[ Knocking ]
COME IN.
I FOUND CAP--
CAPTAIN SAUNDERS
AND THE REST OF
CHIEF RION'S UNIT,
SORT OF.
WHERE?
WELL, THEY FINISHED
THE P.O.W. PHASE
OF THEIR TRAINING...
AND HEADED OUT
TO THE SOUTH RANGE
FOR SOME KIND OF INITIATION.
INITIATION?
YEAH.
THEY COULD BE ANYWHERE
IN THIS 50-SQUARE-MILE AREA.
WELL, I GUESS I BETTER
BRING MY CANTEEN.
UM, NOTHING PERSONAL, SIR,
BUT YOU'LL NEVER FIND THEM.
THEY ARE EXPERTS.
THEY JUST GO OUT THERE
AND DISAPPEAR.
[ Man ]
BRAND'S READY, CAPTAIN SAUNDERS.
YOU'VE EARNED IT, SOLDIER.
GIVE ME THE BOTTLE.
TAKE A HIT.
- YOU READY?
- I'M READY, SIR.
WHOO! YEAH!
YOU DID IT, MAN!
YOU DID IT!
IS THIS WHAT THEY CALL
A WEENIE ROAST?
- HOW THE HELL
DID YOU FIND US, C.I.D.?
- I FOLLOWED YOUR TRACKS.
- WE DON'T LEAVE TRACKS,
STEVENS.
- CALL THEM WHAT YOU WILL.
BUT THERE WAS
A PRESSURE INDENTATION
BY THE CREEK BED,
A STONE WAS KICKED OVER
BY THE OUTCROPPING,
AND SOMEONE WITH A SIZE
11-AND-A-HALF BOOT
HAS A CRACK IN THEIR HEEL.
SENDING UP A FLARE
WOULD HAVE BEEN
LESS CONSPICUOUS.
YOU KNOW, I'D BE CAREFUL
WHO THE HELL YOU'RE
SNEAKIN' UP ON, C.I.D.
AND I'D BE CAREFUL
ABOUT VIOLATING REGULATIONS.
THIS IS TRADITION,
AND IT'S VOLUNTARY.
RIGHT, SEALY?
YES, SIR.
DEMOLITIONS MAN.
- YES, SIR.
- YOU DON'T FIND THAT VERY OFTEN
IN SURVIVAL TRAINING.
WE ALL COME FROM
DIFFERENT DISCIPLINES.
I WAS A MEDICAL OFFICER,
COUNTERINTELLIGENCE.
RION WAS LOGISTICS.
DUVALL HERE TOOK HIS PLACE.
AND WALKER'S OUR WEAPONS EXPERT.
DIFFERENT DISCIPLINES,
ONE MIND, BODY AND SOUL.
- WE TRAIN TO BECOME A TEAM.
- SO YOU ALL KNEW SCOTT RION
PRETTY WELL.
WHEN YOUR TRAINING'S
ABOUT SURVIVAL,
IT'S AS IMPORTANT...
TO GET TO KNOW YOUR FRIENDS
AS IT IS TO GET
TO KNOW YOUR ENEMIES.
- YOUR LIFE DEPENDS ON IT, SIR.
- A WHOLE LOT OF GOOD
THAT DID SCOTT RION.
- SCOTT HAD HIS OWN PROBLEMS.
- WHAT KIND?
PERSONAL. IN FACT, I SENSED
HE WAS FALLIN' APART.
THERE WERE TIMES
I EVEN COVERED FOR HIM
DURING TRAINING.
LOOK, I WANTED RION
TO MAKE IT.
WE ALL...
WANTED RION TO MAKE IT.
AND I GUESS I SHOULD'VE
GONE TO THE COLONEL, BUT I WAS
AFRAID HE'D KICK RION OUT.
MAYBE IF I HAD,
HE'D STILL BE ALIVE.
WELL, LIKE YOU SAID,
IT'S AS IMPORTANT
TO KNOW YOUR FRIENDS...
AS IT IS
TO KNOW YOUR ENEMIES.
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Mr. Lyle ]
WE NEED FLUIDS,
OR WE'LL DEHYDRATE.
THIS TOOTH'LL KILL ME
BEFORE THEN.
WHEN IT COMES TO SURVIVAL,
JAROD DOESN'T KNOW
THE FIRST THING ABOUT ME.
TOO BAD YOU QUIT SMOKING.
GIVE IT UP, DANIEL BOONE.
BRR! I BET IT'S GETTING
PRETTY COLD IN THERE.
I HOPE YOU TWO ARE
GETTING ALONG OKAY.
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY SAY:
WHEN OPPOSITE POLARITIES
COME TOGETHER, THINGS
CAN GET HOT PRETTY QUICKLY.
OH, IN CASE ANYBODY'S
INTERESTED, THERE'S A TUBE
OF ANBESOL IN THERE SOMEWHERE.
SEARCHING FOR IT
CAN KEEP YOU WARM.
NO. MATCHES FOR A FIRE
WOULD KEEP ME WARM.
SHUT UP
AND FIND THE ANBESOL.
"OPPOSITE POLARITIES."
OH, GREAT.
WE'LL SUFFOCATE.
FOUND THE ANBESOL.
I BET YOU'RE GLAD
I'M HERE NOW.
YOU CAN THANK ME LATER.
WE'RE GONNA CHOKE
ON THE SMOKE...
IF I DON'T GET
THIS THING SEALED.
I NEED... DUCT TAPE.
PERFECT.
GOTTA HAND IT TO JAROD.
[ Tape Ripping ]
THEY SAY DUCT TAPE
IS THE BEST THING TO HAVE...
IN A SURVIVAL SITUATION.
VERY CLEVER.
[ Tape Ripping ]
BUT HE'S NOT AS CLEVER
OR SMART AS HE THINKS HE IS.
FEW PEOPLE ARE.
[ Kimbrall ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN' HERE
SO LATE?
I WAS GOING OVER FILES
IN COLONEL DANCE'S OFFICE.
AFTER MIDNIGHT?
WELL, I GUESS YOU DIDN'T
GET THE MEMO ON THE COLONEL'S
NEW "OPEN DOOR" POLICY.
YOU DO LIKE TO
RUFFLE FEATHERS, DON'T YOU?
HOP IN.
I'LL GIVE YOU A RIDE HOME.
GET OUT OF THE CAR.
GET OUT OF THE CAR!
[ Animal Howling ]
TAKING A STROLL DOWN
MEMORY LANE, SEALY?
YOU SCARED ME, STEVENS.
WELL, THERE'S A LOT OF THAT
GOING AROUND TONIGHT.
SOMEBODY TRIED TO BLOW UP
ME AND LIEUTENANT KIMBRALL.
SOMEBODY WHO KNOWS THEIR WAY
AROUND A FIRECRACKER.
IT WASN'T ME.
IF IT HAD HAVE BEEN, THEY'D
BE MOPPING YOU UP ABOUT NOW.
I SEE. SO,
YOU HAVING TROUBLE SLEEPING?
I JUST THOUGHT
I'D TAKE A WALK.
TO THE PLACE
WHERE CHIEF RION DIED.
INTERESTING.
YOU CAN STILL HEAR HIM,
CAN'T YOU?
HIS SCREAMS.
HIS PAIN.
I WAS HERE WHEN IT HAPPENED.
IT WAS HIS LAST NIGHT
IN THE HOLE.
HE WAS DOWN THERE
HOWLIN' AND SCREAMIN'
ALL NIGHT,
CALLIN' OUT
CAPTAIN SAUNDERS'S NAME...
AND YELLIN' ALL KINDS
OF CRAZY STUFF.
[ Groaning ]
[ Yelling ]
IT WAS HORRIBLE LISTENING
TO HIM THE WHOLE NIGHT.
THEN AROUND DAYBREAK,
IT JUST STOPPED.
I THOUGHT HE PASSED OUT
TILL SERGEANT REED
OPENED THE DOOR,
AND WE SAW HIM...
HANGING FROM THE CEILING.
HE'D GONE AND SCRATCHED HIMSELF
ALL UP. IT WAS LIKE SOMETHING
OUT OF A HORROR MOVIE.
I DON'T KNOW WHO OR WHAT
COULD CAUSE SOMEONE
TO FLIP OUT LIKE THAT.
I SWEAR I DON'T.
WHY DIDN'T YOU GET HIM OUT?
I WANTED TO.
WE ALL DID.
- BUT WE WERE ORDERED NOT TO.
- CAPTAIN SAUNDERS?
AND SERGEANT REED. THEY SAID
IF WE PULLED RION OUT,
HE'D BE KICKED OUT OF TRAINING.
SO THEY JUST LEFT HIM
DOWN THERE TO DIE.
IT'S NOT LIKE THEY KNEW
HE'D KILL HIMSELF.
HOW COULD ANYONE
HAVE KNOWN?
[ Mr. Lyle ]
IT HASN'T BEEN EASY TRYING TO
PUT THE MURDERS OUT OF MY MIND.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'VE DONE
A PRETTY GOOD JOB.
I MET SUE AT
THE UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA.
SHE WAS PART OF
AN EXCHANGE PROGRAM
WITH HER SISTER CINDY.
ONE NIGHT,
I STOPPED BY THEIR APARTMENT.
THE DOOR WAS OPEN.
SO I WENT ON IN
AND FOUND 'EM--
WHAT WAS LEFT OF THEM--
IN THE BEDROOM.
I WAS A SUSPECT AT FIRST.
THEN THE POLICE FOUND
A ROLL OF DUCT TAPE...
IN THE TRUNK OF
CINDY'S EX-BOYFRIEND'S CAR.
THE SAME TAPE THAT HAD
BEEN USED ON BOTH SISTERS.
OR MAYBE SOMEONE
PLANTED THE DUCT TAPE
ON AN INNOCENT MAN.
YOU KNOW, TO SURVIVE.
DON'T YOU SEE WHAT
JAROD'S TRYING TO DO?
WHETHER IT'S IN THIS TRAP...
OR AT THE CENTRE,
HE'S TRYING TO KEEP US
FROM TRUSTING EACH OTHER.
YOU'VE GOTTA TRUST ME, PARKER.
IT'S A MUST FOR OUR SURVIVAL.
WHAT'S THAT?
PARKER?
YOU THINK OF EVERYTHING,
DON'T YOU, JAROD?
WHAT'S THE WATCH ABOUT?
SURVIVAL.
SYDNEY! SYD!
THAT SWEEPER TEAM
YOU SENT TO TEXAS--
THEY DIDN'T FIND THEM,
BUT THEY INTERVIEWED SOME BUM...
WHO HAD TAKEN MISS PARKER AND
MR. LYLE TO A SHIPPING CONTAINER
WHERE JAROD HAD BEEN LIVING.
THE SHIPPING CONTAINER--
WAS IT STILL THERE?
OH, NO, IT'S GONE.
I CAN'T FIND IT.
ALL ANYONE SEEMS TO KNOW
IS THAT IT'S HEADING EAST.
ALONG WITH PARKER AND LYLE?
BUT THAT'S NOT ALL.
FOR 10 BUCKS, THE BUM
TOLD THE SWEEPERS THAT...
JAROD HAD TURNED THE CONTAINER
INTO A KIND OF A P.O.W. CAMP,
AND THAT
HE WAS THE PRISONER.
HMM. SURVIVAL.
EXACTLY.
I SIFTED THROUGH EVERYTHING
FROM JAROD'S LAIR.
MOST OF IT IS USED IN TRAINING
AT MILITARY, P.O.W. AND SURVIVAL
UNITS ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
JAROD MAY HAVE BEEN
AT ONE OF THESE FACILITIES.
OR STILL MAY BE.
[ Young Jarod ]
I'VE EVALUATED THE DATA, SYDNEY.
AND WHAT HAVE YOU DETERMINED?
IT'S NOT NECESSARILY
THE PRISONER WHO SUFFERED
THE MOST PHYSICALLY...
OR WERE HELD IN CAPTIVITY
THE LONGEST WHO EXPERIENCED
THE MOST SIGNIFICANT TRAUMA.
THEN WHAT IS
THE CRITICAL FACTOR
TO THEIR SURVIVAL?
[ Young Jarod ]
THEIR MINDS, SYDNEY.
THEIR WILL TO SURVIVE.
IF THE CAPTOR
REMOVES THEIR HOPE,
THEIR ABILITY TO UNDERSTAND
THEIR FEARS AND OVERCOME THEM,
THE PRISONER LOSES
HIS GRIP ON REALITY,
SELF-DESTRUCTS.
[ Imitating Ricky Ricardo ]
LUCY, YOU GOT
SOME EXPLAININ' TO DO.
I SAW THAT ON A RERUN.
THIS ISN'T
WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE.
I HOPE NOT, 'CAUSE
IT SURE DOESN'T LOOK VERY GOOD
TO MY FRIEND OVER HERE.
I CAME HERE TO LOOK
IN CHIEF RION'S FILE.
I CAN'T JUST SIT BACK
AND HOPE THIS ALL GOES AWAY.
I HAVE TO FIND OUT
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED TO SCOTT.
YOU DON'T BELIEVE THAT
IT WAS JUST A SUICIDE EITHER,
DO YOU?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO BELIEVE.
ALL I KNOW IS SCOTT'S FAMILY
DESERVES THE TRUTH.
AND IF THAT MEANS RISKING
MY COMMISSION TO GET IT TO 'EM,
THEN SO BE IT.
WHAT YOU'RE RISKING
IS YOUR LIFE.
THAT BOMB IN YOUR CAR
WASN'T MEANT FOR ME.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
ABOUT CAPTAIN SAUNDERS.
I SEE THE WAY HE LOOKS AT YOU.
WELL, WHEN NO ONE'S AROUND,
HE'S TOUCHED ME...
INAPPROPRIATELY.
- HOW LONG HAS THIS
BEEN GOING ON?
- A FEW MONTHS.
[ Sighs ]
FIRST, IT WAS JUST COMMENTS.
SUGGESTIONS.
YOU GET USED
TO THAT KIND OF CRAP WHEN
YOU'RE A FEMALE IN THE MILITARY.
YOU JUST LEARN TO IGNORE IT
AND HOPE IT STOPS.
- BUT IT DIDN'T?
- NO.
- AND YOU TOLD SCOTT ABOUT IT?
- [ Scoffs ]
I MADE HIM PROMISE
NOT TO TELL ANYONE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
ABOUT A WEEK
BEFORE SCOTT'S DEATH,
I WENT OFF BASE TO MEET
SOME FRIENDS FOR DINNER.
CAPTAIN SAUNDERS WAS THERE,
CHIEF RION,
THE REST OF THE UNIT.
CAPTAIN SAUNDERS
KEPT STARING AT ME...
TO THE POINT THAT
IT WAS SCARING ME.
SO I GOT UP AND LEFT.
I JUST WANTED TO
GET OUT OF THERE AND GO HOME.
CAPTAIN SAUNDERS GRABBED ME.
HE WOULDN'T LET GO.
I TRIED TO FIGHT HIM.
I WAS YELLING AT HIM
TO LET GO OF ME.
GET OFF OF ME!
I WAS SO SCARED.
HE WAS TRYING TO PUSH ME
INTO THE CAR.
THEN, ALL OF THE SUDDEN,
SOMEONE PULLED HIM OFF OF ME.
SCOTT RION.
HE TOLD CAPTAIN SAUNDERS
HE WAS GOING TO REPORT HIM.
THEY ARGUED.
CAPTAIN SAUNDERS TOLD SCOTT
HE'D FORGOTTEN THE FIRST RULE--
THAT THE UNIT
ALWAYS COMES FIRST.
HE SAID IT WASN'T OVER
BETWEEN THEM,
THAT HE'D MAKE SURE
SCOTT LEARNED HIS LESSON.
WHEN SCOTT COMMITTED SUICIDE,
I FELT RESPONSIBLE.
SCOTT DID COMMIT SUICIDE,
BUT IT WASN'T BY CHOICE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HIS PSYCHOLOGICAL PROFILE
SHOWED NO SIGNS OF INSTABILITY.
PRISONER OF WAR TRAINING
IS TOUGH,
BUT SCOTT KNEW HE ONLY HAD
TO ENDURE ONE MORE NIGHT.
THEN WHAT COULD HAVE MADE HIM
GO OUT OF HIS MIND?
SOMETHING I FOUND
IN HIS MIND.
YOU'RE SAYING
HE WAS GIVEN SOMETHING
TO MAKE HIM GO CRAZY?
THAT'S WHAT HE WAS TRYING
TO TELL US.
HE WASN'T MUTILATING HIMSELF.
HE WAS WRITING A WORD.
SCOTT KNEW HE WAS DRUGGED.
HE WAS ATTEMPTING TO TELL US
WHO DID IT AND HOW.
THAT SEEMS SO IMPOSSIBLE.
RION KNEW THAT SAUNDERS
WAS INVOLVED IN A SECRET
RESEARCH PROJECT...
TO DEVELOP DRUGS TO INTERROGATE
PRISONERS OF WAR.
THE NAME OF
THAT PROJECT WAS--
[ Kimbrall ]
"ABYSS."
SCOTT KNEW HE WAS GIVEN
THE ABYSS DRUG.
AS HE BECAME MORE
PSYCHOTIC AND DISORIENTED,
HE ATTEMPTED TO TELL US.
SO WHAT ARE YOU GONNA
DO ABOUT IT?
I'M GOING TO GIVE
CAPTAIN SAUNDERS...
A LITTLE TASTE
OF HIS OWN MEDICINE.
IT'S OKAY TO DRINK NOW.
TRUST ME.
"TICK TOCK."
JAROD WANTED YOU
TO FIND THAT WATCH.
HE KNEW IT MEANT
SOMETHING TO YOU.
IT WAS MY--
OUR MOTHER'S.
SHE WON IT IN A SWIM COMPETITION
WHEN SHE WAS LITTLE,
AND DADDY GAVE IT TO ME
FOR MY 12th BIRTHDAY.
I USED TO USE IT
TO TIME MYSELF...
TREADING WATER WHEN
WE WOULD GO TO THE LAKE.
AND THIS ONE PARTICULAR MORNING,
IT WAS EARLY.
I TOOK THE SKIP OUT ALONE,
AND I WENT WAY OUT
INTO THE MIDDLE.
IT STARTED TAKING ON WATER,
AND BEFORE I COULD MAKE IT BACK,
IT SANK.
AND I TRIED TO SWIM,
BUT IT WAS JUST SO FAR.
ALL I COULD DO WAS TREAD WATER
AND HOPE SOMEONE
WOULD FIND ME.
MY LEGS WERE CRAMPING,
AND MY ARMS WERE ACHING.
IT WAS TERRIFYING.
EVERY TIME I WANTED
TO GIVE IN...
AND TO SURRENDER TO THE PAIN,
TO LET MYSELF SINK,
I WOULD HEAR THE TICKING
OF THIS WATCH.
AND IT WAS LIKE MOTHER'S VOICE
WHISPERING TO ME...
TO FIGHT FOR MY LIFE--
TO FIGHT TO SURVIVE.
AND I DID.
[ Scoffs ]
ANYWAY,
EVENTUALLY DADDY
CAME AND RESCUED ME.
BUT IT WAS THIS WATCH
THAT SAVED MY LIFE.
I LOST IT A LONG TIME AGO.
LOOKS LIKE
SOMEBODY FOUND IT.
[ Engine Shuts Off ]
WHAT NOW?
SYD! SYD!
I FOUND IT.
I FOUND THE CONTAINER,
AND YOU'RE NOT GONNA
BELIEVE WHERE.
[ Pounding ]
[ Broots ]
MISS PARKER? MISS PARKER?
BROOTS?
BROOTS, YOU LOVABLE MORON,
IS THAT YOU?
YEAH, I GUESS.
OPEN THE DOOR!
[ Sydney ]
YOU'LL HAVE TO DO IT.
WHAT?
[ Broots ]
IT SAYS OUT HERE:
"TO OPEN, PULL THE
'DO NOT PULL' LEVER INSIDE."
REALLY!
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
JAROD SHIPPED US BACK
TO THE CENTRE?
- IRONIC, ISN'T IT?
- IT'S A REGULAR JUNIOR JUMBLE.
WHEN I CATCH HIM,
I'M GONNA KILL HIM.
- WELL, YOU MAY GET YOUR CHANCE.
- WE TRACKED HIM TO
AN ARMY SURVIVAL CAMP.
- WHERE?
- IT'S IN TEXAS,
RIGHT NEXT TO THE CONTAINER YARD
WHERE YOU STARTED.
WELCOME BACK, LADIES.
SORRY TO RUIN YOUR "R" AND "R,"
BUT WE HAVE NEW ORDERS TO
MOVE UP YOUR THREE-DAY SURVIVAL
SOLO INTO THE WILDERNESS.
YOU'LL BE ASSIGNED
SEPARATE QUADRANTS.
YOUR MISSION
IS TO ESCAPE AND EVADE
FOR THE NEXT 72 HOURS.
ALL THAT YOU NEED
AND ALL THAT YOU ARE GETTING...
IS IN YOUR GEAR,
WHICH YOU CAN PICK UP
AT THE TABLE.
MAKE ME PROUD!
LET'S GO!
[ All Shouting ]
MAKE ME PROUD!
LET'S GO! COME ON!
[ Shouting Continues ]
MOVE IT!
LET'S GO!
ALL RIGHT!
[ Yelling ]
[ Jarod ]
WAKE UP, SAUNDERS.
WAKE UP!
WHERE AM I?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
I BET SCOTT RION
ASKED HIMSELF THE SAME QUESTION.
- WHO'S IN HERE?
- JUST DEMONS IN YOUR MIND.
AND VICTIMS FROM YOUR PAST.
[ Gasps ]
WHAT'S THE MATTER, SAUNDERS?
FEELING A LITTLE CRAZY?
- STEVENS, IS THAT YOU?
- YOU LOOK SCARED.
SCARED TO DEATH!
[ Yells ]
THIS IS GONNA COST YOU
YOUR COMMISSION.
WELL, IT CAN'T REALLY
COST ME MY COMMISSION, BECAUSE
I DON'T REALLY HAVE ONE.
THE TRUTH IS,
MY NAME'S NOT STEVENS.
I'M NOT EVEN IN THE ARMY.
[ Chuckles ]
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE TO ME?
THE SAME THING YOU DID
TO SCOTT RION.
[ Echoing ]
RION HUNG HIMSELF.
HE COULDN'T COPE.
I TOLD YOU THAT!
BECAUSE OF THE HALLUCINOGENS
YOU PUT IN HIS M.R.E.
DRUGS YOU DESIGNED TO INCREASE
HIS FEELINGS OF FEAR AND TERROR.
MAN, THIS IS CRAZY!
ALMOST AS CRAZY
AS SCOTT RION MUST HAVE FELT...
WHEN YOU LEFT HIM
IN THE HOLE ALL NIGHT!
AS THE DRUG
TOOK CONTROL OF HIS MIND,
HE HAD TWO OPTIONS--
EITHER GO CRAZY,
OR KILL HIMSELF.
NO! NO!
YOU KNEW HE WAS GOING
TO REPORT YOU FOR THE SEXUAL
HARASSMENT OF LT. KIMBRALL.
YOU WOULD HAVE BEEN
COURT-MARTIALED,
LOST YOUR PRECIOUS CAREER.
YOU CAN'T PROVE ANY OF IT.
YOU CAN'T PROVE IT.
THAT'S WHY I WHIPPED UP
MY OWN LITTLE SPECIAL BATCH...
OF ABYSS.
- [ Gasping ]
- AS YOU KNOW,
IT STARTS OUT SLOWLY.
AND THEN IT BUILDS,
GETTING STRONGER
WITH EACH WAVE...
UNTIL YOUR MIND SLOWLY
SLIPS INTO INSANITY.
IT SHOULD BE KICKING IN
PRETTY WELL RIGHT NOW.
YOUR EYES
PLAYIN' TRICKS ON YOU?
YOUR SKIN CRAWLING?
YOUR MIND LOSING ITS GRIP?
OH, UH, THE KEY
TO YOUR HANDCUFFS.
YOU SHOULD HAVE YOUR HANDS FREE
IN CASE YOU WANNA
MUTILATE YOURSELF.
WELL, GOTTA GO NOW.
HAVE FUN IN YOUR OWN
PRIVATE LITTLE...
HELL.
OH, ONE MORE THING.
RION'S BELT,
JUST IN CASE YOU WOULD WANT
TO, UH, HANG AROUND.
- HAVE FUN.
- WAIT! WAIT!
DON'T LEAVE ME IN HERE!
WAIT! DON'T LEAVE!
[ Whimpering ]
LET ME OUT, MAN!
LOOK.
YOU'RE RIGHT!
OKAY? I DID IT!
I DID IT!
[ Panting ]
I DRUGGED HIM.
[ Sobbing ]
COME ON, MAN!
LET ME OUT!
MMM-- UH-UH.
HOW LONG SHOULD
WE LEAVE HIM IN THERE?
THE DRUG SHOULD WEAR OFF
IN A COUPLE OF HOURS.
AFTER THAT,
HE'LL JUST WEEP.
[ Panting ]
LET ME OUT!
[ Kimbrall ]
THE COLONEL ASSURES ME SAUNDERS
WILL GET EVERYTHING HE DESERVES.
TWENTY TO LIFE
AT LEAVENWORTH MINIMUM.
AND RION'S FAMILY WILL GET
A FULL APOLOGY
AND DISCLOSURE OF WHAT HAPPENED.
FROM COLONEL DANCE
PERSONALLY.
THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
AND I HAVE A FEELING...
THOSE BARS OF YOURS
WON'T BE LONG IN COMING.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW
YOUR RANK, JAROD,
BUT I AM HONORED
TO CALL YOU "SIR."
THANK YOU.
NOW IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
I'M GOING TO PRACTICE
SOME OF THOSE...
ESCAPE AND EVASION SKILLS
I'VE LEARNED HERE.
GOOD LUCK.
[ Phone Ringing ]
WHAT?
[ Jarod ]
ASIDE FROM THE CHIPPED MOLAR,
IT SOUNDS LIKE
YOU SURVIVED.
NO THANKS TO YOU.
ACTUALLY, EVERYTHING YOU NEEDED
WAS THERE ALL ALONG.
ALL YOU HAD TO DO
WAS OPEN YOUR EYES AND SEE.
WHAT EXACTLY WAS IT
I WAS SUPPOSED TO SEE?
THAT SURVIVAL COMES DOWN
TO KNOWING THE DIFFERENCE...
BETWEEN YOUR FRIENDS
AND YOUR ENEMIES.
I SUPPOSE YOU'RE TRYING
TO TELL ME THAT...
LYLE IS MY ENEMY
AND YOU'RE MY FRIEND.
MAYBE. AND YOU HAVE
TO BE WILLING...
TO DO WHATEVER IT TAKES
TO SURVIVE.
YOU CAN SURE BET
THAT LYLE WILL.
[ Line Disconnects ]
[ Gunfire ]
[ Man Shouts ]