[ Indistinct Whisper ]
JAROD? JAROD. DANGER.
HATE! HATE DESTROY JAROD!
[ Gasps, Panting ]
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDEN!
OPEN UP YOUR HEART!
LET THE HEALING START!
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDEN!
OPEN UP YOUR HEART.
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDEN.
LET THE--
[ Children Singing ]
♪ HEALING START ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDEN ♪
♪ OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDEN ♪♪
VERY GOOD. VERY GOOD.
YOU SOUND LIKE TWO ANGELS.
AND I CAN'T WAIT
TO HEAR YOU AT THE RALLY.
- THANKS, DADDY.
- ALL RIGHT. I GOTTA
GET YOU TWO HOME, OKAY?
YOU GOT A BIG WEEKEND
AHEAD OF YOU.
FINISH YOUR HOMEWORK?
I DID, BUT KATI DIDN'T.
'CAUSE I WAS
TOO BUSY DOIN' YOURS.
OKAY, THAT'S ENOUGH OF THAT.
WE HAVE PLENTY OF TIME
BEFORE WE GO TO BED.
OKAY, LET'S HEAR YOU
PRACTICE THAT SONG AGAIN.
DADDY!
UH-UH.
PRACTICE MAKES WHAT?
[ Girls ]
PERFECT.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE GO.
[ Together ]
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDEN ♪
♪ OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪
VERY GOOD.
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDEN
OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪♪
[ Man ]
EVENIN', PASTOR JONES!
DADDY!
LISTEN, GENTLEMEN,
I'D APPRECIATE IT...
IF YOU ALL JUST TURN
RIGHT AROUND AND GO BACK
WHERE YOU CAME FROM.
THAT'S NOT VERY FRIENDLY COMIN'
FROM A CIVIL RIGHTS LEADER
FAMOUS FOR PREACHIN' UNITY!
- [ Man Yells ]
- [ Girls Screaming ]
- NO, NO. IT'S OKAY.
- OF COURSE, SOME OF US HAVE
A DIFFERENT OPINION...
ABOUT THE WORLD BEIN'
UNDER ONE BIG RAINBOW AND SUCH.
- [ Men ] YEAH!
- [ Girl ] WHO ARE THEY?
- BACK INSIDE NOW!
- I SAY WE SHOW PASTOR JONES
THE LIGHT...
THE WAY WE SEE IT!
[ Men Shouting, Whooping ]
- GO ON!
- LET'S GO. GET DOWN.
GET DOWN. GET DOWN!
[ Girls Screaming ]
GET DOWN!
[ Glass Shattering ]
[ Whooping Continues ]
[ Men Shouting ]
MAKE 'EM STOP!
[ Screaming ]
IT'S OKAY.
GRAB THAT END!
SET IT RIGHT HERE.
[ Whooping Continues ]
GET OUT!
[ Shouting ]
MAKE 'EM STOP!
IT'S OKAY. IT'S OKAY.
DADDY'S HERE, BABY.
[ Yelling, Laughing ]
THIS IS YOUR LAST WARNING!
NOBODY WANTS UNITY
WITH YOU PEOPLE!
GET THE HELL OUTTA HERE
WHILE YOU STILL CAN!
[ Sobbing ]
WHY DO THEY DO THIS
TO US, DADDY? WHY?
- OKAY, BABY. OKAY.
- I THINK WE MADE OUR POINT.
[ Laughs ]
YEAH, I THINK THEY GET
THE MESSAGE THIS TIME.
[ Vehicles Departing ]
[ Men Whooping ]
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
- [ Miss Parker ] HE DEFENDS
THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
- [ Jarod ] LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
[ Broots ]
ANGELO'S GONE POSTAL.
HE'S GOING THROUGH THE EVIDENCE
FROM JAROD'S OLD PRETENDS,
AND HE'S FLIPPIN' OUT.
THE LITTLE FREAK'S
POSSESSED.
HAS HE SAID ANYTHING?
PLENTY. BUT NONE OF IT
MAKES ANY SENSE.
FIRE! FIRE!
LIKE I SAID,
HE'S POSSESSED.
[ Groaning ]
FIRE BURN! JAROD!
MUST HELP JAROD!
- [ Groans ]
- ANGELO.
JAROD.
[ Panting, Gasping ]
WHAT'S WRONG?
WE MUST SAVE JAROD.
FROM WHAT?
FROM FIRE. FROM HATE.
HATE KILLS.
HATE WILL KILL JAROD.
MUST SAVE JAROD.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF IT, SYD?
I BELIEVE ANGELO THINKS THAT
SOMEONE FROM JAROD'S PAST...
IS GOING TO TRY AND KILL HIM.
[ Angelo ]
JAROD. WE MUST SAVE JAROD!
THE QUESTION IS, WHO?
[ Angelo Yells ]
[ Men Whooping ]
[ Indistinct Shouting ]
I'D SAY WE LEARNED PASTOR JONES
A LESSON OR TWO TONIGHT!
WHOO!
WELL, A LITTLE VISUAL AID
ALWAYS HELPED MY THIRD-GRADE
STUDENTS GET THE POINT.
I'D SAY A BURNING CROSS
IS A LOT MORE EFFECTIVE
THAN A FILMSTRIP.
I GUESS WE SHOWED HIM
THE LIGHT, HUH, JAROD?
IF A PICTURE'S
WORTH A THOUSAND WORDS,
A FLAMIN' CROSS
IS WORTH A MOUTHFUL!
- YEAH!
- [ Whooping ]
IT OUGHTA BE
AGAINST THE LAW
TO HAVE THAT MUCH FUN.
IN FACT, I BELIEVE
IT IS AGAINST THE LAW.
- [ All Laughing ]
- IT BEATS THE HELL OUTTA
SELLIN' LIFE INSURANCE.
- I SAY WE GO CELEBRATE!
- [ All Cheering ]
NO, NOBODY'S GOIN' ANYWHERE.
CHANGE OF PLANS.
-IS THERE SOMETHIN' WRONG?
-WHILE YOU WERE ALL OUT PLAYIN',
I GOT A CALL FROM THE GENERAL.
THE GENERAL?
WHAT'D HE WANT?
HE'S COMIN' IN EARLY.
HE COULD BE HERE ANYTIME.
SO, WHY'S THAT CHANGE
OUR PLAN?
'CAUSE HE'S GOT A NEW
MISSION. A BOLD MESSAGE.
ONE THAT'S JUST NOT GONNA
BE HEARD AROUND THE COUNTRY.
IT'S GONNA BE HEARD
AROUND THE WORLD.
- THAT SOUNDS BIG.
- YEAH, IT IS, DONNY.
AND ON ACCOUNT OF THAT,
HE WANTS EACH OF YOU HERE
WHEN HE SHOWS UP.
- WE GOTTA STAY HERE ALL NIGHT?
- WAIT. WE CAN'T GO ANYWHERE?
UNTIL HE SHOWS UP.
Y'ALL BEEN RECRUITED
FROM OUTSIDE THE STATE.
THE GENERAL'S WORRIED
YOU GO INTO TOWN,
AND YOU'LL STAND OUT
LIKE A RACCOON IN A HENHOUSE.
NOW, I GOT A LITTLE GIFT
HERE FROM THE GENERAL...
HE WANTS US TO USE
TO DELIVER OUR MESSAGE.
- C-4 EXPLOSIVE?
- YEAH.
WELL, THAT PACKS
A HELL OF A PUNCH.
DAMN RIGHT.
YOU'RE OUR DEMOLITION EXPERT.
YOU'RE GONNA RIG US UP
A LITTLE DEVICE TO DIS-UNIFY
THIS UNITY RALLY!
- [ Laughing ]
- I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHIN', BOYS.
WHEN WE'RE FINISHED,
THE PARTYIN' AIN'T GONNA STOP.
- [ All Cheering ]
- YEAH!
YEAH! WHOO!
[ Dispatcher ]
A FLAG DOWN
AT 4581 PROSPECT STREET.
HOW LONG HAS THIS
CRAZINESS BEEN GOIN' ON?
SEVERAL WEEKS AGO,
WE ORGANIZED A UNITY RALLY.
THIS EVENT'S SUPPOSED
TO BRING TOGETHER...
PEOPLE FROM THE COMMUNITY
FROM ALL WALKS OF LIFE.
WELL, AFTER SUPPORT GREW,
THAT'S WHEN WE STARTED
RECEIVIN' THREATS.
WHAT KIND OF THREATS?
WARNINGS.
TELLIN' US
TO CALL OFF THE RALLY.
AND WHEN YOU DIDN'T?
THAT'S WHEN THE ACTS
OF VANDALISM BEGAN...
LEADIN' UP TO LAST NIGHT.
LOOK, PASTOR,
THE RALLY'S TOMORROW.
THESE TYPES PROBABLY
AREN'T GOING AWAY. MAYBE--
MAYBE WHAT, SHERIFF? HUH?
MAYBE WE SHOULD JUST
GIVE IN, HUH? GIVE IN AND
JUST CALL THE WHOLE THING OFF.
NO, SHERIFF.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT THEY WANT.
POSTPONE IT.
THINK ABOUT YOUR GIRLS.
YOU KNOW, SHERIFF,
WHEN I WAS 13,
I SAW A MAN BEATEN
AND DRAGGED BEHIND A TRUCK,
AND NOBODY
DID NOTHIN' TO STOP IT.
NOT EVEN ME.
THAT MAN LIVED
FOR THREE DAYS,
THE WHOLE TIME
PRAYIN' TO DIE.
THAT MAN, SHERIFF,
WAS MY BIG BROTHER.
SEE, IF YOU DON'T FIX
THIS KIND OF HATE,
IT WILL DESTROY
EVERYONE THAT IT TOUCHES.
IT'S BECAUSE OF MY DAUGHTERS
I GOTTA DO THIS.
SO YES, SIR.
YES, I WILL BE AT THAT RALLY
TOMORROW WITH MY CHURCH...
AND MY FAMILY.
ANY PROGRESS?
ANGELO SENSES THAT SOMEONE
JAROD BROUGHT TO JUSTICE...
IS GOING TO TRY TO KILL HIM.
WE'RE TRYING TO FIND OUT WHO
BY LETTING HIM EMPATH...
VARIOUS ITEMS THE CENTRE
RECOVERED FROM PAST PRETENDS.
I'M CERTAINLY NOT SURPRISED
SOMEONE FROM JAROD'S PAST
WANTS TO KILL HIM.
IN FACT, THAT'S
A HELL OF A LONG LINE,
AND IT STARTS BEHIND ME.
HEY, LOOK. THAT'S THE DRESS
THE BLACK WIDOW WAS WEARING.
THE ONE THAT JAROD TOOK DOWN
FOR MURDERING HER HUSBAND.
SHE CERTAINLY
HAS ENOUGH REASON.
AND SHE DID TRY
TO KILL HIM ONCE.
[ Whispering ]
DOES HE THINK IT'S HER?
I WANT THIS TO BE OVER.
I KNOW YOU DO.
JAROD? I LOVE YOU.
[ Yells, Mutters ]
JAROD'S IN DANGER!
BUT NOT HER. NOT A WOMAN.
SYD, DOES HE EVEN KNOW
WHAT HE'S DOING?
JAROD DOESN'T KNOW.
ANGELO IS SYSTEMATICALLY
EVALUATING AND ELIMINATING
INDIVIDUALS IN JAROD'S PAST...
WITH THE MOST INTENSE
FEELINGS OF HATRED FOR HIM.
THEN WE NEED TO KEEP THIS
FROM LYLE AND RAINES.
THEY'LL ONLY INTERFERE
WITH ANGELO'S PROGRESS.
THEN WE'D BETTER MOVE FAST,
BECAUSE, UH, SECRETS
AREN'T KEPT LONG AROUND HERE.
IF ANGELO CAN SUCCESSFULLY
ISOLATE THE POTENTIAL KILLER,
HE CAN TAKE US TO HIM.
- AND TO JAROD?
- HOPEFULLY IN TIME TO SAVE HIM.
EVEN BETTER,
IN TIME TO CATCH HIM.
[ Dog Barking ]
♪♪ [ Hip-hop Beat ]
[ Laughing ]
HEY, TURN THAT DAMN THING OFF,
WILL YA? JUNGLE MUSIC.
CAN'T EVEN LISTEN
TO THE RADIO ANYMORE
WITHOUT HEARIN' THAT CRAP.
AIN'T YOU ABOUT DONE
WITH THAT THING?
ABOUT.
JUST MAKE SURE IT WORKS.
- IT'LL WORK.
- IT BETTER.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THIS DAMN
UNITY RALLY A WAKE-UP CALL.
GENERAL SAYS THAT WHEN THE BLOOD
OF ALL THEM SONS OF CAIN...
FLOWS THROUGH THE GUTTERS,
OUR PEOPLE WILL UNITE.
SEE GOD'S WILL TO EXTERMINATE
ALL THE PARASITES...
WHO ARE SUCKING THE LIFE
OUT OF THIS COUNTRY.
- AMEN, BROTHER. AMEN.
- AMEN.
[ Martin Luther King ]
TRANSFORMED INTO AN OASIS
OF FREEDOM AND JUSTICE.
I HAVE A DREAM!
[ Applause ]
THAT MY FOUR
LITTLE CHILDREN--
[ Continues ]
WHY DO PEOPLE HATE
OTHER PEOPLE BECAUSE
OF THE COLOR OF THEIR SKIN?
I DON'T KNOW, JAROD.
IT'S CALLED RACISM.
IT'S IMPORTANT THAT YOU LEARN
WHAT'S WRONG IN THE WORLD...
AS WELL AS WHAT'S RIGHT.
I HAVE A DREAM
THAT ONE DAY--
ARE THEY TAUGHT TO DO THIS?
IN SOME WAYS, YES.
JAROD, THERE IS NO SIMPLE
SOLUTION TO RACISM.
BUT THERE IS.
STOP HATING.
IT TAKES TIME AND COMPASSION.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
THIS, JAROD?
[ Martin Luther King Continues ]
I UNDERSTAND IT,
BUT I CAN'T ACCEPT IT.
I HAVE A DREAM--
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU, BOY? YOU LOOK
LIKE YOU SEEN A GHOST.
NO, BROTHER.
JUST SEEIN' THE LIGHT.
THERE. IT'S FINISHED.
WHEN WE PULL THIS OFF,
YOU'RE GONNA SCORE BIG
POINTS WITH THE GENERAL.
I'M GONNA TAKE THIS INTO TOWN,
MAKE SURE IT'S ALL
IN PLACE FOR TOMORROW.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Man ]
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Door Closes ]
NOBODY'S GOIN' INTO TOWN
TILL THE GENERAL ARRIVES.
I DON'T WANNA MAKE
ANYBODY SUSPICIOUS.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF THIS
FROM NOW ON.
YOU WANT SOMETHIN' TO DO,
FINISH RELOADIN'
THOSE SHOTGUN SHELLS.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
THE PLAN WAS THAT I WOULD SET
ANY EXPLOSIVES THAT WE USED.
WELL, THE PLAN CHANGED,
HOTSHOT.
GENERAL'S ORDERS.
HE WANTS THIS SET SPECIAL.
HE WANTS THE PREACHER'S
GIRLS TO BE THE MESSAGE.
HE WANTS US TO KILL THEM?
YEP. HE'S GONNA PUT AN END
TO THIS UNITY CRAP
ONCE AND FOR ALL.
[ Sydney ]
I HAVE TRIED EVERY POSSIBLE
AVENUE TO CONTACT JAROD.
- NO RESPONSE.
- SYDNEY, I THINK ANGELO'S
ON TO SOMETHING.
[ Gun Clicking ]
I HOPE HE DOESN'T FIND
THE BULLETS.
THE GUN BELONGED
TO A MID-LEVEL THUG--
A JOEY MELINO.
KILLED AN UNDERCOVER COP.
JAROD SENT HIM AWAY.
WORD FROM PRISON IS,
JOEY'S NOT TOO HAPPY ABOUT IT.
MAYBE HE'S PAYING SOMEONE
TO KILL JAROD.
- [ Gun Clicks ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming ]
ANGELO, WHAT IS IT?
THERE IS DANGER! DEATH! HATE!
HATE GETTING CLOSER TO JAROD!
OH!
[ Uncocks ]
[ Sighs ]
JAROD DOESN'T WANT HATE.
DOESN'T WANT TO KILL.
BUT SOMEONE WANTS
TO KILL JAROD!
DID YOU REALLY THINK
I WOULDN'T FIND OUT
WHO YOU ARE? HUH?
JAROD!
[ Shuddering ]
YOU'RE A DEAD MAN, JAROD!
YOU HEAR ME? YOU'RE DEAD!
OOH, YOU NEED TO CHILL OUT.
LISTEN, JAROD, I'LL
GIVE YOU ANYTHING YOU WANT.
- SEE YA.
- JAROD, NO!
LET US OUT!
HE'S DEAD! HE'S DEAD!
YOU'RE DEAD!
[ Gasps, Whimpering ]
ANGELO, IS IT JOEY?
NO, NOT-- NOT JOEY!
SOMEONE HATES JAROD MORE.
HATES OTHERS.
WE MUST FIND SOON.
THIS IS GOING NOWHERE.
JAROD WILL DIE!
PATIENCE, PARKER.
ANGELO IS NARROWING DOWN
THE SUSPECTS.
MUST FIND SOON,
OR JAROD WILL DIE.
WE DON'T HAVE TIME
TO BE PATIENT.
FINISH THEM SHELLS,
JAROD. WE NEED ANOTHER
LOSER AT THE TABLE.
[ Laughing ]
YOU BEEN CHEATIN'. YOU GOTTA
GIVE ME A CHANCE TO WIN.
- EVERYBODY'S CHEATIN', DONNY.
- WHO'S CHEATIN'?
DELBERT.
YEAH!
WHAT YOU GOT?
[ Laughing ]
LET'S MOVE ALONG, MAN.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
TWO PAIR. TWO PAIR.
TWO 10s, TWO SIXES,
AND ALL MINE, PARTNER.
[ Laughing ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Donny ]
LOOK. FIVE. TWO ACES.
A PAIR OF ACES.
JUST GIVE ME THREE MORE.
ATTABOY.
[ Laughs ]
- [ Indistinct Chattering ]
- LOOK AT THAT THING.
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Rifle cocks ]
GOIN' SOMEWHERE?
YEAH. TO GET
A LITTLE BLACK POWDER
TO PACK AROUND THE C-4.
I THOUGHT IT MIGHT GIVE
MORE IMPACT VISUALLY.
GENERAL WANTS TO USE NAPALM.
NAPALM? BUT THAT
WASN'T PART--
NAH, NO BUTS.
HIS PLAN, HIS CAUSE--
WE DO THINGS HIS WAY.
YOU GOT A PROBLEM WITH THAT?
HELL, NO.
I'M A BELIEVER.
I JUST LIKE TO KNOW
WHAT'S GOIN' ON. THAT'S ALL.
AND RIGHT NOW WHAT'S GOIN' ON
IS YOU'RE STAYIN' HERE.
YES--
GENERAL'S ORDERS.
YES, SIR.
LUKE.
WHAT?
YOU GOT ANOTHER MESSAGE
FROM THE GENERAL.
THERE A PROBLEM?
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
THERE IS.
HE HAS WORD ONE OF US ISN'T
EXACTLY WHO WE CLAIM TO BE.
SOUNDS LIKE ONE OF US
IS A TRAITOR.
GENERAL SAID TO TELL YOU
NO ONE LEAVES TILL HE GETS HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU BOYS GET BACK IN THE HOUSE.
WE'LL SORT THIS OUT
WHEN THE GENERAL SHOWS UP.
HEY.
[ Whistles ]
GOD BLESS KATI AND DADDY.
AND GOD BLESS MOMMA
UP IN HEAVEN. AMEN.
AMEN.
ALL RIGHT, YOU TWO.
TIME FOR BED.
DADDY'S ANGELS
GOT TO REST THOSE VOICES
FOR THE RALLY TOMORROW.
WHY DO THOSE PEOPLE
HATE US?
WHAT DID WE DO?
HERE. SIT DOWN.
COME HERE, BABY.
[ Sighs ]
LISTEN.
YOU DIDN'T DO ANYTHING WRONG.
YOU HEAR ME, SWEETHEART?
YOU DID NOTHING AT ALL.
PEOPLE HATE...
'CAUSE THEY'RE AFRAID.
THEY'RE AFRAID OF THINGS
THAT THEY DON'T KNOW.
THINGS THAT
THEY DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THAT'S WHY THIS RALLY
IS SO IMPORTANT.
UNDERSTAND?
MM-HMM.
YOU SURE?
YES.
GOOD. ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GET TO BED.
GET SOME SLEEP, AND WE'LL
SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
ALL RIGHT.
MM. NIGHT. UH-OH.
GOT IT? DADDY GOT IT.
MM. LOVE YOU.
DADDY?
CAN YOU PLEASE
CLOSE THE WINDOW?
SURE, SWEETHEART.
AND LOCK IT.
THERE. IT'S LOCKED.
- GOOD NIGHT.
- [ Both ] GOOD NIGHT.
[ Exhales ]
ANY WORD ON JAROD?
- LOOKS LIKE SATURDAY NIGHT
AT YOUR HOUSE, BROOTS.
- HUH?
ANGELO'S TRYING TO EMPATH
CAPTAIN ROBERT SAUNDERS.
[ Broots ]
HE'S THE ONE SERVING 20 TO LIFE
AT LEAVENWORTH, THANKS TO JAROD.
CAPTAIN ROBERT SAUNDERS.
TEXTBOOK SOCIOPATH.
AS WELL AS A CONVICTED
RAPIST AND MURDERER.
HE CERTAINLY FITS
THE PROFILE.
AND HE'S ON RECORD AS HAVING
SWORN TO GET BACK AT JAROD.
JAROD SURE KNOWS HOW TO PICK
HIS ENEMIES, DOESN'T HE?
- YES, HE HAS A PENCHANT
FOR PISSING PEOPLE OFF.
- [ Angelo Screams ]
[ Groans ]
SAUNDERS!
HATES JAROD!
WANTS TO HURT JAROD!
[ Jarod ]
WHAT'S THE MATTER, SAUNDERS?
YOU LOOK SCARED.
- WHO'S IN HERE?
- JUST DEMONS IN YOUR MIND.
STEVENS, IS THAT YOU?
HEY, THIS IS CRAZY!
WELL, GOTTA GO NOW.
HAVE FUN IN YOUR OWN
PRIVATE LITTLE... HELL.
DON'T LEAVE! COME ON!
LET ME OUT!
[ Echoing ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Grunts ]
SAUNDERS HATES JAROD,
BUT... NOT HIM.
SOMEONE ELSE
HATES JAROD MORE.
IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE
IT COULD GET MUCH WORSE.
[ Panting ]
BROOTS! HURRY!
THERE'S NO TIME
LEFT FOR JAROD!
ANGELO, CALM DOWN!
I'VE NEVER SEEN HIM LIKE THIS.
CAN'T CALM DOWN!
[ Screaming ]
HATES JAROD! HATES JAROD!
[ Yells ]
HATES MISS PARKER TOO!
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Barking Continues ]
ALL RIGHT. HE'S HERE.
JAROD, GET THEM DAMN
BEER BOTTLES OUTTA HERE.
[ Dog Continues Barking ]
GENERAL,
WE'RE GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
GENERAL.
SIR.
EVERYTHING'S READY
FOR TOMORROW, SIR. WE'RE
JUST WAITIN' ON YOUR WORD.
JUST LIKE YOU ORDERED,
NONE OF US HAVE LEFT.
WE'RE ALL HERE
TO HELP YOU FIGURE OUT
WHO THE TRAITOR IS, SIR.
WELL, THAT WON'T
BE NECESSARY,
WILL IT, JAROD?
[ Screams ]
WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
YOU GONNA STAND THERE
OR CUT ME OUT OF THIS?
I SPENT A LONG TIME
MAKING THAT THING.
YOU CUT ME OUTTA THIS NOW,
OR I'LL BLOW YOU AWAY.
[ Gun Clicking ]
GUESS YOUR CLIP'S EMPTY.
GOTTA GO. HURRICANE'S COMIN'
RIGHT THROUGH HERE.
YOU'RE DEAD! YOU'RE DEAD,
YOU SON OF A--
MATTER OF FACT, WE GO BACK
A LONG WAY, DON'T WE?
LAST TIME WE WERE TOGETHER,
THERE WAS A HURRICANE
BLOWIN'.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
THAT STORM AIN'T GOT
HALF THE FURY THAT I GOT
LEFT IN ME RIGHT NOW.
- [ Jarod Grunting ]
- [ Men Cheering ]
- TRAITOR!
- [ Men Shouting ]
- YEAH, GET HIM! GET HIM!
- [ Men Cheering ]
GENTLEMEN,
WE'RE BACK ON SCHEDULE.
BARTLETT'S THE GUY THAT
TRIED TO KILL JAROD...
AND YOU.
AND ALMOST SUCCEEDED.
I HAD TRACKED JAROD TO
THE MIDDLE OF THE EVERGLADES...
WHERE WE WERE TRAPPED
TOGETHER IN A HURRICANE.
SO THAT'S THE NET
JAROD USED TO CAPTURE HIM.
TOOK MORE THAN A NET TO HOLD
AN ANIMAL LIKE BARTLETT.
[ Growling ]
[ Gunshot ]
HONEY, I'M HOME.
BARTLETT, ANGELO.
IS HE THE ONE WHO'S
GOING TO KILL JAROD?
BARTLETT.
MUST STOP BARTLETT.
BARTLETT HATES JAROD.
HATES EVERYONE.
BARTLETT WANTS TO KILL.
WANTS TO KILL JAROD.
SYDNEY, HELP JAROD NOW.
PARKER, WE HAVE
TO DO SOMETHING.
BROOTS, CALL THE
FLORIDA BUREAU OF PRISONS.
- FIND OUT IF BARTLETT
IS STILL IN CUSTODY.
- OKAY.
BARTLETT IS
A RACIST SLEAZEBAG...
WHO WOULD KILL HIS OWN MOTHER.
SYD, WE HAVE TO FIND HIM.
IF BARTLETT FINDS JAROD
FIRST, HE WILL KILL HIM.
AND RUIN MY CHANCE.
[ Gasps, Sighs ]
LET'S JUST PRAY
WE'RE NOT TOO LATE.
JAROD, THE LORD WORKS
IN MYSTERIOUS WAYS.
SEE, YOU WERE HIS INSTRUMENT
TO HAVE ME THROWN INTO JAIL...
WHERE I COULD COME TO SEE
HIS PURPOSE IN MY LIFE.
AND THEN THROUGH HIS DIVINE
PROVIDENCE, I WAS SET FREE...
SO THAT I COULD UNITE MY PEOPLE
AND CLEANSE THIS COUNTRY.
AND NOW HERE YOU ARE,
DROPPED RIGHT IN MY LAP.
- MANNA FROM HEAVEN.
- YOU'RE SICK, BARTLETT.
YOU'RE SO CONSUMED WITH HATE,
YOU'LL DESTROY YOURSELF
AND EVERYONE AROUND YOU.
- NO, JAROD. I'M NOT SICK.
- [ Jarod Groans ]
MISUNDERSTOOD, YES.
PERSECUTED LIKE THE PROPHETS
OF OLD, YES. BUT NOT SICK.
- [ Grunts, Groans ]
- WHAT DO WE DO WITH HIM?
I'LL TAKE HIM OUT IN THE WOODS
AND SEND HIM TO HIS JUDGMENT.
[ Whimpers ]
[ Grunting ]
YOU DON'T NEED TO DIRTY
YOUR HANDS WITH THIS.
LET ME DO IT.
IT'D BE MY HONOR TO TAKE
THIS JUDAS TO HIS JUSTICE.
A TRUE APOSTLE.
DO IT DOWN BY THE CREEK AND
JUST LEAVE HIS BODY THERE.
DUST TO DUST.
WE HAVE THINGS TO DO
FOR THE UNITY RALLY
TOMORROW, DON'T WE?
THERE ARE GONNA BE
A LOT OF PEOPLE SINGING
THE BLUES TOMORROW.
GET HIM OUTTA HERE.
COME ON. COME ON.
LET'S GO.
LET'S GO!
[ Grunts ]
[ Jarod Panting ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Gasps ]
LET'S GO.
GO ON! GET DOWN!
GET DOWN ON YOUR KNEES!
[ Panting ]
YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
[ Gunshot ]
[ Panting Continues ]
I HOPE I DIDN'T
SCARE YA TOO BAD.
WELL, I GOTTA CHECK MY PANTS.
BUT I'M STILL ALIVE.
I'M UNDERCOVER TOO.
GEORGIA STATE POLICE.
A.T.F., FEDERAL TASK FORCE.
WE'VE BEEN AFTER BARTLETT
EVER SINCE HIS CONVICTION
FOR MURDER...
AND CIVIL RIGHTS VIOLATIONS
WERE OVERTURNED.
SOME FED POPPED HIM FOR THOSE.
MY GUESS IS THAT WAS YOU.
GUILTY.
I HAD NO IDEA
HE'D BEEN RELEASED.
DO YOU HAVE A PLAN?
NO, BARTLETT'S CHANGING
EVERYTHING. I'M COMPLETELY
CUT OFF FROM THE OUTSIDE.
LOOK, WE GO BACK IN THERE
RIGHT NOW, WE CAN POP HIM
FOR CONSPIRACY.
NO. WE CATCH HIM IN THE ACT
OF SETTING THOSE EXPLOSIVES,
WE CAN PUT HIM AWAY FOR LIFE.
IF WE DON'T STOP HIM,
HE'S GONNA KILL
PASTOR JONES'S LITTLE GIRLS.
HERE. HERE.
[ Panting ]
YOU GO BACK IN THERE.
YOU KEEP HIM COMPANY.
I'LL THINK OF SOMETHING.
AND, UH, GOOD LUCK.
GOOD LUCK.
HE DIDN'T BEG... MUCH.
[ Men Laughing ]
WELL, THAT'S TOO BAD.
TAKES SOME OF THE FUN OUT OF IT.
I SHOULD'VE KNOWN. JAROD
CROSSED THE DETONATOR WIRES.
THIS THING
WOULD'VE NEVER GONE OFF.
WELL, LOOK AT THAT.
AIN'T THAT PRETTY?
A LITTLE C-4 AND NAPALM--
THAT OUGHTA MAKE
QUITE A LITTLE STATEMENT.
YES, SIR, IT WILL.
I'LL JUST RUN THAT
INTO TOWN.
YOU TELL ME WHERE YOU
WANT ME TO PLACE IT.
NO. THIS IS MY VISION.
MY CALLING.
- THEN WE'LL DO IT TOGETHER.
- I SAID IT WAS MY CALLING.
I DO IT ALONE.
YOU BOYS JUST BE READY
TOMORROW.
BE READY FOR WAR.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Young Sydney ]
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET
SOMEONE, JAROD.
YOU'RE A GIRL.
- WHY DID YOU SAVE MY LIFE?
- BECAUSE...
I STILL REMEMBER THE LITTLE GIRL
WHO GAVE ME MY FIRST KISS.
I FOUND OUT SOMETHING
ON BARTLETT. HE'S BEEN
RELEASED FROM PRISON.
LET ME GUESS.
HIS CONVICTION WAS OVERTURNED
ON A TECHNICALITY.
EXACTLY. BUT WHILE HE WAS
IN PRISON, HE STARTED A VIOLENT
WHITE SUPREMACIST GROUP.
AND?
AND RUMOR IS
HE'S IN GEORGIA...
AND HE'S ORGANIZED
A MARCH IN OPPOSITION
TO A UNITY RALLY TOMORROW.
THEN LET'S STOP
THE SON OF A BITCH.
OKAY.
AND GET JAROD.
[ Muttering Prayer ]
[ Piano Keys Slamming ]
- HERE TO REPENT, BROTHER!
- JAROD?
- NOW WHO'S SINGING THE BLUES?
- I'M SO SICK TO DEATH OF YOU!
YOU HAVE MORE LIVES
THAN A BARNYARD CAT.
BUT THIS IS GONNA BE
YOUR LAST ONE.
YOU WEREN'T ABLE TO TAKE
THE ROUNDS OUT OF MY CLIP
THIS TIME.
WELL, I AM SORRY
TO DISAPPOINT YOU,
BUT GUESS WHO RELOADED
THOSE SHELLS?
I MUST HAVE FORGOT
TO PUT SHOT IN THEM.
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
[ Grunts ]
OH, BY THE WAY,
I OWE YOU THIS ONE.
[ Grunts ]
[ Drops Bat ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Jarod ]
OH, BARTLETT?
BARTLETT?
- WAKE UP!
- [ Sighs ]
JAROD, WHAT
THE HELL IS THIS?
THINK OF IT
AS YOUR CROSS TO BEAR.
AND SINCE YOU SO ENJOY
BURNING CROSSES...
AND TERRORIZING
INNOCENT FAMILIES,
I THOUGHT IT MIGHT BE FUN
FOR YOU TO EXPERIENCE
TERROR FOR ONCE.
LIKE YOU WERE GOING TO DO
TO THOSE TWO INNOCENT
LITTLE GIRLS!
I WASN'T GONNA SCARE 'EM.
I WAS GONNA KILL 'EM!
[ Laughs ]
DON'T MAKE ME LAUGH.
NOW, WE'VE BEEN THROUGH THIS
BEFORE, JAROD.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA DO ANYTHING.
[ Laughing ]
YOU AIN'T GOT
THE HEART FOR IT.
NOW, THAT BITCH
YOU WERE WITH BEFORE--
SHE COULD DO IT.
YEAH.
WELL, YOU SEE,
IT'S NOT HEART THAT I NEED
TO BURN YOU AT THE STAKE.
IT'S ANOTHER PART
OF MY ANATOMY.
AND LET ME TELL YA,
I GOT THOSE.
[ Grunts ]
YOU'LL NEVER GET AWAY WITH THIS!
I GOT PEOPLE OUT THERE.
LUKE AND THE BOYS.
LUKE! LUKE!
[ Laughs ]
YOU KNOW, SOMETHING, BARTLETT?
YOU'RE NOT AS SMART
AS YOU THINK YOU ARE.
YOU HAD TWO INFILTRATORS
IN YOUR GROUP.
LUKE WAS AN UNDERCOVER COP
WITH THE GEORGIA STATE POLICE.
THE REST OF YOUR APOSTLES
SHOULD BE IN CUSTODY
JUST ABOUT NOW.
- DAMN YOU! DAMN YOU!
- NO! DAMN YOU!
YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
PLEASE DON'T DO IT!
DON'T DO IT! DON'T!
HELP! I DON'T WANNA DIE!
NO! NO! NO!
DON'T BURN ME ALIVE!
PLEASE!
JAROD, I'M SORRY! PLEASE!
I DON'T WANNA DIE!
JAROD, I'M BEGGING YOU!
PLEASE, NOT LIKE THIS!
GOD! NO! NO!
I DON'T WANNA DIE!
SOMEONE HELP ME!
HELP! HELP, JAROD, PLEASE!
I'M SORRY! I'M SO SORRY!
DEAR GOD! PLEASE! NO!
[ Sobbing ]
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I DON'T HAVE
THE HEART TO KILL.
- [ Sirens Wailing ]
- OR THE HATE.
[ Sirens Continue ]
MMM.
HAVE FUN...
ROTTING IN PRISON.
[ Whimpering ]
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDEN ♪
♪ OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪
♪ LET THE HEALING START ♪
♪ BE BLESSED AND GUIDED ♪
♪ THROUGH ETERNITY ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDEN ♪
♪ AND BE FREE ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪
LET THE HEALING START ♪
♪ BE BLESSED AND GUIDED
THROUGH ETERNITY ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
AND BE FREE ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
♪ AND BE FREE ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
AND YOU WILL BE FREE ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
AND YOU WILL BE FREE ♪
YOU START SPEAKING IN TONGUES,
AND I'LL SEND YOU
ON TO THE NEXT LIFE
RIGHT HERE AND NOW.
[ Chuckles ]
SORRY. IT KINDA REMINDS ME
OF GOIN' WITH MY COUSIN NEWT...
TO THE SLIPPERY ROCK CHURCH
OF THE GREAT REDEEMER
WHEN I WAS A KID.
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
AND YOU WILL BE FREE ♪
HI. THANKS FOR COMIN'.
SORRY. STANDIN' ROOM ONLY.
WE'RE NOT HERE
TO WORSHIP, REVEREND.
PASTOR. I'M PASTOR JONES.
PASTOR JONES, WE
ARE LOOKING FOR THIS MAN.
THE NAME IS JAROD.
WE BELIEVE HE'S INVOLVED
IN A CONFRONTATION WITH
A RACIST NAMED BARTLETT.
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
AND YOU WILL BE FREE ♪
I'M SORRY.
NEVER SEEN HIM BEFORE.
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
NOW, I DO KNOW ABOUT BARTLETT.
IF YOU WANNA TALK TO HIM,
TRY THE STATE PENITENTIARY.
GOOD. I HOPE THEY
FRY HIS ASS THIS TIME.
WELL, MA'AM,
IT'S MY HOPE AND PRAYER...
THAT ONE DAY BARTLETT WILL
CHOOSE TO END THAT LIFE OF HATE.
- ♪♪ [ Singing Continues ]
- AND START THE HEALIN'...
THAT ONLY LOVE
AND FORGIVENESS WILL BRING.
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
- BETTER PRAY FOR ALL OF US.
- GOD BLESS YOU.
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
PASTOR JONES,
THANK YOU KINDLY.
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
AND YOU WILL BE FREE ♪
WE'RE OUTTA HERE, SYD.
LOOKS LIKE THEIR GUARDIAN
ANGEL'S COME AND GONE.
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
AND YOU WILL BE FREE ♪
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
OPEN UP YOUR HEART ♪
LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS
AND YOU WILL BE FREE ♪
♪ LAY DOWN YOUR BURDENS ♪♪