ALL RIGHT, COULD IT BE BEHIND
DOOR NUMBER ONE, TWO OR THREE?
AND YOU HAVE FIRST CHOICE
RIGHT NOW, KATHY.
WHAT DOOR DO YOU WANT?
[ Kathy ]
THREE.
DOOR NUMBER THREE.
AND, DEBBIE? DEBBIE,
JUST FOR THE FUN OF IT--
JUST FOR THE FUN OF IT,
WHICH ONE WOULD YOU HAVE CHOSEN
IF YOU WENT FOR IT?
[ Debbie ] TWO.
NUMBER TWO.
WHAT WAS BEHIND NUMBER TWO?
JUST TWO--
$2,000 IN CASH,
BECAUSE THE SUPER DEAL
WAS BEHIND... NUMBER ONE!
AND NUMBER THREE
HAD THE $1,000.
[ Knocking ]
[ Woman ]
READY TO TAKE THE PLUNGE?
READY.
IT'S MY "BIG DEAL OF THE DAY."
[ Man ]
JAROD MUST'VE SCREWED UP BAD...
IF THEY SENT
THREE OF YA OUT HERE
TO CLOSE HIM DOWN.
YOU SURE THAT YOU'RE HIS
AMWAY FIELD REPRESENTATIVES?
DO YOU REALLY THINK
THAT WE COULD FOOL SOMEONE
AS SMART AS YOURSELF?
WELL, UH, I-I GUESS
IT'S THAT AMWAY THING.
UH, I JUST NEVER THOUGHT
OF JAROD AS A GLYCERIN
AND HONEY SOAP KIND OF GUY.
THAT IS WHAT YOU PEOPLE SELL,
ISN'T IT? SOAP?
YEAH, UH, EVERYTHING
FROM, UH, BABY SHAMPOO...
TO, UH, INDUSTRIAL-STRENGTH
POOL CLEANER.
THAT'D BE GOOD FOR YOU.
OH, LOOK.
THE MATCH GAME,
THE HOME VERSION.
UH, JAROD, HE'S A--
HE'S A REGULAR
LIGHTNING ROUND LUNATIC.
WHEN HE'S NOT SURFIN' THE WAVES,
HE'S SURFIN'
THE GAME SHOW CHANNEL.
PARKER?
PUSHING THE LIMITS.
TAKING RISKS.
CONFESSIONS OF
AN ADRENALINE JUNKIE.
WHAT ARE WE TALKIN' ABOUT HERE,
SYD? JAROD KNIEVEL
JUMPING BUICKS AT CAESARS?
IT'S DAREDEVIL STUFF,
YOU KNOW? HE'S ALWAYS
DOING DANGEROUS THINGS,
LIKE NIGHT SURFING
AND STREET LUGE AND--
HE EVEN STRAPPED THAT
BULLETPROOF VEST ON ONCE AND
HE HAD ME SHOOT HIM BLINDFOLDED!
ALL MANIFESTATIONS OF
AN OBSESSION WITH RISK-TAKING.
WHAT KIND OF TRAINING
DO YOU PUT YOUR SALESPEOPLE
THROUGH, ACTUALLY?
WE'LL SEND YOU A BROCHURE.
DR. QUACKENBUSH,
ONCE AGAIN,
YOUR DIAGNOSIS HAS COME
TOO LATE TO FIND JAROD.
WELL, NOT THAT LATE.
HE LEFT LESS THAN AN HOUR AGO.
WAS THAT WITH OR WITHOUT
HIS BLINDFOLD?
YOU DON'T NEED A BLINDFOLD
TO JUMP OFF A BRIDGE.
[ Woman ]
YOU SURE YOU WANT TO STAY
WITH THIS OLD CORD, JAROD?
YOU'VE DONE 295
ON THIS ONE.
WELL, I ONLY REALLY NEED IT
TO LAST 296.
[ Yelling ]
[ Man Narrating ]
THERE ARE PRETENDERS AMONG US.
[ Jarod ]
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
THIRTY-SIX HOURS AND HE'S
ALREADY DEMONSTRATING MORE
TALENT THAN ANY OF OUR OTHERS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT I THOUGHT UP?
SINCE I BROKE OUT,
I'VE SPENT EVERY MOMENT
SEARCHING FOR MY PAST.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE'S A PRETENDER--
A GENIUS WHO CAN BECOME
ANYONE THAT HE WANTS TO BE.
- THE CENTRE WANTS HIM ALIVE.
- PREFERABLY.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE DEFENDS THE WEAK AND ABUSED.
[ Jarod ]
LIFE'S A GIFT.
- YOU A DOCTOR?
- I AM TODAY.
MR. GOLTZ'S M.R.I. REVEALS
A CLOSED FRACTURE...
OF THE RIGHT PARIETAL BONE
WITH A SUBDURAL HEMATOMA.
[ Man ]
WE'VE INSERTED A C.S.F. SHUNT,
SO WE SHOULD KNOW MORE
ONCE HIS EDEMA'S RESOLVED.
I NOTICE ON HIS ADMISSION CHART
THE PRESENCE OF
GLASS FRAGMENTS IN HIS HAIR.
[ Man ] IT'S A MYSTERY.
I ASSUMED THEY CAME
FROM HIS GLASSES.
BUT HIS MOTHER SAYS
TONY DOESN'T WEAR THEM.
COULD IT HAVE BEEN
A SPORTS GOGGLE OF SOME KIND?
NO. INDUSTRIAL-GRADE GLASS.
I, UH, DID
A LAB ANALYSIS MYSELF.
YOU DID IT,
NOT THE POLICE?
[ Man ] THEY'RE TREATING
THE ENTIRE GOLTZ CASE
AS A BUNGEE STUNT GONE BAD.
OPEN AND SHUT.
NO MORE, NO LESS.
TONY? HONEY,
COME ON BACK HOME.
YOUR SISTER AND I
MISS YOU SO.
I ALWAYS KEEP
MY FAMILY CLOSE TOO.
SORRY. YOU MUST BE
DR. NICHOLS.
- CALL ME JAROD.
- OH, PLEASE, SIT DOWN.
WHEN TONY WAKES UP,
I JUST WANT HIM TO REMEMBER.
ACTUALLY,
I DIDN'T THINK I'D EVER
SEE THESE PHOTOS AGAIN.
I THOUGHT TONY'S WALLET
HAD BEEN LOST IN THE ACCIDENT,
BUT SOMEBODY FOUND IT
AT THE NURSES' STATION
THIS MORNING.
IT WAS LEFT IN THAT ENVELOPE
WRAPPED IN WAX PAPER.
WELL, AT LEAST THE PICTURES
WERE STILL THERE.
HIS SISTER CARRIE TOOK THOSE
AT HIS LAST BIRTHDAY.
A WEEK LATER, HE WAS OFF
LOOKING FOR HIS DAD.
HE WAS SEARCHING FOR HIS FATHER?
HIS FATHER RODE OFF
ON A DIRT BIKE IN '91
AND NEVER LOOKED BACK.
SEARCHING FOR YOUR FAMILY.
IT'S INSTINCT.
NOW HIS--
HIS SISTER CARRIE'S
DOING IT.
NOT LONG AFTER WE CAME
OUT HERE TO LOOK AFTER TONY,
SHE JUST TOOK OFF.
I'M JUST HOPING THAT SOMEDAY,
WE'LL ALL BE SMILING
LIKE IN THOSE PICTURES AGAIN.
THE BEST THERAPY FOR HIM
IS TO HEAR THE VOICE
OF HIS FAMILY AND HIS FRIENDS.
I GUESS THAT'S JUST ME NOW.
HIS FRIENDS USED TO COME BY
AND VISIT, BUT THEY STOPPED.
- WHERE ARE THEY?
- I DON'T KNOW.
HE AND HIS DAREDEVIL
FRIEND ZED...
USED TO RIDE MOTORCYCLES
OUT AT A PLACE
CALLED WILLOW RIDGE.
I GUESS ZED'S
RIDING ALONE NOW.
♪♪ [ Rock, Indistinct ]
[ Honking ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
YOU OKAY?
HEY, NO PROBLEM.
I ALWAYS WANTED TO BE
A HOOD ORNAMENT.
I'LL TAKE THAT AS A "YES."
YOU KNOW, THE WAY
YOU FLEW UP MY TAILPIPE,
I THOUGHT YOU WERE A COP.
NOT TODAY.
ARE YOU SURE YOU'RE ALL RIGHT?
NO, IT'S OKAY.
THE CHICK CAN HANDLE IT.
CHICKS?
THEY CALL ME JAROD.
- FRIENDS CALL ME SHAY.
- HMM.
FRIENDS LIKE ZED?
- YOU KNOW ZED?
- I UNDERSTAND THAT HE AND
HIS FRIENDS RACE THIS ROAD.
HUH. WELL, MAYBE
I WAS RIGHT ABOUT YOU.
MAYBE YOU ARE A COP.
JUST SOMEBODY TRYIN'
TO FIGHT THE BOREDOM.
OH, BY THE WAY,
NICE RACING.
[ Engine Sputtering ]
IT'S NOT EXACTLY
A POLICE ESCORT,
BUT I HAVE AN EXTRA SEAT.
ASK ME, SPEED RACER'S
KISSED THE ASPHALT...
ONE TOO MANY TIMES
WITHOUT A HELMET.
[ Sydney ]
COULD BE A PSYCHOTIC CRY
FOR HELP.
HI, SIS.
SO I HEARD JAROD NEVER
CAME BACK TO HIS LAIR.
ANY LUCK DECIPHERING
HIS NEW OCCUPATION?
DON'T QUOTE ME,
BUT I THINK HE MORPHED INTO
THE HUMAN CANNONBALL.
JAROD SEEMS TO BE EXHIBITING
ALL THE SIGNS OF AN OBSESSION
WITH EXTREME THRILL-SEEKING.
HMM.
MAYBE HE'S REJUVENATING.
SOME JUMP OFF CLIFFS,
OTHERS SEEK RELIGION.
I, FOR ONE, REPLENISH MY SOUL
BY GOING BACK TO NATURE.
OH.
WHAT, SURPRISED TO FIND
I LIKE TO CAMP?
NO. SURPRISED TO FIND
YOU HAVE A SOUL.
ON THAT LOVING NOTE, I'M OFF
TO THE WILDS FOR THREE DAYS.
MY OFFICE WILL KNOW
HOW TO REACH ME.
I CAN DIE NOW.
I'VE SEEN IT ALL.
[ Chuckles ]
YOU WANNA BET?
THEY WERE JUST DELIVERED.
SCRATCH "HUMAN CANNONBALL."
- HE'S FREAKIN' CHUCK BARRIS.
- WELL, ACTUALLY, MONTY HALL.
AND WHAT EXACTLY IS THE DEAL
WITH JAROD'S BIG DEAL, BROOTS?
WE OPEN DOOR NUMBER ONE
WITH THIS KEY.
- WHAT ABOUT THE OTHER TWO?
- TIME-LOCKED.
THEY'LL OPEN AT
PREDETERMINED INTERVALS.
[ Miss Parker ] GIVE ME THAT.
OKAY, QUIZMASTER,
WHAT IS BEHIND DOOR NUMBER ONE?
[ Broots ]
LOOKS LIKE A GIANT
FORTUNE COOKIE.
[ Miss Parker ]
IT IS A GIANT FORTUNE COOKIE.
[ Broots ]
SO WHAT'S OUR FUTURE HOLD?
IT'S NOT ABOUT OUR FUTURE.
IT'S ABOUT THE PAST.
IT'S A DINNER BILL
FROM A FEW WEEKS AGO.
"THE HIDDEN TRUTH."
AND THE WAITRESS
WAS CALLED MAY LIN.
"THE HIDDEN TRUTH." YEAH.
THAT'S THE CHINESE RESTAURANT
I PASS BY ON MY WAY HERE.
- I'VE NEVER BEEN THERE.
- ME EITHER. YOU, SYD?
I DON'T EAT RICE.
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK
IT MEANS, MISS PARKER?
THAT WE NEED RESERVATIONS.
[ Man ]
YOU LOSE.
[ Shay ]
YO, ZEDDIE, JOJO, MACKEY.
WHAT UP, SHAY?
WHERE YOU BEEN, CHILLIN'
ON A BEACH WITH A COLDIE?
JUST RIDING.
YEAH?
YOU GONNA DO THAT LUGE
IN A WET SUIT?
I'VE BEEN SURFIN' TODAY,
DARLIN'. JOJO?
BUT I HEAR THAT WHALING STRETCH
OF ROAD IN THE GLEN'S
GETTIN' SHUT DOWN NEXT WEEK.
- SO THEY'RE DROPPING THE HILL?
- NOT SOON ENOUGH. NAME'S ZED.
-JAROD.
-HE'S NOT SOME JEHOVAH'S WITNESS
KNOCKIN' ON MY DOOR, IS HE?
WELL, I'VE WITNESSED A LOT,
BUT NEVER JEHOVAH.
THAT'S GOOD, 'CAUSE I'M BROKE.
AND I HAVEN'T SEEN GOD.
AT LEAST NOT SINCE I HAD
THAT AWESOME MELTDOWN LUGIN'
A CANYON LAST WEEK, HEY, GUYS?
[ Man ]
RIGHT ON!
- YOU LIKE TO RIDE, "J"?
- ANYTHING AND EVERYTHING.
WHAT DO YOU DO FOR A LIVING?
WELL, I SEEM TO HAVE TROUBLE
HOLDING DOWN A STEADY JOB.
I GET BORED PRETTY EASILY.
AH, BOREDOM.
THE ENDLESS BOWEL.
- WHAT ABOUT YOURSELF?
- A JOB HERE, A JOB THERE,
YOU KNOW.
- WHATEVER KEEPS CHEERIOS
ON THE TABLE.
- AMEN TO THAT.
HE CAN RIDE, ZED.
I KNOW SINCE TONY'S BEEN OUT,
YOU'VE BEEN LOOKING
FOR ANOTHER PLAYER.
IS THAT RIGHT?
- YOU UP FOR AN ENDORPHIN FIX?
- IF IT TAKES MORE NAD THAN
LUGING DOWN A CANYON, SURE.
WHY NOT?
WELL, IF YOU GOT 'EM,
BRING 'EM ALONG.
THEN YOU TELL ME.
COME ON, MATES.
[ Zed ]
200 YARDS, HEAD ON.
KEEP YOUR WHEELS
ON THE DOUBLE YELLOW.
IN THE OLD DAYS, THEY USED TO
CALL THIS CHICKEN. I THINK
OF IT MORE OF A CHANCE...
TO, UH, GET A GRIN
FROM THE GODS.
LET'S MAKE THEM SMILE.
LET'S DO IT.
I'M DAMN GOOD, JAROD,
BUT ZED'S GREAT.
DON'T BLINK.
HE'S CAGEABLE.
- OH!
- OOH!
NICE ONE, "J" MAN.
NOT EVEN MY MATE TONY
TOOK ME THAT FAR.
THERE'S A SPOT IN MY TRIBE
IF YOU WANT IT.
MMM.
GOT NOTHIN' BETTER TO DO.
YOU KNOW, I'VE NEVER SEEN ZED
TAKE TO ANYBODY SO FAST, JAROD.
EASY COME, EASY GO,
I GUESS.
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT TONY?
YEAH.
WHO IS THIS GUY?
TONY USED TO HANG WITH
THE GROUP BEFORE I GOT HERE.
THEN HE GOT MESSED UP
IN A BUNGEE ACCIDENT
A LITTLE OVER A MONTH AGO.
DID HIS CORD BREAK?
FRAYED OR SOMETHING
WHILE TAKIN' A PLUNGE
OFF THE PARKER'S MILL ROAD.
THE DOCTORS DON'T GIVE HIM
MUCH OF A CHANCE.
BUT, HEY,
LIKE ZED ALWAYS SAYS,
FIRST ONE TO 40 ALIVE LOSES.
"J" MAN!
I'M REALLY GLAD
YOU MADE IT TONIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW IF SHAY TOLD YOU,
BUT FRIDAY NIGHTS...
WE DON'T EXACTLY
SQUARE DANCE AROUND THE RADIO.
WE LIKE TO TRY NEW THINGS,
PUSH THE ENVELOPE.
THEN LET'S MAKE THE GODS GRIN.
NO, NO, NO.
LET'S MAKE 'EM LAUGH OUT LOUD.
[ Man ]
WHOO!
FREE THE BRAIN, FREE THE BODY.
FREE THE BODY, FREE THE SOUL.
AND YOU THOUGHT WE WERE GOIN'
HANG GLIDIN' TONIGHT, "J."
FIRE WALKERS IN MAURITIUS LEARN
HOW TO CHANNEL THEIR FEARS,
HARNESS THEM,
TO CREATE A POWER
THAT COULD NOT BE DENIED.
IT'S A POWER
FREE FOR THE TAKING.
NOTHING IS FREE.
I'M STARTIN' TO THINK
YOU'RE A SLAVE
TO THE SAME DEMONS I AM, "J."
WITHOUT DEMONS,
THERE CAN BE NO ANGELS.
F.Y.I.
BASALTIC ROCK.
IT'S A MUCH BETTER
CONDUCTOR OF HEAT.
IF YOU'RE GOING
TO FREE YOUR SOUL,
I SAY FREE IT.
I GUESS OUR CHINESE DINNER WAS
OFFICIALLY A ZONK LAST NIGHT.
ANY RESULTS YET
ON THAT DINNER BILL
FROM THE FORTUNE COOKIE?
WELL, MY PAL BODIE
DOWN IN PHYSICAL
DID A RUSH JOB FOR ME.
THE GEEK WITH
CLOUDY CATARACTS?
YEAH.
HAVE YOU SEEN THEM LATELY?
IT'S MILKIER THAN A GUERNSEY.
SAYS THE KIDS LOVE IT
ON HALLOWEEN.
SOME ZOMBIE THING HE DOES.
THE RESULTS, BROOTS.
UH--
THE-THE ONLY PRINTS ON THE BILL
BELONG TO THE WAITRESS.
MAY, LAST NAME, LIN.
THE ONE WHO QUIT
OVER A MONTH AGO
WITH NO FORWARDING ADDRESS?
LIKE I SAID, ZONK.
OH, MISS PARKER?
JAROD'S DOOR NUMBER TWO
JUST OPENED.
COME SEE WHAT I FOUND INSIDE.
[ Jarod ]
THANK YOU, THANK YOU,
THANK YOU!
IT'S TIME FOR
ANOTHER EXCITING GAME OF
YOU DON'T HAVE A CLUE.
I'M YOUR HOST,
JAROD WINKERDALE,
AND IT'S TIME TO SEE
IF YOU HAVE A CLUE.
THIS IS NO STRESS DISORDER, SYD.
IT'S CHERNOBYL OF THE BRAIN.
TODAY'S LUCKY CONTESTANT
IS MISS PARKER!
SHE'LL HAVE OVERNIGHT
TO FIGURE OUT HER CLUE.
AND IF SHE DOES, SHE'LL WIN
A TRIP TO THE BEAUTIFUL
CABINS O' LOVE HIDEAWAY...
NESTLED INTO THE ROLLING HILLS
OF THOMPSON, WEST VIRGINIA.
DON'T LOOK AT ME.
I WATCH SOAPS.
OKAY, MISS PARKER,
HERE'S YOUR CLUE.
THE HIDDEN TRUTH MAY BE MISSING,
BUT YOU WON'T FIND IT
UNTIL YOU CLAIM YOUR PRIZE.
[ Bell Dings ]
"THE HIDDEN TRUTH."
THE NAME OF THE RESTAURANT.
"MAY. MAY MISSING."
THE WAITRESS MAY LIN
IS MISSING.
"YOU WON'T FIND IT
UNTIL YOU CLAIM YOUR PRIZE."
A TRIP TO THE BEAUTIFUL
CABINS 0' LOVE.
BEAUTIFUL INDEED.
[ Tony's Mother's Voice ]
TONY'S WALLET HAD BEEN LOST
IN THE ACCIDENT,
BUT SOMEBODY FOUND IT
AT THE NURSES' STATION
THIS MORNING.
IT WAS LEFT IN THAT ENVELOPE
WRAPPED IN WAX PAPER.
- FOUR BUCKS.
- THESE ARE DELICIOUS.
OUGHTA BE.
HARRY'S GOT THE DIRTIEST
DIRTY WATER DOGS IN TOWN.
FOUR DUCKIES.
MY WALLET.
- HAVE YOU SEEN MY WALLET?
- HOW WOULD I KNOW WHERE IT IS?
WELL, SINCE YOU HAVE SUCH
A KNACK FOR FINDING WALLETS,
I THOUGHT MAYBE YOU KNEW
WHERE MINE WAS.
LOOK, WHEN I SAW ON THE NEWS...
THAT THE GUY WAS IN A COMA
FROM THAT BUNGEE ACCIDENT,
I FELT GUILTY.
OH, AN HONORABLE THIEF.
I DIDN'T ROB HIM.
I FOUND IT.
ABOUT A MONTH AGO IN THE BUSHES
WHEN I WAS SWEEPIN' UP GLASS.
INDUSTRIAL-GRADE GLASS.
IT WAS ON THE SIDEWALK
BELOW THAT HIGH-RISE THERE.
THE MORNING AFTER THE ROBBERY,
A RARE COIN DEALER
ON THE 30th FLOOR.
A BUNCH OF 'EM ZIP-LINED
FROM THAT BUILDING THROUGH
THE WINDOWS TO THAT ONE.
YOU'D HAVE TO BE CRAZY
TO TRY A STUNT LIKE THAT.
OR SEARCHING FOR YOUR SOUL.
[ Door Closes ]
JAROD, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I WAS LOOKING FOR A WRENCH.
MY-MY BIKE'S LOSING COMPRESSION.
AND YOU?
OH, UH, I THOUGHT
YOU WERE ZED.
DID YOU TAKE THIS PICTURE?
NO.
BEFORE I GOT HERE.
IS THAT TONY?
YEAH.
I-I GUESS. ZED USED TO
TALK ABOUT HIM ALL THE TIME
RIGHT AFTER THE ACCIDENT.
MORE THAN HE DOES NOW.
TONY AND ZED,
THEY WERE REALLY GOOD FRIENDS?
TONY WAS IN ZED'S INNER GROUP.
SEE, WITH ZED
IT'S ALL ABOUT
THE ULTIMATE THRILL,
PUSHING THE ENVELOPE,
CHALLENGING THE PEOPLE AROUND
HIM TO FIND THEIR TRUE SELVES.
WHEN HE THINKS YOU'RE READY,
HE INVITES YOU ON
THE ULTIMATE THRILL.
ULTIMATE THRILL,
OR ULTIMATE TEST?
- BOTH, I GUESS.
- HAVE YOU BEEN INVITED?
- I GUESS HE DOESN'T THINK
I'M READY YET.
- AND TONY?
WAS THAT THE ULTIMATE THRILL,
OR THE ULTIMATE TEST?
I DON'T KNOW.
IF YOU'RE NOT IN,
YOU'RE NOT IN.
WELL, I DIDN'T MEAN
TO INTERRUPT.
[ Forced Chuckle ]
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
- SO WHEN DOES ALL
THIS FUN BEGIN?
- MEANING?
MEANING I'M NOT HANGING
AROUND HERE FOR MY HEALTH.
THE ONLY PEOPLE AROUND HERE
WHO ARE HAVING ANY FUN ARE YOU
AND YOUR MERRY LITTLE MEN.
WELL, THOSE MERRY LITTLE MEN
ARE SPECIAL PEOPLE, JAROD.
PEOPLE WHO HAVE PROVEN
THEMSELVES, YOU KNOW?
- PUSHED THE LIMITS OF BOTH
MIND AND BODY.
- AND THE LAW?
YOUR TOYS, THEY WEREN'T
EXACTLY DROPPED OFF
BY SANTA CLAUS, WERE THEY?
LIKE I SAID, "J,"
WHATEVER IT TAKES TO PUT
CHEERIOS ON THE TABLE.
DO YOU THINK YOU HAVE
WHAT IT TAKES, JAROD?
I DON'T KNOW.
WHY DON'T YOU BE THE JUDGE?
IT'S SIMPLE, "J."
I DUMP YOU IN THE WATER,
THEN I THROW IN A KEY.
OBJECT: FREE YOURSELF
BEFORE YOU DIE.
- ZED, THIS IS TOO FAR.
- A CLOSED MIND IS
A CRIPPLED MIND, SHAY.
MAKE FEAR WORK FOR YOU.
CONQUER IT.
JAROD KNOWS.
YOU HAVE TO TASTE DEATH
TO LIVE LIFE.
RIGHT?
OH, I ALMOST FORGOT.
CAN YOU CONQUER THE FEAR, "J"?
YOU'D BE SURPRISED
WHAT I CAN DO.
- ONE MINUTE.
- GIVE HIM THE KEY.
HE'S JUST GETTIN' STARTED,
MY LOVE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
LIKE THE ADS SAY,
HELPING HIM BE
ALL THAT HE CAN BE.
HOW ABOUT YOU, SHAY?
HOW FAR WILL YOU PUSH IT
TO BE YOUR BEST?
NINETY SECONDS.
TWO MINUTES.
NO.
HE DON'T WANT HELP.
2:15.
[ Coughs ]
MIND CONQUERS BODY.
WELCOME TO
THE OTHER SIDE, "J."
WELCOME TO THE MERRY MEN.
MAY LIN STAYED
IN THIS CABIN HERE.
PERFECT.
I TRIED TO ENGAGE MAY
IN SOME OCCASIONAL CHITCHAT,
BUT THE LITTLE WAITRESS
WAS A BIT STAND-OFFISH.
I CAN'T IMAGINE
WHAT WOULD MAKE HER
UNCOMFORTABLE AROUND HERE.
ME NEITHER.
BUT I GUESS THEM PEOPLE JUST
LIKE TO STICK TO THEMSELVES.
WHAT KIND OF A RACIST COMMENT
IS THAT?
OH, NO.
I'M NOT UNSOPHISTICATED.
I WAS TALKING ABOUT HER GENDER.
SINGLE WOMAN AND SUCH.
YOU'RE UNATTACHED,
AREN'T YOU?
AS UNATTACHED AS YOUR LIMBS
ARE GONNA BE...
IF YOU KEEP EYEBALLING ME
LIKE THAT, MR. DATSUN.
WELL, ANYHOO,
MAY LIN UP AND VAMOOSED
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT,
SKIPPIN' ON HER BILL.
LEFT HER STUFF BEHIND TOO--
THREE DRESSES, FOUR TOPS,
SHOES, SOCKS, COSMETICS,
AND SIX PAIR OF...
LITTLE BLACK PANTIES.
WELL, I HAD
TO INVENTORY IT.
I BET YOU DID.
KINDA CREEPY.
PRETTY GIRL LIKE THAT
JUST VANISHIN' AND ALL.
YEAH. CREEPY.
A GOOD WRENCH IS HARD
TO COME BY, ISN'T IT,
CARRIE?
[ Chuckles ]
HOW'D YOU KNOW?
THE PAIN IN YOUR EYES
WHEN YOU SAW YOUR BROTHER
IN THIS PICTURE.
TONY IS YOUR BROTHER.
YOUR MOTHER IS
VERY WORRIED ABOUT YOU.
I'M GONNA FIND OUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO TONY.
NOW, I KNOW ZED IS RESPONSIBLE.
I JUST CAN'T PROVE IT YET.
ZED IS NOT SOMEONE
THAT YOU MESS WITH.
NOW, HE TALKS A MEAN GAME
ABOUT LIFE AND ABOUT DEATH,
BUT WHEN PUSH COMES TO SHOVE,
YOU'LL BE THE ONE
DOING THE DYING.
I'M HERE TO HELP YOU.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO TRUST ME.
TONY TOLD ME THAT
HE MET THIS--
HE MET THIS GUY NAMED ZED,
WHO PROMISED TO HELP HIM
FIND OUR FATHER.
HE SAID HE USED TO RIDE
WITH DAD BACK IN '96.
TONY TRUSTED HIM.
HE BELIEVED HIM.
WHAT HAPPENED?
A MONTH AGO,
THE NIGHT OF TONY'S ACCIDENT,
HE CALLED ME.
I TOLD HIM THAT
OUR MOTHER GOT A CALL
FROM OUR GRANDMOTHER,
AND THEY HADN'T SPOKEN
IN YEARS.
SHE SAID MY FATHER
DIED IN '92.
THAT'S WAY BEFORE ZED
CLAIMS HE KNEW HIM.
SO ZED WAS STRINGING
YOUR BROTHER ALONG.
TONY GOT REALLY ANGRY,
AND HE SAID
HE WAS GONNA CONFRONT ZED.
BUT I GUESS
HE NEVER GOT THE CHANCE.
MAYBE HE DID.
CARRIE, YOU ARE IN
WAY OVER YOUR HEAD.
I WANT YOU TO GO HOME
AND BE WITH YOUR FAMILY.
- I'LL FIND OUT WHAT REALLY
HAPPENED TO YOUR BROTHER.
- NO!
NO WAY.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU MESS WITH MY FAMILY,
YOU MESS WITH ME.
CARRIE, LISTEN TO ME.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
I HAVE NO IDEA
HOW YOU GOT INVOLVED IN THIS,
JAROD, BUT... I LIKE YOU.
SO DON'T CROSS ME.
PLEASE?
[ Broots ]
FIND ANYTHING AT
THE CABINS O' LOVE?
YEAH. HOW TO RUIN A PAIR
OF GUCCI'S WITH RED CLAY.
YEAH, THAT'S FUNNY.
THE ENTIRE TRIP
WAS A REGULAR LAUGH RIOT,
THANKS TO JAROD'S
WHACKED-OUT RENDITION
OF ALEX TREBEK.
IT'S MONTY HALL.
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
NO TIME LIKE THE PRESENT
TO FIND OUT
JUST HOW WHACKED-OUT.
WHAT IS IT?
SOMETHING FOR YOU TO CLEAN UP
YOUR THEORIES WITH.
THERE'S A NOTE.
"BE CAREFUL WHAT YOU DIG FOR."
THERE'S AN ADDRESS ON HERE.
- IT'S LYLE'S ADDRESS.
- HUH.
HMM.
SO, LOVE, IT'S UP TO YOU.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
"J." SAME INVITE STANDS
FOR YOU AS IT DOES FOR SHAY.
- INVITE?
- YEAH.
GOT A JUICY LITTLE EXCURSION
TO THE OTHER SIDE
PLANNED FOR TONIGHT.
THAT IS, IF YOU'RE UP TO IT.
ANYTHING JAROD CAN HANDLE,
I CAN TOO.
EVEN DEATH?
AS THE ANCIENTS SAID,
WHEN THE GODS CREATED MAN,
THEY SAW DEATH
AND SAVED LIFE FOR THEMSELVES.
I SAY,
SINCE WE CAN'T LIVE FOREVER,
LET'S AT LEAST LIVE.
TIME TO DO BATTLE WITH THE GODS.
PASS TONIGHT'S TEST,
AND THERE'LL BE NO LIMIT.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO DO THIS, CARRIE.
THE NAME IS SHAY.
DON'T FORGET IT.
GOOD NEWS, SHAY. THE OWNERS
OF THE HOUSE AREN'T HOME,
MAKIN' YOUR JOB EASIER.
THERE'S A SET OF BLUEPRINTS
IN THE DESK IN THE OFFICE.
BRING THEM TO ME,
WIN VALUABLE PRIZES.
YOU WANT ME
TO ROB THE HOUSE?
THIS IS NOT
ABOUT STEALIN', LOVE.
THIS IS ABOUT
PUSHIN' THE ENVELOPE.
- SHE'S NOT READY.
- I CAN DO IT!
HEY, I KNOW YOU CAN DO IT.
BUT CAN YOU FEEL IT?
CAN YOU FEEL THE DANGER?
THAT'S YOUR PASSAGE
TO THE OTHER SIDE.
[ Dialing, Line Ringing ]
YEAH, PAC TECH SECURITY?
I'D LIKE TO REPORT A BURGLARY.
1600 SEAWARD.
YOU'RE SENDING HER INTO A DANGER
SHE'S NOT READY FOR.
THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY
TO FIND OUT, YOU KNOW?
UH, HELLO. SORRY.
I JUST MADE
A REAL BIG MISTAKE.
IT WAS JUST MY DAUGHTER
COMING HOME LATE WITHOUT A KEY.
YOU'RE MESSIN' WITH MY GAME.
JUST TRYIN' TO HAVE
A LITTLE FUN.
RAISE THE BAR A LITTLE BIT.
NOTHING LIKE A FEW 911 CALLS
TO SPICE UP THE SOUP.
- GO.
- [ Dogs Barking ]
CIRCLE.
CARRIE?
[ Grunting ]
IT'S ME! IT'S ME!
IT'S ME.
JAROD!
I DID IT.
I GOT THE BLUEPRINTS.
YOU'RE BLEEDING.
I CUT MYSELF
BREAKING IN, AND--
FREEZE! POLICE!
DAMN IT!
GO THAT WAY!
STOP!
GO, GO, GO!
MOVE IT!
"J" MAN. THE CHEERIOS
ARE IN THE CUPBOARD.
DAMN THING STARTED BLEEDING
AGAIN. I WAS LOOKING
FOR SOMETHING TO STOP IT UP.
YEAH, WELL, THERE'S NO THRILL
IN BLEEDIN' TO DEATH,
IS THERE?
YOU KNOW, WHETHER IT'S
A SUICIDE LUNGE,
BUNGEE DIVE,
IT'S ALL ABOUT TRUST...
IN YOURSELF
AND THE ONES AROUND YOU.
- TRUST IS KEY.
- EXACTLY.
- FIRST AID KIT'S IN
THE BATHROOM DOWN THE HALL.
- THANK YOU.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
IT'S ME. SHH. IT'S JAROD.
WE'RE GETTING OUT OF HERE.
JAROD, ZED'S BEEN ASKING
FOR YOU ALL NIGHT.
IT'S ALMOST TIME.
FOR WHAT, HIS FINAL CHALLENGE?
YOU'RE COMING WITH ME.
FORGET IT!
IF THIS SON OF A BITCH IS
RESPONSIBLE FOR MY BROTHER'S
COMA, I HAVE TO PROVE IT.
THAT'S GOING TO BE
VERY DIFFICULT FOR YOU
TO DO FROM PRISON.
I FOUND OUT THAT
THE ACME WAREHOUSE IS
A FRONT FOR MONEY LAUNDERING.
HE'S GONNA USE YOU
TO STEAL CASH,
JUST LIKE HE USED YOUR BROTHER
TO ROB THAT COIN DEALER...
THE NIGHT OF YOUR BROTHER'S
SO-CALLED ACCIDENT.
NOW, WE ARE LEAVING.
I DON'T THINK SO, "J."
YOU KNOW, SHAY,
YOUR BROTHER TONY...
WAS THE CALMEST DUDE
I EVER SAW AT 30 STORIES.
YOU, ON THE OTHER HAND,
LOOK A LITTLE PALE.
BUT THAT'S ALL RIGHT,
'CAUSE I ONLY NEED YOU AS
A SACRIFICIAL LAMB RIGHT NOW.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT, DOC?
JOJO FOLLOWED YOU
TO THE HOSPITAL.
I DON'T KNOW WHO YOU ARE, BUT
THIS DIFFERENT IDENTITY SCENE
MUST BE A RUSH, HUH?
LET'S GO.
NOW I KNOW WHAT TONY
MUST HAVE FELT...
WHEN YOU PUSHED HIM
OFF THAT BRIDGE WEARING
THAT FAULTY BUNGEE CORD.
- THIS SIDE WON'T BE THE SAME
WITHOUT YOU, "J."
- WEIGHTS ARE IN, ZEDDIE.
GIVE MY BEST TO
THE BEAST OF THE GODS.
HE'LL DIE!
BRING HER WITH.
YOU---
[ Gasping ]
[ Broots ]
I SURE HOPE LYLE
IS STILL ON HIS CAMPOUT.
IT'S STUFFY IN HERE.
BEING HERE
GIVES ME THE CREEPS.
WOW.
HIS DECOR IS LIKE
KUNG FU MEETS THE JETSONS.
[ Sarcastic Chuckle ]
FROM CHINESE RESTAURANTS
TO LOVE LODGES...
TO THIS GQ SPREAD
FOR ANAL RETENTION,
JAROD'S HAD US RUNNING AROUND
IN HIS GAME SHOW HELL.
- WHY?
- TO FIND A GRAND PRIZE OF SOME
KIND HERE IN LYLE'S APARTMENT.
SOMETHING INCONGRUOUS
WITH THE SURROUNDINGS.
SOMETHING OUT OF PLACE.
A SPECK OF DUST WOULD BE
OUT OF PLACE IN THIS JOINT.
I FOUND HIS CENTRE
EXPENSE REPORT.
YOU CAN LEARN A LOT ABOUT
A MAN BASED ON THE WAY
HE SPENDS HIS MONEY.
LIKE THE FACT THAT
MY THUMBLESS SIBLING RIPS OFF
THE CENTRE FOR EVERYTHING...
FROM SILK STOCKINGS
TO HERBAL LAXATIVES.
LIKES TO DINE OUT TOO.
LOOK AT THAT.
- THERE MUST BE OVER A DOZEN
CHARGES FOR THE HIDDEN TRUTH.
- THAT'S WHERE MAY LIN WORKED.
AND HE HAS CHARGES FROM
THE CABINS 0' LOVE LODGE.
CHECKED OUT THE SAME DAY
MAY LIN VANISHED.
MISS PARKER?
THERE'S TWO SHOVELS HERE.
THEY BOTH HAVE RED CLAY ON THEM.
NOT UNLIKE THE CLAY
YOU FOUND ON YOUR SHOES.
UH-OH.
WHAT?
THERE'S A DOOR.
OW.
I GOT A BAD FEELING ABOUT THIS.
SMILE, BROOTS. WE JUST WON
THE BIG DEAL OF THE DAY.
[ Broots ]
IT'S A SHED, JUST LIKE
THE ONE JAROD SENT US.
THIS DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
IT MAKES PERFECT SENSE.
MR. LYLE IS LOCKING
HIMSELF AWAY.
OH. THAT MAKES SENSE?
[ Sydney ]
AS A CHILD,
MR. LYLE'S FOSTER FATHER...
KEPT HIM LOCKED IN A WOODSHED
WEEKS AT A TIME.
WE ALL TRY TO PRESERVE
OUR CHILDHOOD...
WITH ONE RITUAL OR ANOTHER.
IN LYLE'S CASE, THIS WOODSHED
MAY BE THE ONLY PLACE...
IN THE WHOLE WORLD
WHERE HE FEELS SAFE.
- WHAT DOES THAT HAVE TO DO
WITH MAY LIN?
- EVERYTHING.
YOU MEAN HE--
I BELIEVE THE WORD
IS TORTURE.
IS MURDER.
AND THE JEOPARDY ANSWER
IS HE SLEEPS IN A SHED...
JUST LIKE THE ONE
HE WAS TORTURED IN
WHEN HE WAS LITTLE.
HE STALKS AND KIDNAPS
ASIAN WOMEN,
WHO HE THEN BRINGS TO
A HIDDEN TORTURE CHAMBER.
- WHO IS MR. LYLE?
- OR WHAT?
[ Zed ]
WE'RE ALMOST INTO
THE CASH ROOM, BOYS.
[ Beeping ]
GOT IT. WE'RE IN.
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
IT'S PAYDAY.
GO GET THE CASH.
GO!
[ Gasps ]
SMILE, SHAY.
THIS IS SUPPOSED TO BE
THE FUN PART.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
BEST THRILL YET.
YO, ZEDDIE!
IT'S LOCKED.
COME ON, ZEDDIE!
[ Men Shouting, Indistinct ]
[ Alarm Sounding ]
WHAT IS GOIN' ON HERE?
AAH!
YOU KNOW, IT'S AMAZING
WHAT YOU CAN DO WITH
A PAIR OF WIRE CUTTERS...
AND A GARAGE DOOR
OPENER.
TAKE THESE CUFFS OFF NOW!
THAT WOULDN'T BE ANY FUN.
WHERE'S THE THRILL IN THAT?
SPEAKING OF WHICH,
I GOT A SURPRISE FOR YOU.
JUST...
DON'T GO AWAY.
[ Yells ]
HERE. GO TO YOUR MOM.
SHE'S WORRIED ABOUT YOU.
NOW, GO.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
I'M GIVING YOU SOMETHING
THAT YOU DIDN'T GIVE TONY--
A CHANCE.
SLIM, BUT A CHANCE.
- WHAT'S GOING ON, "J"?
- THE ULTIMATE THRILL.
THE ULTIMATE TEST.
OR SHOULD I SAY,
THE ULTIMATE SPLAT?
WOW. THIS CORD IS SO OLD.
I DON'T--
I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S GONNA
MAKE IT THROUGH ANOTHER JUMP.
OH, WELL, LIKE YOU SAY:
[ Imitating Zed ]
"IT'S TIME TO DO BATTLE
WITH THE BEAST OF THE GODS."
- PULL ME UP, "J," NOW!
- OH, CAN YOU FEEL IT?
CAN YOU FEEL THE FEAR?
THAT'S YOUR TICKET
TO THE ULTIMATE THRILL.
YEAH!
GET ME DOWN FROM HERE!
DID YOU GIVE TONY GOLTZ
THAT CHANCE?
HE TRUSTED YOU.
HE TRUSTED YOU
TO FIND THE FATHER THAT
HE'D BEEN SEARCHING FOR.
HE FOUND OUT YOU LIED TO HIM,
THAT YOU WERE JUST USING HIM,
TURNING HIM INTO A THIEF.
TONY WAS GUTSY...
BUT STUPID.
HE WAS GOING TO TURN YOU
INTO THE POLICE,
SO YOU TIED HIM TO
A FAULTY BUNGEE CORD AND
YOU TOSSED HIM TO HIS DEATH.
ONLY HE DIDN'T DIE, DID HE?
NOW HE'S LYING IN A HOSPITAL BED
TRAPPED INSIDE HIS OWN BODY,
AND HE MAY NEVER AGAIN
EXPERIENCE ANOTHER THRILL.
BUT THEN AGAIN,
NEITHER WILL YOU.
NO. NO. NO.
NO. NO!
READY, SET--
OKAY! OKAY!
I DID IT!
I KNEW TONY WAS GONNA GO
TO THE POLICE.
NOW GET ME DOWN FROM HERE!
YOU'D BETTER RELAX, ZED.
- COME ON. YOU FEEL IT?
- YEAH, WELL--
YOU FEEL THE DANGER?
THAT'S YOUR PASSAGE TO
THE OTHER SIDE, REMEMBER?
NO!
ENJOY YOUR JOURNEY.
- NO!
- OH, LIKE YOU SAID:
YOU'VE GOT TO TASTE DEATH
TO EXPERIENCE LIFE.
[ Yelling ]
I GUESS THIS OLD CORD HAD
ONE MORE JUMP IN IT AFTER ALL.
GET ME OUT OF HERE!
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
WHAT? JAROD ATTEND
A MONTY HALL GARAGE SALE?
MR. LYLE,
YOU SEEM SO, UM--
RELAXED?
YEAH, I JUST CAME IN FROM
THE MOUNTAINS. I HEARD
YOU HAD A LEAD ON JAROD.
NO, ALL OF THIS...
WAS A DEAD END.
DIDN'T EVEN SHED ANY LIGHT
ON HIS PERSONALITY, SYD?
NO. NOT ON HIS.
OH, WELL.
UM, NOTHING PERSONAL,
BUT YOU THREE
LOOK TERRIBLE.
YOU SHOULD TAKE A BREAK,
REJUVENATE,
GET INTO THE GREAT OUTDOORS,
RELIEVE SOME OF THAT STRESS.
GOD KNOWS IT MAKES ME FEEL
SO ALIVE.
♪♪ [ Whistling ]
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
I'M GONNA THROW UP.
WHAT?
ONE OF US HAS TO STOP HIM,
MISS PARKER.
I WAS TOO LATE FOR MAY LIN.
I'LL KEEP MY EYES OPEN.
COUNT ON IT.
JAROD, WE TOOK A HELL OF A RISK
BREAKING INTO LYLE'S APARTMENT.
SOMETIMES, THE RISKS
WE TAKE ARE WORTH IT.
WELL, I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON "THE FEUD."