[ Man ]
JAROD WAS A REAL
EVEN-TEMPERED MAN.
STAYED HERE FOR ABOUT A WEEK,
THEN HE WAS GONE.
I SORT OF ACT AS
BUILDING MANAGER HERE,
BUT MY REAL PASSION
IS ACUPUNCTURE.
JAROD REALLY GOT INTO IT TOO.
YOU STUCK NEEDLES INTO HIM?
ACTUALLY, I TAUGHT HIM
HOW TO DO IT HIMSELF.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE?
STRESS REDUCTION.
I'M VERY GOOD AT REDUCING
TENSIONS IN THE BODY.
FUNNY. I'M VERY GOOD
AT CAUSING THEM.
JAROD WANTED THE NEEDLES PLACED
ALONG THE BRACHIAL PLEXUS.
BRACHIAL PLEXUS?
NERVE CENTER FOR
THE UPPER EXTREMITIES?
[ Man ]
HE WANTED ME TO LEAVE THEM IN
UNTIL HIS ARM WAS PARALYZED.
HE'D WALK AROUND
LIKE THAT FOR DAYS.
YOU OBVIOUSLY LIVED
THROUGH THE '60s.
DOES YOUR COMPANION KNOW
THE CONCEPT OF FREE LOVE?
- WHEN DID HE LEAVE?
- TWO DAYS AGO.
WELL, THEN OUR WORK HERE
IS MERCIFULLY DONE.
OH.
BUT THEN YOU'LL
MISS OUT ON THIS.
HE SAID YOU'D KNOW
WHAT IT MEANT.
THIS BUILDING
ISN'T FAR FROM HERE.
HMM.
[ Chattering ]
[ Woman ]
HE'S UP THERE.
[ Sirens Wailing ]
WHERE THE HELL'S
MY CAMERAMAN?
IT'S A LONG WAY DOWN.
STAY AWAY FROM ME.
I JUST WANT
TO TALK TO YOU.
JAROD, WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING UP THERE?
YOU'D BETTER BE
ROLLING ON THIS GUY.
MY NAME'S JAROD.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
DAVE. MY NAME'S DAVE.
BEAUTIFUL FAMILY.
I'M GUESSING THAT'S YOUR WIFE
AND YOUR CHILDREN.
THEY'RE GONE.
THEY WERE EVICTED,
AND NOW I CAN'T FIND THEM.
DAVE, I'M SURE THEY'RE FINE.
I'LL BET THEY'RE OUT THERE
SOMEWHERE WORRYING ABOUT YOU.
NOBODY'S WORRIED ABOUT ME.
IF THAT WERE TRUE,
WOULD I BE UP HERE
ON THIS LEDGE?
I'M SURE THAT THEY
ARE LOOKING FOR YOU.
WHY SHOULD THEY?
I DRINK SOME.
I CAN'T HOLD A JOB.
I'VE LOST THEM FOR GOOD.
I CAN HELP YOU FIND THEM, DAVE.
USE THE CAMERA.
TELL THEM HOW MUCH
YOU LOVE THEM,
HOW MUCH YOU MISS THEM,
HOW MUCH YOU NEED THEM.
BUT FIRST, WE HAVE TO
GET OFF THIS LEDGE.
GRAB MY HAND.
[ Man Narrating ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Jarod ]
GRAB MY HAND.
ONLY THING WOULD'VE MADE
THIS BETTER WAS IF THE JUMPER
WAS A TOPLESS DANCER.
- [ Laughs ]
- POOR GUY.
ANNIE, EDIT OUT SOME CLIPS
FOR THE PROMO TEAM A.S.A.P.
THIS RUNS TONIGHT.
WE GOTTA GET SOME FOOTAGE OF
THIS LOSER'S WIFE AND KIDS.
MAYBE THEY'VE CHECKED INTO
A HOMELESS SHELTER.
AFTER ALL THIS,
DON'T YOU THINK THE FAMILY
DESERVES A LITTLE PRIVACY?
PRIVACY? TO GET HER FACE
ON THE 10:00 NEWS AND SOME
PARTY MONEY IN HER POCKET,
THIS GUY'S WIFE'LL JUMP
AT THE CHANCE.
- NO PUN INTENDED, HUH?
- [ Men Laugh ]
TOO BAD YOU GOT SUCH
A GOOD GRIP THERE, JAROD.
- WHY IS THAT?
- A HEROIC ATTEMPT
IS AS GOOD AS A SAVE.
THE PLUNGE WOULD'VE GIVEN
THIS PIECE A BETTER PUNCH.
SPOKEN LIKE AN ANCHORMAN
WHO WANTS HIS ANCHOR BACK.
YOU KNOW, JAROD,
IF MY INSTINCTS ARE AS
GOOD AS I KNOW THEY ARE,
YOUR FACE IS GOING TO
BE RUNNING IN EVERY
LIVING ROOM IN AMERICA.
ACTUALLY, I THINK IT
WOULD PLAY BETTER...
IF PHIL GOT CREDIT FOR THE SAVE.
- WHAT?
- I MEAN, HE'S THE TALENT.
HE'S THE HERO THAT EVERYONE
TUNES IN TO SEE EACH DAY,
NOT ME.
ONLY PROBLEM IS, OUR HERO
WAS STANDING IN A PARKING LOT
100 FEET BELOW THE ACTION.
- YES, I KNOW,
BUT YOU NEVER SAW MY FACE.
- SO?
SO IF YOU CUT IN JUST AFTER
I MAKE THE GRAB,
WE USE ALL THE COVERAGE I SHOT
BEFORE I GOT UP ON THE ROOF.
WE LAY IN PHIL'S VOICE-OVER,
AND THEN WE TAG IT WITH...
A PICKUP SHOT OF PHIL EXITING
THE BUILDING WITH THE JUMPER.
WE'RE NOT LONG FOR A TWO-SHARE
AND LAST PLACE WITH THAT KIND
OF ATTITUDE. DO IT.
BUT CHRIS, IT'S--
UNETHICAL?
YOU HEARD ME.
MAKE PHIL A HERO.
- I THOUGHT ONLY GOD
REWROTE HISTORY.
- GOD NEVER WON SWEEPS.
[ Miss Parker ]
BEAUTIFUL PART OF TOWN.
[ Sydney ] DANGEROUS.
NO WONDER JAROD
LEFT THE NOTEBOOK
WITH THE ACUPUNCTURIST.
HE DOESN'T WANT US DOWN HERE.
COME ON, SYDNEY.
WE'RE HERE.
LET'S SEE IF RATBOY
LEFT ANYTHING BEHIND.
THIS IS FUTILE.
JAROD'S LONG GONE.
AFRAID OF THE DARK, SYD?
ONLY WHEN I
CAN'T SEE WHAT'S IN IT.
[ Clatter ]
DAMN IT.
MISS PARKER, MAYBE WE SHOULD
GET THE CLEANUP TEAM
TO CHECK THIS PLACE OUT.
FORGET IT, SYD.
I'D TRADE A DOZEN FERRAGAMOS
FOR ONE JAROD ANY DAY.
[ Object Clangs ]
I'M COUNTING TO THREE.
THEN I'M GONNA SHOOT
WHOEVER YOU ARE.
ONE,
TWO--
THREE!
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- WHAT YOU GOT?
I HAVE A NINE MILLIMETER
IN YOUR FACE,
AND YOU APPEAR
TO HAVE A KNIFE--
A RUSTY KNIFE.
OH, YOU MUST BE FEELING
LUCKY TODAY.
- [ Glass Shatters ]
- [ Sydney Shouts ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Chuckles ]
ARE YOU FEELING
LUCKY TODAY, HMM?
GET THEIR WALLETS AND JEWELRY
AND LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[ Keyboarding ]
WRITING PHIL'S COPY FOR HIM TOO?
I'M JUST TRYING TO SEND
A MESSAGE TO AN OLD FRIEND.
SO YOU THINK I WAS WRONG,
LETTING PHIL TAKE CREDIT
FOR SAVING THE JUMPER.
AS OUR NEW, ESTEEMED
NEWS DIRECTOR ALWAYS REMINDS ME,
I GET PAID TO CUT TAPE,
NOT TO THINK.
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND,
YOU WIN AWARDS DOING IT.
WELL, AWARDS DON'T COUNT
FOR MUCH AROUND HERE.
PULITZER'S ROLLING OVER
IN HIS GRAVE, AND NIELSEN'S
PACKING DOWN THE DIRT.
PHIL HAS ASKED ME TO GO OVER
SOME OF HIS OLD FOOTAGE...
TO SEE HOW HE LIKES
TO BE SHOT.
DO YOU THINK MAYBE
YOU COULD SHOW ME
SOME OF HIS OLD TAPES?
YEAH.
SECOND SHELF.
GREAT. THANK YOU.
THE KEN WATANABE SHOOTING.
I HEARD ABOUT THIS.
SO HAS HALF THE WORLD.
AND OUR IVY LEAGUE HITLER
WAS PISSED WE DIDN'T
HOOK THE OTHER HALF.
IT'S CHRIS'S JOB
TO KNOW WHAT PEOPLE WANT,
AND IT'S OUR JOB TO
MAKE SURE THEY GET IT.
WHICH DOESN'T MEAN WE SHOULD
THROW OUT ANYTHING RESEMBLING
JOURNALISTIC INTEGRITY.
IF IT BLEEDS, IT LEADS.
THAT'S THE NEW WAVE
OF THE NEWS, ANNIE,
LIKE IT OR NOT.
WE EITHER SURF ALONG WITH IT,
OR WE GET TORN APART
IN THE RIPTIDE.
[ Annie ]
IT'S REALLY AN ACT.
PHIL ACTUALLY WORSHIPS CRONKITE
IN SECRET MIDNIGHT RITUALS.
HMM.
WHO'S CRONKITE?
YOU'RE GONNA FIT IN
JUST FINE HERE.
TONIGHT, EXCLUSIVELY
ON SEATTLE'S CHANNEL 43,
OUR CONTINUING SERIES
ON LOCAL GANGS.
IN THIS SHOCKING FOOTAGE,
OUR OWN CAMERAMAN, KEN WATANABE,
CAPTURED ON VIDEOTAPE
A GANG GATHERING...
AT THE NORTH PUGET DOCK AREA.
BUT WHAT HAPPENED NEXT
TOOK US BOTH BY SURPRISE.
OUT OF NOWHERE,
THE 15th STREET BLEEDERS...
CRASHED THE TURF
OF THE BURNS,
LEADING TO
AN EXPLOSIVE CONFLICT--
A CONFLICT IN WHICH ONE OF
OUR OWN BECAME A CASUALTY.
OH, GOD, I'M HIT.
OH, GOD. OH, GOD.
[ Gunfire ]
PHIL, WHERE ARE YOU?
PHIL, I'M HIT. I'M HIT, MAN.
MY ARM. MY ARM.
I CAN'T MOVE MY ARM.
GET ME OUT OF HERE, MAN.
GET ME OUT OF HERE.
COME ON. COME ON.
COME ON. GET UP.
TONIGHT, OUR PRAYERS
ARE WITH KEN WATANABE,
A COURAGEOUS YOUNG CAMERAMAN.
GOD BLESS YOU, KEN.
PHIL CAMPBELL,
CHANNEL 43 NEWS, AT 10:00.
DEHLILA, I THINK ABOUT YOU
SO MUCH, MY BRAIN HURTS.
I HAVE TO MEET YOU,
TO SEE YOU.
- [ Phone Rings ]
- SAMSON.
I MEAN, BROOTS.
MR. PARKER?
UH, MR. PARKER, SIR.
HOW-HOW CAN I HELP YOU, SIR?
UH-- UH, NO.
NO, SIR, I HAVEN'T SEEN YOUR
DAUGHTER SINCE YESTERDAY.
SYDNEY NEITHER.
I MEAN, EITHER.
Y-YES, SIR.
I'LL GET ON IT RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
YEAH, WELL,
IT'S A PLEASURE TALK-- TALK--
[ Click, Dial Tone ]
HELLO? HELLO?
- JAROD!
- DAVE?
YOU LOOK GREAT.
A STEP AT A TIME.
THAT'S WHAT THEY TELL ME.
I JUST CAME BY TO SAY THANKS.
OF COURSE,
THE WAY THAT STORY AIRED,
I DON'T KNOW IF I SHOULD THANK
THAT REPORTER PHIL OR YOU.
[ Laughs ]
WELL, STRANGE THINGS
HAPPEN IN TV.
I'M GLAD YOU'RE DOING WELL.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT GOT INTO ME.
DID YOU FIND
YOUR WIFE AND KIDS?
YEAH, BUT SHE
DOESN'T WANT ME BACK
UNTIL I FIND A JOB, SO--
I'LL KEEP MY EYES OPEN.
YEAH.
WHAT DO YOU
KEEP LOOKING AT?
OH, THOSE WIRES THERE.
IF THEY'RE PLANNING ON
HOOKING UP THAT SATELLITE DISH
TO THEM WIRES,
THEY'RE GONNA BLOW OUT THEIR
ELECTRICITY IN NOTHING FLAT.
YOU'RE AN ELECTRICIAN?
NOPE. SATCOM GRUNT.
I WASN'T ANY BETTER
AT JUMPING OUT OF AIRPLANES
THAN I AM FROM BUILDINGS,
BUT I DO KNOW A WIRING PROBLEM
WHEN I SEE ONE.
HEY, THANKS AGAIN, REALLY.
GOOD LUCK.
THANKS.
PHIL, THESE PIECES
ARE EXCELLENT.
TWENTY YEARS OF BROADCASTING
WILL DO THAT.
I WAS ESPECIALLY IMPRESSED WITH
THE KEN WATANABE SEGMENT.
I WAS WONDERING.
IS THE RAW FOOTAGE
LYING AROUND SOMEWHERE?
I'D LOVE TO SEE
HOW IT WAS CUT TOGETHER.
MOST OF THOSE TAPES
GET RECYCLED.
EVEN WITH A PIECE THIS GOOD?
YEAH, WELL, THE STATION
DIDN'T USE TO CHARGE ME
FOR PARKING EITHER.
YEAH, RIGHT.
WAY TO GO, DAVE.
[ Chattering ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Pipes Clanking ]
AS IF GETTING MUGGED
WASN'T ENOUGH.
[ Weakly ]
YOU SHOT ME.
I DID NOT SHOOT YOU.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
I NEVER LIKED GUNS.
I HOPE YOU'LL STOP
CARRYING YOURS NOW.
[ Sighs ]
YOU'RE BLEEDING AGAIN.
[ Groans ]
I NEED SOMETHING ELSE
TO TIE THIS WOUND WITH.
WHAT ABOUT THAT NECK SCARF?
- IT'S ONE OF A KIND, SYDNEY.
- [ Chuckles ]
WHICH IS WHAT
MY GOOD LEG WILL BE
IF WE DON'T STOP THE BLEEDING.
[ Shuddering ]
I'M SORRY.
[ Groaning, Grunting ]
[ Sighs ]
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE GOING INTO SHOCK.
YOU NEED TO BE WARM.
OH, MY GOD.
OH, MY GOD, SYDNEY.
DON'T LOOK NOW, BUT WE ARE
GROUND ZERO FOR DETONATION...
TO BRING THIS DUMP DOWN.
PLEASE TELL ME
THAT YOU TOLD SOMEONE
WHERE WE WERE GOING.
[ Sighs ]
[ Cooing ]
THERE'S SOMETHING
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
- WHAT'S THAT?
- WHERE ARE THE LITTLE ONES?
THE WHAT?
YOU ALWAYS SEE THE BIG PIGEONS,
YOU KNOW, WITH THE SCARS...
AND THE BROKEN WINGS
AND THE MISSING LEGS.
BUT YOU NEVER SEE
THE LITTLE ONES.
I NEVER REALLY
THOUGHT ABOUT IT.
HEY, I KNOW YOU.
YOU'RE THE CAMERAMAN
THAT WAS ON THE NEWS.
I'M JAROD CRANE.
KEN.
THAT WAS INCREDIBLE
FOOTAGE YOU CAPTURED.
THANKS. I NEVER PLANNED ON
BECOMING A STORY THOUGH.
WHEN ARE YOU GOING
BACK TO WORK AT THE STATION?
AND DO WHAT?
LOG COMMERCIALS?
I'M A SHOOTER, MAN.
MY DAYS ON THE FRONT LINE
ARE OVER.
YOU KNOW, IT'S FUNNY.
YOU PLAN FOR YOUR LIFE
TO GO UP ONE ROAD,
AND WHEN YOU FINALLY GET THERE,
THE BRIDGE WASHES OUT.
WELL, YOU NEVER KNOW.
LIFE HAS A STRANGE WAY
OF SURPRISING YOU.
HEY, LOOK AT THAT.
[ Ken ]
I'LL BE DAMNED.
LIKE I SAID,
LIFE IS FULL OF SURPRISES.
[ Beeping ]
KEN WATANABE AND PHIL CAMPBELL,
FEBRUARY 18, ROLL NUMBER ONE.
OKAY. UH--
NOTHING FANCY, KENNY.
WE'RE JUST GONNA GO IN THERE,
AND WE'RE GONNA SIT DOWN,
AND WE'RE GONNA LISTEN
TO THE BURNS...
TALK ABOUT THEIR SIDE
OF THIS TURF WAR.
THESE GUYS TEND TO
TALK WITH THEIR GUNS.
KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING?
YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT GETTING FANCY FROM ME.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT, KEN.
YOU'LL BE FINE.
[ Exhales ]
LET'S DO IT.
[ Ken ]
YOU SURE THESE GUYS
ARE GONNA SHOW?
[ Phil ]
YEAH, THEY'LL BE HERE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
OKAY, UM--
RIGHT UP THERE.
HEAD THERE.
[ Ken ]
YOU BEEN HANGING WITH
THE HOMIES, PHIL, HUH?
YO! HEY, D-MAC!
HEY, D-MAC!
BLEEDERS IN THE HOOD!
[ Gunfire Resumes ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
I'M HIT!
I'M HIT! OH, GOD!
MY ARM! MY ARM!
[ Gunfire Continues ]
I'M HIT, MAN! PHIL,
GET ME OUT OF HERE, MAN!
GET ME OUT OF HERE!
YOU'RE OKAY.
GET ME OUT OF HERE, MAN!
GET ME OUT OF HERE!
INTERESTING UNDERSHIRT, PHIL.
FLAK JACKET STANDARD ISSUE
FOR A STREET REPORTER NOW, PHIL?
I'M DYING FOR A CIGARETTE!
HOW THE HELL
DID I END UP HERE?
YOU REGRET TAKING ON
THE JAROD ASSIGNMENT?
- I REGRET A LOT OF THINGS.
- SUCH AS?
I REGRET NOT GOING TO THE PROM.
I REGRET LAUGHING
AT MY FIRST BOYFRIEND...
WHEN HE TOLD ME I WAS THE ONE.
AND IN THIS INSTANT,
I REGRET NOT HAVING...
A NICOTINE PATCH
THE SIZE OF A DOORMAT.
[ Groans ]
OH, NO.
YOUR ULCER, HUH?
AND NO MEDICATION.
[ Sighs ]
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE FABULOUS SHERLOCK HOLMES.
[ Groaning ]
LET ME SEE IT, SYDNEY.
REGRET'S OFTEN BORN OUT
OF A LACK OF CHOICE, YOU KNOW?
UNLIKE YOU, SYD,
I DON'T THINK THAT EVERYTHING
IS OUT OF MY CONTROL.
YOU DO WHEN IT
COMES TO YOUR FATHER.
PLEASE, DON'T--
DON'T MISUNDERSTAND THAT.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST SAY IT?
I CAVED.
I ALWAYS DO AROUND HIM.
YOU CAN STILL WALK UP
TO YOUR FATHER AND TELL HIM,
"DAD, I'M LEAVING."
[ Chuckling ]
RIGHT. I CAN SEE IT NOW.
TWO KIDS,
A LITTLE YELLOW HOUSE,
CHITCHATTING WITH THE GIRLS
OVER LATTES AT THE MALL.
YOU STILL HAVE A FUTURE,
MISS PARKER.
IT'S A HELL OF A FUTURE,
SITTING HERE WAITING
TO GET BLOWN TO BITS.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Laughing ]
HERE I AM,
TRYING TO COMFORT YOU.
[ Laughing Continues ]
AS IF ANYTHING YOU COULD EVER DO
WOULD GIVE ME COMFORT.
IT DID ONCE.
YOU ARE ONE HELL
OF A THROWER, JAROD.
IT'S ABOUT UNDERSTANDING
THE PROJECTILE'S AERODYNAMICS.
WELL, ACTUALLY,
I JUST CLOSE ONE EYE
AND LET IT FLY.
OH.
THAT'S IT. GOOD GAME.
I SHOULD'VE WARNED YOU.
I DON'T LIKE TO LOSE.
GOOD MAN.
NEXT ROUND'S ON ME.
[ Patrons Cheering ]
PHIL CERTAINLY IS
IN A GOOD MOOD TONIGHT.
YOU MUST BE VERY PROUD OF ANNIE
AND PHIL GETTING NOMINATED
FOR THE KEN WATANABE SEGMENT.
YEAH, EVEN STIFFS LIKE PHIL
GET LUCKY. IF ONLY
GRECIAN FORMULA WERE TALENT.
AWARDS HELP THE PROMO GUYS,
I SUPPOSE. THEY ALSO
MAKE A NEWS TEAM LAZY.
NEWS IS ABOUT BEING HUNGRY.
ALWAYS HAS BEEN.
YOU GUYS GONNA DRINK WATER
ALL NIGHT, OR ARE YOU COMING
TO JOIN THE REAL PARTY?
AND YOU, SMILE.
[ Laughing ]
- IS THIS ABOUT KEN?
- HE SHOULD BE HERE.
SOMEBODY FORGOT TO INVITE HIM.
[ Inaudible ]
HE MUST'VE BEEN VERY PROUD,
TAKING ONE FOR THE TEAM.
[ Chris ] KTJE's GOT
A HELL OF A MEDICAL PACKAGE.
WATANABE'S ALL RIGHT.
KEN'S GONNA BE FINE.
LOOK, EVERYBODY IN
THIS BUSINESS KNOWS...
THAT PUTTING YOUR TAIL ON
THE LINE IS A JOB REQUIREMENT.
KEN WAS GREEN.
HE WAS TOO ZEALOUS,
AND IT COST HIM.
IF I'D HAVE KNOWN HOW DANGEROUS
IT WAS, I NEVER WOULD'VE
LET HIM GO OUT THERE.
I'M SURE YOU WOULDN'T.
I'M NOT TRYING TO BE A PEST,
BUT I'VE GOT THE TOWER BREATHING
DOWN MY NECK TO FIND THEM.
NOW SURELY THERE'S GOT TO BE
A SWEEPER TEAM SOMEWHERE NEAR
THE NEW YORK CITY AREA.
EXCUSE ME?
WHAT BUSINESS IS IT OF YOURS
WHAT MY CLEARANCE LEVEL IS?
NOW, LISTEN. YOU S.I.S. GUYS ARE
REALLY STARTIN' TO TICK ME OFF.
[ Phone Ringing ]
HOLD ON A SECOND.
JUST HOLD ON.
- BROOTS!
- IT'S ME.
DON'T BOTHER TRYING TO TRACE ME.
- I'VE SCRAMBLED
THE SOURCE SIGNAL.
- JAROD?
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO CONTACT SYDNEY.
JOIN THE PARTY.
HE AND MISS PARKER WENT LOOKING
FOR YOU TWO DAYS AGO. WE
HAVEN'T HEARD FROM THEM SINCE.
SHE'S TOO PERSISTENT
FOR HER OWN GOOD. YOU'RE
GOING TO HAVE TO FIND THEM.
YOU DON'T KNOW HOW PEACEFUL
IT'S BEEN HERE WITHOUT HER.
WOULD IT BE MORE PEACEFUL
WORKING FOR RAINES?
MR. RAINES? NO.
TAKE DOWN THIS ADDRESS.
1811 NORTH BUSHNELL STREET,
THE BRONX.
[ Crying ]
[ Soft Chattering ]
MISS PARKER?
TELL ME AGAIN
HOW MY MOTHER DIED.
STOP TORTURING YOURSELF.
I KNOW IT WASN'T SUICIDE.
WAS SHE MURDERED BECAUSE
OF THE RESCUED CHILDREN?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- WAS IT MY FATHER?
MISS PARKER,
I KNOW ABOUT YOUR MOTHER'S LIFE,
NOT ABOUT HER DEATH.
SHE WAS A KIND WOMAN,
A DRIVING FORCE AT THE CENTRE
IN THOSE DAYS WHEN
IT WAS STILL INVOLVED IN...
ALTRUISTIC PROJECTS.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THE CENTRE
WAS EVER INVOLVED WITH
ANYTHING POSITIVE.
WE HELPED FOUR COUNTRIES BECOME
DEMOCRACIES DURING THE COLD WAR.
WE BROUGHT THE SIDES TOGETHER
FOR THE KOREAN PEACE ACCORD.
AND RUMOR HAS IT THAT WE EVEN
HELPED DESIGN THE POPEMOBILE.
THE CENTRE
SAVED THOUSANDS OF LIVES--
LIVES THAT THEY
LATER RECLAIMED,
AS IT TURNED OUT,
IN OTHER WAYS.
WHY DIDN'T YOU LEAVE
WHEN THINGS TURNED?
THERE WERE OTHERS
WHOSE WELFARE...
WAS OF MORE CONCERN TO ME
THAN MY OWN.
JAROD.
HE'S NOT VERY DIFFERENT FROM US,
YOU KNOW?
WE'D ALL HAVE TAKEN
VERY DIFFERENT PATHS...
HAD WE HAD OUR WAY.
HERE YOU GO.
PASS THE BALL, MAN.
[ Chattering ]
- BOO-YA!
- EXCUSE ME. EXCUSE ME.
I THINK THAT WAS TRAVELING.
YOU MUST BE CRAZY,
STUPID OR BOTH.
NO, NO. AFTER YOU LIFTED
YOUR PIVOT FOOT, YOU TOOK MORE
THAN THE ALLOTTED TWO STEPS,
AS OUTLINED IN
THE OFFICIAL RULE BOOK.
MMM.
PIZZA?
THANK YOU, ANYWAY,
BUT IT ALREADY COMES PRESLICED.
HELP YOURSELVES.
WHAT, YOU GOT A DEATH WISH
OR SOMETHING, MAN?
NOT THAT I KNOW OF.
DIDN'T YOUR MAMA EVER TELL YOU
THAT WHITE PEOPLE SHOULDN'T...
GO WALKING THROUGH
OTHER PEOPLE'S NEIGHBORHOODS?
WELL, I NEVER ACTUALLY
KNEW MY MOTHER,
SO I GUESS THE ANSWER IS NO.
MY NAME'S JAROD CRANE.
I'M WITH CHANNEL 43 NEWS.
I'M LOOKING FOR A D-MAC.
YOU GONNA PUT HIM ON TV?
QUITE POSSIBLY, YES.
I'M D-MAC.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
OW! HE'S GOT GAME.
THE BOY'S GOT SOME GAME.
[ Chattering ]
HEY, MAN, THAT CAMERA GUY
SHOULDN'T HAVE BEEN THERE.
TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED.
A MAN HITS MY CELL PHONE.
HE MUST'VE PAID SOMEBODY
OFF TO GET THE NUMBER.
SOUNDED WHITE.
TELLS ME HE WANTS
TO TALK ABOUT THE TURF WARS.
SOUNDED COOL TO ME.
THIS WHITE MAN THAT CALLED YOU,
IS THAT UNUSUAL?
YOU REALLY DIDN'T HAVE
NO MOTHER, DID YOU?
I NEVER KNEW MY OLD LADY EITHER.
LATER I HEARD WORD THE BLEEDERS
GOT THE SAME CALL.
THEY SHOW UP, AND BOOM, BOOM,
THE FIREWORKS STARTED.
DO YOU REMEMBER WHAT DAY
YOU GOT THIS CALL?
I DON'T KNOW.
HEY, DUANE, MAN,
BRING MY DAY RUNNER.
WE'RE BANGERS, NOT CAVEMEN.
THANKS, MAN.
OKAY, HERE YOU GO. FEBRUARY 18,
AT ABOUT 8:00 AT NIGHT.
COULD YOU TELL ME
YOUR CELL PHONE NUMBER?
[ Chattering ]
[ Crying ]
TAKE MISS PARKER UPSTAIRS.
YES, SIR.
YOU GET SOME REST NOW.
IF YOU EVER WANT TO TALK TO ME,
I'M ALWAYS HERE.
[ Crying Continues ]
OKAY?
THANK YOU, SYDNEY.
SYDNEY?
WHY IS EVERYONE WEARING BLACK?
HOW COME YOU'RE SO SAD?
WE'RE REMEMBERING SOMEONE
WHO HAS LEFT US, JAROD.
IS IT THE WOMAN
THAT GOT SHOT
IN THE ELEVATOR?
MISS PARKER'S MOTHER, ISN'T IT?
DON'T YOU EVER SPEAK OF THAT
TO ANYONE EVER AGAIN,
UNDERSTAND?
[ Groans ]
I COULD'VE SAVED HIM.
WHO?
JAROD.
HE SHOULD HAVE LIVED
A NORMAL LIFE.
THEY WOULD'VE KILLED YOU.
[ Chuckles ]
YOU CAN'T KILL SOMEONE
WHO'S ALREADY DEAD.
[ Shuddering ]
YOU DO REMEMBER.
YOU BROKE INTO MY EDIT FILE
AND STOLE FOOTAGE?
"BORROWED" IS MORE LIKE IT.
AND I DID IT
FOR KEN WATANABE.
YOU LOST ME.
KEN WAS SET UP.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WHAT HAPPENED TO KEN
HAPPENED BECAUSE PHIL
IS DESPERATE FOR RATINGS.
I-I-I DON'T BUY THAT.
BUY IT.
WHY ELSE WOULD PHIL HAVE BEEN
WEARING A BULLETPROOF VEST
THE NIGHT THAT KEN WAS SHOT?
YOU ACTUALLY THINK PHIL WOULD DO
SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
I'M CERTAIN OF IT.
ANNIE, YOU KNOW HIM.
YOU'VE SEEN THE KIND OF PRESSURE
THAT PHIL HAS BEEN UNDER
TO GET BACK ON TOP.
YEAH, BUT TO RISK
SOMEBODY ELSE'S LIFE.
HE'S A DESPERATE MAN, ANNIE.
HE WAS THE KING OF THE HILL,
AND NOW HE'S ON HIS WAY OUT.
ANNIE, I NEED YOUR HELP
TO STOP HIM.
HELLO, DAVE. THIS IS JAROD.
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE TO
COME TO WORK FOR CHANNEL 43?
UH-HUH. YOU CAN TELL YOUR WIFE
YOU'VE GOT A JOB.
♪♪ [ Rap, Indistinct ]
LIGHTS.
♪♪ [ Continues ]
CAMERA.
HELLO, ANNIE. I'M SETTING UP
A VERY SPECIAL SCREENING
IN CHRIS'S OFFICE.
I WANT YOU TO DO ME A FAVOR.
MAKE SURE THE GENERAL MANAGER
IS THERE.
ACTION.
[ Jarod ]
PHIL.
CHRIS JUST GOT WORD
OF A SUMMIT GOING DOWN
BETWEEN TWO RIVAL GANGS.
HE THINKS IT'S GOING TO MAKE
A TERRIFIC FOLLOW-UP
TO THE KEN WATANABE SEGMENT.
CHRIS TIPPED YOU ON THIS?
HIS SNITCH SAID THERE
COULD BE FIREWORKS,
AND FIREWORKS MEAN RATINGS.
LET'S GO.
PHIL, WHY DON'T
YOU TEST YOUR HEADSET?
CHECK, ONE, TWO.
SO, WHERE SHALL WE SET UP?
OVER HERE.
WE CAN COVER THE DOOR,
STAY IN THE SHADOWS.
UH, JAROD.
SOMETHING DOESN'T FEEL
RIGHT ABOUT THIS.
WELL, IT'S A PRETTY SCARY PLACE.
THAT AND THE FACT THAT
KEN WATANABE WAS SHOT
JUST OUTSIDE OF THAT DOOR.
THAT MIGHT HAVE SOMETHING
TO DO WITH IT.
BUT PUTTING OUR TAIL
ON THE LINE-- IT'S PART
OF THE JOB, ISN'T IT?
OKAY, JAROD. JAROD?
JAROD!
[ Door Opens ]
- [ Man ] BURNS IN THE HOUSE!
- [ Man #2 ] WORD!
[ Men Shouting ]
- BRING YOUR PUNK-ASSES OUT!
- LET'S GO!
- DON'T WAIT FOR THEIR ASSES.
- JAROD, WHERE ARE YOU?
[ Jarod On Headset ]
ABOVE YOU.
[ Phil ]
THIS IS NOT GOOD.
[ On Headset ]
IT'S OKAY. I'VE GOT
YOU IN MY SIGHTS.
SMILE, PHIL. IT'S SHOWTIME.
ANNIE, WHY IS
THE GENERAL MANAGER HERE?
I THINK YOU HAVE
A MEETING WITH HIM.
MR. FERREN, WHAT A SURPRISE.
NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN,
MR. FERREN.
SHOW'S ABOUT
TO BEGIN, GENTLEMEN.
PLEASE, TAKE YOUR SEATS.
I'M INTRIGUED, ROCKWELL.
THIS MUST BE SOME SHOW
YOU'VE PUT TOGETHER.
YES, SIR. THE BEST.
[ Men Shouting ]
- [ Man On TV ] WHAT?
- WHAT YOU WANT WITH ME?
WHAT'S UP, FOOL?
[ Mr. Ferren ]
WHAT IS THIS, A GANG FIGHT?
WANT SOME OF THIS, HUH?
YOU WANT SOME OF THIS?
[ Chris ] IS THAT PHIL?
WHAT YOU GOT?
JAROD, THESE GUYS
ARE GONNA KILL EACH OTHER.
[ Jarod ] IT'LL BE GREAT TV.
YOU CALL ME HERE
TO THREATEN MY ASS?
THIS IS ON YOU, DOG.
DEAL OR DIE.
[ Chattering ]
THIS IS GREAT STUFF, PHIL.
GET CLOSER SO WE CAN
PICK UP SOUND.
I'VE GOT NO COVER HERE,
YOU IDIOT!
I'M GETTING OUT OF HERE.
[ Jarod ]
DON'T LEAVE NOW, PHIL.
YOU'RE GONNA MISS THE STORY.
[ Man ]
YOU WANT SOME OF THIS? HUH?
YOU WANT SOME OF THIS?
[ Jarod ]
OR MAYBE YOU ARE THE STORY.
[ Banging ]
WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
-HE'S MINE!
-JAROD, HELP ME! JAROD, HELP ME!
JAROD!
[ Men Chattering ]
JAROD, HELP ME!
YEAH!
THIS IS GREAT.
THIS IS GREAT. KEEP IT UP.
LOOK WHAT WE GOT HERE, FELLAS.
UH-HUH.
DAVE, READY TO GO CITYWIDE?
GET READY, SEATTLE.
[ Men Whooping ]
- SO WHAT WE GONNA DO
WITH THIS WHITE PUNK?
- [ Men Grumbling ]
I SAY WE BURY HIS SORRY ASS
RIGHT WHERE HE STANDS.
[ Clicking ]
[ Grumbling Continues ]
[ Man ]
HEY, IT'S ON EVERY CHANNEL.
[ Man #2 ]
SOMETHING'S GOING ON.
LOOK AT THIS.
[ Jarod ]
THIS IS GONNA BE A GREAT PIECE,
PHIL. JUST KEEP THEM TALKING.
[ Men Chattering On TV ]
THIS GUY'S GONNA
SHOOT ME.
- JUST LIKE KEN WATANABE?
- WHAT?
JAROD, COME DOWN HERE!
WHAT'S UP? YOU GONNA DO
THE DEED OR NOT?
'CAUSE IF YOU'RE NOT--
[ Guns Cocking ]
NO, NO, YOU CAN'T SHOOT ME!
NO, YOU CAN'T!
HE'S GOT A TV CAMERA ON YOU.
CAMERAS.
THEY CAN DO WONDERFUL THINGS.
BUT KEN WATANABE'S CAMERA
COULDN'T STOP HIM
FROM GETTING SHOT.
I DIDN'T KNOW THERE WAS
GONNA BE SHOOTING.
BUT YOU DID KNOW THAT A RIVAL
GANG WAS GOING TO BE THERE,
BECAUSE YOU TIPPED THEM OFF,
AND THAT'S WHY YOU WORE
A BULLETPROOF VEST.
I TIPPED THEM OFF.
OKAY, OKAY!
[ Jarod ]
YOU KNEW YOU WERE PUTTING
KEN WATANABE IN DANGER,
BUT YOU DIDN'T CARE BECAUSE
ALL YOU CARE ABOUT
IS GETTING THE STORY.
YES! PLEASE, HELP ME!
I CAN'T DO THAT, PHIL.
IT'S RATINGS AT ALL COSTS.
LIKE YOU ALWAYS SAY,
"IF IT BLEEDS, IT LEADS."
I SET HIM UP. I SET HIM UP.
I SET IT UP, OKAY?
YOU GOT WHAT YOU NEED, BRO?
IT'S A SLAM DUNK.
I GOT EVERYTHING
I NEED RIGHT HERE.
[ Men Laughing ]
"I SET HIM UP! I SET HIM UP!"
[ Voices, Indistinct ]
THAT WAS THE MONEY SHOT
YOU'VE ALL BEEN WAITING FOR.
JAROD CRANE,
CHANNEL 43 NEWS, REPORTING.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
I'M HOLDING YOU RESPONSIBLE
FOR THIS, MR. ROCKWELL.
FORGET THE LIABILITY THIS
STATION FACES IN LIGHT OF THIS.
YOU RUINED A MAN'S LIFE.
SIR, I--
SAVE IT. SAVE IT.
YOU WANT A NEWS FLASH, CHRIS?
YOU'RE FIRED.
[ All Murmuring ]
OH, MY GOD.
MISS PARKER! SYDNEY!
- IT CAN'T BE.
- SYDNEY! MISS P.!
BROOTS! YOU MORON!
MISS PARKER!
DOWN HERE!
SYDNEY, WAKE UP.
[ Chattering ]
HI.
HOW'RE YOU DOING?
I FIGURED YOU GUYS
MIGHT BE HUNGRY.
FORGET THAT.
DOES ANYBODY SMOKE? SMOKE?
NO.
HI. UH, CAN I--
THANK YOU.
BOY, IT'S LUCKY
I FOUND YOU GUYS.
OTHERWISE,
YOU WOULD'VE BEEN TOAST.
YOU CAN PUT ANY FANTASY ABOUT ME
THANKING YOU TO REST, BROOTS.
[ Huffs ]
RIGHT.
[ Chuckles ]
SO, WHAT DID YOU GUYS
TALK ABOUT ALL THIS TIME?
NOTHING.
NOTHING AT ALL.
[ Huffs ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THIS IS GREAT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO THANK YOU.
I MEAN, YOU BUILT
THIS HARNESS FOR ME...
[ Chuckling ]
AND GOT ME MY JOB BACK
AT THE STATION.
YOU'VE GOT TO PROMISE ME THAT
THIS WILL NEVER MAKE THE AIR.
I PROMISE.
WELL, YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
SEND ME THE VIDEO.
- THAT'S WHAT YOU DO, ISN'T IT?
- YEAH, IT IS.
GOOD LUCK, HUH?
TAKE CARE.
[ Woman Over Headset ]
WE GOT YOU COVERED
DOWN HERE, JAROD.
THIS COULD BE
A NEW WORLD RECORD.
NOW, THAT WOULD BE NEWS,
WOULDN'T IT?
[ Mews ]