PREVIOUSLY ON THE PRETENDER.
I KNOW THE TRUTH.
AND WHAT TRUTH
IS THAT, JAROD?
THE TRUTH...
ABOUT WHAT MAKES YOU SAD.
YOUR MOTHER WAS
A SPECIAL PERSON.
MY MOTHER WAS WEAK. PERIOD.
THE ONLY THING THAT
EVER BOTHERED ME WAS:
WHY IN AN ELEVATOR?
YOUR MOTHER
WAS A VERY SPECIAL WOMAN.
THERE WAS A PART OF HER
I KNEW BETTER THAN ANYONE.
SHE KEPT HIDDEN, SEPARATE.
[ Miss Parker ]
IS THAT ALL YOU DO, JAROD?
DIG UP THE PAST?
THAT'S EASY FOR YOU TO SAY.
YOU HAVE ONE.
[ Screaming ]
MAMA! MAMA!
THEY'RE TRYING TO HURT HER!
STAY HERE, JAROD.
- [ Gunshot ]
- MAMA, NO!
- NO!
MAMA!
[ Gunshot ]
[ Phone Rings ]
WHAT?
[ Sydney ]
WE'VE GOT A HIT.
JAROD'S THE FINEST SEWER RAT
I'VE HAD THE PLEASURE TO
WORK WITH.
I'VE NEVER SEEN SOMEONE
SO EXCITED ABOUT EXCREMENT
IN MY LIFE.
A REAL FECAL AFICIONADO.
[ Miss Parker ]
HOW CHARMING.
[ Sydney ]
HOW LONG WAS JAROD HERE?
COUPLE OF WEEKS.
THAT'S ALL IT TOOK HIM
TO FIGURE IT OUT.
[ Miss Parker ] FIGURE WHAT OUT?
THAT WE WERE DIGGING
INTO AN AQUIFER.
IF WE HAD HIT THAT THING,
IT WOULD'VE FLUSHED
45 MEMBERS...
OF THE INTERNATIONAL BROTHERHOOD
OF SEWAGE WORKERS...
RIGHT INTO
THE JAWS OF OBLIVION.
JUST LIKE THAT EGYPTIAN ARMY
IN THE TEN COMMANDMENTS.
WHOOSH!
GREAT.
NOW JAROD IS MOSES.
MOSES?
CHARLTON HESTON.
[ Chuckles ]
RIGHT.
THANKS.
MR. McELROY, THIS IS WHERE
JAROD ALWAYS EMERGED?
RIGHT IN THIS SPOT.
SOMETHING SPECIAL ABOUT IT,
BUT HE WOULDN'T TELL ME.
SAID HE HAD TO SHIP OUT.
COMMANDER FORRESTER,
WE HAVE A SITUATION HERE.
REPORT.
BOGEY, SIR.
VICTOR-CLASS SUBMARINE,
BEARING ONE FOUR EIGHT.
[ Jarod ] AND CLOSING.
THIS COULD BE THE ROGUE
WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
RELAX, SAILOR.
THIS IS THE FUN PART.
WHY DOES THE FUN PART
HAVE TO HAPPEN ON MY WATCH?
ALERT THE X.O.
AND THE CAPTAIN.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
WE'VE GOT A FIGHT
ON OUR HANDS.
[ Man Narrating ]
[ Man ]
ATTENTION ON DECK.
[ Man #2 ] AS YOU WERE.
CAPTAIN NAGEL.
COMMANDER NASHTON.
IT'S THE ROSTOV, SIR.
AFTER SHE DEPLOYED
FROM ODESSA,
THE UZBEKI CAPTAIN
DECLARED INDEPENDENCE
FROM THE BLACK SEA FLEET.
HE'S ROGUE.
WITH A HIP POCKET
FULL OF NUCLEAR WARHEADS.
AND JUDGING FROM THE INTEL FILE,
HER FIRST STRIKE TARGET...
IS LOS ANGELES.
[ Beeping ]
- SOMETHING'S UP, SIRS.
- THEY'VE OPENED
THE V.L.S. DOORS.
THOSE S.L.B.M.'s WILL BE
READY TO FIRE IN
APPROXIMATELY TWO MINUTES.
TORPEDOES IN THE WATER,
BEARING ONE THREE SEVEN
AND ONE FOUR TWO.
READY TORPEDO DECOY.
READY DECOY.
READY DECOY. AYE.
SOMETHING'S WRONG WITH
THIS RELAY, SIR.
- WHAT'S THE PROBLEM, BAKER?
- AAAH!
WE'VE LOST THE DECOY SIGNAL.
- GENTLEMEN, WE GOT
A TORPEDO ON OUR ASS.
- TORPEDOES CLOSING, 300 YARDS.
- THE DECOY SIGNAL'S
STILL DEAD, SIR.
- 200 YARDS.
NINETY SECONDS
TO S.L.B.M. LAUNCH.
COME ON, BAKER.
- GOT IT.
DECOY'S ON LINE, SIR.
- [ Beeping ]
TORPEDO NUMBER ONE
JUST TOOK THE BAIT.
NUMBER TWO CLOSING.
IT'S A MISS.
ROSTOV'S V.L.S. SYSTEM
IS STILL READY.
THOSE NUKES FLY
IN ONE MINUTE, SIR.
FORTY DEGREES STARBOARD.
[ Man ]
STEADY ON COURSE...
ZERO NINE ZERO.
[ Man ] ZERO NINE ZERO.
SIR, SUGGEST WE FIRE
BOTH TORPEDOES NOW WHILE
HE'S STILL IN RANGE.
[ Jarod ]
SIR.
I RECOMMEND
THAT WE FIRE ONE NOW,
THAT WE VEER APPROXIMATELY
30 DEGREES STARBOARD
AND THEN FIRE TORPEDO TWO.
- VEER? WHY DON'T WE JUST--
- FIRE TORPEDO ONE.
[ Woman ]
FIRE ONE. AYE.
TORPEDO AWAY.
THIRTY SECONDS
UNTIL WARHEAD LAUNCH.
VEER THIRTY DEGREES STARBOARD.
[ Jarod ] RIGHT FULL RUDDER.
STEADY COURSE
ONE TWO ZERO.
[ Man ]
RIGHT FULL RUDDER,
ONE TWO ZERO. AYE.
ONE IS A MISS, SIR.
- FIRE TWO.
- FIRE TWO. AYE.
- TORPEDO AWAY.
- TWENTY SECONDS UNTIL
WARHEAD LAUNCH.
THOSE BIRDS ARE HOT.
TEN SECONDS UNTIL
WARHEAD LAUNCH.
NUMBER TWO IS
A DIRECT HIT.
SHE'S GOING DOWN.
[ Cheering, Clapping ]
[ Man ]
THIS IS CAPTAIN DRUCKER
OF THE HARRISON.
[ Mimics Russian Accent ]
YOU'VE BLOWN US OUT OF WATER,
YOU CRAZY YANKEE PIG.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
ALWAYS A PLEASURE TO RUN
A SIMULATION WITH YOU, TED.
NEVER A COLD WAR
WHEN YOU NEED ONE.
HARRISON OUT.
YOU GOT NOTHING
TO SMILE ABOUT.
ANOTHER THREE SECONDS,
AND L.A.'s A PARKING LOT.
[ Woman ]
WAY TO GO, BAKER.
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER
FORRESTER,
THIS CREW IS LOOSE.
IT'S TOO LOOSE.
THE MONROE IS A TEAM,
LIKE LINKS IN A CHAIN.
IF ONE OF THOSE LINKS
BREAKS UNDER STRESS,
WE SLIP THAT MUCH CLOSER
TO DISASTER.
[ Loudly ]
IN ONE WEEK,
WE HIT THE BIG BLUE.
IT IS IMPERATIVE THAT
YOUR RESPONSE TIMES IMPROVE.
AFTER WHAT HAPPENED
ON OUR LAST TOUR,
I WANT THIS SHIP RUNNING
LIKE A DAMN SWISS WATCH.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU JUST TRADED YOUR DAY OFF
FOR A RIDE ON MY PERSONAL
HIGHWAY TO HELL.
[ Nashton ]
LEFT, LEFT, LEFT!
COME ON, PEOPLE!
IT'S A HIGHWAY TO HELL.
WE LOVE IT!
COME ON!
HAVING FUN YET?
[ All ]
YES, SIR!
COME ON, PEOPLE!
DO YOU LOVE IT?
YES, SIR!
I CAN'T HEAR YOU!
LET'S GO. LET'S GO.
COME ON. LET'S GO. COME ON.
WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
LET'S GO. MOVE IT.
MOVE IT OUT. MOVE IT OUT.
MOVE IT OUT.
[ Yells ]
MOVE IT OUT!
MOVE! MOVE! MOVE!
[ Jarod ]
[ All Shouting ]
I DIDN'T REALLY WANT
A DAY OFF. DID YOU, BAKER?
WHAT?
YOU CAN'T EVEN HANDLE
A LITTLE CIRCUIT FLARE-UP?
I MEAN, IF SOMETHING
GOES WRONG THIS TOUR,
YOU'RE NOT GONNA SCREW UP
ON US LIKE YOU DID IN
THE PUMP ROOM WITH SEAVER?
SEAVER WAS A DUMB-ASS.
[ Woman ]
HEY, GET HIM!
GET HIM!
[ All Yelling ]
[ Jarod ]
BREAK IT UP! GET UP!
BREAK IT UP!
KNOX! MARCUS!
BAKER, YOU'VE GOT
THE HIGHEST RANK HERE.
IF I EVEN CATCH YOU
LOOKING AT THESE SAILORS
THE WRONG WAY,
I'M GONNA HAVE YOU
IN THE SCULLERY
EVERY DAY FOR A WEEK!
UNDERSTOOD, SAILOR?
YES, SIR!
FALL OUT!
[ Man ] ALL RIGHT. MOVE OUT.
[ Man #2 ]
SIR.
WELL, YOU HANDLED
THAT LITTLE SITUATION WELL.
JUST AS WELL AS
MANEUVERS THIS MORNING.
SIR, I'M SORRY ABOUT THAT.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO
STEP OUT OF LINE.
OH, YES, YOU DID.
YOU'RE JUST LUCKY THAT
YOU MADE THE RIGHT CALL.
I GUESS.
NAGEL SEEMED PRETTY STEAMED
ABOUT THE LAST TOUR.
YEAH, WELL, THAT'S
THE ONLY CHINK IN HIS ARMOR.
WE LOST A SAILOR.
THERE WAS A GAS LEAK
IN THE PUMP ROOM.
A GAS LEAK?
YEAH. JX-5.
WHOA. A ROOMFUL OF THAT
COULD'VE SET OFF
THE ENTIRE SHIP.
WHOO. TELL ME ABOUT IT.
I HAD THE DECK THAT NIGHT.
IT'S PRETTY INTENSE.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING I WANT TO
LIVE THROUGH AGAIN.
HEY, TELL ME SOMETHING,
WILL YA?
HOW DID YOU KNOW
THAT THE HARRISON
WAS GONNA CUT AND RUN?
"BULLDOG" TED DRUCKER
WAS AT THE CONN.
IT'S HIS FAVORITE
EVASIVE TECHNIQUE.
OH, YOU SERVED WITH HIM?
ACTUALLY, JAROD'S
FROM THE GRANT, SIR.
LIEUTENANT PAULA PRATT.
AT EASE.
SECURITY OFFICER.
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER
JAROD FORRESTER.
YES. I JUST RAN THE REQUIRED
CHECKS ON YOUR FILE.
YOUR DATES ON THE GRANT
DON'T JIBE WITH
THE BUREAU OF PERSONNEL.
SO WHY DON'T YOU
CALL THE GRANT
AND HAVE 'EM CLEAR IT UP?
I WILL. AS SOON AS
SHE GETS BACK FROM
A SILENT ESCORT IN ANTARCTICA.
NEXT MONTH.
COME SEE ME
AT P.S.D. TOMORROW.
THAT WOMAN NEEDS A HOBBY.
SHE REMINDS ME OF SOMEONE
I USED TO KNOW.
GO THROUGH THE BOX
FROM JAROD'S LAST LAIR.
CALL ME WITH SOLID LEADS.
[ Sydney ]
WHERE WILL YOU BE,
MISS PARKER?
OUT.
[ Beeps Off ]
WELL, THERE MUST BE SOMETHING
YOU CAN TELL ME ABOUT MY MOTHER.
IT'S BEEN NEARLY 30 YEARS,
BUT I REMEMBER HOW MUCH
SHE LOVED THE CHILDREN HERE.
I HAVE REASON TO BELIEVE
THAT SHE MIGHT HAVE
RESCUED SOME OF THEM.
RESCUED?
IT'S A LONG STORY.
DID SHE--
DID SHE BRING
ANY CHILDREN HERE?
NO. WE'VE ALWAYS GOTTEN
OUR CHILDREN THE USUAL WAY:
ORPHANS, RUNAWAYS,
VICTIMS OF CHILD ABUSE.
I'M AFRAID I WOULDN'T KNOW
WHERE TO BEGIN.
[ Sighs ]
I MIGHT.
I'M SORRY.
NONE OF THEM RING A BELL.
THAT'S OKAY.
YOU'VE BEEN--
YOU'VE BEEN VERY HELPFUL.
WHO IS THIS JAROD
YOU'RE ASKING ABOUT?
AN ASSOCIATE.
I THOUGHT MAYBE
HE MIGHT HAVE VISITED YOU.
NO.
[ Sighs ]
IT'S NOT A DEAD END,
MISS PARKER.
WELL, THE PERSON
WHO GAVE THIS TO ME
IS THE MASTER OF THE DEAD END.
YOU COULD MATCH THESE
WITH OUR FILES,
BUT YOU'D HAVE TO GO DOWN
TO THE HALL OF RECORDS.
ALL OF THESE KIDS
ARE PRE-1970.
OUR FILES WERE DESTROYED
IN A FIRE THAT YEAR.
YOU HAD A FIRE IN 1970?
YES.
APRIL.
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
THAT'S WHEN MY MOTHER DIED.
AT EASE.
GOOD AFTERNOON, SIR.
GOOD AFTERNOON.
JUST WANT TO WELCOME YOU
TO THE MONROE.
AT EASE.
UH, BAZOOKA.
FROM MY PERSONAL STASH.
FOR ME?
THIS IS INTERESTING.
BUBBLE GUM
NAMED AFTER A WEAPON.
HMM.
WELL, IT'S BEEN
AROUND A WHILE.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
AND IT COMES WITH
ITS OWN PERSONAL STORY.
[ Laughing ]
VERY CLEVER.
WELL, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AS YOU WERE.
[ Laughing ]
[ Girl ]
GET AWAY FROM ME!
LEAVE ME ALONE!
I SAID GET--
GET AWAY FROM ME!
STOP IT!
[ Panting ]
[ Yelps ]
ARE YOU GOING SOMEPLACE?
LOOK, THERE'S TWO MEN
CHASING ME. I THINK
THEY'RE SOME KIND OF PERVERTS.
YOU'VE REALLY GOTTA HELP ME.
THAT'S THEM!
COMMANDER.
IS THERE SOME KIND OF
PROBLEM, SERGEANT?
YES, SIR.
WE CAUGHT THIS BUG TRYING TO
HOT-WIRE AN ENSIGN'S JEEP.
OH, THAT'S A GREAT BIG LIE.
BESIDES, I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
THE JEEP BELONGED TO THE ENSIGN.
IT'S THE THIRD TIME
THIS WEEK WE'VE HAD A RUN-IN
WITH THIS DESPERADO.
I SEE.
I THINK I CAN HANDLE IT
FROM HERE.
MY NAME'S JAROD.
MELINA PRATT.
PRATT? AS IN
SECURITY OFFICER PRATT?
AS IN HER DAUGHTER.
YOU'RE GONNA TELL HER
ABOUT THIS, AREN'T YOU?
WHAT ABOUT YOUR FATHER?
HE'S THE NAVIGATOR
ON THE FARRAGUT.
THAT'S ON THE INDIAN OCEAN,
ON PATROL?
YEAH.
HE'S BEEN GONE FOR
ABOUT FOUR MONTHS NOW.
FOUR AND A HALF.
MUST BE PRETTY TOUGH
ON YOU...
AND YOUR MOTHER,
YOUR FATHER BEING GONE
THAT LONG.
MY MOM JUST WORKS MORE.
TO ME, IT'S NO BIGGIE.
SO YOUR DAD IS GONE,
AND YOUR MOM WORKS ALL DAY.
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND,
A TEENAGER LIVES FOR
THAT KIND OF FREEDOM.
IS THAT TRUE?
IF YOU'RE SO INTERESTED IN
TEENAGERS, MAYBE YOU SHOULD
BECOME A HIGH SCHOOL COUNSELOR.
I ALREADY TRIED THAT ONCE.
I MEAN, THE HOURS WERE GREAT,
BUT...
THE FOOD WAS TERRIBLE.
SO, ARE YOU GONNA
TELL MY MOM ABOUT
THIS JEEP THING OR NOT?
MELINA.
WHAT?
NEXT TIME YOU GO TO
SO MUCH TROUBLE...
TO GET INTO TROUBLE,
HOT-WIRE AN ADMIRAL'S JEEP.
[ Man On P.A. ]
COMMUNICATIONS WATCH OFFICER
AND D.D.O.,
PLEASE REPORT
TO THE QUARTERDECK.
COMM WATCH OFFICER AND D.D.O.,
REPORT TO THE QUARTERDECK.
THAT'S NICE WORK...
FOR AN OXYACETYLENE WELD.
IT'S OLD-SCHOOL, I KNOW,
BUT IT HOLDS TIGHTER THAN
ANY OF THAT NEWFANGLED STUFF.
SNIPES ARE ALWAYS
GETTING ON ME.
TIG WELD THIS,
GAS TUNGSTEN THAT.
GOT NO RESPECT FOR
THE OLD WAYS, YOU KNOW.
I GUESS NOT.
[ Chuckles ]
EXCUSE ME.
AS YOU WERE.
PETTY OFFICER MIKE BAKER.
I PULLED HIM OUT OF A FIGHT
A COUPLE OF DAYS AGO.
- I HAVE A GOOD MIND
TO GO UP THERE--
- WHOA, WHOA.
I KNOW THAT YOU'RE
EAGER TO CRACK SKULLS,
BUT, UH,
DON'T START ON BAKER.
HE LOST HIS BEST FRIEND
ON OUR LAST TOUR.
SCOTT SEAVER.
I TOLD YOU ABOUT IT, JAROD.
THE, UH, JX-5 LEAK
IN THE PUMP ROOM.
- OH, YES. RIGHT.
- SEAVER BOTCHED THE RETROFIT.
WHICH GAVE THE BOARD OF INQUIRY
AN EXCUSE TO TRY TO MOTHBALL
THE SHIP AGAIN.
DAMN LEECHES CAME IN HERE.
THEY WENT OVER
EVERY PIECE OF PAPERWORK,
EVERY INSPECTION RECORD,
TRIED TO HAUL HER
OUT OF THE WATER.
FINALLY, IT TOOK
SEVEN ADMIRALS TO DECIDE...
THE PROBLEM WAS SEAVER'S
SHODDY WORK.
I SEE.
WELL, I GUESS
I'LL EASE OFF BAKER THEN.
HE DOES KNOW
THAT HE'S ON THIS SHIP
FOR THE NEXT SIX MONTHS.
[ Jarod ]
WHERE HIS BEST FRIEND DIED.
[ Seaver's Voice ]
OH, MY GOD!
BAKER, HELP ME!
[ Man ]
SURPRISE INSPECTION,
OR ARE YOU STEALING STOCK TIPS?
I WAS JUST...
GETTING TO KNOW
THE TERRITORY.
YOU PLAY THE STOCK MARKET.
HEY, YOU WANT TO PUT A KID
THROUGH COLLEGE ON MY SALARY,
YOU GOTTA TAKE SOME CHANCES.
ACTUALLY, MY SON PICKS OUT
ALL MY STOCKS.
HE WANTS TO SEE
HIS TUITION KEEP COMING,
HE BETTER PICK 'EM RIGHT.
IS HE A BUSINESS MAJOR?
HE'S A TIGHT END.
GOT A GOOD BRAIN.
AVERAGE HANDS. NO SCHOLARSHIP.
BUT I'LL BE DAMNED
HE'S GONNA SPEND HIS WHOLE LIFE
SWEATING IN A HOLE LIKE THIS.
YOU SURE THIS AIN'T
NO INSPECTION?
PROMISE.
GOOD. I MEAN,
NOTHING PERSONAL, SIR,
BUT, UH,
I'VE BEEN TURNING
WRENCHES DOWN HERE...
SINCE YOU AND MOST OF THIS CREW
WERE PLAYING KICK THE CAN.
AND WHAT CAN WAS I KICKING?
ALL I'M SAYING IS, UH,
YOU DON'T NEED TO GO
WASTING YOUR TIME...
CHECKING UP ON
LIEUTENANT ALBERT DANES.
AS YOU WERE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THANK YOU.
[ Man Shouting Commands
In Distance ]
[ Laughing ]
THEY'RE VERY FUNNY.
THEY STILL MAKE THOSE?
[ Jarod ] YEAH.
BUT WHAT I DON'T UNDERSTAND IS
WHY DOES HE WEAR THE EYE PATCH?
MATTERS OF COSMIC IMPORTANCE
I'M NOT PREPARED TO ADDRESS.
HUH.
I WANTED YOU HERE
WHEN I CALL ADMIRAL MASON.
YOU REMEMBER ADMIRAL MASON.
HE SIGNED YOUR RECOMMENDATION.
HOW COULD I FORGET?
[ Autodial Beeps,
Line Ringing ]
[ Woman ]
ADMIRAL MASON'S OFFICE.
LIEUTENANT PAULA PRATT
CALLING FROM
LONG BEACH NAVAL STATION.
[ Woman ] I'M SORRY.
THE ADMIRAL IS ON HIS
ANNUAL FISHING TRIP TO BIMINI.
[ Pratt ]
IT'S NICE SOMEBODY
HAS TIME FOR A VACATION.
HOW LONG WILL HE BE GONE?
[ Woman ]
TWO WEEKS.
AND HE LEFT STRICT ORDERS
NOT TO BE DISTURBED--
UNLESS, OF COURSE, IT'S URGENT.
I'LL CALL BACK.
- BUMMER.
- BUMMER?
MELINA,
SHE'S BUSY!
THAT'S WHAT JOE WOULD SAY.
I DON'T CARE HOW BUSY SHE IS.
I NEED TO SEE HER!
MELINA, I'M IN A MEETING.
I KNOW.
HI.
BUT I CAN'T EVEN GET AN
APPOINTMENT, AND I NEED TO KNOW
TODAY IF I CAN GO SEE R.E.M.
RAPID EYE MOVEMENTS?
- NO. IT'S A BAND.
- OH.
- TICKETS GO ON SALE IN AN HOUR.
- I TOLD YOU.
I DON'T WANT YOU
GOING ALONE.
I WON'T BE ALONE, MOM.
THERE'LL BE 40,000
OTHER PEOPLE THERE.
[ Sighs ]
I AM BUSY.
WE WILL TALK ABOUT THIS LATER.
YEAH, WHAT ELSE IS NEW?
MY DAUGHTER.
YO. WHAT'S UP?
WHY WON'T YOU TALK TO ME?
[ Chattering ]
HOW'D YOUR TATTOO COME OUT?
WHAT ARE YOU, STALKING ME?
NOT EXACTLY.
THIS POLICE OFFICER
STOPPED BY AND, UH,
LEFT YOU
THIS PARKING TICKET.
GREAT.
MY MOM'S GONNA GO BALLISTIC
WHEN SHE SEES THIS.
NOT TO MENTION
WHEN SHE FINDS OUT
YOU STOLE HER CAR.
BUT HAVING HER GO BALLISTIC--
THAT'S THE GENERAL IDEA,
ISN'T IT?
COME ON. YOU CAN DO IT.
TRY IT AGAIN.
WRAP IT AROUND
YOUR TONGUE AND...
BLOW.
[ Laughs ]
YES!
I CAN'T BELIEVE NO ONE TAUGHT
YOU HOW TO BLOW BUBBLE GUM.
I HAD A LONELY CHILDHOOD.
YEAH, JOIN THE CLUB.
"I.L.Y."
IS THAT ANOTHER BAND?
NO. JUST THREE LETTERS
I WANT TO REMEMBER.
THAT'S ALL.
WHAT ARE YOUR PARENTS
GOING TO SAY?
I DON'T CARE.
MY MOM HATES ME,
AND MY DAD'S NEVER AROUND.
YOUR MOM DOES NOT HATE YOU.
PARENTS LOVE THEIR CHILDREN.
OH, WHAT SITCOM
ARE YOU LIVING IN?
[ Laughs ]
[ Bubble Pops ]
[ Man On Recording ]
IN CONCLUSION,
VICTIM SEAVER EXPIRED AFTER
INHALING THE JX-5 TOXIC GAS
FROM THE SHIP'S COOLANT SYSTEM.
ICE CRYSTALS FORMED
IN THE LUNGS WITHIN 30 SECONDS,
RESULTING IN ASPHYXIATION.
FURTHERMORE,
ADDITIONAL TRAUMA--
[ Seaver ]
BAKER! BAKER!
OH, MY GOD!
CAN'T SLEEP?
SIR.
AT EASE, SAILOR.
SIT DOWN.
I HAVE NIGHTMARES TOO.
ABOUT FAMILY
I'VE NEVER SEEN,
BEST FRIENDS I'VE LOST.
SCOTT SEAVER DID NOT
BOTCH THAT RETROFIT, SIR.
AND JUST BECAUSE
SOME BIG PANEL
OF ADMIRALS SAYS SO--
DOESN'T MEAN IT'S TRUE.
RIGHT.
SCOTT WAS EDGY...
THE WHOLE WEEK
BEFORE IT HAPPENED.
I THINK HE KNEW
THERE WAS SOMETHING
WRONG WITH THE MONROE,
BUT HE NEVER WOULD'VE
LET US DEPLOY LIKE THAT.
LOOK,
YOU DON'T GOTTA WORRY ABOUT ME
GETTING TANKED OR GETTING INTO
FIGHTS ANYMORE, SIR.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
I'M GONNA TALK TO
LIEUTENANT PRATT.
I'M OUT OF HERE.
YOU'RE GOING TO RESIGN.
YOU THINK THAT'S GOING TO
SOLVE ANYTHING?
I WATCHED HIM DIE, SIR.
YOU KNOW, UH,
IT HIT US OUT OF NOWHERE.
THE PIPE BURST,
AND THE WHOLE PLACE
WAS FILLING UP WITH JX-5.
SCOTT TOLD ME TO
GET OUT OF THERE.
HE SAID HE COULD HANDLE IT.
I COULD'VE SAVED HIM.
BUT THEN NASHTON
SEALED THE HATCH.
NASHTON.
I COULD SEE SCOTT...
THROUGH THE PORTAL.
THE GAS WAS
STARTING TO GET TO HIM.
WELL, FIRST IT
MAKES YOU CRAZY.
FILLS UP YOUR LUNGS
AND FREEZES 'EM.
HE COULDN'T BREATHE.
WAIT.
THE X.O. WAS ON DECK
THAT NIGHT.
NOW, WHY WOULD NASHTON
COME DOWN HERE
TO SEAL THE HATCH?
HE SAID THE WHOLE SHIP
COULD'VE BLOWN.
HE SAID HE HAD TO
SEAL THE HATCH.
SOME BEST FRIEND
I TURNED OUT TO BE, HUH?
HE DIDN'T HAVE TO DIE, SIR.
I SHOULD'VE STAYED.
IT SHOULD'VE BEEN ME
THAT DIED.
IT WASN'T YOUR FAULT.
[ Nashton ]
THERE'S BEEN A LOT OF TALK
ABOUT DECOMMISSIONING HER,
BUT I'M HERE
TO TELL YOU GENTLEMEN
THAT THE U.S.S. MONROE...
IS A LONG WAY FROM MOTHBALLS.
THIS ACCIDENT--
THIS TRAGEDY--
HAPPENED BECAUSE OF SUBSTANDARD
WORK BY A YOUNG ENGINEER
NAMED SCOTT SEAVER.
[ Man ] YOU BELIEVE THAT
SEALING THAT ROOM WAS
THE CORRECT COURSE OF ACTION.
JX-5 GAS MIGHT HAVE SEEPED
TO THE REST OF THE SHIP.
SHE WAS A POWDER KEG,
READY TO BLOW.
IF I HAD HAD THE TIME TO PULL
HIM OUT, I WOULD HAVE DONE SO.
AS RANKING OFFICERS,
THESE ARE THE KINDS OF CALLS
THAT WE'RE EXPECTED TO MAKE.
IT'S ONE OF THE DEMONS
WE HAVE TO LIVE WITH.
I DID IT TO SAVE THE SHIP.
YOU DID IT... TO SAVE YOUR JOB.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Sydney ]
THE DOOR WAS OPEN.
MAKING HOUSE CALLS NOW, SYD?
WHERE WERE YOU TODAY?
LAST TIME I CHECKED,
THAT WAS A RAINES QUESTION.
WHAT KIND OF GAME
ARE YOU PLAYING WITH JAROD?
GAME?
HALL OF RECORDS.
YOU'RE STARTING TO
ASK QUESTIONS.
THE WAY YOUR MOTHER DID.
HER FINAL SESSION WITH ME,
BEFORE SHE GOT ON THE ELEVATOR,
SHE WAS LOOKING FOR ANSWERS.
SHE DIDN'T HAVE THE MEANS
TO FIND THEM.
- I DO.
- THEN YOU'LL END UP LIKE HER.
IS THAT A THREAT?
A WARNING...
FROM A FRIEND.
MAIL CALL.
THESE SEEM TO HAVE SLIPPED
THROUGH THE CRACKS.
HEY. PERSONAL DELIVERY
FROM THE OPS OFFICER.
THANKS.
LETTER FROM MY KID AT COLLEGE.
GONNA BE AN ENGINEER.
OH, YEAH?
CORNELL.
MUST BE EXPENSIVE.
- HOW'D YOU KNOW
HE WAS GOING THERE?
- INTERESTING.
THIS IS
AN OXYACETYLENE WELD.
NOW, SCOTT SEAVER,
HE WAS ONLY RATED FOR
GAS TUNGSTEN WELDING.
IF THOSE ADMIRALS HAD KNOWN
WHAT TO LOOK FOR,
THEY WOULD'VE KNOWN
THAT SEAVER DIDN'T
BOTCH THE RETROFIT.
NASHTON FORCED YOU
TO DO THE WORK,
AFTER IT RUPTURED,
AND MAKE IT LOOK LIKE
SEAVER BOTCHED IT.
- COME ON. THAT'S CRAZY.
- TELL THAT TO SCOTT SEAVER.
I SPOKE TO HIS BEST FRIEND.
HE SAID SEAVER WAS NERVOUS
THE WHOLE WEEK
BEFORE THE DEPLOY.
HE KNEW SOMETHING
WAS WRONG, DIDN'T HE?
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, SIR.
YOU'VE LOST IT.
DID NASHTON THREATEN
YOUR CAREER, OR DID HE THREATEN
YOUR SON'S EDUCATION?
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
NASHTON SAID HE WAS GONNA TURN
THE INVESTIGATING PANEL ON ME.
I'D HAVE BEEN
KICKED OUT ON MY ASS.
NO PENSION, NO NOTHING.
AND HE FORCED SEAVER AND ME
TO SIGN OFF ON THAT
INSPECTION REPORT...
EVEN THOUGH THE JX-5 LINE
NEEDED WORK.
BRASS NEVER KNEW.
AND THE EXTRA WORK
WOULD HAVE DELAYED
DEPLOYMENT.
OR WORSE,
PUT THE MONROE IN MOTHBALLS.
NO MORE MONROE,
NO MORE CAREER FOR NASHTON.
SO A 20-YEAR-OLD KID...
CHOKES TO DEATH.
- IT COULD'VE BEEN YOUR SHIFT.
- OH, COME ON.
NASHTON TRIED TO SAVE
THAT POOR KID. THE PUMP ROOM WAS
GONNA BLOW. THERE WAS NO TIME.
THERE WAS PLENTY OF TIME.
BUT SEAVER KNEW THE TRUTH.
NASHTON MADE SURE
HE DIED WITH IT.
[ Car Alarm
Blaring In Distance ]
[ Bottle Rattles ]
[ Car Alarm Continues Blaring ]
[ Car Alarm Stops ]
YOUR MOM'S GOING TO MISS YOU.
YEAH, WELL, YOU CAN'T
MISS SOMETHING THAT'S
NOT THERE TO BEGIN WITH.
I'M NOT GOING
BACK THERE-- EVER.
OKAY.
YOU FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE NOT VERY IMPORTANT,
DON'T YOU?
YOU FEEL LIKE...
YOU WERE FORGOTTEN,
BUT YOU HAVEN'T BEEN.
YEAH, WHAT DO YOU
KNOW ABOUT IT?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHO MY PARENTS ARE.
I DON'T KNOW
IF THEY GAVE ME UP...
OR I WAS TAKEN FROM THEM.
BUT I KNOW...
THEY'RE STILL OUT THERE.
SOMEWHERE.
I KNOW THEY LOVE ME.
DEEP DOWN INSIDE,
[ Sobs ]
JUST LIKE DEEP DOWN INSIDE
YOU KNOW YOUR PARENTS LOVE YOU.
MY MOM JUST BURIES HERSELF
IN WORK EVERY TIME
MY DAD'S OUT TO SEA.
YOUR MOM IS RESPONSIBLE
FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE'S LIVES.
MAYBE IN ALL THAT, SHE OVERLOOKS
THE LIFE THAT'S MOST IMPORTANT
TO HER, BUT I KNOW...
SHE LOVES YOU VERY MUCH.
I REALLY MISS MY DAD.
"I LOVE YOU."
I.L.Y.
MY DAD USED TO PUT IT ON ALL
THE SATELLITE COMMUNICATIONS
HE'D SEND US FROM THE SUBS.
YOU KNOW, THEY ONLY GIVE YOU,
LIKE, 40 WORDS TO SAY EVERYTHING
YOU CAN TO EACH OTHER,
SO YOU GOTTA ABBREVIATE.
I JUST WISH HE WAS HERE
TO SAY IT IN PERSON.
SHH, SHH, SHH.
SHH.
SORRY, MAMA.
I'M SORRY TOO, HONEY.
WE'LL TALK INSIDE.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S OKAY.
- YOU HAVE A GREAT KID.
- YEAH.
I THINK I SHOULD TELL HER THAT
A LITTLE MORE OFTEN.
THANKS.
[ Engine Starts ]
ARE YOU SURE THAT RESIGNING
IS THE RIGHT THING TO DO?
MADE UP MY MIND, SIR.
- DID I SAY "AT EASE," SAILOR?
- NO, SIR!
ARE YOU SURE
IT'S THE RIGHT THING
TO DO, SAILOR?
YES, SIR!
IS THAT WHAT SCOTT SEAVER
WOULD HAVE WANTED?
HOPE TO SEE YOU
ON BOARD,
SAILOR.
AT EASE.
[ Young Jarod ]
WHAT'S THAT, SYDNEY?
[ Young Sydney ] I DON'T KNOW.
[ Woman Screaming ]
NO! NO! NO.
THEY'RE TRYING TO HURT HER.
[ Young Sydney ]
STAY HERE, JAROD.
NO!
- NO.
- [ Man ]
GET HER ON THE ELEVATOR!
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Man ]
GET THE KID OUT OF HERE!
[ Young Jarod ] STOP!
- WHAT?
- JAROD HAS THEM, DOESN'T HE?
HAS WHAT?
THE ANSWERS
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
WHEN I CATCH HIM,
I'LL JUST HAVE TO FIND OUT.
YOU MAY HAVE THAT CHANCE.
COMMANDER JAROD FORRESTER
IS CURRENTLY SERVING ABOARD...
THE DESTROYER U.S.S. MONROE.
ONE OF BROOTS'S
ROUTINE SCANS CAUGHT IT.
HOWEVER,
NAVAL INTELLIGENCE
MAY ALREADY BE ONTO HIM.
NAVAL INTELLIGENCE?
THAT'S CORRECT.
HAVE MY FATHER
CALL THE SECRETARY.
YES, MISS PARKER.
MMM.
[ Phone Beeps Off ]
[ Young Miss Parker ]
MAMA!
[ Sydney ]
NO. KEEP HER BACK. GO BACK.
[ Young Jarod ]
LEAVE ME ALONE!
[ Young Miss Parker ] MAMA!
YES. I'D LIKE TO PURCHASE
SOME TICKETS, PLEASE.
FROM THE SECRETARY.
I'M IMPRESSED.
YOU SHOULD BE.
HELL OF A DAY
FOR A DEPLOYMENT.
- WHAT'S THE GOOD WORD?
- SURPRISE.
YOUR KNACK FOR DISCIPLINE
HAS INSPIRED ME.
I PUT TOGETHER
ONE LAST SURPRISE DRILL
BEFORE WE DEPLOY. HERE.
CRANK IT TO MAXIMUM.
THE JX-5 MAIN?
THAT'LL OVERLOAD THE SYSTEM.
OH, RELAX.
I'VE SHUT OFF THE PRESSURE.
ONLY THE ALARM WILL SOUND.
THINK OF IT AS MY PERSONAL
HIGHWAY TO HELL.
WHAT'S JAROD WANTED FOR?
YOU NAME IT, HE'S DONE IT.
AFTER YOU.
[ Whistling ]
PRESSURE'S BUILDING UP.
HEY, WHERE THE HELL
IS EVERYBODY?
THEY'RE IN THE MESS.
WHICH IS SORT OF
WHAT YOU'RE IN NOW.
[ Alarm Blaring ]
HEY, O-OPEN THE HATCH!
FORRESTER!
OPEN THE HATCH! NOW!
ARE YOU STARTING TO FEEL
OUT OF IT?
DISORIENTED?
- OPEN THE HATCH!
- I CAN'T DO THAT.
IT COULD BLOW
THE WHOLE SHIP UP.
YOU'RE JUST
GOING TO HAVE TO DIE...
TO SAVE EVERYBODY ELSE.
JUST LIKE SCOTT SEAVER DID.
IT'S A HORRIBLE WAY TO DIE.
YOUR LUNGS,
THEY FILL UP WITH TOXIC ICE,
AND THEN THEY FREEZE.
NO MATTER HOW HARD YOU TRY,
YOU WON'T BE ABLE TO BREATHE.
BUT THIS IS JUST
A JUDGMENT CALL
I'M GOING TO HAVE TO MAKE.
THINK OF IT AS
JUST ANOTHER DEMON
YOU HAVE TO DEAL WITH...
WHEN YOU'RE AN OFFICER.
HUH, NASHTON?
OPEN THE HATCH!
THAT'S AN ORDER, COMMANDER!
THAT'S AN ORDER
I CAN'T REALLY FOLLOW.
YOU SEE,
I'M NOT AN OFFICER
ON THIS SHIP.
THINK OF ME AS...
NAVAL INTELLIGENCE.
YOU DON'T HAVE
ANYTHING ON ME!
[ Jarod On Speaker ]
I KNOW THAT YOU FORCED DANES...
TO TAMPER WITH THE EVIDENCE
AFTER THE ACCIDENT,
TO RUIN SCOTT SEAVER'S NAME.
YOU HAD TO PRESERVE
THE MONROE TO SAVE YOUR CAREER,
SO YOU LET
A 20-YEAR-OLD KID DIE!
DIDN'T YOU, NASHTON?
DIDN'T YOU? DIDN'T YOU?
DIDN'T YOU?
YES. YES.
GOD, I'M SORRY.
I LET HIM DIE.
[ Gasping ]
NOW, DID YOU REALLY THINK
THAT I WOULD PUT
THIS SHIP INTO DANGER?
THAT WAS JUST LAUGHING GAS.
SO TRY TO LAUGH A LITTLE.
[ Panting ]
TAKE HIM STRAIGHT TO
CAPTAIN NAGEL.
AND THAT'S AN ORDER.
YES, SIR.
[ Jarod ]
DISMISSED.
SIR, YOU HAVE A MAN
IMPERSONATING AN OFFICER
ON THIS SHIP.
I KNOW THAT.
AT EASE, LIEUTENANT.
THERE HE IS.
WE WERE TALKING ABOUT
COMMANDER FORRESTER.
JAROD?
YES.
JAROD IS NAVAL INTELLIGENCE.
- I PLAN TO SEE TO IT
HE GETS A MEDAL.
- WHERE IS HE?
WELL, HE WAS ORDERED
BACK TO NORFOLK
BY THE SECRETARY NO LESS.
IF YOU HURRY,
YOU MIGHT STILL CATCH HIM.
[ Horn Honks ]
THE NEAREST OCEAN
IS 1,756 MILES FROM HERE.
THAT'S JUST THE WAY I LIKE IT.
[ Mews ]