YOU JUST MISSED HIM.
ONLY BEEN GONE
A COUPLE DAYS.
[ Man #2 ]
I'LL CHECK THE DRESSER.
HOW DID HE LOOK?
OH. ABOUT 6'2",
170 POUNDS, I GUESS.
[ Sydney ]
THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEAN.
I MEAN, WAS HE OKAY?
DID HE SEEM IN GOOD HEALTH?
ARE YOU KIDDIN'?
MAN HAD A PHYSIQUE
THE PROS WOULD KILL FOR.
[ Man ] SO, TELL ME, UH,
IF MR. SPITZ WASN'T REALLY
AN ATOMIC ENGINEER,
HOW DID HE STOP THE NUKE PLANT
FROM TURNIN' US
INTO PORK RIND?
MR. SPITZ IS, UM--
A FASCINATING MAN.
OH.
SO, ANY STAB AT
JAROD'S OEDIPAL TRAGEDY,
DR. FREUD?
[ Man ]
JAROD. THAT WAS
HIS FIRST NAME, YEAH.
STRANGE,
BUT YOU'D THINK A GROWN MAN
WITH A LAST NAME OF SPITZ...
WOULD ALREADY KNOW
HOW TO SWIM, WOULDN'T YA?
HE WAS HERE
FOR SWIMMING LESSONS?
HEY, WE ARE THE "Y."
HE WAS
A QUICK LEARNER TOO.
FROM PIKE TO ADVANCED ADULT
IN JUST FIVE WEEKS.
DAY IN, DAY OUT,
SWIMMING WAS ALL HE DID.
EXCEPT FOR
THIS PAST WEEK.
HE SPENT EVERY SECOND
IN THE POOL, BUT
HE DIDN'T SWIM A STROKE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
FROM THE TIME WE OPENED
IN THE MORNING UNTIL THE
MIDNIGHT CREW CLOSED HER DOWN,
HE'D BE THERE
IN THE DEEP END...
TREADING WATER
WITHOUT EVER STOPPING.
JUST TREADING WATER.
I WONDER WHAT
YOUR SCIENCE PROJECT
IS UP TO NOW.
[ Woman Over Radio ]
BANKING TWO-NINER
AND HEADING DOWN.
[ Jarod ]
GO IN FOR A CLOSER LOOK.
IT'S SMOKING PRETTY BADLY.
I'LL CALL IN A RESCUE CRAFT.
[ Jarod ]
SHE'S GOING OVERBOARD.
THERE'S NO TIME!
[ Woman ]
JAROD, NO!
COME ON, JAROD.
[ Coughing ]
HELLO. MY NAME IS JAROD.
YOU'RE GONNA BE JUST FINE.
[ Man Narrating ]
MISS PARKER,
YOU HAVE A FAX.
[ Together ]
1,324.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
VERY GOOD, GIRLS,
AND ABSOLUTELY CORRECT.
SYDNEY, NOW!
YOUR THEATRICS
UPSET THE CHILDREN.
SAVE THE MR. ROGERS, SYD.
I SET UP A TEXT SESSION
WITH BROOTS SO THAT
HE CAN HELP US TRACK JAROD.
I THINK THAT TAKES PRECEDENCE
OVER THING 1 AND THING 2.
BROOTS'S TECHNOLOGY ISN'T GOING
TO HELP US TRACK A CHAMELEON.
JAROD CHANGES COLOR.
HE BLENDS IN.
WE'LL GET CLOSE
WHEN HE LETS US.
PATIENCE, PARKER.
WE NEED PATIENCE.
SYD, PATIENCE MAY BE
A SOOTHING CATCHALL...
FOR THE POTATO HEADS
IN PSYCHOGENIC SERVICES.
BUT MY FATHER AND
THE BOYS IN THE TOWER
EQUATE PATIENCE WITH FAILURE.
BUT JAROD IS A PRETENDER.
HE CAN BECOME
ANYONE HE WANTS TO BE.
WE'LL NEVER CATCH HIM WITH
ONE OF BROOTS'S PHONE TAPS.
THAT'S WHAT THEY SAID
ABOUT THE UNABOMBER, SYD.
AND HOW DID THEY CATCH
THAT WHACKED-OUT PRODIGY?
A LETTER TO MOMMY.
IT'S THE SMART ONES
WHO ALWAYS DO SOMETHING STUPID.
LET'S USE THE STAIRS.
IT'S ONLY THREE FLIGHTS UP.
COME ON.
STOP NURTURING, SYDNEY.
[ Bell Dings ]
HELL, IT'S BEEN 20 YEARS.
I DON'T HAVE ANY PROBLEM
RIDING THIS ELEVATOR.
YOU SHOULDN'T EITHER.
YOUR MOTHER
WAS A SPECIAL PERSON.
MY MOTHER WAS WEAK. PERIOD.
SHE COULDN'T HANDLE
THE PRESSURES OF S.I.S.
OR THIS PLACE.
I DON'T HAVE
THAT PROBLEM.
ONLY THING THAT
EVER BOTHERED ME WAS--
WHY IN AN ELEVATOR?
THEY GO UP,
THEY GO DOWN.
THEY END UP NOWHERE.
IT'S AMAZING HOW
A SINGLE BULLET
CAN CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
IF YOU EVER WANT
TO TALK ABOUT IT--
CORRECT ME IF I'M WRONG, SYDNEY,
BUT WASN'T MY MOTHER'S
SESSION WITH YOU...
ONE OF THE LAST THINGS SHE DID
BEFORE SHE GOT ON THIS ELEVATOR?
NO, THANKS.
[ Bell Dings ]
[ Chuckles ]
SYDNEY, I'LL TAKE
MY OWN CHANCES.
[ Chattering ]
MARTHA.
GOOD MORNING.
YOU LOOK WAY TOO RESTED TO BE
STAYING IN COAST GUARD HOUSING.
I LIVE OFF-BASE.
IT TOOK THREE YEARS
AND A HUSBAND TO GET ME
OUT OF THE IRON COT.
- HOW'D YOU SWING IT?
- I FORGED MY TRANSFER PAPERS.
[ Laughs ]
OH.
MARTHA, ARE YOU OKAY?
YEAH, IT'S, UH,
BAD SUSHI.
IS THERE ANY OTHER KIND?
LIEUTENANT CAMPBELL.
GOOD MORNING.
I'M GLAD I CAUGHT YOU.
I WANTED YOU TO MEET
MY LIEUTENANT COMMANDER,
PAUL BILSON.
PLEASURE TO MEET YOU, SIR.
WORD IS YOU DID SOME PRETTY
GOOD WORK OUT THERE YESTERDAY.
HEARD YOU EVEN PLUCKED A VICTIM
OUT OF THE SOUP.
WELL, IT'S A GOOD THING
I TOOK THOSE SWIM LESSONS
AT THE "Y."
[ Laughing ]
I WISH ALL MY TRANSFERS HAD YOUR
HUMILITY, NOT TO MENTION TALENT.
COMMANDER POWELL, I WAS HOPING
TO GET A FEW MINUTES
REGARDING MY RANK REVIEW.
- WELL, ALL RANK REVIEWS
GO THROUGH THE L.C.
- I KNOW. IT'S ON MY DESK.
- I'LL GET ON IT A.S.A.P.
- THANK YOU, SIR.
WELL, I'LL LEAVE YOU IN
ABLER HANDS, LT. CAMPBELL.
THANK YOU, SIR.
WELL, THE REAL QUESTION IS,
WHAT KIND OF SEA LEGS
DO YOU HAVE?
AS YOU KNOW,
ANYBODY CAN FLY,
RIGHT, POOLE?
A KITE MAYBE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT.
GOOD MORNING, L.C.
HEY, GOT THE CHRISTI
PURRIN' LIKE A KITTEN.
I DON'T TRUST THAT OLD NAG.
I'LL TAKE THE 45.
YES, SIR!
COMMANDER POWELL LIKES HIS MEN
TO BE REAL SAILORS.
YOU UP FOR SOME SEA DUTY?
AS READY AS
I'LL EVER BE, SIR.
JAVI, WE'RE WAITING!
[ Javi ]
RUMBLE BASE ALPHA SIGNING OFF.
HAVEN'T YOU EVER HEARD
OF THE INTERNET? E-MAIL?
- I'M A PURIST.
I CRAVE STATIC.
- YOU COMIN'?
YEAH.
HI. JAROD CAMPBELL.
JAVI PADILLA.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
IS BILSON ALWAYS
IN SUCH A HURRY?
ONLY WHEN THE OCEAN CALLS.
COMMANDER POWELL TELLS ME
YOU'VE BEEN RUNNING
ICEBREAKERS OFF KATIMA BAY.
GREAT LAKES?
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME THIS WAS
A FRESHWATER BOY, SIR.
AH, GIVE ME A BREAK.
AT LEAST I TRANSFERRED
TO THE UNIT...
WITH THE BEST S.A.R. RECORD
IN THE GUARD.
YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT. WE CONDUCTED
178 SEARCH-AND-RESCUES
LAST YEAR ALONE.
WHOO!
[ Bilson ]
LOOKS LIKE A 42-80 TO ME.
IT'S LISTING
ABOUT THREE DEGREES.
ABANDONED?
[ Bilson ] THAT'S MY GUESS.
JAVI, CALL IT IN.
JAROD, CHECK IT OUT.
HELLO?
IT'S THE COAST GUARD.
IS ANYBODY HERE?
HELLO?
WHOA, NOW, SIR.
NOBODY'S HERE TO HURT YOU.
[ Both Laughing ]
OH, HELL.
ROY ABBOTT, SAY HELLO
TO LT. CAMPBELL.
HI. CALL ME JAROD.
GET OFF MY BOAT.
AH, COME ON, ROY. IS THAT
ANY WAY TO TREAT THE NEW GUY?
SIR.
YOUR STORES APPEAR TO BE LOW,
AND YOU ALSO APPEAR
TO BE TAKING ON WATER.
WHY DON'T YOU LET US
TOW YOU ASHORE
SO WE CAN HELP YOU RESUPPLY?
NOTHIN' I NEED OVER THERE.
I'M FINE WHERE I AM.
[ Bilson ]
MR. ABBOTT,
THE COMMANDER DID NOT AGREE.
YOU HAVE ONE WEEK TO COME IN,
OR WE'RE AUTHORIZED
TO BRING YOU IN, SIR.
IT'S FOR YOUR OWN GOOD,
MR. ABBOTT.
[ Telephone Ringing ]
SYDNEY.
WELL, I'M SURPRISED
YOU'RE NOT OUT MAKING ROUNDS
DOWN CORRIDOR 15.
EVEN A PSYCHIATRIST
NEEDS A DAY OFF.
AND ALL THIS TIME,
I THOUGHT YOUR INTEREST IN ME
WAS PURELY PATERNAL.
I UNDERSTAND LEARNING TO SWIM,
BUT AREN'T YOU A LITTLE OLD...
TO BE PLAYING
WITH BATHTUB TOYS?
WELL, IT'S CERTAINLY BETTER
THAN THE KIND OF PLAYTIME
YOU FOISTED UPON ME.
IT'S FUNNY.
I CAN'T SEE THEIR FACES.
BUT THEIR EYES--
THEY WON'T STOP
STARING AT ME.
WHOSE EYES, JAROD?
I DON'T KNOW.
DEAD EYES.
EYES OF PEOPLE
THAT AREN'T ALIVE TODAY...
BECAUSE OF HOW YOU EXPLOITED
MY SIMULATIONS.
AND NOW, YOU WANT
TO RIGHT THOSE WRONGS...
BY USING YOUR GIFT
AS AN AVENGING ANGEL.
- IS THAT IT?
- SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
[ Sydney ]
THEN WHY ARE YOU CALLING?
I WANTED TO KNOW IF--
IF JAROD WAS MY REAL NAME.
I THINK IT IS. AT LEAST,
THAT'S WHAT I WAS TOLD.
THANK YOU, SYDNEY.
DON'T HANG UP.
I'M WORRIED ABOUT YOU.
IF YOU'RE SO WORRIED ABOUT ME,
WHY DON'T YOU GO
TO THE AUTHORITIES?
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THAT.
WHY?
BECAUSE YOU LOVE ME?
OR BECAUSE YOU'RE AFRAID
OF WHAT I KNOW?
JAROD, IF THOSE PEOPLE
FROM THE BELTWAY
FIND OUT WHAT YOU HAVE,
I WON'T BE ABLE
TO PROTECT YOU.
IF THEY FIND OUT
WHAT I HAVE,
YOU WON'T BE ABLE
TO PROTECT YOURSELVES.
THOSE D.S.A.'s
CONTAIN MY WORK.
NO, SYDNEY.
THEY CONTAIN MY LIFE.
GOOD-BYE.
[ Sighs ]
WE GOT YOU, GENIUS.
[ Jarod ]
NOW THIS IS VERY INTERESTING.
YOU MEAN SOMEBODY
ACTUALLY MANUFACTURES...
IMITATION CANINE FECES?
YEP. ONLY THEY COULDN'T
FIT ALL THAT ON THE LABEL,
SO THEY JUST CALL IT
FAKE DOG POOP.
OH.
AND WHY EXACTLY WOULD
SOMEBODY WANT FAKE DOG POOP?
'CAUSE IT'S FUNNY.
- OH.
- NO, I MEAN THE WHITE ONES.
YEAH.
THANK YOU.
IT IS FUNNY.
I GOT THE WHITE ONES, MOMMY.
THOSE WERE HIS FAVORITES.
[ Miss Parker ]
BROOTS TRACED JAROD'S CALL
BACK TO THIS Y.M.C.A.
GET HIM!
HEY, HEY, HEY!
I AIN'T DONE NOTHIN'.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING IN THIS ROOM?
I AIN'T TRESPASSIN'. NO.
THIS GUY GAVE ME THE ROOM.
IS THIS THE MAN?
YEAH, THAT-THAT'S HIM.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
HE CONDUCTS THE PHILHARMONIC.
MM-HMM.
AND-AND HE GIVES ME
SIX MONTHS' FREE RENT
JUST TO TRANSFER HIS CALLS.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
HE SAYS HE LIKES
TO TRAVEL A LOT.
SHUT UP, SYDNEY.
♪♪ [ Opera Over Radio ]
♪♪ [ Whistling ]
GOOD MORNING, MR. ABBOTT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I DON'T KNOW.
I WAS JUST PASSING THROUGH.
PERMISSION TO COME ABOARD?
GRANTED.
MAGDELINE'S A PRETTY LADY.
HOW DO YOU KNOW MAGDELINE?
I WAS TALKING ABOUT YOUR BOAT.
IS THAT YOUR WIFE?
COULD'VE BEEN.
PROBABLY WOULD'VE.
I NEVER ASKED HER.
DO YOU THINK THE DUTCHMAN
EVER FOUND HIS LOST LOVE?
WHAT?
THE OPERA
YOU WERE LISTENING TO.
WAGNER'S DUTCHMAN.
THAT'S THE STORY.
I ALWAYS WONDERED...
IF HE EVER SEARCHED
FOR HIS LOVE...
OR SPENT THE REST OF HIS DAYS
FLOATING AROUND ON
THAT GHOST SHIP.
I NEVER REALLY
GAVE IT MUCH THOUGHT.
IT'S NOT EASY WONDERING
IF SOMEONE YOU LOVE
IS STILL OUT THERE.
I AIN'T MOVIN' MY BOAT.
I'M NOT ASKING YOU TO.
I'M JUST BORROWING THE UNIFORM.
I BROUGHT YOU SOME SUPPLIES
FROM TOWN.
I'LL TRADE YOU FOR...
THIS CHEST YOU CARVED.
THROW IN SOME CANDLES
NEXT TIME YOU PASS,
YOU GOT YOURSELF A DEAL.
DONE. THANKS.
DO YOU EVER LISTEN
TO MOZART, MR. ABBOTT?
THE MAGIC FLUTE?
I LIKE THIS ONE FINE.
IT'S ALL I NEED.
I WAS ALLOWED TO LISTEN TO IT
ONCE WHEN I WAS A CHILD.
I'D CLOSE MY EYES,
AND IN MY MIND...
I BECAME AN EAGLE.
I COULD GO ANYWHERE,
DO ANYTHING.
NOTHING COULD STOP ME.
MAYBE MOZART KNEW SOMETHING
THAT WAGNER DIDN'T.
I AIN'T MOVIN' MY BOAT.
LT. CAMPBELL,
EVEN ON ROUTINE PATROL,
I EXPECT YOUR EYES ON THE DECK.
THIS IS A HELICOPTER,
NOT A LIBRARY.
TRYING TO ORIENT MYSELF
TO THE WEST COAST
OCEAN SEARCH PATTERNS.
TELL YOU WHAT.
I WILL BUY YOU LUNCH...
IF YOU LET ME PICK YOUR BRAIN
ABOUT SOME OF THESE
OLD SEARCHES.
AS LONG AS IT'S NOT SUSHI.
GREAT. I DON'T WANT
COMMANDER POWELL...
TO TAG ME "FRESHWATER BOY"
ON MY RANK REVIEW.
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'VE BEEN HERE THREE DAYS,
AND YOU'RE GETTING
A RANK REVIEW?
OH, GREAT!
ALL I NEED IS ANOTHER GUY
IN THIS OPERATION...
ELBOWING FOR ROOM
ON THE LADDER.
WHEN ARE YOU DUE?
I SHOULD'VE MADE L.C.
MONTHS AGO,
BUT COMMANDER POWELL
KEEPS PUTTING IT OFF.
NOT YOUR PROMOTION.
YOUR BABY.
I'D SAY FROM YOUR NAUSEA
AND YOUR SORE BACK,
YOU'RE ABOUT NINE WEEKS.
MY HUSBAND DOESN'T EVEN KNOW.
WHAT ARE YOU,
A PART-TIME OBSTETRICIAN?
NO, BUT I WAS
A MIDWIFE ONCE.
YOU HAVEN'T TOLD
THE COMMANDER YET, HAVE YOU?
HELL NO! IF POWELL
OR ANYONE ELSE AROUND HERE
FINDS OUT ABOUT THIS,
I CAN KISS AWAY
MY CHANCES AT L.C.
YOUR SECRET'S SAFE WITH ME.
WELL, BROOTS, WHAT HAPPENED?
I'M BACKTRACKING HIS CALL
THROUGH THE OTHER PHONE.
ALL I KNOW RIGHT NOW
IS THAT THEY'RE ALL
INTERNATIONAL LANDLINES.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
THAT WAS POSSIBLE.
HOW LONG TO TRACE IT?
UH, THAT'S HARD TO SAY.
I MEAN, JAROD'S METHOD
IS SO BASIC, SO SIMPLE.
UH, 20--
24 HOURS.
YOU HAVE 12.
I CAN DO IT IN EIGHT.
THE KING FILE?
YOU CERTAINLY PICKED
A SENSITIVE ONE.
IT'S ALL DOWNHILL
AFTER THIS.
YOU-YOU SHOULD TALK
TO BILSON.
THIS WAS HIS BABY.
HOW SO?
WELL, IT HAPPENED DURING HIS
REGULAR TUESDAY NIGHT PATROL.
SO, BILSON WAS IN CHARGE.
IT WAS A TOUGH ONE TOO.
NO ONE WAS SURE
HOW KING'S BOAT WENT DOWN.
NEVER DID FIND IT.
THIS ONE WAS PARTICULARLY SAD.
CORONER SAID TOM KING
TREADED WATER A DAY AND A HALF
BEFORE HE DROWNED.
FOR AN S.A.R. TEAM
THAT'S COME UP EMPTY,
THAT'S THE KIND OF NEWS
THAT HURTS THE MOST.
THIS REPORT SAYS THAT THE SEARCH
PATTERNS WERE BASED...
ON WATER CURRENT INFORMATION
PROVIDED BY DIRECTIONAL BUOYS.
YEP.
I DROPPED THEM MYSELF.
HERE.
PILCHER'S POINT.
THAT'S THE AREA
TOM KING WAS KNOWN
TO HAVE BEEN FISHING IN.
SO BILSON DEPLOYED
STANDARD GRID SEARCHES
SOUTHEAST OF THAT POINT?
THAT'S S.O.P. YOU SEEM
TO BE FOLLOWING THIS FINE.
WHAT IS THE MATTER?
ACCORDING TO
SATELLITE MONITORING,
THE D.F. BUOYS INDICATED
THAT THE CURRENT
WAS MOVING SOUTHWEST.
YOU'RE DOING IT WRONG.
HMM?
DIDN'T YOU EVER
EAT COOKIES AS A KID?
THEY DIDN'T HAVE COOKIES
WHERE I GREW UP.
WHERE'D YOU GROW UP-- MARS?
SORT OF.
FIRST,
YOU TWIST THE COOKIE,
SO THE TOP COMES OFF
LIKE A LITTLE LID.
THEN, YOU GET
ALL THE WHITE STUFF OFF.
I PICK IT WITH MY TEETH,
BUT YOU CAN SCRAPE IT
OR LICK IT.
THEN WHAT DO YOU DO
WITH THE BROWN PART?
GROWN-UPS PUT IT
IN ICE CREAM.
WHY DON'T THEY JUST SELL
THE WHITE STUFF?
IT WOULDN'T BE ANY FUN.
HMM.
YOUR MOM WORKS HARD.
SINCE MY DAD DIED,
THAT'S ALL SHE DOES.
HE'S WITH ST. ANDREW--
THE ONE FOR FISHERMEN.
I GOT MY DAD A STATUE
OF HIM AT CHURCH.
IT WAS ON HIS BOAT.
THEY NEVER FOUND THAT.
IT'S HARD TO LOSE A PARENT.
I KNOW.
WHAT PART DO YOU MISS
THE MOST?
MY MOM'S SMILE.
[ Young Jarod ]
I CAN'T FIGURE IT OUT!
[ Sydney ] YOU HAVE TO.
HOW MUCH OXYGEN IS LEFT?
LESS THAN 48 HOURS.
[ Young Jarod ]
WELL, WHAT CAUSED THE EXPLOSION?
WE DON'T KNOW!
FUEL.
OXYGEN.
THERE'S NOTHING
THAT CAN SAVE US!
IT'S YOUR DUTY
TO SAVE YOUR CREW!
NO! I CAN'T DO IT!
YOU SHUT DOWN NOW,
YOU ALL DIE!
[ Sighs ]
COME ON, JAROD! THINK!
[ Young Jarod ]
WAIT! WAIT!
I'VE GOT IT! I'VE GOT IT!
I CAN USE THE GRAVITATIONAL
PULL OF THE MOON
TO HELP GET US BACK.
VERY GOOD, JAROD.
I KNEW YOU WOULD SAVE THEM
IF YOU WANTED TO.
THEY DIDN'T WANT
TO SAVE TOM KING.
THEY WANTED HIM TO DIE.
[ Telephone Ringing ]
WHAT?
OH! I INTENTIONALLY WAKE YOU
IN YOUR DEEPEST SLEEP PHASE,
AND ALL I GET
IS A LIFELESS "WHAT"?
[ Sighs ]
YOU WANT WIT,
READ NOEL COWARD.
WHAT TIME IS IT
WHERE YOU ARE?
CUTE.
NOT FUNNY, BUT CUTE.
YOU'RE MAKING HOUSE CALLS NOW.
I'M HONORED.
WELL, I WAS FEELING
A LITTLE GUILTY ABOUT
MY VIRTUAL PHONE GAME.
YOU KNOW, I REALLY
SHOULD TAPE THIS TO REPLAY
AT THE CHRISTMAS PARTY.
YOU'LL BE THERE, YOU KNOW,
REST ASSURED.
I'M NOT RESTING MUCH
AT ALL THESE DAYS.
BREAKING MY HEART.
SO, JAROD,
WHY THE Y.M.C.A.?
I WAS WATCHING RETRO NIGHT
ON VH1, AND
THEY WERE DOING THE '70s,
WHICH, AS YOU KNOW,
I MISSED.
THERE WAS THIS SINGING GROUP
THAT WAS EXTOLLING THE VIRTUES
OF STAYING AT THE "Y."
SO, HERE I AM.
CUTE.
NOT FUNNY, BUT CUTE.
DID YOU KNOW THAT
THEY MAKE FAKE DOG POOP?
IT'S AMAZING--
HOW IT APPEARS TO BE ONE THING,
BUT IT'S REALLY
SOMETHING COMPLETELY DIFFERENT.
[ Clatters On Table ]
AND I SHOULD CARE BECAUSE--
WELL, THIS SORT OF THING
COULD BE A REAL MONEYMAKER
FOR THE CENTRE.
BESIDES, ISN'T IT
THE PERFECT METAPHOR...
FOR THE WAY YOUR FATHER
AND THE CENTRE
DISTORT THE TRUTH?
AND WHAT TRUTH IS THAT, JAROD?
IT'S ALL IN THE NOTE
I SENT YOU.
THE TRUTH ABOUT
WHAT MAKES YOU SAD.
[ Boat Departing ]
[ Horn Honks ]
I DOUBT THE BOYS
BACK AT KATIMA BAY ARE SITTIN'
BEACH-SIDE THIS TIME OF YEAR.
PROBABLY FREEZING
THEIR BUTTS OFF ON SOME
FUTILE CAPE-HOPPING S.A.R.
SO, UM, BESIDE THE OBVIOUS,
WHY PULL UP STAKES?
WELL, I WAS FEELING KIND OF
COOPED UP WHERE I WAS LIVING.
SO I DECIDED
TO HEAD OUT WEST.
I INTERVIEWED AT
THE CHANNEL ISLANDS
STATION FIRST,
BUT I DECIDED THAT
THIS WAS THE SPOT FOR ME.
WELL, YOU MADE
THE RIGHT DECISION.
THE CHANNEL ISLANDS
IS FULL OF OUR REJECTS.
THAT'S FUNNY.
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
THEY SAID
THAT THIS GROUP WAS
A BUNCH OF RENEGADES.
THAT'S A CROCK.
THEY SAID GUYS WHO
COULDN'T RESCUE A FISHERMAN
FROM THEIR OWN BAY...
DIDN'T DESERVE
TO WEAR THE UNIFORM.
WERE THEY TALKING ABOUT
THE KING RESCUE?
YES, I THINK THAT WAS
THE NAME THEY USED.
DID SOMETHING GO WRONG?
YOU KNOW, IT'S AMAZING HOW
THE PEOPLE WE PUT OUR LIVES
ON THE LINE FOR...
CAN JUST TURN AROUND
AND SMEAR THE GUARD
WITH ONE NEWS STORY.
THE MAN'S WIFE
TOOK IT HARD.
SHE BLAMED US.
I UNDERSTAND HER TRAGEDY.
I GUESS
SHE HAD TO BLAME SOMEBODY,
SO SHE COULD DEAL WITH IT.
I PROMISE YOU.
WE DID EVERYTHING WE COULD DO
TO SAVE THAT MAN.
WE DID OUR JOB.
[ Martha ]
PILCHER'S POINT IS WHERE
TOM KING...
WAS KNOWN
TO HAVE BEEN FISHING.
[ Jarod ]
THE CURRENT
WAS GOING SOUTHWEST.
[ Martha ] NO ONE WAS SURE
HOW KING'S BOAT WENT DOWN.
NEVER DID FIND IT.
[ Telephone Ringing ]
WHAT? I'M ON MY WAY.
[ Broots ]
IT WASN'T EASY,
BUT I-I HAVE TO ADMIT,
FIGURING JAROD'S MIND
IS A REAL TREAT.
HE'S A DAMN CLEVER GUY.
HE'S A ONE-MAN
SIEGFRIED AND ROY.
SHOW ME WHAT YOU HAVE.
OKAY.
WE BACKTRACKED THE CALL
WE THOUGHT WAS COMING
FROM THIS Y.M.C.A....
FROM JAROD'S ROOM--
ROOM 334.
JAROD INTERCONNECTED
173 INTERNATIONAL CALLS,
BUT-BUT BACKTRACKING
THOSE CALLS WAS IMPOSSIBLE...
BECAUSE INSTEAD OF
A CALL-FORWARDING DEVICE
TRIGGERED BY A SINGLE CALL,
ALL 173 CALLS...
WERE INDIVIDUALLY INITIATED.
INGENIOUS.
[ Broots ] AND A HELL
OF A LOT OF WORK FOR JAROD,
I MIGHT ADD, AND VERY EXPENSIVE.
I DON'T CARE WHAT IT COST.
OH, THAT'S GOOD,
BECAUSE JAROD CHARGED IT
TO YOUR CALLING CARD.
WHERE IS HE?
OH, THE-THE LAST PLACE
WE WOULD EXPECT TO LOOK.
[ Chuckles ]
ROOM 335.
IN THE SAME "Y"?
[ Broots ]
YEAH, IN THE VERY NEXT ROOM.
[ Chuckles ]
GOTCHA.
I FOUND THIS AT
A NOVELTY SHOP ON THE PIER.
YEAH, VERY FUNNY.
JUST WHEN YOU THINK
IT'S YOUR LUCKY DAY,
YOU FIND OUT IT'S NOT.
SO, WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
SAME AS YOU.
LOOKING FOR PEACE OF MIND.
AND THE ANSWER TO WHY
SHE'LL NEVER SEE
HER FATHER AGAIN.
- WHO THE HELL ARE YOU, HUH?
- I DON'T REALLY KNOW.
BUT LAST NIGHT I BECAME YOU,
AND I REALIZED
WHY YOU COME HERE SO MUCH,
WHY YOU FEEL SO GUILTY,
AND WHY YOU AND BILSON
DIDN'T SAVE HER FATHER'S LIFE.
WE SEARCHED FOR HIM
FOR TWO DAYS.
BUT YOU MADE SURE THAT
THE SEARCH WAS IN AREAS THAT
YOU KNEW HE WOULDN'T BE FOUND.
YOU COULDN'T AFFORD FOR HIM
TO BE FOUND ALIVE, COULD YOU?
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT THE HELL
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT!
I KNOW YOU AND BILSON MAKE
THE SAME PATROL ON THE SOUTH
SECTOR EVERY TUESDAY NIGHT.
AND EVERY WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON,
YOU MAKE A RATHER
SIZABLE DEPOSIT...
INTO YOUR PRIVATE ACCOUNT
ON CORONADO.
SO WHAT KIND OF CONTRABAND
WERE YOU RUNNING?
- YOU'RE CRAZY, MAN.
- AM I? THE PAINT ON THE HULL.
IT'S GONNA MATCH
THE RESCUE CRUISER THAT
YOU AND BILSON WERE IN...
THE NIGHT THAT HE WENT DOWN.
YOU CAN SEARCH EVERYWHERE
YOU WANT FOR SALVATION.
THE ONLY PLACE
YOU'RE GONNA FIND IT IS IN
THE TRUTH YOU'RE RUNNING FROM.
[ Javi ]
ME AND BILSON MEET
A MEXICAN HAULER...
NAMED THE SANTA MARCA
EVERY TUESDAY NIGHT,
BRINGING IN A SHIPMENT
OF SOMETHING.
I THINK IT'S ROCK,
BUT I'M NOT POSITIVE.
WE'RE JUST
PAID DELIVERY BOYS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
WE HIT HIS BOAT.
I MEAN, IT WAS FOGGY.
I JUST-JUST COULDN'T SEE IT.
BUT WE SHEARED IT
RIGHT IN HALF.
AND THEN--
THEN I SWUNG AROUND AND--
AND I SPOTTED HIM
IN THE WATER.
HE WAS STILL ALIVE.
YEAH.
AND HE LOOKED UP
AT ME, AND--
AND ALL I CAN THINK WAS,
"WHAT A SMALL WORLD,"
YOU KNOW?
I USED TO SEE HIM
WITH HIS DAUGHTER
AND HIS WIFE AT MASS,
AND I THINK
HE RECOGNIZED ME TOO.
AND THEN HE PUT
HIS HAND UP TO ME.
SO I TRIED
TO PULL HIM ON BOARD,
BUT BILSON STOPPED ME.
HE LITERALLY
PUT A GUN TO MY HEAD
AND TOLD ME TO LEAVE HIM.
- AND IF YOU SAVED HIM--
- THAT WE'D GO TO JAIL.
BUT I'LL TAKE PRISON
IN A HEARTBEAT...
IF I CAN GET OUT OF
THIS HELL I'M IN.
HEY, COULD YOU DO ME A FAVOR?
NOW, THAT'S FUNNY.
I'M SORRY I'M LATE, SIR.
LATE FOR WHAT?
PATROL.
I JUST GOT THE CALL
THIS MORNING
ABOUT RIDING WITH YOU.
RIDING WITH ME?
WHERE'S JAVI?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
THEY TOLD ME HE WAS SICK.
SICK?
ACTUALLY, I'M NOT FEELING
VERY WELL MYSELF.
BAD SUSHI.
DO YOU MIND IF I HIT THE HEAD
AND CATCH UP WITH YOU?
NAH, SURE, SURE.
IS THERE SOMETHING WRONG?
NO, EVERYTHING'S GREAT.
ALL RIGHT.
I WILL SEE YOU IN A MINUTE.
- WHERE'S 45?
- I GUESS IT'S ON PATROL.
THE CHRISTI'S--
YEAH, PURRING.
I KNOW.
JAVI?
[ Man Over Radio ]
SANTA MARCA TO ROBIN 247.
COME IN, 247.
ARE YOU INSANE?
WE DON'T HAVE SCHEDULED
RADIO CONTACT UNTIL TONIGHT.
WE'RE CONFIRMING
WE GOT YOUR MESSAGE.
AT YOUR REQUEST, THE RENDEZVOUS
WILL BE AT 10:00 A.M. TODAY.
YOU WILL BE THERE, JAVI?
HELLO? JAVI?
RIGHT. TODAY.
I'LL BE THERE.
ADIOS.
WELL, THERE YOU ARE, SIR.
I'M READY IF YOU ARE.
OH, THAT'S ALL RIGHT,
LIEUTENANT.
IT'S-IT'S A ROUTINE PATROL.
I'LL DO IT ALONE.
ARE YOU SURE, SIR?
- YEAH, YEAH.
GO TAKE CARE OF YOUR GUT.
- WELL, THANK YOU, SIR.
YOU DIDN'T TELL US
HE LIVED NEXT DOOR.
YOU DIDN'T ASK.
PAINT.
COME ON.
[ Engine Stalls ]
[ Engine Cranking ]
EXCUSE ME.
HAVE EITHER OF YOU
SEEN THIS MAN?
WELL, THAT'S GREAT.
THAT'S JUST GREAT.
PURRING LIKE
A DAMN KITTEN.
ROBIN 247 TO SANTA MARCA.
COME IN, SANTA MARCA.
RESCUE 45, COME IN.
IS THAT YOU, JAVI?
RESCUE 45, YOU'RE ON
A DIRECT COURSE TO MY CRAFT.
VEER OFF.
RESCUE 45, VEER OFF!
RESCUE 45,
YOU'RE COMING RIGHT AT ME!
RESCUE 45, VEER OFF!
HEY!
- OH, MY GOD!
- WHAT THE HELL'S WRONG
WITH YOU, MAN?
- YOU BLIND OR SOMETHIN'?
COME ON! TOSS ME A LINE!
- I CAN'T, SIR.
- WHAT?
- I'M SORRY,
BUT I CAN'T RESCUE YOU.
YOU'RE BUCKING FOR
A COURT-MARTIAL, LIEUTENANT!
WELL, THAT IS SERIOUS, SIR.
BUT, YOU SEE,
A COURT-MARTIAL,
IT WON'T EXACTLY AFFECT ME.
I'M NOT REALLY A LIEUTENANT.
THE TRUTH IS,
I'M NOT REALLY
IN THE COAST GUARD.
YOU GET ME OUT OF HERE!
OH, DON'T WORRY.
YOU'LL BE OKAY.
MEN HAVE BEEN KNOWN
TO TREAD WATER FOR DAYS.
THIS ISN'T FUNNY!
OH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S TERRIFYING.
YOU'RE ALL ALONE.
YOU CAN'T SEE ANYTHING
BUT WATER,
AND YOU START THINKING ABOUT
WHAT MIGHT BE DOWN THERE,
WHAT JUST BUMPED YOU
BELOW THE SURFACE.
BUT AFTER A WHILE,
YOUR NERVES WILL SETTLE DOWN.
BUT, UNFORTUNATELY,
THAT'S WHEN YOUR BODY
STARTS TO ACHE,
AND THE ONLY WAY
TO STOP THE PAIN...
IS TO STOP TREADING.
BUT THEN YOU START TO SINK.
AND IN THAT INSTANT
BETWEEN LIFE AND DEATH,
YOU THINK ABOUT
ALL THE PEOPLE AND
ALL THE THINGS YOU LEFT BEHIND.
SO YOU START FIGHTING YOUR WAY
BACK TO THE SURFACE.
YOU FIGHT FOR YOUR LIFE.
YOU CAN'T LEAVE ME HERE!
SURE, I CAN.
JUST LIKE YOU LEFT
TOM KING.
NO!
[ Gasping ]
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU HAVE TO SEE.
WHAT'S THIS?
[ Javi ]
IT'S THE TRUTH, SIR.
[ Jarod ]
RESCUE UNIT 45 TO BASE.
REQUESTING PICKUP NEAR
D.F. BUOY NUMBER 29.
BUT TAKE YOUR TIME
GETTING THERE.
JUST A LITTLE FLOATING DEBRIS.
[ Miss Parker ]
THERE HE IS!
[ Sydney ]
HELLO, JAROD!
HELLO, SYDNEY!
[ Miss Parker ]
GIVE THAT TO ME!
THERE'S NOWHERE
TO GO THIS TIME!
SYDNEY RAISED ME TO BELIEVE
MY MIND CAN TAKE ME ANYWHERE!
[ Engines Stall ]
[ Sydney ]
HE'S OUT OF FUEL.
LIKE I TOLD YOU, SYDNEY.
THE SMART ONES
ALWAYS DO SOMETHING STUPID.
GET HIM.
[ Sydney ]
HE'S NOT THERE?
HOW?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT HE LEFT YOU THIS.
♪♪ [ Opera ]
HIYA, ROY!
JAROD?
NICE DAY FOR A SWIM!
[ Inaudible ]
[ Clattering ]
WHAT'S THAT, SYDNEY?
I DON'T KNOW.
[ Woman ]
NO! NO!
[ Screaming, Sobbing ]
THEY'RE TRYING TO HURT HER!
STAY HERE, JAROD.
NO!
[ Man ]
GET HER ON THE ELEVATOR!
[ Young Jarod ]
STOP IT!
[ Gunshot ]
[ Man ]
GET THE KID OUT OF HERE!
STOP!
[ Gunfire ]
[ Girl Screaming ] MAMA!
NO, KEEP HER BACK!
KEEP HER BACK!
- [ Young Jarod ]
LEAVE ME ALONE!
- NO! MAMA!
[ Sobbing ]
IT'S ME.
I WANNA KNOW WHAT
REALLY HAPPENED TO MY MOM.
THANKS, ROY.
IT AIN'T NOTHIN'.
MAGDELINE'S
OUT THERE SOMEWHERE.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
I THINK I'LL TAKE A WALK.
THANK YOU.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
I THINK I'LL TAKE A DRIVE.
[ Cheering ]
[ Man Over P.A. ]
GENTLEMEN, START YOUR ENGINES!
OKAY, JAROD,
YOU'RE SET.
[ Mews ]