[ Miss Parker ]
PEOPLE DON'T JUST SIT AROUND
A JUNKYARD FOR A MONTH.
MR. WOODS SAID HE WAS TIRED
OF BEING ON THE ROAD AND
WANTED SOME PEACE AND QUIET.
HE WANTED TO CATCH UP
ON HIS READING.
LIKE THERE WAS MONEY IN IT.
THAT MAN READ NIGHT AND DAY.
READ?
READ WHAT,
EXACTLY?
BOOKS.
HUNDREDS OF 'EM.
LOOK AT ALL THESE.
MR. WOODS BROUGHT
ALL OF THESE WITH HIM?
MOST WERE DELIVERED
WHEN HE BOUGHT OUT STOCK
FROM THE OLD LIBRARY.
ALL OF THESE ARE ABOUT
MATHEMATICS AND SCIENCE.
- SAME HERE.
- MR. WOODS WAS
A BIG SCIENCE NUT.
ONCE, HE SPENT 14 HOURS
SITTING IN THIS ROCKING CHAIR,
FLIPPIN' A HALF-DOLLAR.
FOURTEEN HOURS?
WEIRD, HUH?
SAID HEADS
WERE BETTER ODDS.
SOMETHIN' ABOUT THE SURFACE
AND THE, UH, AERODYNAMICS.
EXCEPT FOR DIMES.
HE SAID NEVER BET WITH A DIME.
DIDN'T SAY WHY.
"FACTORING STATISTICS."
"PHYSICS AND
RANDOM PROBABILITIES."
OH, I THINK I'LL WAIT
FOR THE MOVIE ON THAT EPIC.
"MAKING ODDS EVEN."
MAY I?
JAROD'S LEFT A MESSAGE.
WE'RE CLOSE.
WE'RE NOWHERE EXCEPT
WHERE JAROD WANTS US.
WHY WOULD A MAN
WANT TO LEARN SO MUCH?
DAMN GOOD QUESTION.
- [ Bell Ringing ]
- [ Dealer ] BLACKJACK.
- THE GUY ON TABLE NINE
IS KILLING US.
- ON MY WAY.
- THIS GUY'S GOTTA BE A CHEAT.
- NO, NO. THERE'S NO WAY
HE'S COUNTING EIGHT DECKS.
- [ Dealer ] ANOTHER WINNER!
- [ Cheering, Applauding ]
- HOW MUCH IS HE UP?
- OVER A HUNDRED GRAND,
IT'S GOTTA BE.
-WHAT?
-THE CHIEF, MR. MORGAN, APPROVED
THE INCREASED CREDIT LIMIT.
WHO THE HELL
IS THIS GUY?
[ Cheering,
Applauding Continue ]
IVY, COME HERE.
- WHAT'S HE DRINKING?
- DR. PEPPER.
OFFER CRISTAL OR STOLI.
I TRIED THAT.
HE WANTS DR. PEPPER.
[ Cheering,
Applauding Continue ]
EXCUSE ME, PLEASE.
DR. PEPPER.
HEADS.
- TEN IN A ROW.
- [ Dealer ] ALL BETS ARE DOWN.
BE MY LUCK.
MISTER, I COULDN'T EVEN WIN
THE BIG HALF OF A WISHBONE.
HI. I'M IVY.
MR. FELSON.
HIT ME.
HOUSE STANDS ON 17.
TWENTY-TWO.
HOUSE WINS.
SEE?
I'M A TOTAL JINX.
YOU CAN ONLY BE A JINX
IF YOU BELIEVE IN LUCK.
DO YOU BELIEVE
IN LUCK?
NO.
- [ Dealer ] BLACKJACK.
- ALL RIGHT!
NEITHER DO I.
- AND ANOTHER BLACKJACK.
- [ Cheering,
Applauding Continue ]
THAT'S IT.
I'LL DEAL WITH MR. MORGAN.
SHUT HIM DOWN.
SO MUCH FOR JINX.
LET IT RIDE.
[ Cheering, Applauding ]
[ Man Narrating ]
[ Man ]
IF HE'S COUNTING CARDS,
I CAN'T CATCH IT.
- YOU THINK THIS IS A GAME?
- WELL, THIS IS LAS VEGAS.
- ISN'T EVERYTHING?
- [ Door Opens ]
THIS IS THE GUY,
MR. MORGAN.
LIKE TO COUNT CARDS,
DO YOU?
DAVIS?
HIS NAME
IS JAROD FELSON.
I RAN HIS I.D.--
CRUISE SHIPS TO MONTE CARLO.
DIDN'T FIND A FILE
ON HIM ANYWHERE.
I'M HONORED MR. FELSON HAS
SELECTED THE MARQUIS CASINO...
FOR HIS FIRST SCAM.
WHO HERE THINKS THAT MAKES
MR. FELSON A COMPLETE IDIOT?
[ Jarod ]
MAYBE YOUR SECURITY CHIEF
DIDN'T DIG DEEP ENOUGH.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY
THE F.B.I. FILE UNDER RICO?
YOU RUN RACKETS?
[ Typing On Keyboard ]
HELLO, MR. MORGAN!
YOU SET THIS UP.
YOU KNEW WE'D HAVE
THIS CONVERSATION.
NOT BAD
FOR A COMPLETE IDIOT.
[ Davis ]
WHERE ARE YOUR
BLACKJACK WINNINGS?
I HAD THEM DELIVERED
TO MR. MORGAN'S OFFICE
BY A NICE YOUNG LADY NAMED IVY.
- YOU'RE GIVING ME
THE MONEY BACK?
- MONEY DOESN'T INTEREST ME.
IF NOT MONEY,
WHAT DOES INTEREST YOU?
I'M NOT HERE TO MAKE
A FOOL OF YOU, MR. MORGAN,
OR TO RIP YOU OFF.
SO, WHAT DO YOU WANT?
EXCUSE ME?
YOU HAVE AN INCREDIBLE
SECURITY SYSTEM, MR. MORGAN.
IT'S A SHAME NO ONE HERE
KNOWS HOW TO USE IT.
[ Jarod ]
THE BET WAS $1,000.
WHAT DID THE DEALER PAY OUT?
PURPLE CHIP.
A GRAND.
[ Jarod ]
MEET MARTIN RAWLINGS.
HE'S BEEN DEALING BLACKJACK HERE
FOR 10 YEARS.
HE'S THE BEST WE HAVE.
THAT'S TOO BAD, BECAUSE
HE'S ABOUT TO LOSE HIS JOB.
HE USED TO WORK
AT A MAGIC CLUB IN KENTUCKY.
HIS SPECIALTY?
SLEIGHT-OF-HAND.
AN EXTRA THOUSAND FOR THE PLANT.
HE PASSES IT TO THE COURIER.
GAVE THE CHIP TO THE WAITRESS.
WHERE'S SHE GOING?
FORGET THE COURIER.
FOCUS ON THE CHIP.
BECAUSE IT
AND DOZENS LIKE IT...
ARE ON THEIR WAY
TO YOUR SECURITY CHIEF'S
MACE HOLSTER.
MR. MORGAN--
[ Morgan ]
REMOVE IT.
I'VE WORKED HERE
FOR TEN YEARS.
- ALL OF A SUDDEN SOME JERK
IN A SHINY SUIT--
- HELP HIM.
THAT'S OVER $10,000.
GET HIM OUTTA HERE.
IT'S NOT GONNA STOP HERE.
A CASINO-- IT'S ALWAYS A TARGET.
[ Door Closes ]
SO, MR. FELSON,
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
FIVE PERCENT
OF WHAT YOU DON'T LOSE
WHILE I'M IN CHARGE.
DON'T YOU LITTLE LADIES FORGET--
COME SEE MY SHOW TONIGHT.
THERE'S NO COVER, NO MINIMUM,
AND THERE'S FREE
HOT HORS D'OEUVRES.
[ Ladies Giggling ]
I'LL SEE Y'ALL LATER.
BYE-BYE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
HEY THERE, TEDDY BEAR.
YOU COME TO RUB ELBOWS
WITH THE KING OF ROCK AND ROLL?
NO. I'M TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND THIS.
YOU DRESS UP IN A RENTED COSTUME
AND PRETEND TO BE A DEAD SINGER?
"SINGER"?
SON, DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO I AM?
- WELL, ACTUALLY, I WOULD ASSU--
- YOU ARE LOOKING
AT A NATIONAL MONUMENT.
MOUNT RUSHMORE
IN BLUE SUEDE SHOES.
THERE'S NOT A HUMAN BEING
ON GOD'S GREEN EARTH...
THAT HAS EVER DEMANDED
THE ATTENTION AND RESPECT...
OF THE MAN
YOU ARE LOOKIN' AT
THIS VERY MOMENT.
HEY, BERNIE, SOME GUY AT THE
CRAPS TABLE SAYS HE'LL GIVE YOU
FIVE BUCKS TO GOOSE HIS WIFE.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
WELL, MY FANS BECKON.
I MUST GO.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THAT IS THE LAST OF THEM.
I'VE RUN EVERY ONE OF THESE
THROUGH THE MAINFRAME,
AND I CAN STILL FIND
NO CORRELATION.
ALTHOUGH THERE IS SOMETHING
TO BE SAID FOR JAROD'S THEORY...
ON THE AERODYNAMICS
OF A 50-CENT PIECE.
HEADS.
OKAY.
JAROD IS TRYING
TO TELL ME SOMETHING,
AND THIS BOOK IS THE CLUE.
THAT'S A HELL OF A CLUE, SYD.
JAROD HIGHLIGHTED
THE ENTIRE BOOK.
BUT LOOK AT
THIS PAGE OF STATISTICS.
HE TRACED OVER
ALL THE NUMBER EIGHTS.
NOW, EIGHT
IS JAROD'S FAVORITE NUMBER.
HIS FAVORITE FIGURE.
HE CALLS IT
UPRIGHT INFINITY...
BECAUSE OF THE WAY ONE LOOP
COILS INTO THE NEXT,
NEVER ENDING.
MAYBE YOUR BOY WONDER
HAS TURNED INTO BRIAN BOITANO.
MM-MMM.
JAROD IS LOOKING
FOR A PURPOSE.
HE'S PLAYING GAMES.
GAMES?
GAMES WITH NUMBERS?
HIGH-STAKES GAMES?
HIGH-STAKES POKER.
BACCARAT.
WELL, THAT NARROWS IT DOWN...
TO ANY OF THE THOUSANDS
OF GAMING ESTABLISHMENTS
ON THE PLANET.
ANY IDEAS WHERE TO START?
I KNOW
JUST THE MAN TO SEE.
HELLO.
HAVE YOU READ THIS?
IT'S-- IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S ABOUT THIS INQUISITIVE
LITTLE MONKEY NAMED GEORGE.
HE WAS CURIOUS.
I'VE ONLY READ IT
ABOUT A THOUSAND TIMES.
OH, WELL, GOOD.
THEN MAYBE YOU CAN HELP ME.
WHO IS THE MAN
IN THE YELLOW HAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
OH, WELL.
THANK YOU ANYWAY.
OKAY!
CAN I HELP YOU?
JAROD.
IT'S ABOUT TIME.
HANLON'S
BEEN ASKING FOR YOU.
ASKING FOR ME?
EXPOSING DAVIS'S SCAM
SAVED HIM MORE MONEY THAN HIS
CREATIVE ACCOUNTANT EVER DID.
STEVE HANLON,
JAROD FELSON.
IT'S A PLEASURE
TO MEET YOU, SIR.
I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR HELPING US OUT.
HERE AT THE MARQUIS,
WE THINK OF OURSELVES AS FAMILY.
NOTHING WORSE THAN BEING
BETRAYED BY THOSE CLOSE TO YOU.
TRULY IMPRESSIVE, THE WAY
YOU CAME IN AND CLEANED HOUSE.
I GUESS THE ONLY QUESTION
I HAVE... IS WHY?
WHY WOULD A MAN
I NEVER HEARD OF,
NEVER LAID EYES ON...
STEP IN TO HELP MY BUSINESS
OUT OF THE BLUE LIKE THAT?
I'M A FAN, MR. HANLON.
YOU TOOK A NO-NAME VIDEO STORE.
YOU TURNED IT INTO AN EMPIRE.
YOU LISTEN TO PEOPLE.
YOU GIVE THEM WHAT
THEY WANT. I LIKE THAT.
YOU STUDY PEOPLE TOO.
MASTER YOUR SPACE.
MY LECTURE AT BROWNSTONE.
- THAT MUST HAVE BEEN
12 YEARS AGO.
- IT WAS 11.
AND IT WAS THE FIRST TIME
YOU USED "FAMILY FIRST"
AS THE COMPANY MOTTO.
YOU WERE THERE?
NO, SIR.
BUT I BOUGHT THE CASSETTE.
I WORE OUT MY TAPE PLAYER.
PETER, WATCH OUT.
I MIGHT STEAL THIS MAN
FOR CORPORATE.
[ Laughs ]
WELL, THANK YOU, SIR.
WE FINALLY GOT CORRUPTION
OUT OF THE MARQUIS.
I WOULD LIKE TO HELP
KEEP IT THAT WAY.
JAROD, YOU HAVE MY PERMISSION
TO DO WHATEVER IT TAKES.
I THANK YOU, SIR.
JAROD,
THIS IS MY WIFE, KITTY.
KITTY, JAROD FELSON,
OUR NEW SECURITY CHIEF.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
A PLEASURE, MR. FELSON.
I SAW YOUR PICTURE
IN THE LOBBY.
KITTY USED TO
HEADLINE THE SHOW HERE.
UH, I NEED TO STEAL
MR. HANLON FOR A MOMENT.
- NICE TO MEET YOU, MR. FELSON.
- NICE TO MEET YOU.
SO, YOU'RE A COMPANY MAN, HUH?
I AGREE WITH MR. HANLON'S
THEORIES ON FAMILY,
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU MEAN.
THE ONLY THING
HANLON LIKES ABOUT FAMILY
IS THE PROCREATING PART.
HE SPENDS MILLIONS
BUILDING THIS PLAYGROUND...
AND PROCLAIMS FAMILIES NOW HAVE
A REASON TO VACATION TOGETHER.
AND YOU DON'T THINK
THEY DO?
AT A CASINO?
JAROD, PEOPLE WHO NEVER EVEN
DREAMED OF GAMBLING NOW THINK
IT'S SANCTIONED BY GOD.
ADD A FEW FLASHY ARCADES,
EVEN THE DAMN KIDS
GO HOME BROKE.
DON'T LET HANLON FOOL YOU.
HE MAY TALK
THE NEW CORPORATE ATTITUDE
IN THIS TOWN--
DEEP DOWN,
HE'S STILL OLD VEGAS.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
I'M SORRY IT TOOK ME
SO LONG TO GET HERE, MAGGIE.
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Door Opens ]
VISITING HOURS
ARE OVER AT 8:00.
[ Woman On P.A. ]
DR. RYAN TO O.R.
I THOUGHT
SHE WAS ALL ALONE.
WELL...
SHE'S NOT ALONE
ANYMORE.
NO OFFENSE, UH--
SHE ISN'T GOING
TO WAKE UP.
I KNOW.
BUT IT DOESN'T MEAN
SHE CAN'T HEAR ME.
MY NAME'S JAROD.
OH.
NAME'S BUDDY.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
IF-IF ANYTHING
HAPPENS TO HER,
WILL YOU PAGE ME?
I DIDN'T MEAN TO...
SOUND COLD BEFORE, BUT...
I'VE LEARNED NOT TO
GET TOO ATTACHED.
BUT IT IS NICE TO KNOW...
SOMEONE GIVES A DAMN.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
MISS PARKER,
WHAT ARE WE DOING HERE?
SAYING HELLO
TO AN OLD FRIEND.
HEY, I KNOW YOU'RE EXCITED
TO SEE ME. JUST KEEP IT
IN YOUR PANTS, VITO.
SYDNEY,
SAY HELLO TO JOHNNY.
JOHNNY'S BROTHER
HACKED INTO
THE COMPUTER PROFILES...
AT ONE OF OUR
SATELLITE COMPANIES
IN CHICAGO.
NOW HE'S SERVING
10 HARD IN JOLIET.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
HE'S WORKING A CON
IN A CASINO.
THIS FACE?
HE'S NOT A CON.
HE'S NOT THE TYPE.
HE IS EVERY TYPE.
FIND HIM FOR ME.
PASS.
MMM.
NOT AN OPTION.
BECAUSE, YOU KNOW,
I HEARD THAT
AT 3:00 TOMORROW,
YOU'RE SHIPPING OUT
A BOATLOAD OF-- [ Whispering ]
STOLEN CARS TO VENEZUELA.
NOW, IF YOU DON'T WANT
THE PORT AUTHORITY ALL OVER
YOUR LITTLE BOAT, WELL--
YOU WOULDN'T.
WANNA BET?
FIFTY THOUSAND
FOR INFORMATION.
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
[ Applause ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Emcee ]
THANKS, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
YOU'VE BEEN
A TERRIFIC AUDIENCE TONIGHT.
HEY.
IF YOU'RE NOT STAYING
AT OUR FABULOUS HOTEL,
PLEASE DRIVE SAFELY.
WELL, WELCOME
TO THE HEARTBREAK HOTEL.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
YOU SHOULD BE ON STAGE.
OH, NO.
THERE'S NO MORE STAGE
FOR THE KING.
THE CASINO FIRED ME.
I'M SORRY.
DID IT HAVE SOMETHING TO DO
WITH THAT BIRD THING?
- BIRD THING?
- THE... GOOSE.
[ Snickers ]
NO. NO, THEY SAID
THEY HAD HAD COMPLAINTS
ABOUT THE SHOW.
SO I PUT ON
20, 30 POUNDS.
YOU THINK IT'S EASY
BEING THE IDOL OF MILLIONS?
I WOULD GUESS NO.
YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT IT ISN'T.
I SACRIFICED EVERYTHING.
I DID IT 'CAUSE I LOVED IT.
IT'S WHAT
THE PEOPLE WANTED.
I JUST WISH SOME OF
THOSE CASINO BIGWIGS
COULD SPEND ONE HOUR...
WEARING THE CAPE--
JUST ONE HOUR.
THEY'D WALK AWAY
SINGING A DIFFERENT TUNE,
I GUARAN-DAMN-TEE YOU.
WELL, COULDN'T YOU GET A JOB
AT ANOTHER CASINO?
NO. NO, BUDDY BOY.
AFTER 24 YEARS
OF MAKING PEOPLE SMILE,
SINGING THE SONGS AND...
SPREADING
THE GOOD VIBRATIONS,
I'M AFRAID IT'S
THE END OF THE LINE
FOR THE KING.
NO, WE-- WE HAD
ONE HELL OF A RIDE THOUGH.
DIDN'T WE?
I BET YOU DID.
LOOK, I-- I'M SORRY.
I'M SPILLING MY GUTS,
AND I DON'T EVEN
KNOW YOUR NAME.
JAROD.
FELSON.
BERNIE BAXLEY.
WELL, IT'S NICE TO MEET YOU,
THANKS.
JAROD?
I'M SCARED.
OF WHAT?
HIM.
[ Phone Rings ]
- SYDNEY.
- HELLO, SYDNEY.
JAROD.
GOOD TO HEAR FROM YOU.
IT'S BEEN A WHILE.
WHERE ARE YOU CALLING FROM?
YOU'LL FIGURE THAT OUT
SOONER OR LATER.
- I'M COUNTING ON LATER.
- COUNTING ON OR BETTING ON?
YOU ARE SO WELL READ.
YOU KNOW, IT'S SUCH A PLEASURE
TO HAVE THE FREEDOM TO READ
WHATEVER I WANT THESE DAYS.
WHY THE GAMES, JAROD?
IT'S IN THE MAIL.
JAROD?
[ Dial Tone ]
[ Imitating Monkey Hooting ]
[ Jarod ]
I'M HAVING TROUBLE UNDERSTANDING
THE ACCOUNT TOTALS FROM JULY.
GUY EVEN WORKS
ON HIS DAY OFF.
YOU PAY ME
TO LOCATE DISCREPANCIES,
AND I CAN'T RECONCILE
THE FIGURES AGAINST LAST YEAR,
SPECIFICALLY JULY.
- JUST SET IT ASIDE.
- SET IT ASIDE?
JAROD, THERE'S A REASON
THOSE NUMBERS DON'T MATCH.
ONE OF OUR SHOWGIRLS
WAS ATTACKED
IN THE PARKING GARAGE.
OUR REVENUE DROPPED 30%
FOR THREE DAYS.
IT WAS AN ANOMALY.
[ Morgan ]
NOT TO MENTION
A PUBLICITY NIGHTMARE.
FORTUNATELY,
THE MEGABUSTER JACKPOT
HIT TWO DAYS LATER...
AND EVERYBODY
CAME BACK.
SOMETIMES LADY LUCK
EVEN SMILES ON THE HOUSE.
[ Hanlon Chuckling ]
[ Ivy ]
THANKS FOR THE ESCORT,
MR. FELSON.
NONE OF US
WALK ALONE ANYMORE.
NOT SINCE MAGGIE.
MAGGIE.
SHE WAS THE WOMAN
THAT WAS ATTACKED.
RIGHT.
YOU KNEW HER?
WELL, I'D SEEN HER
IN THE SHOW AND AROUND--
BACKSTAGE, YOU KNOW.
I READ IN THE PAPER
THERE WAS NO EVIDENCE
OF A ROBBERY.
NO.
THE NIGHT IT HAPPENED,
THE SHOWROOM
WAS COMPLETELY PACKED.
IT WAS
THE FOURTH OF JULY.
MAGGIE
WAS SO HAPPY.
SHE'D JUST LANDED
THE LEAD IN A BIG SHOW
IN ATLANTIC CITY.
MAGGIE WAS LEAVING TOWN?
YEAH, I GUESS SO.
I KNOW I WOULD.
GOD, IT HAPPENED
RIGHT HERE.
- GARDENIAS.
- EXCUSE ME?
UH, MAGGIE ALWAYS WORE
A GARDENIA IN HER HAIR.
I KNOW IT SOUNDS STRANGE,
BUT...
EVERY TIME I PASS THIS SPOT,
I SWEAR I CAN SMELL GARDENIAS.
LISTEN, THANKS.
SURE.
DRIVE SAFE.
THANK YOU.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Young Jarod ]
THIS IS WEIRD, SYDNEY.
THIS DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
I MADE IT INSIDE.
SHE DOESN'T HEAR ME.
THE HALLWAY'S DARK.
IT SMELLS LIKE...
FLOWERS.
I ROUND A CORNER.
TO WHERE?
THE KITCHEN.
I'M GETTING CLOSER.
I KNOW THEY MADE HER
DO THINGS THAT SHE
DIDN'T WANT TO DO.
DID SHE DO SOMETHING WRONG?
KEEP GOING, JAROD.
NOW FOCUS ON THE KILLER
AND NOT THE VICTIM.
IS THE WOMAN ON THE BED
HER OLD SELF
OR HER NEW SELF?
THEY ARE THE SAME PERSON.
SHE DOESN'T THINK SO.
[ Sydney ]
YOU HAVE WHAT YOU NEED
TO COMPLETE THE SIMULATION.
[ Young Jarod ]
BUT I DON'T KNOW WHY HE'S THERE.
IS HE TRYING TO KILL NORMA JEAN
OR MARILYN?
I'M CONFUSED.
[ Sydney ]
FINISH THE SIMULATION.
[ Young Jarod ]
IT JUST SEEMS SO UNFAIR.
NO ONE
SHOULD HAVE TO DIE ALONE.
SOMETHING'S WRONG
WITH THIS PICTURE.
WITH THIS PICTURE TOO,
SYDNEY.
SOMEBODY'S LUCK
JUST RAN OUT.
[ Bell Dings ]
THANKS FOR THE ESCORT,
MR. FELSON.
IT WAS MY PLEASURE.
NOW, YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY SURE
THAT YOU DON'T KNOW WHO THIS
MAN IN THE YELLOW HAT WAS?
SORRY.
MY CAR'S RIGHT HERE.
WELL,
HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
THANKS.
THIS WAS JUST DELIVERED.
COME ON, SYDNEY.
WE HAVE
A PLANE TO CATCH.
PACKIN' UP, HUH?
GOTTA STAY MOBILE, SON.
YOU KNOW, I WAS THINKIN'
ABOUT HEADIN' BACK EAST.
YOU KNOW, TRY BRANSON.
VEGAS HAS CHANGED,
YOU KNOW.
NOT MUCH
IN A CITY LIKE THIS
FOR AN OLD DOG LIKE ME.
THANKS.
OH, THAT...
IS AN OFFICIAL PIECE...
OF GRACELAND
MEMORABILIA.
WELL,
IT'S VERY NICE.
[ Sighs ]
OH, KID, YOU KNOW,
YOU SHOULD SEE THE HOUSE
IN PERSON.
IT'S, UH-- THE KING
NAMED IT FOR HIS MAMA.
PEOPLE TALK ABOUT
HOW ELVIS LET HIMSELF GO
THERE NEAR THE END,
HOW HE STOPPED CARING
ABOUT THE PEOPLE,
ABOUT THE MUSIC.
TO ME,
IT WAS JUST THE OPPOSITE.
THE OPPOSITE?
YEAH.
HE CARED TOO MUCH.
HE RAN SO FAST,
SO QUICK,
HE DIDN'T HAVE ANYTHING LEFT
TO FINISH THE RACE.
TOO BAD I WON'T BE ABLE
TO FINISH IT FOR HIM.
YOU NEVER KNOW, BERNIE.
SOMETIMES A CHANGE OF SCENERY
CAN DO YOU GOOD.
MAYBE.
[ Pager Beeping ]
[ Monitor Beeping ]
IT'S OKAY, MAGGIE.
YOU'RE NOT ALONE.
[ Monitor: Sustained Tone ]
[ Monitor Clicks Off ]
IT'S A HUNDRED GRAND.
- THAT WAS NOT THE ARRANGEMENT.
- ACTUALLY, SYDNEY, IT WAS.
YOUR BOY IS IN
THE MARQUIS CASINO IN VEGAS.
IT'S ALWAYS A PLEASURE
TAKING WHITE COLLAR
TO THE CLEANERS.
[ Miss Parker
Chuckles ]
I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
I BROUGHT 200,000 WITH ME.
WHO KNEW YOU'D BE
SUCH A CHEAP DATE?
COME ON, SYD.
WE'RE GOING TO LAS VEGAS,
A PLACE
WHERE MAYBE EVEN YOU
COULD GET LUCKY.
[ Line Rings ]
[ Woman ]
HOSPITAL ADMINISTRATION.
CAN YOU HOLD, PLEASE?
[ Jarod ]
UH, YES, I'LL HOLD.
YES, I WOULD LIKE TO ARRANGE
TO PAY MAGGIE BLAIRE'S
HOSPITAL BILLS.
THEY HAVE?
COULD YOU TELL ME
BY WHOM?
THANK YOU.
[ Line Disconnects ]
I THOUGHT
YOU'D COME.
I WANTED
TO PAY MY RESPECTS.
JUST LIKE YOU PAID
FOR MAGGIE'S
HOSPITAL BILLS...
AND FOR THIS FUNERAL?
YOU FOUND THE VIDEOTAPE,
DIDN'T YOU?
WHAT?
THE REAL SECURITY TAPE
FROM THE NIGHT
OF THE ATTACK.
THE ONE
THAT PETER MADE SURE
THE POLICE NEVER SAW.
IT SHOWS MAGGIE
LEAVING THE MARQUIS
WITH YOUR HUSBAND.
THEY WERE HAVING AN AFFAIR,
WEREN'T THEY?
WHO ARE YOU?
SOMEBODY WHO DOESN'T
BELIEVE THAT MAGGIE
DESERVED HER FATE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO PRETEND
LIKE IT'S NOT HAPPENING ANYMORE.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HE DOESN'T MEAN TO HURT ME.
YES, HE DOES.
THIS IS YOUR HUSBAND'S
RAP SHEET.
YOU'RE NOT THE FIRST PERSON
THAT HE'S HURT.
AND UNLESS HE'S STOPPED,
MAGGIE'S NOT GONNA BE
THE LAST PERSON HE KILLS.
MY GOD.
KITTY... I'M HERE
BECAUSE I WANT TO HELP YOU.
I CAN STOP HIM...
IF YOU HELP ME.
NO. NO, I--
I CAN'T DO THAT.
WHEN I TOLD HIM
THAT MAGGIE WAS DEAD AND THAT
I KNEW WHAT HAD HAPPENED,
H-HE LOST IT.
HE SAID HE'D KILL ME
IF I TOLD ANYONE.
AND THEN HE JUST HIT ME
AGAIN... AND AGAIN--
[ Sobbing ]
AND AGAIN.
WHY DID HE STOP?
THE PHONE RANG.
KITTY, ONE DAY
THE PHONE'S NOT GONNA RING.
MR. HANLON.
JAROD FELSON.
I'VE DISCOVERED
A SERIOUS PROBLEM,
AND I'D LIKE
TO DISCUSS IT WITH YOU
ONE-ON-ONE.
SAY TOMORROW MORNING,
AROUND 10:00?
IVY, IT'S MR. FELSON.
I WAS WONDERING IF YOU
COULD DO ME A FAVOR.
[ Speaking German ]
HELLO?
PETER.
JAROD FELSON.
JAROD. WHAT'S UP?
I'VE DISCOVERED
AN EVEN LARGER PROBLEM
THAN BEFORE.
- IS IT DAVIS AGAIN?
- NO.
BUT IT'S BIG,
SOMETHING YOU NEED TO HANDLE...
PERSONALLY.
CAN YOU MEET ME
TOMORROW MORNING,
AROUND 10:00?
ABSOLUTELY.
I'LL SEE YOU THERE.
SO, WHAT ARE YOU,
ABOUT A 38?
WHAT?
WAIST.
UH, 30-- 36.
SEÑOR JAROD,
FIVE NIGHTS
AND YOU DON'T SLEEP.
[ Chuckles ]
HMM?
TOO MUCH TO DO, BLANCA.
NOT ENOUGH HOURS IN THE DAY.
JORGE!
¿HAS LEÍDO ESTE LIBRO?
SI.
MUCHO.
TENGO CINCO NIÑOS.
¡BLANCA, PERFECTO!
¿QUIÉN ES EL HOMBRE
EN EL SOMBRERO AMARILLO?
MMM.
NO SÉ, SEÑOR.
NO SÉ.
[ Sighs ]
GRACIAS.
¿BLANCA?
¿SÍ?
WOULD YOU DO ME A FAVOR?
PETER, COME ON.
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
WHAT'S THIS ABOUT?
IT'S ABOUT A HUNDRED GRAND
WALKING OUT OF THIS CASINO
RIGHT UNDER YOUR VERY NOSE.
MR. HANLON!
FROM JAROD FELSON.
HE SAID HE'D MEET YOU
IN THE SECURITY BAY
AS SOON AS HE CAN.
[ Jarod ] SOMEBODY
HAS BEEN DOUBLE-COUNTING
THE CASH OUTLAYS.
BASED ON MY FINDINGS,
OVER A HUNDRED GRAND
IS BEING SKIMMED OFF THE TOP...
EVERY TUESDAY
CASH PICKUP.
YOU THINK DAVIS
WAS BEHIND THIS?
I'M NOT SURE.
BUT IT'S BIGGER
THAN ONE GUY.
AN ACCOUNTING SCAM
TIED INTO
THE ARMORED CAR COURIER.
FOR EVERY $300,000
THAT'S DEPOSITED ON PAPER,
ANOTHER HUNDRED GRAND
IS BEING DROPPED OFF
AT A SECOND LOCALE.
BUT IF WE KEEP
THIS SCAM GOING,
WE FIND OUT
WHERE THE LOCALE IS,
WE CAN BRING DOWN
EVERYBODY THAT'S BEEN
RIPPING OFF THE MARQUIS.
WHY DON'T WE JUST
BRING IN THE COPS?
PETER,
THINK ABOUT THIS.
IF YOU PULL THIS OFF,
YOU ARE GONNA BE
STEVE HANLON'S
$20 MILLION HERO.
THE MARQUIS. NOW.
YES, MA'AM.
WHY ME?
I'M THE NEW FACE AROUND HERE.
NOBODY'S GONNA TRUST ME.
BUT IF THEIR COURIER
IS GREETED BY
THE PRESIDENT OF THE CASINO,
HE'S GONNA PLAY
RIGHT INTO YOUR HANDS.
IT'S SHOWTIME.
WHERE'S MR. DAVIS?
[ Clears Throat ]
MR. DAVIS WORKED FOR ME
IN MORE WAYS THAN ONE.
I'M PETER MORGAN.
I RUN THE MARQUIS.
IT'S BUSINESS AS USUAL.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
SURE.
BUSINESS AS USUAL.
TAKE THE SKIM TO THE DROP.
DEPOSIT THE REST IN THE BANK.
WE'LL SEE YOU
NEXT TUESDAY.
OKAY.
[ Imitates Elvis Presley ]
WELL, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THAT WAS EXCITING!
GUY FELL FOR
EVERYTHING I SAID.
HE MUST BE A COMPLETE IDIOT.
[ Sighs ]
FIND HIM.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Morgan ]
STEVE!
- I DIDN'T THINK YOU'D BE HERE.
- SURPRISE.
- YOU WON'T BELIEVE
WHAT I'VE BEEN DOING.
- BET ME.
BUSINESS AS USUAL.
TAKE THE SKIM TO THE DROP.
DEPOSIT THE REST IN THE BANK.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TUESDAY.
[ Bernie ]
OKAY.
STEVE, I WASN'T REALLY
TAKING THE MONEY. WE WERE--
THERE'S A GREAT DEAL
OF UNREPORTED CASH
LEAVING THIS CASINO.
I KNOW!
AND, UH, WE WERE--
AND A GREAT DEAL OF CASH
IS GOING IN YOUR
SWISS BANK ACCOUNT.
- I DON'T HAVE A SWISS ACCOUNT.
- OH.
ELECTRONIC TRANSFERS...
FOR $4.6 MILLION.
THAT IS YOUR SIGNATURE,
ISN'T IT?
I DIDN'T DO THIS.
TELL HIM.
TELL HIM THE TRUTH.
I AM SORRY, MR. HANLON.
I'M SORRY
I DIDN'T CATCH THIS SOONER.
AND THE FIGURE IS CLOSER
TO 4.8.
EVERY INSTINCT IN MY GUT
TOLD ME YOU WERE BAD NEWS.
STEVE, I DIDN'T DO
ANYTHING WRONG--
[ Groans, Panting ]
FELSON, DAMN IT!
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
I DIDN'T DO
ANYTHING WRONG.
NEITHER DID MAGGIE BLAIRE.
DETECTIVE BENSON,
HOMICIDE.
I'M LOOKING FOR
A PETER MORGAN.
HE'S IN A MEETING RIGHT NOW.
[ Thud, Crash ]
I THINK HE'S ASKING
FOR A RAISE.
[ Blow Lands ]
♪♪ [ Whistling ]
[ Snapping Fingers ]
[ Bell Rings ]
[ Coins Falling Into Tray ]
♪♪ [ Continues Whistling ]
♪♪ [ Slows, Stops ]
JAROD!
TAKE THE REAR!
DON'T RUN! PLEASE!
THERE'S NOWHERE TO GO.
[ Man On Radio ]
SECURITY ALERT. POOL AREA.
MY LUCKY DAY!
[ Approaching Footsteps
Running ]
WE GOT YOUR RADIO CALL,
MR. FELSON.
IS THERE A PROBLEM?
YES, THERE IS.
A COUPLE OF GRIFTERS
TRYING A ROULETTE SCAM.
CALL THE L.V.P.D.
AND HAVE THEM PICKED UP.
LET GO OF ME.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO
STRIP-SEARCH THIS ONE.
SHE COULD BE PALMING CHIPS.
OH, YOU BASTARD!
I'M JUST DOING MY JOB,
MA'AM.
HEAD OF SECURITY, YOU KNOW.
- I WILL GET YOU.
- YOU WANNA BET?
TAILS.
COME ON, LADY.
NOT A PAPER CLIP.
NO TRASH, NO LINT.
NOTHING BUT THIS.
AND THE USUAL.
SEÑOR SYDNEY?
DÍGAME.
PARA USTED.
"TO THE MAN
IN THE YELLOW HAT.
FROM THE MONKEY
WHO GOT AWAY."
ALL RIGHT.
[ Chuckles ]
YOU'RE REALLY GONNA RELEASE
HIM BACK INTO THE WILD?
THAT'S THE PLAN.
LIVING CREATURES,
THEY DON'T BELONG
IN CAPTIVITY.
[ Hooting Quietly ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Mews ]