- PREVIOUSLY ON THE PRETENDER.
- MAMA!
- THEY'RE TRYING TO HURT HER!
- MAMA, NO!
- [ Gunshot ]
- BRING JAROD BACK.
- MY FATHER WANTS ME TO DO IT.
- I'M NOT AFRAID OF YOUR FATHER.
I HAVE REASON TO BELIEVE
MY MOTHER MAY HAVE RESCUED
THESE CHILDREN.
[ Fly Buzzing ]
YOU KNOW, GATOR HEAVEN HAS
THE FINEST GATOR WRESTLING...
IN ALL OF SOUTH FLORIDA.
IN FACT, WE PRODUCE
MORE WRESTLING CHAMPIONS THAN
ANY OTHER ROADSIDE ATTRACTION.
- THAT'S JAROD?
- CAN YOU BELIEVE HE MASTERED
GATOR WRESTLING IN A WEEK?
A REGULAR TARZAN.
GAVE 'EM ALL NICKNAMES TOO.
CALLED THE ONE WITH THE SHARPEST
TEETH MISS PARKER.
BEEN GONE ABOUT A MONTH.
DID HE LEAVE ANYTHING BEHIND?
LIKE A RED NOTEBOOK?
HE LEFT SOMETHIN' BETTER.
SAID THIS WAS FOR YOU.
BEAUTIFUL.
GENUINE NATIVE ART.
HANDCRAFTED BY THE TRIBE.
IN TAIWAN?
EASTERN TRIBE.
LOVELY, JAROD.
ANOTHER GAME.
SAID IF YOU WANTED IT,
YOU HAD TO SIGN FOR IT.
THANK YOU.
NO. JAROD SAID THE PEN
WAS FOR YOU TOO.
[ Sighs ]
[ Man ]
THERE IT IS.
NOW COME ON, BUBBA.
WE GOTTA RELOCATE
THIS PREHISTORIC HANDBAG...
BEFORE THE HURRICANE EVAC.
REPORTS GOT IT COMIN' IN
PRETTY FAST TOO.
IT'S STILL A FEW HOURS OFF.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE A DAY
THIS BEAUTIFUL IS GONNA
TURN INTO A STORM.
WELL, IF YOU'RE IN A HURRY,
I COULD WRESTLE IT FOR YOU.
WHAT? THE GATOR?
YEAH.
YOU LOST YOUR MIND, BUBBA.
I USED TO WRESTLE
FOR THE SEMINOLES.
FLORIDA STATE?
NO. THE TRIBE.
COME HERE, GIRL.
WHOA, WHOA. WAIT A MINUTE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
THAT'S A SHE?
I KNOW THAT SMILE.
[ Man Narrating ]
MISS PARKER,
YOU'RE TO COME WITH ME.
DADDY, THE NEXT TIME
THAT YOU WANT TO SEE ME,
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SEND
THE WELCOME WAGON.
YOU'RE HERE AT MY INVITATION,
NOT YOUR FATHER'S.
YOU'VE BEEN BUSY.
I DON'T FOLLOW YOU, SIR.
I FOLLOW YOU.
WHAT WAS IN
THE SAFETY DEPOSIT BOX?
NOTHING, SIR.
LET ME REPHRASE,
MISS PARKER.
I KNOW IT WAS MOMMY'S BOX.
WHAT DID YOU FIND IN IT?
[ Wheezing ]
I WAS LOOKING FOR ANSWERS.
ABOUT WHAT?
ABOUT HOW SHE DIED.
- YOUR MOTHER SHOT HERSELF.
- DADDY.
LEAVE US, MR. RAINES.
DON'T I GET A HUG?
[ Laughs ]
BEEN TOO LONG.
SO, HOW ARE THINGS
AT THE SUMMER HOUSE?
ARE THE LEAVES COMING BACK?
SLOWLY. YOU KNOW HOW
SPRING CAN BE UP THERE.
STUBBORN. YOUR MOTHER
ALWAYS GOT IMPATIENT.
I DON'T REMEMBER
THAT ABOUT HER.
BUT I--
I DO REMEMBER THIS.
YOU LOOK LIKE HER.
WATCHING YOU,
IN SOME WAYS
SHE NEVER LEFT.
DADDY, I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO MY MOTHER.
- I'M DISAPPOINTED IN YOU.
- YOU'RE DISAPPOINTED IN ME?
DON'T TELL ME
YOU BELIEVE THIS CRAP.
BUT I REMEMBER
THAT THANKSGIVING!
THE FIGHT THAT YOU HAD.
AND A FEW MONTHS LATER,
SHE WAS DEAD.
DON'T LET YOUR EMOTIONS
RUN AWAY WITH YOU.
I TAUGHT YOU BETTER.
JUST TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED.
I KILLED HER.
AT LEAST, THAT'S WHAT
I TORTURE MYSELF BELIEVING.
WHEN SOMEONE YOU LOVE
COMMITS SUICIDE,
YOU SEARCH FOR ANSWERS
TO THE MYSTERY
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE DOING NOW.
I MISS HER.
YOU WERE YOUNG. THERE'S NO WAY
YOU COULD'VE KNOWN
WHAT SHE WAS GOING THROUGH.
IT WAS A SAD TIME.
I DON'T KNOW WHY SHE LEFT US.
DON'T YOU THINK
I MISS HER TOO?
OF COURSE.
YOU CAN BELIEVE YOUR FATHER
OR JAROD. WHO'S IT GOING TO BE?
DADDY, I WANT
A NEW ASSIGNMENT.
JAROD IS SYDNEY'S MESS,
AND MR. RAINES'S.
PLEASE PUT ME
BACK IN CORPORATE.
WE HAVE OUR ARRANGEMENT.
I KNOW.
YOU WERE A QUIET,
UNCERTAIN LITTLE GIRL,
AND NOW YOU'RE THIS...
PRESENCE.
IT'S TIME
FOR MY TREASURE TO SHINE!
I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE CAPABLE OF.
DO YOU?
I DO.
AND OUR DEAL STANDS.
[ Miss Parker ]
FLORIDA?
I WAS THERE YESTERDAY.
[ Broots ]
I KNOW. YOU JUST
WEREN'T SOUTH ENOUGH.
WHILE YOU WERE AWAY,
BROOTS AND I REVISITED THE OLD
NOTEBOOK FROM THE ATLANTA SITE,
AND WE FOUND SOME CLUES.
GLOBAL COORDINATES
WRITTEN IN IT THAT LEAD US TO--
HURRICANE CASSANDRA. TOP WIND
SPEEDS OF 150 MILES PER HOUR.
[ Sydney ]
WHEN JAROD WAS IN ATLANTA,
CASSANDRA WAS JUST
A BADLY FORMED TROPICAL
DEPRESSION.
HE MUST HAVE PREDICTED
ITS COURSE.
JAROD PUT HIMSELF
IN THE PATH OF A HURRICANE?
SOMEONE FROM MARINE PATROL
IN BAHIA GRANDE IS USING
THE CENTRE'S ACCESS CODE...
TO HACK INTO DEFENSE DEPARTMENT
WEATHER SATELLITES.
IT'S THE SAME ONE I'M USING.
[ Phone Rings ]
TECH ROOM. BROOTS.
UH-- [ Clears Throat ]
NO. YES, SIR.
UH, RIGHT HERE. HOLD ON.
IT'S FOR YOU.
YES.
OF COURSE.
VERY CLEAR.
WHO WAS THAT?
IT WAS PERSONAL.
HOW FAST CAN WE
GET DOWN THERE?
UH, A COUPLE OF HOURS.
BUT THEY'RE ALREADY
STARTING TO EVACUATE
PEOPLE FROM SOUTH FLORIDA.
THEN I'LL GO WITH SAM.
MISS PARKER, IT ISN'T SAFE.
IF JAROD'S REALLY
ON THAT ISLAND, I HAVE HIM
RIGHT WHERE WE WANT HIM.
- WHO WAS ON THAT CALL?
- MR. RAINES.
[ Helicopter Approaching ]
[ TV Announcer ]
RESIDENTS AND MERCHANTS
OF BAHIA GRANDE...
ARE FRANTICALLY BOARDING UP
WINDOWS AND PACKING CARS
THIS AFTERNOON.
CASSANDRA IS EXPECTED
IN FOUR TO FIVE HOURS,
AROUND 7:00 P.M. THIS EVENING.
ISLANDERS ARE BEING REMINDED--
I'M GONNA BE OUT--
OUT FRONT.
BUT DON'T WORRY, SIMONE.
WE'LL GET YOU TO THE DOCTOR
REAL SOON.
HEY!
BATTENING DOWN THE HATCHES?
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
MY CRACKER BUTT IS GONNA
SELL THIS PLACE AND MOVE
TO OKLAHOMA AFTER THIS ONE.
FOR WHAT? TORNADOES?
OKAY. CALIFORNIA.
EARTHQUAKES?
SOMEWHERE 'SIDES HERE.
HOW'S SHE DOING?
FEVER'S NOT BREAKING.
[ Sighs ]
YOU BETTER HURRY UP.
JAROD, ARE YOU SURE
YOU SHOULD'VE PULLED SIMONE
OUT OF THAT FACILITY?
THEY WERE GOING TO SHIP HER
BACK TO HAITI.
I CAN'T BELIEVE BARTLETT
WOULD DO THAT-- JUST LET
HER FOLKS DIE IN A STORM.
PEOPLE WILL DO ALL KINDS
OF THINGS FOR MONEY.
I'LL SEE THAT HE GETS PAID.
JAROD, FORGET ABOUT HIM.
COME GO WITH US. I, UH--
WHAT IS IT?
I'M JUST--
I'M NOT VERY GOOD
AROUND SICK PEOPLE.
I WATCHED MY OLD MAN
HAVE A HEART ATTACK.
I KNEW HE NEEDED
C.P.R. OR SOMETHING,
BUT I FROZE.
I JUST--
I WATCHED HIM GO.
I CAN'T HANDLE
THE RESPONSIBILITY.
THE ANALGESIC I GAVE HER
SHOULD HELP WITH HER FEVER.
ALL YOU NEED TO DO
IS DRIVE HER TO MIAMI.
THE DOCTORS
WILL TAKE OVER FROM THERE.
YOU CAN DO IT.
I TRUST YOU.
[ Sighs ]
IF YOU SAY SO.
- JAROD.
- HI.
- IT'S EMPTY.
- NO MORE CANDY.
DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
BUT I'LL GET YOU SOME MORE,
AS SOON AS WE SEE
YOUR FAMILY IN MIAMI.
I PROMISE.
[ Whispering ]
I'LL SEE YOU IN A BIT.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
ARE YOU GONNA HELP ME
WITH THIS CAGE?
I CAN'T, SIR. I JUST GOT
THIS DOWNLOAD FROM THE STATE
DEPARTMENT OF LAW ENFORCEMENT.
THEY SUSPECT THAT THE PARENTS
OF THE HAITIAN GIRL WERE KILLED
AROUND HARRISON MARSH.
THEY WANT EVIDENCE GATHERED
BEFORE CASSANDRA WASHES IT AWAY.
LET ME SEE THAT.
HMM. UH, WHY DON'T YOU
FINISH UP HERE, AND I'LL
TAKE CARE OF THIS.
- I'LL GO WITH YOU.
- NO. I CAN HANDLE IT.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Woman ] NO!
[ Man ]
I WON'T LET YOU DO IT!
[ Woman ]
DON'T! YOU'RE HURTING ME!
[ Man ]
COME BACK HERE!
[ Thunder Continues ]
- [ Creaking ]
- [ Thunderclap ]
FASTER, SAM.
OKAY. WE'RE GONNA BE LEAVING
HERE IN JUST A FEW MINUTES.
OKAY?
[ Thunder Continues ]
BOO!
DAMN IT! YOU SCARED
THE HELL OUT OF ME.
[ Shouts, Grunts ]
I'M SORRY.
HEY! HEY, BUBBA!
WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
ARE YOU GONNA STAND THERE
OR CUT ME OUT OF THIS?
CUT YOU OUT? I SPENT
A LONG TIME MAKING THAT THING.
YOU RIGGED THIS NET?
THINK OF IT AS A BAG.
A TRASH BAG.
YOU CUT ME OUT OF THIS NOW,
OR I'LL BLOW YOU AWAY!
MOST CRIMINALS, THEY SMUGGLE
DRUGS OR STOLEN CARS.
DO IT!
YOU TRADE IN HUMAN LIFE.
YOU SMUGGLE HAITIANS,
AND THEN YOU CHARGE
THEIR FAMILIES IN MIAMI.
[ Gun Clicks ]
AND ONCE YOU GET THEM HERE,
YOU RAISE THE PRICE.
NOW THAT'S RANSOM,
PURE AND SIMPLE.
AND IF THEY CAN'T AFFORD TO PAY,
WELL, YOU JUST LET 'EM DIE
IN A STORM.
KINDA LIKE THE ONE
THAT'S COMING NOW.
YOU GOT NO PROOF
OF NOTHIN'!
I SENT IT TO THE STATE
DEPARTMENT OF LAW ENFORCEMENT.
SIMONE'S FAMILY, THEY JUST
WANTED TO START A NEW LIFE.
BUT YOU TOOK THAT
AWAY FROM THEM.
AND THAT LITTLE GIRL, SHE
DOESN'T HAVE A MOM AND DAD...
BECAUSE YOU LOCKED THEM OUT HERE
IN A SHACK TO DIE IN A STORM.
AS THE SHACK COLLAPSED
AROUND THEM,
HER PARENTS THREW THEMSELVES
ON THEIR DAUGHTER.
THEY DIED TRYING
TO SAVE HER LIFE!
DO YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO GROW UP WITHOUT PARENTS?
HEY, HEY! BUBBA, WAIT, WAIT!
YOU CAN'T LEAVE ME OUT HERE!
THIS HURRICANE'LL KILL ME!
OH, NO, IT WON'T.
YOU'RE ABOUT THREE MILES
NORTH OF THE DAMAGE PATH.
AT LEAST I THINK SO...
BUBBA.
HEY! HEY!
HEY! COME BACK HERE!
YOU CAN'T LEAVE ME HERE!
YOU'RE DEAD! YOU'RE
DEAD, YOU SON OF A-- JAROD!
[ Man On Radio ]
THIS IS THE EMERGENCY
BROADCAST SYSTEM.
HURRICANE CASSANDRA IS MAKING
LANDFALL AT THIS HOUR ALONG
THE ISLAND'S EASTERN SHORE.
WINDS ARE AT 150 MILES PER HOUR.
EVACUATION OF BAHIA GRANDE
HAS BEEN COMPLETED.
REMAINING RESIDENTS ARE ADVISED
TO SEEK SHELTER IN THE CENTER
OF A SAFE, SECURE STRUCTURE.
- I'M SORRY, JAROD.
- WHAT HAPPENED?
I GOT GOOD NEWS AND BAD.
BRIDGE IS WASHED AWAY.
POWER'S OUT.
PHONE LINES ARE DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO RIDE OUT
THE STORM HERE.
WHAT'S THE GOOD NEWS?
[ Miss Parker ]
THAT IS THE GOOD NEWS.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
PILOT HAD TO EVACUATE.
HE LOST CONTACT WITH MISS PARKER
20 MINUTES AGO.
THANK YOU FOR MAKING US
SOUTH FLORIDA'S CHOICE FOR NEWS.
FEED'S UP.
OUR TOP STORY IS--
WHO ELSE-- CASSANDRA,
WHOSE TOP WINDS HAVE NOW BEEN
UPGRADED TO 175 MILES AN HOUR.
CASSANDRA HAS VEERED
30 DEGREES NORTH-NORTHEAST,
AND IT LOOKS LIKE BAHIA GRANDE
WILL BEAR THE BRUNT
OF CASSANDRA'S FURY.
WELL, CASSANDRA
HASN'T MET MISS PARKER.
[ TV Continues, Indistinct ]
I HOPE THEY'RE ALL RIGHT.
[ Cork Pops ]
AFTER ALL THOSE DEAD ENDS,
ALL I NEEDED WAS A LITTLE
HELP FROM CASSANDRA.
TO WOMEN.
HELL HATH NO FURY--
THAT ISN'T GOOD
FOR YOUR ULCER.
NEITHER ARE YOU.
DON'T UNDERESTIMATE
THE POWER OF CASSANDRA.
HER WINDS ARE PROBABLY PEAKING
AT 175 MILES PER HOUR.
- THIS PLACE'LL HOLD.
- JUST IN CASE IT DOESN'T,
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
WHO MY PARENTS ARE?
TELL ME WHO I AM.
MAYBE I SHOULD SEND YOU
TO EVERY Y.M.C.A.
IN THE COUNTRY FIRST.
OR LOCK YOU IN THE BATES MOTEL
WITH SYDNEY AND BROOTS.
THIS IS ABOUT THAT STRIP SEARCH
IN LAS VEGAS, ISN'T IT?
COME ON. YOU'VE GOT ME.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME?
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE WASTED YOUR
TIME HELPING THE DOWNTRODDEN.
I HAVEN'T WASTED
MY FREEDOM.
JAROD, YOU WERE
WRESTLING AN ALLIGATOR.
[ Laughing ]
SO YOU GOT
THE MEDICAL REPORT.
I HAVE WHAT YOU FORGOT.
YOU DIDN'T COME HERE
JUST TO RETRIEVE ME.
YOU WANT ANSWERS.
I HAVE EVERYTHING I NEED.
DADDY'S GOING TO BE THRILLED.
BUT DADDY DOESN'T GIVE YOU
WHAT YOU WANT NOW, DOES HE?
WHAT DID DADDY TELL YOU
ABOUT YOUR MOTHER'S...
SUICIDE?
THAT'S ENOUGH!
I BET IT WASN'T THE TRUTH.
YEAH, WELL, THE TRUTH IS
YOU'RE A LIAR! ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
YOU FAKED THAT MEDICAL REPORT.
I WOULDN'T FAKE
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
I DIDN'T WANT
TO HAVE TO TELL YOU,
BUT I COULDN'T WITHHOLD
A KEY TO YOUR PAST.
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Scoffs ]
NICE TRY.
YOU'RE SO IN CONTROL.
SO AHEAD OF THE GAME,
AREN'T YOU?
WELL, NOT ANYMORE.
NOW I MAKE THE RULES.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Grunting, Muttering ]
HOLD ON.
YOU'RE SUCH A GOOD, GOOD GIRL.
HOW MANY MERIT BADGES
DID THIS GET YOU?
YOU DON'T THINK
THAT RESCUING CHILDREN
IS A GOOD IDEA?
YOUR MOTHER CERTAINLY
THOUGHT IT WAS.
[ Thunderclap ]
THE LEADING EDGE
JUST PASSED.
THE EYEWALL SHOULD HIT
IN ABOUT 17 MINUTES.
HONEY, WAKE UP.
THAT'S THE WORST PART.
- JAROD, I CAN'T WAKE HER.
- LET ME TAKE A LOOK AT HER.
- SAM CAN DO IT.
- SAM IS NOT A DOCTOR.
I-- I CAN BE. PLEASE!
[ Thunder Continues ]
SIMONE? IT'S ME.
SIMONE.
TALK TO ME. COME ON.
SIMONE? SIMONE?
IF HE TRIES ANYTHING,
SHOOT HIM IN THE FOOT.
SIMONE? SIMONE,
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Woman ]
NO!
[ Man ]
LISTEN TO ME!
STOP!
I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE DOING!
YOU'RE HURTING ME!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
COME BACK HERE!
[ Creaking ]
SHE'S DIPPING IN AND OUT
OF CONSCIOUSNESS.
I NEED TO GET
HER FEVER DOWN.
THE INFECTION IS SPREADING.
SHE NEEDS PENICILLIN.
I CAN GET SOME
FROM THE FIRST AID KITS
AT THE BOATHOUSE.
- ACROSS THE ISLAND?
- AFTER THE STORM, WHILE YOU'RE
ON YOUR WAY TO BLUE COVE,
I'LL MAKE SURE SHE GETS
THE BEST SPECIALISTS.
THERE IS NO TIME.
SHE COULD GO INTO SEPTIC
SHOCK OR A COMA.
I NEED TO GET HER
THE PENICILLIN.
THE EYE SHOULD BE HERE
IN A FEW MINUTES.
THAT WILL GIVE US
ABOUT 20 MINUTES OF CALM.
- HOW CAN YOU BE SO SURE?
- JAROD USED TO BE A WEATHERMAN
IN PUERTO RICO.
MAMA, PAPA,
POUVEZ-VOUS ME VOIR?
SIMONE, TOUT VA BIEN.
TOUT VA BIEN.
- WHAT'S SHE SAYING?
- SHE'S LOOKING FOR THE SKY.
HER MOTHER TOLD HER
BEFORE SHE DIED THAT SHE WOULD
LOOK AFTER HER FROM THE SKY,
THAT THE SUN AND THE MOON
WOULD BE HER EYES.
I'M GOING TO THE BOATHOUSE.
ARE YOU GOING
TO LET HER DIE?
SAM, CUFF HIM.
I'M GOING WITH YOU.
PAT, TRY TO KEEP HER
TEMPERATURE UNDER CONTROL
WHILE I'M GONE.
I'M COUNTING ON YOU.
SO IS SHE.
[ Thunder Continues ]
YOU'RE DOING THE RIGHT THING.
CALL ME MOTHER TERESA
FROM NOW ON.
- IT DOESN'T SUIT YOU.
- WHAT?
THIS FACADE YOU PUT UP.
YOU TRY TO ACT LIKE YOUR FATHER,
BUT HE'S NOT WHO YOU ARE.
THIS IS BUSINESS,
JAROD, NOT PERSONAL.
NO MATTER HOW HARD YOU TRY
AND MAKE IT THAT WAY.
IT'S PERSONAL TO ME.
THEN WHY CAN'T YOU LEAVE
MY MOTHER OUT OF IT?
BECAUSE SHE TRIED TO RESCUE ME
FROM YOUR FATHER.
- [ Tree Falls ]
- [ Tires Skidding ]
WHAT NOW?
IT'S LESS THAN A MILE.
IF WE MOVE FAST,
WE'LL BEAT THE EYE.
IT SURE WOULD BE
A LOT EASIER WITHOUT THESE.
YOU TRY ANYTHING,
AND I'LL PUT A BULLET
THROUGH YOUR KNEE.
I THOUGHT IT WAS MY FOOT.
FEVER'S NOT BREAKING.
COME ON, KIDDO.
WORK WITH ME.
WHY ARE YOU AFTER JAROD?
SHUT UP AND WATCH THE KID.
- I NEED MORE ICE.
- I'LL GET IT.
[ Quiet Muttering ]
JAROD, WHAT'S TAKING SO LONG?
I'VE GOT IT. THERE'S
STILL PLENTY OF TIME.
SIMONE'S GONNA BE OKAY.
HONEY, I'M HOME.
[ TV Announcer ]
CASSANDRA, CLOCKED AT SPEEDS
UP TO 160 MILES AN HOUR--
YOU HEARD FROM HER?
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
NO. I'M CONCERNED.
SO AM I.
OH, YOU ARE?
MR. RAINES
ORDERED HER INTO THAT.
DO YOU HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH RAINES?
HE IS OUT OF CONTROL.
RAINES ISN'T. JAROD IS.
TORMENTING MY DAUGHTER
WITH LIES ABOUT HER MOTHER.
LIES?
YOU SAW HER LAST.
YOU KNEW HER CONDITION.
HER ONLY OPTION WAS SUICIDE.
MRS. PARKER, GOD REST HER SOUL,
WAS MANIC-DEPRESSIVE.
HER MARRIAGE
WAS FALLING APART,
AND, OF COURSE, THERE WAS
THE QUESTION OF HER BEATING.
EXACTLY WHAT DID SHE SAY
ABOUT THAT?
I CAN'T DISCLOSE THAT.
BUT YOU KNOW PSYCHIATRISTS,
MR. PARKER.
WE WRITE EVERYTHING DOWN.
SO DO I.
YOUR WIFE WAS MY PATIENT.
THE DETAILS OF HER SESSIONS
ARE PRIVILEGED.
I HAVE PRIVILEGES, SYDNEY.
I'M WELL AWARE OF THAT.
[ Mr. Parker On Speaker ]
ANYTHING ELSE, DOCTOR?
[ Sydney ]
NO.
[ Jarod ]
THAT ROPE WAS TOUGHER
THAN I THOUGHT.
LOOKS LIKE IT COST YOU
A MOLAR.
TWO. NOW SHUT UP!
YOU NEVER HAD TO CLEAN UP
ONE OF YOUR MESSES,
HAVE YOU, JAROD?
YOU SHOULD'VE MET THAT COP
YOU FRAMED IN MIAMI.
- WHAT A WHINER!
- I TOLD YOU TO SHUT
YOUR PIE HOLE!
LISTEN... GOOBER.
THE CENTRE WILL PAY YOU--
SHUT UP! SHUT UP!
I DON'T GIVE A DAMN
ABOUT THE CENTRE.
SOON AS THIS STORM
IS OUTTA MY FACE,
WE'RE TAKIN' A LITTLE
BOAT RIDE OUT TO THE SWAMP.
BUT I'M THE ONLY ONE
COMIN' BACK.
TONIGHT YOU TWO
SLEEP WITH THE MANATEES.
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Simone Moaning ]
MAMA, PAPA,
POUVEZ-VOUS ME VOIR?
HEY, HEY. SHH, SHH, SHH.
SHE-- SHE CAN'T
KEEP ANY FOOD DOWN.
LET ME MAKE HER SOME JUICE.
THE VITAMINS WILL DO HER GOOD.
[ Thunder Continues ]
HEY!
YOU SCARED ME.
STOP WASTIN' TIME.
YOUR CRUSADE FOR THE LITTLE GUY
IS BACKFIRING.
HOW DOES IT FEEL
TO FACE THE CONSEQUENCES?
I SPENT AN ENTIRE LIFE
SIMULATING REALITY.
CONSEQUENCES?
THEY FEEL PRETTY GOOD.
JAROD, WHAT DID YOU MEAN
WHEN YOU SAID MY MOTHER
TRIED TO SAVE YOU?
SHE WAS PLANNING
ON SMUGGLING ME
OUT OF THE CENTRE.
YOU WERE ONE OF THE CHILDREN
SHE TRIED TO RESCUE?
SHE DIED BEFORE SHE COULD
GET TO ME OR THE OTHERS.
OTHERS?
SHE HAD A LIST
OF SEVEN CHILDREN.
THE UNLUCKY ONES.
AND WHERE DID YOU
GET THIS LIST?
THE MEDICAL REPORT
WASN'T THE ONLY THING
IN THE SAFETY DEPOSIT BOX.
THE MEDICAL REPORT IS REAL.
[ Shudders ]
I REMEMBER MY PARENTS
FIGHTING THAT NIGHT.
SHE WENT OFF THE DEEP END.
WOULDN'T EVEN WEAR
HER WEDDING RING.
IT WAS A BAD TIME
FOR MY FATHER.
HOW CAN YOU STILL TRUST HIM?
I NEVER SAW HIM HIT HER.
EVER.
[ Glass Shattering ]
[ Blow Landing ]
[ Creaking ]
I NEVER SAW ANYONE.
NOT THAT I CAN REMEMBER.
PEOPLE REPRESS MEMORIES.
ESPECIALLY TRAUMATIC ONES.
UNLESS SOMETHING
HELPS BRING THEM OUT,
LIKE A-- A SMELL...
OR A SOUND.
I USED TO SELL
POWER MEMORY TAPES
ON LATE-NIGHT CABLE.
PERHAPS
YOU MISSED THAT ONE.
LET ME HELP YOU.
THANKS FOR THE OFFER,
BUT I CAN TAKE CARE OF MYSELF.
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Loud Groaning ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Raines ]
IF YOU WERE
SO WORRIED ABOUT HER,
YOU SHOULD HAVE GONE
WITH HER.
SHE ONLY WENT
BECAUSE YOU INTIMIDATED HER.
MISS PARKER
IS DOING HER JOB.
I'M GLAD TO SEE SOMEONE IS.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
TOO MANY CIGARETTES,
NOT ENOUGH VACATIONS.
WHEN YOU WERE DR. RAINES,
YOU WERE MY COLLEAGUE.
I NEVER DETECTED
THIS OBSESSION.
I DON'T HAVE TO FOLLOW
THE HIPPOCRATIC OATH
ANYMORE.
MY ONLY DIRECTIVE
IS TO BRING JAROD BACK.
FOR THAT TO HAPPEN,
MISS PARKER NEEDS FOCUS.
SHE HAS A LOT OF ISSUES
ON HER MIND.
SHE'S ALWAYS BEEN
A CURIOUS GIRL.
TAKES AFTER HER MOTHER.
[ Broots ]
WEATHER SERVICE SAYS THE EYE
JUST PASSED THE ISLAND.
WE COULD-- WE COULD--
[ Clears Throat ]
WE COULD BE THERE
BY MORNING.
GET A JET.
COME ON, BROOTS.
WE WOULDN'T WANT ANY HARM
TO COME TO MISS PARKER.
THAT'S IT.
A LITTLE TANGERINE,
A LITTLE KEY LIME.
GOOD FOR THE SOUL.
BUT YOU'RE STILL BURNING UP.
COME ON, JAROD.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO GET SOME MORE.
LOOKING FOR THIS?
OKAY. TIME
FOR A LITTLE BOAT RIDE.
LADIES FIRST.
[ Grunts ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Grunts, Groans ]
- [ Chuckles ]
- DROP IT!
[ Laughing ]
THAT'S A FLARE GUN.
IT'S GONNA REDEFINE HEARTBURN
UNLESS YOU DROP IT.
[ Groans ]
WHERE'D YOU GET THAT?
I SNUCK IT INTO THE FIRST AID
KIT WHEN YOU WEREN'T LOOKING.
[ Panting ]
YOU WERE GONNA USE THAT ON ME.
I STILL AM.
TRY GUMMING THROUGH THIS.
AND YOU ARE GOING
TO HAVE TO DISLOCATE
A LOT MORE THAN YOUR THUMB...
TO GET THROUGH THAT.
WHY DID YOU SAVE MY LIFE?
BECAUSE... I STILL REMEMBER
THE LITTLE GIRL...
WHO GAVE ME MY FIRST KISS.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Shutter Banging ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
[ Glass Shattering ]
[ Man ]
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING!
[ Woman ]
LEAVE ME ALONE!
[ Creaking ]
- MAMA.
IT'S OKAY, SWEETHEART.
MAMA'S ALL RIGHT.
MR. RAINES.
HEY.
- HEY!
- WHAT?
DON'T YOU PEOPLE KEEP
A SPARE KEY TO THAT CAGE
AROUND HERE?
YES, WE DO.
IT'S IN THAT MIAMI HEAT
ASHTRAY ON THE DESK.
TRICK IS GETTING THERE.
LOOK, WE BOTH WANT
TO CATCH JAROD, RIGHT?
OH, YEAH.
SO YOU JUST FLIP YOUR CAGE
OVER A FEW TIMES.
YOU HELP ME CATCH HIM,
AND YOU WON'T JUST GET PAID.
I'LL MAKE SURE THAT
YOU GET A SWEET REWARD.
[ Grunting ]
PUT SOME MUSCLE INTO IT!
[ Grunts ]
YES!
[ Bird Squawking ]
AHH.
SO, WHEN DO I GET
THAT SWEET REWARD?
[ Chuckles ]
NOW.
[ Grunts ]
[ Groans ]
STORM'S CLEAR. WE'LL BE LANDING
IN FIVE, DOCTOR.
- JAROD.
- WHERE'S MISS PARKER?
I SAID, WHERE IS SHE?
SHE HAD A DATE.
DROP IT AND STAND
AGAINST THE WALL!
SHE NEEDS THIS.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO, SAM?
YOU GONNA KILL ME?
I DON'T THINK YOU HAVE
THE AUTHORIZATION TO DO THAT.
- [ Glass Shattering ]
- WHOA!
- [ Laughs ]
- THANK YOU.
I SHOULD'VE DONE THAT SOONER.
- SIMONE.
- JAROD.
THIS'LL HURT
JUST A LITTLE BIT,
BUT I PROMISE YOU--
IT'S GONNA MAKE YOU FEEL
A WHOLE LOT BETTER.
STORM IS OVER?
YES. IT'S OVER.
[ Helicopter Approaching ]
HELP!
[ Grunts ]
HE'S A MANIAC.
A MANIAC!
HE TRIED TO TEACH ME A LESSON.
HE THINKS HE'S SOME KIND
OF ONE-MAN JUDGE AND JURY!
WHERE IS HE?
THAT WAY.
BY THE FRONT DESK.
OUT. BUNGALOW 32.
IT'S WAY, WAY, WAY TO THE BACK.
OH, YEAH.
OH, YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
SUCKERS.
[ Helicopter Rotors Whirring ]
READY?
YOUR MAMA AND PAPA--
THEY CAN SEE YOU NOW.
[ Laughing ]
I WAS CLOSE, AND I LEARNED
A FEW THINGS THAT ARE GOING
TO GET ME EVEN CLOSER.
THE STATUS QUO REMAINS?
WE HAVE OUR DEAL,
BUT IT'S NOT QUITE
STATUS QUO.
HOW SO?
NO MORE SURVEILLANCE.
NO LIE DETECTORS.
NO MORE GAMES.
YOU SECOND-GUESS
MY WORK AGAIN,
I'LL PUT A BULLET
IN THAT PET OXYGEN TANK,
AND THEY'LL HAVE TO
CLEAN YOU UP WITH TWEEZERS.
I CATCH JAROD MY WAY.
AND ONCE HE'S
IN THE CENTRE, I'M GONE.
THAT'S THE DEAL.
ARE WE CLEAR?
[ Strained ]
AS A BELL.
[ Breathes ]
I'LL SEE YOU LATER, DADDY.
GOOD TO HAVE YOU BACK.
[ Miss Parker Reading ]
"MY DEAREST DAUGHTER, THIS RING
WAS YOUR GREAT-GRANDMOTHER'S.
"IF SOMETHING SHOULD HAPPEN
TO ME, I LEAVE IT FOR YOU.
MAYBE YOU'LL HAVE
BETTER LUCK. MOM."
[ Phone Ringing ]
- WHAT?
- DID YOU GET THE RING?
[ Miss Parker On Phone ]
YES. THANK YOU, JAROD.
[ Jarod On Phone ]
DID YOU FIND YOUR ANSWER?
I THINK I KNOW WHO KILLED MY
MOTHER, BUT RIGHT NOW I'M MORE
CONCERNED WITH WHY SHE DIED.
IT WAS FOR THE CHILDREN.
FOR YOU, JAROD.
THE WAY I SEE IT,
SHE DIED TRYING TO SAVE YOU.
YOU'RE ANGRY.
I WON'T STOP CHASING YOU.
AND I WON'T CHASE
MY PAST ANYMORE.
WHAT IF IT CHASES YOU?
I'LL IGNORE IT.
YOU MAKE THE RULES.
THAT'S JUST THE WAY I LIKE IT.
NICE BOOTS. SNAKESKIN?
MM-MMM. GATOR.
[ Mews ]