[ Bell Ringing ]
SORRY ABOUT THE PRINCIPAL NOT
BEING ABLE TO GIVE YOU THE TOUR.
HE'S REAL BUSY.
WORKING UP
THE SCHOOL LUNCH SCHEDULE
IS TRYING WORK, I'M SURE.
THIS WAS MR. JAROD'S CLASSROOM.
HE WAS, LIKE,
THE BEST SUBSTITUTE.
KIDS WOULD SIT IN
ON THE CLASS EVEN THOUGH
THEY WEREN'T ENROLLED.
AND HE DID
THE COOLEST EXPERIMENTS.
I CAN SEE THAT.
OH, YEAH.
WE EVEN DID
A VIROLOGY UNIT ON BUGS
TO LEARN THEIR RESILIENCY.
HE TOLD US THAT ROACHES
WOULD BE THE ONLY LIVING THING
AFTER A BIOLOGICAL HOLOCAUST--
THEM AND SOME WOMAN
NAMED PARKER.
HARDLY SOUNDS LIKE
HIGH SCHOOL BIOLOGY.
MR. JAROD, LIKE,
MARCHED TO HIS OWN DRUMMER.
HE'S A ONE-MAN BAND, ALL RIGHT.
THE BEST PART IS
HE WOULDN'T GRADE US.
IT WAS LIKE HE WAS
CONDUCTING HIS OWN EXPERIMENT,
AND WE WERE COLLECTING
THE DATA FOR HIM.
YOU RUN ALONG
TO HOMEROOM NOW.
AAH!
CARLOS?
WAIT! COME BACK HERE!
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE!
COME ON, NOW! STOP!
CARLOS, COME ON!
THAT'S IT!
AAH!
WHERE'S YOUR DAD?
DOWN THE HALL, LAST ROOM.
MY NAME IS JAROD.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE JUST FINE.
[ Man Narrating ]
OKAY, THE FATHER'S SYMPTOMS
INCLUDE WEIGHT LOSS, FEVER,
NIGHT SWEATS, VIOLENT COUGH,
SWOLLEN LYMPH NODES--
MYCOBACTERIUM TUBERCULOSIS.
LOOKS LIKE IT.
YOU DON'T SEE THAT
MUCH ANYMORE.
NO.
BUT HE'LL BE FINE
ONCE WE GET HIM ADMITTED.
HOW'S THE BOY?
TOO EARLY TO TELL.
BUT MUCH BETTER OFF
THAN YOU'RE GONNA BE...
ONCE GARBER FINDS OUT
WHAT YOU DID WITH THE KID.
VIOLATING QUARANTINE PROCEDURES
WITH THESE PEOPLE
WAS DAMN FOOLISH.
I REALIZE IT WAS
A BIT UNORTHODOX, SIR,
BUT T.B. IS
A LEVEL 2 CLASSIFICATION.
IT DOESN'T REQUIRE
AN ON-SITE QUARANTINE.
FRIENDLY ADVICE, DR. REILLY.
IF YOU DON'T WANNA END UP DEAD,
YOU'LL REMEMBER THAT...
EVERY ONE OF THESE SITUATIONS
SHOULD BE TREATED
AS A LEVEL 4 SITUATION.
WALTER, WHETHER OR NOT THE BOY
WAS ALREADY EXPOSED, OR--
WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE?
- HE'S PROTECTED EITHER WAY.
- [ Jarod ] AND THE BOY GETS
TO BE WITH HIS FATHER NOW.
I FELT LIKE HE NEEDED THAT.
GREAT. OUR NEW GUY'S
FLORENCE NIGHTINGALE.
[ Man Coughing ]
YEAH, YOU'RE GONNA
LOVE THIS PLACE.
STOVE AND OVEN IN THE KITCHEN,
HOT AND COLD RUNNING.
170 A MONTH PLUS UTILITIES.
170?
OKAY, 150.
I'LL PAY THE WATER.
COME ON DOWN TO THE OFFICE.
WE'LL SIGN THE PAPERS.
DOES IT HAVE ROACHES?
OF COURSE NOT. THIS PLACE
IS A BOHEMIAN'S DREAM,
NOT SOME SLUM.
COME ON TO THE OFFICE.
NO ROACHES?
♪♪ [ Violin ]
DAMN IT!
WHAT IS THAT?
IT'S A NEVER-ENDIN'
CAT-GUT NIGHTMARE
IS WHAT IT IS,
NOT TO MENTION
THE WORST RENTAL DECISION...
OF MY LIFE!
[ Baby Crying ]
THERE'S ANOTHER BUILDING
TWO BLOCKS WEST OF HERE.
MIGHT BE ABLE TO FIND
SOMETHIN' QUIETER THERE.
NO. I'LL TAKE THIS PLACE.
IT'S A LOT NICER
THAN WHERE I USED TO LIVE.
[ Sneezes ]
BLESS YOU.
SOUNDS LIKE THE FLU.
IT'S COLD AND RAINY IN PORTLAND
THIS TIME OF YEAR.
HERE, KEEP IT.
IT'S CLEAN.
SO I TOOK A TRIP WITHOUT YOU.
DON'T TELL ME YOU'RE JEALOUS.
CONFUSED.
I THOUGHT WE WERE
WORKING TOGETHER.
SO DID I,
UNTIL I DISCOVERED
YOUR PERSONAL ADS...
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
TRYING TO CONTACT JAROD.
I DON'T LIKE SECRETS.
WELL, HE WASN'T ANSWERING
MY E-MAIL MESSAGES,
SO I TRIED ANOTHER TACK.
BUT I WOULD HAVE LET YOU KNOW
IF HE HAD CONTACTED ME.
I HAVE A FEVER, SYD--
[ Door Opens ]
BUT IT'S NOT BAD ENOUGH
TO BELIEVE THAT.
WHAT?
UM--
[ Clears Throat ]
HE'S IN THE LAB.
WHO?
MR. RAINES.
MR. RAINES HASN'T BEEN
IN THE LAB IN 10 YEARS.
WELL, UH, HE'S IN THERE NOW,
AND HE'S LOOKING FOR YOU TWO.
SO, GOOD LUCK.
[ Labored Breathing ]
MR. RAINES?
THE EMPIRE STATE BUILDING.
WHO WOULD'VE THOUGHT
SOMETHING SO BEAUTIFUL
COULD BE REPLICATED...
BY A FOUR-YEAR-OLD BOY
IN ONLY TWO HOURS?
JAROD WAS BRILLIANT
THE DAY HE GOT HERE.
HE WAS BRILLIANT
THE DAY HE ESCAPED.
AND THE QUESTION IS,
WHERE IS HE?
MR. RAINES, JAROD
HAS BEEN HARDER TO CATCH
THAN WE THOUGHT.
SYDNEY, WE NEED HIM.
I KNOW.
[ Sneezes ]
[ Coughs ]
MAY I?
MR. RAINES,
I HAVE THE FLU.
I'M DYING.
MMM.
[ Coughing ]
KEEP IT.
BRING JAROD BACK
WHERE HE BELONGS,
OR I'LL GET SOMEONE WHO WILL.
ARE WE CLEAR?
MY FATHER
WANTS ME TO DO IT.
UNLIKE EVERYONE ELSE
AROUND HERE,
I'M NOT AFRAID OF YOUR FATHER.
I DON'T HAVE TO BE.
[ Garber ]
OUR JOB HERE AT RIDA
IS TO CONTAIN VIRAL OUTBREAKS...
BEFORE THEY SPREAD.
I'VE SEEN THE WORST
THAT A VIRUS CAN DO,
AND BECAUSE OF IT,
BY THE NUMBERS
IS USUALLY BEST.
IN RETROSPECT,
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING
WITH BRIGGS AND HIS SON, JAROD.
LISTEN, I WAS OUT OF LINE.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WELL, YOUR CREDENTIALS
ARE IMPRESSIVE.
A STINT IN BAMRID
IN LONDON,
M.D./Ph.D IN VIROLOGY.
WHERE DID YOU DO YOUR DOCTORATE,
BY THE WAY?
HORACE GREELEY HIGH SCHOOL,
PORTLAND.
[ Chuckling ]
THE DOOR'S UNDER
NEGATIVE AIR PRESSURE
TO CONTAIN LEAKS.
YEAH, WE PIONEERED
THE TECHNIQUE HERE.
I NOTICED IN YOUR FILE
THAT YOU WERE VACCINATED FOR
ANTHRAX AND THE W.E.E. SERIES.
I WAS WORKING IN THE GULF
WITH NATO's Q.R.T.,
AND THE W.E.E. WAS FOR
THE PEKOWSKY SYNDROME
IN JOHANNESBURG.
A FRIGHTENING SCENARIO.
YES, VERY.
WATCHING SOMEBODY SUFFER
CAN HAVE AN EFFECT ON YOU.
I HOPE I CAN MAKE
A DIFFERENCE HERE.
[ Beeping ]
[ Female Electronic Voice ]
CODE ACCEPTED.
JAROD, JEFF BAYTOS,
DECONTAMINATION
AND FACILITIES SPECIALIST.
- NICE TO MEET YOU.
- UH, IX-NAY ON
THE ANDSHAKE-HAY, DOC.
[ Chuckling ]
MR. BAYTOS TENDS
TO BE OVERCAUTIOUS.
NO SUCH THING
IN A PLACE LIKE THIS.
ONE WRONG MOVE
LIKE PRESSING THE FLESH,
AND, UH,
IT'S OFF TO THE SUBMARINE
FOR 10,000 YEARS.
YOU CALL YOUR MORGUE
THE "SUBMARINE"?
WHAT DID YOU CALL IT
AT BAMRID?
CHERNOBYL.
WELL, WE'RE WORKING
A LEVEL 3 TODAY.
AN OFFSHOOT STRAIN
OF RIFT VALLEY FEVER.
YOU READY TO BATTLE
THE UNSEEN ENEMY?
ABSOLUTELY.
WILL YOU BE JOINING US,
MR. BAYTOS?
LEVEL 2 IS
MY LIMIT NOW, MAN.
LIVE LONG AND PROSPER.
[ Garber Chuckles ]
BAYTOS WITNESSED A MAN
DIE OF EBOLA.
HE'S BEEN RELUCTANT TO GO
PAST LEVEL 2 EVER SINCE.
FORTUNATELY,
HE'S THE BEST THERE IS...
WHEN IT COMES TO DECON.
[ Woman ]
IT'S NICE TO HAVE VISITORS.
OUR FRIENDS DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO THINK OR SAY,
SO THEY JUST STAY AWAY.
DID YOU MEET JON
IN SOUTH AFRICA?
NO, BUT I HEARD
A LOT ABOUT HIM.
WE WERE BOTH WORKING
ON SEPARATE STRIKE TEAMS
IN THE MUTABA VILLAGE.
OH. YOU KNOW,
HE LOVED THAT JOB.
HE WAS THE FIRST TO ARRIVE
AND THE LAST TO LEAVE.
HE'D STAY IN PLACES
WHERE THERE WAS NO HOPE,
NO CHANCE TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
HOLDING THE HAND OF A DYING MAN
TO LET HIM KNOW HE'S NOT ALONE--
THAT'S MAKING
A DIFFERENCE.
I'M WORKING WITH WALTER GARBER
NOW. I'M TRYING TO FINISH
THE WORK YOUR HUSBAND STARTED.
WELL, YOU'RE LUCKY
TO BE WORKING UNDER WALTER.
JON THOUGHT THE WORLD OF HIM.
THAT'S THEM AT
THE W.H.O. BANQUET.
[ Door Opens ]
HEY, YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE NAPPING.
I THOUGHT I HEARD DADDY.
NO, IT'S NOT DADDY.
IT'S JUST A FRIEND.
- OH.
- HI. MY NAME'S JAROD.
- HI.
- GO LIE DOWN, HONEY.
THIS HAS BEEN
ESPECIALLY HARD ON HER.
HE VANISHED RIGHT BEFORE
HER BIRTHDAY.
HOW DO I EXPLAIN THAT TO CINDY?
I MEAN,
HOW DO I EXPLAIN ANY OF IT?
YOU KNOW, I-I KNOW
HE'S NOT COMING BACK.
YOU KNOW,
I-I'VE ACCEPTED THAT.
I HAVE.
I JUST, UH, WISH I KNEW
WHERE TO GO FROM HERE.
I MEAN,
HOW TO GO FROM HERE.
I MEAN, IS HE DEAD?
IS HE ALIVE?
THAT'S A VERY BEAUTIFUL RING.
JON DESIGNED
OUR WEDDING BANDS.
YOU KNOW, I KNOW IT'S CORNY,
BUT HE WANTED THEM TO BE
THE ONLY TWO ALIKE IN THE WORLD.
HERE. JON WORE THIS WHEN
HE WENT INTO THE FIELD TO WORK.
HE NEVER GOT SICK WEARING IT.
I'D LIKE YOU TO HAVE IT.
I--
I COULDN'T POSSIBLY
ACCEPT THAT.
NO, HE'D HAVE WANTED
SOMEBODY WHO CARED
AS MUCH AS HE DID TO HAVE IT.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
FITS LIKE A GLOVE.
[ Chatter, Indistinct ]
EXCUSE ME. I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU MIGHT HELP ME.
UH, SURE. WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
IT SAYS HERE THAT
THIS IS A-A MOTEL FOR ROACHES?
YEAH. IT'S LIKE, UH,
THE HOTEL CALIFORNIA...
FOR OUR LITTLE
SIX-LEGGED FRIENDS, YOU KNOW?
HOTEL CALIFORNIA?
YEAH, THEY CAN CHECK OUT
ANYTIME THEY LIKE,
BUT THEY CAN NEVER LEAVE.
OH.
OH! LIKE A TRAP.
YEAH.
SOMETHIN' LIKE THAT.
WELL, THAT'S PERFECT.
I'LL TAKE 100.
RIGHT ON.
♪♪ [ Trumpet ]
[ Pounding On Wall ]
[ Woman ]
I'M GONNA WRAP THAT THING
AROUND YOUR NECK...
IF YOU DON'T SHUT UP!
COME AND GET IT.
[ Pounding ]
YOU'RE A DEAD MAN, HANSEL!
COME AND GET IT.
♪♪ [ Trumpet ]
[ Man ]
I'VE PAID MY RENT.
YOU CAN'T EVICT ME.
SIR, MY NAME IS JAROD.
I'M YOUR NEIGHBOR.
I-I JUST WANTED TO TELL YOU
THAT I'M VERY INTRIGUED
BY YOUR MUSIC.
I'M NOT FALLING FOR THAT!
I WOULD VERY MUCH LIKE
TO MEET YOU, AND I WOULD
LIKE TO ASK YOU A QUESTION.
[ Chain Rattling ]
ARE YOU HERE
TO GIVE ME THE BOOT?
I WASN'T PLANNING ON IT, SIR,
BUT YOU'RE MORE
THAN WELCOME TO MINE.
COME IN.
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
A FRIENDLY AUDIENCE
FOR A CHANGE.
BEN HANSEL'S THE NAME.
BEN, I NEED YOUR HELP.
AND I YOURS.
DO YOU PLAY?
I'VE CONDUCTED A SYMPHONY
HERE AND THERE.
AH!
WELL, THEN WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF THIS?
♪♪ [ Loud, Harsh ]
[ Woman ]
SHUT UP!
YOU'RE DRIVING ME CRAZY!
CULTURAL DWARVES,
ALL OF THEM.
[ Man ] YOU SUCK!
THAT'S VERY INTERESTING.
HAYDN'S
"CELLO CONCERTO IN 'C' MAJOR,"
I BELIEVE.
I REWROTE IT FOR TRUMPET.
I'M WORKING ON AN ARRANGEMENT
FOR GLOCKENSPIEL.
AN ARTIST MUST STRETCH,
YOU KNOW.
YES.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
A MUSICIAN?
FIFTEEN-ODD YEARS.
THAT'S A LONG TIME.
BUT IT'LL ALL BE WORTH IT
WHEN THE PHILHARMONIC CALLS.
I SENT THEM A TAPE
ABOUT A WEEK AGO.
YOU-- YOU HAD A QUESTION.
YES.
I'M TRYING TO ATTRACT ROACHES,
AND THIS DOESN'T SEEM TO WORK.
DO YOU HAVE ANY?
ROACHES?
I CAN'T GET RID OF THEM.
I SPILLED A BOX OF
CRUNCHY CRAWLERS CEREAL
BEHIND THE FRIDGE ONCE.
NOW EVERY NIGHT,
THEY COME OUT HUNTING.
CRUNCHY CRAWLERS?
"THEY'RE
GROTESQUELY DELICIOUS."
YOU KNOW, I WAS WONDERING
ABOUT MY INTERPRETATION
OF THE FIRST MOVEMENT.
IT WAS A TAD SUBTLE.
SUBTLETY IS A VIRTUE
IN ANY FORM.
A NEIGHBOR WHO'S A SCHOLAR
OF THE ARTS AND LETTERS.
THANK YOU, JAROD.
UM, YOU CAN YELL AT ME
THROUGH THE WALL ANYTIME.
AND THANK YOU FOR THE TIP.
YOU WILL DO VERY NICELY HERE.
[ Jarod ]
IN SECONDS,
THE VIRUS INVADES THE HOST CELL.
- WITH A LEVEL 4 VIRUS,
THE RESULTS ARE DEVASTATING.
- [ Chattering, Laughing ]
THE MUTABA VILLAGE OUTBREAK.
SUBJECTS BEGIN COUGHING
ONLY FOUR HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE.
INTERNAL BLEEDING
COMMENCES AT HOUR 12,
AND BY HOUR 36,
THE SUBJECT COMPLETELY
BLEEDS OUT.
[ Chattering ]
GENTLEMEN, YOU CAN IGNORE
THE FLIGHT ATTENDANT...
AS SHE TRIES TO TEACH YOU
HOW TO FASTEN THE SEAT BELT,
BUT WITH THE MUTABA VIRUS
AND OTHER LEVEL FOURS,
THE KILL RATE IS 90%.
AND, MAY I ADD,
AN AIRBORNE VIRUS...
COUPLED WITH A PINPRICK
IN YOUR GLOVE
OR A FAULTY SEAL...
SENDS YOU INTO THE SLAMMER,
AND FROM THERE...
IT'S AN EXPRESS
STRAIGHT TO THE SUBMARINE.
LIGHTS.
THANK YOU FOR
THE SAFETY REVIEW, DR. REILLY.
YOU MISLED THEM BACK THERE.
YOU AND JON FLORENCE
DID DEVELOP A VACCINE
FOR THE CAHUENGA VIRUS.
WE GOT LUCKY ON THAT.
BUT WITH EBOLA OR MUTABA--
WELL, I HAVE
TO KEEP 'EM HONEST.
I'M SORRY ABOUT DR. FLORENCE.
YOU MUST MISS HIM.
- VERY MUCH.
- FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND,
DR. FLORENCE WAS A FAMILY MAN.
- HARDLY THE TYPE
TO JUST UP AND LEAVE.
- HE WAS A GOOD MAN.
OF ALL PEOPLE,
YOU TWO SHOULD KNOW THAT...
AWFUL THINGS SWIRL BENEATH
THE HEALTHIEST OF EXTERIORS.
JON CONFIDED IN ME THAT
THINGS AT HOME WEREN'T OPTIMAL.
HE NEVER WENT INTO SPECIFICS,
BUT HE CERTAINLY ENJOYED WORKING
THE EXTRA HOURS HERE...
RATHER THAN BEING AT HOME.
THIS IS AN AIRBORNE
LEVEL 4 VIRUS.
LET'S BE ON OUR TOES.
COMMENCING
PHASE TWO DISSECTION.
WE ARE 72 HOURS AFTER EXPIRATION
BY MUTABA STRAIN "B,"
SUBJECT 247.
- WALTER.
- GOOD GOD!
DECON!
COME ON.
LET'S MOVE IT. GO!
[ Alarm Blaring ]
OKAY, LET'S REMAIN CALM.
PROCEED WITH DECON SHOWER.
- COMING THROUGH.
- [ Garber ]
STAY CALM. YOU'LL BE FINE.
CODE DENIED.
DAMN IT!
THE CODE ISN'T WORKING!
HERE, LET ME.
[ Electronic Voice ]
CODE ACCEPTED.
GET THE GLOVE OFF.
INOCULATE.
HURRY UP.
NO SKIN BREAKS.
THE BLOOD MUST'VE BEEN
FROM THE SAMPLE.
WELL DONE, EVERYBODY.
EVERYTHING BY THE NUMBERS.
WE'LL REVIEW
THE SECURITY TAPE TOMORROW.
WELL, YOU HANDLED
THAT SIMULATION AS IF IT WERE
COMPLETELY REAL, JAROD.
WELL, I'VE HAD
A LOT OF PRACTICE, SIR.
WHO CHANGED
THE SLAMMER ACCESS CODE?
LISA, THE FEWER PEOPLE
THAT HAVE THE CODE, THE
FEWER PEOPLE THAT ARE AT RISK.
I DON'T WANT ANYBODY
NEAR THE SLAMMER
UNLESS THEY HAVE TO BE.
IT'S YOUR FUNERAL.
NO, IT'S HIS.
GARBER'S THE ONLY PERSON
THAT HAS THE ACCESS CODE
TO THE SLAMMER?
AND THE SUBMARINE.
OH, JON.
HOW'S MY GODDAUGHTER?
ABOUT TO TURN SIX, BUT
SHE THINKS SHE'S 16. I HOPE
YOU CAN MAKE IT TO HER PARTY.
I WOULDN'T MISS IT
FOR THE WORLD.
I'VE PROCEEDED WITH
THE AUTOPSY ON THE MONKEY.
LOOK AT THE LIVER.
MUSH.
THIS VIRUS HAS MUTATED.
WE'LL FINISH THIS
FIRST THING MONDAY.
FORGIVE ME, FATHER,
FOR I HAVE SINNED.
IT'S BEEN--
OH, MY GOD--
33 YEARS SINCE
MY LAST CONFESSION.
I HAVE BETRAYED A FRIEND.
THEN YOU MUST SEEK
HIS FORGIVENESS.
MM-MMM.
HE HAS SHUT ME OUT.
YOU'RE TROUBLED
BY SOMETHING ELSE.
HAVE YOU PRAYED TO THE LORD
FOR FORGIVENESS?
NOT EVEN HE CAN FORGIVE ME
FOR WHAT I'VE DONE.
LOOK AT THE LIVER.
[ Jon ]
MUSH. THIS VIRUS HAS MUTATED.
MM-HMM.
IT'S LIKE
THE CAHUENGA VIRUS,
BUT WORSE.
THIS IS A LEVEL 5 VIRUS.
WHAT THE HELL HAVE YOU DONE?
YOU MADE EBOLA
LOOK LIKE THE FLU.
- I'VE BEEN WORKING ON IT,
GENETICALLY.
- NO, YOU'VE BEEN PLAYING GOD.
WE GOTTA SHUT DOWN
THIS PROJECT NOW.
I'M DESTROYING IT.
YOU CAN'T.
YES, I CAN.
I WON'T LET YOU.
LET GO OF MY AIR HOSE!
MY GOD, WALTER,
YOU'VE KILLED ME!
QUICK,
INTO THE DECON SHOWER.
[ Alarm Blaring ]
THE LAB IS FULL OF THE VIRUS.
STAY CALM. DON'T PANIC.
PRESSURE FAILURE!
GET INTO THE SLAMMER.
I'LL MEET YOU THERE.
HELLO, JON.
I WAS AFRAID I'D FIND YOU HERE.
♪♪ [ Cello ]
[ Woman ]
HANSEL, YOU ARE DRIVING ME NUTS!
SHUT UP!
INTERESTING INTERPRETATION.
[ Pounding On Wall ]
[ Man ]
YOU SUCK!
YOU'RE A POLITE NEIGHBOR,
JAROD,
BUT I FEAR
THE CULTURAL DWARVES
ARE RIGHT.
I'M TERRIBLE.
IT TAKES A LONG TIME
TO MASTER MUSIC, BEN.
A LIFETIME WOULD NOT BE
LONG ENOUGH FOR ME.
MY MUSIC KILLS PLANT LIFE.
I'M SALIERI
TO MOZART, JAROD.
I CURSE GOD FOR BESTOWING ME
WITH MEDIOCRE ABILITY.
♪♪ [ Music Box ]
WHAT ARE THESE?
TRIFLES, LARKS.
POINTLESS EXERCISES.
DID YOU MAKE THESE?
YES.
BEN, THESE ARE EXQUISITE.
YOUR COMPLIMENT
IS APPRECIATED, JAROD.
BUT, ART IT IS NOT.
ART IS MANY THINGS.
SOME CHOOSE A BRUSH,
SOME A BOW,
SOME A PEN,
AND SOME... CHOOSE GLASS.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
MAYBE THE WAY YOU CREATE
IS THROUGH THESE PIECES
RATHER THAN THAT.
YOU SAID IT YOURSELF, BEN.
SOMETIMES AN ARTIST
NEEDS TO STRETCH.
[ Beeping ]
[ Young Jarod ]
SYDNEY, I'M SCARED.
I CAN'T DO THIS.
[ Young Sydney ]
YOU HAVE TO, JAROD.
THERE'S SMOKE.
PEOPLE ARE SCREAMING.
SYDNEY, THEY'RE BURNING!
THEY'RE BURNING!
MAKE IT STOP!
MAKE THE BURNING STOP!
- JAROD!
- MAKE IT STOP!
NO, GO AWAY!
LEAVE ME ALONE!
IT'S ALL RIGHT, JAROD.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
AAH!
IT'S ALL OVER, JAROD.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I WANT MY DADDY.
THE CODE WORD
MAKES IT STOP, JAROD.
YOU DIDN'T USE THE CODE WORD
WE CAME UP WITH.
I SAID, I WANT MY DAD.
LET ME.
JAROD, REMEMBER.
WHEN YOU'RE DOING
THE SIMULATION
AND YOU BECOME FRIGHTENED...
AND WANNA STOP,
SAY, "REFUGE."
ALL RIGHT?
MM-HMM?
REFUGE.
[ Beeping ]
[ Miss Parker Sneezing ]
[ Coughing ]
HE CONTACTED ME.
NO SECRETS.
WHY THE SUDDEN
CHANGE OF HEART?
LATELY, I'VE BEEN SEEING THINGS
FROM ANOTHER ANGLE,
AND MAYBE IT'S BEST
IF YOU GET HIM.
DR. HOFFMAN,
DO YOU HAVE A MINUTE?
WHAT'S UP?
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THIS?
HMM?
WELL, LET'S SEE.
LIQUEFICATION OF ORGANS,
BLOOD SECRETION THROUGH
SKIN PORES, LOSS OF HAIR.
LOOKS LIKE AN ADVANCED
VERSION OF MUTABA.
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT
UNTIL I FOUND THIS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THIS BEFORE.
DID YOU CROSS-CHECK IT?
AGAINST EVERY SAMPLE
ON RECORD.
THERE'S OVER 3,000 ON RECORD.
IT DID GET A LITTLE TEDIOUS
AFTER THE FIRST 800.
[ Chattering ]
[ Hoffman ]
MY GOD.
JAROD, THIS IS WORSE THAN
ANY LEVEL 4 I'VE EVER SEEN.
- IT'S A LEVEL 5.
- WHAT?
THERE'S A LEVEL 5 HERE?
IT'S A SAMPLE OFF A BODY
IN THE SUBMARINE.
WAIT. H-HOW DID YOU GET
IN THE SUBMARINE?
ONLY GAR--
GO. GO.
GARBER HAS THE CODE.
IS ALL RESEARCH HERE
SANCTIONED BY
A GOVERNING BODY?
WHICH PROJECT ISN'T?
IT'S ONLY HEARSAY,
BUT I TRUST THE SOURCE.
GARBER WAS WORKING
ON SOME RESEARCH.
I-I DON'T KNOW WHAT.
WHAT ELSE DID
JON FLORENCE TELL YOU?
HOW'D YOU KNOW
JON WAS THE SOURCE?
BESIDES GARBER,
HE WAS THE ONLY PERSON...
THAT KNEW EVERYTHING
THAT WAS GOING ON HERE.
WHAT ELSE DID HE TELL YOU?
THAT GARBER WAS WORKING
ON SOME RADICAL MUTATIONS
OF A LEVEL 5.
HE SAID IT STARTED OUT GOOD,
BUT IT GOT CORRUPTED.
JON SAID GOD
WOULD NEVER FORGIVE HIM...
IF HE LET
THIS PROJECT CONTINUE.
WELL, UNFORTUNATELY
FOR JON FLORENCE,
HE NEVER HAD THE CHANCE
TO STOP IT.
OH, MY GOD.
[ Jon ]
MUSH. THIS VIRUS HAS MUTATED.
MM-HMM.
WE'LL FINISH THIS
FIRST THING MONDAY.
[ Tape Rewinding ]
I'M GUESSING BETWEEN THE KNOB,
THE MOUTHPIECE AND THE
CITY WATER YOU'RE DRINKING,
THERE'S ENOUGH GERMS
TO KILL A COCKROACH.
DR. REILLY. HI.
YEAH, YOU'RE PROBABLY RIGHT.
I DEAL WITH THE GERMS I CAN,
BUT SOMETHING TELLS ME...
I WOULDN'T LAST LONG
LIVING IN A PLASTIC BUBBLE.
EVEN ONE EQUIPPED
WITH A DECON SHOWER?
IT WAS AN EXCELLENT
PERFORMANCE, JEFF.
LOOK, I-I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU MEAN.
ARE YOU GONNA MAKE ME
ENHANCE THE IMAGE
SO I CAN SEE YOUR FACE?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
NOT BEING ABLE TO SLEEP?
YOU'D BE SURPRISED.
I WATCHED A MAN
BEG FOR HIS LIFE.
HE BEGGED TO SEE
HIS WIFE AND KID AGAIN,
AND I--
I-- I DIDN'T HELP HIM.
I KNOW JON FLORENCE
GOT INFECTED, I KNOW
HIS BODY'S IN THE SUBMARINE,
AND I KNOW THAT YOU HELPED
GARBER DOCTOR THIS TAPE.
BUT WHAT I CAN'T FIGURE OUT
IS WHY.
BECAUSE IT WAS MY FAULT,
THAT'S WHY.
I-I WAS WORKING LATE
LIKE JON AND DR. GARBER,
AND I-I SAW JON
COME INTO THE SLAMMER,
AND HE-HE--
HE LOOKED SO FRIGHTENED.
THE DECON SHOWER LOST PRESSURE,
AND THAT IS MY JOB
TO MAKE SURE THAT IT DOESN'T.
THAT-THAT IS MY JOB,
DR. REILLY.
AND THEN GARBER WENT BALLISTIC,
AND HE BLAMED ME
FOR JON'S CONTAMINATION.
YOU KNOW, I-I HAVE NEVER
SEEN A VIRUS DO WHAT IT DID
TO HIM, OR SO QUICKLY.
AND THAT'S WHY YOU WON'T
GO PAST LEVEL 2 ANYMORE.
IT'S JUST THAT JON--
HE BEGGED ME TO GET
HIS WIFE AND KID,
AND-AND GARBER--
GARBER TOLD ME TO KEEP IT QUIET.
HE SAID THAT--
THAT THE AUTHORITIES
WOULD HAVE TO BE CALLED...
AND THAT THEY WOULD
SHUT DOWN THE FACILITY,
AND THAT MORE LIVES WOULD
BE LOST BECAUSE OF MY ERROR.
JON FLORENCE DID NOT DIE BECAUSE
OF YOU OR THE DECON SHOWER.
HE DIED BECAUSE
WALTER GARBER MURDERED HIM.
HELLO, BUTCHER BOB'S?
I'D LIKE TO ORDER
A DOZEN PIG LIVERS, PLEASE.
YES, A DOZEN.
SAY "CHEESE."
GOOD MORNING, CLASS.
TODAY'S LESSON TAKES US
INTO THE FASCINATING WORLD
OF COCKROACHES.
WALTER?
YES?
IT'S JAROD.
I'VE MADE A VERY
INTERESTING DISCOVERY THAT
I THINK YOU SHOULD CHECK OUT.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
WELL, IT'S STILL
TOO EARLY TO BE SURE,
BUT I THINK I FOUND
A VACCINE FOR MUTABA.
I'LL-I'LL MEET YOU IN THE LAB
IN AN HOUR, JAROD.
PERFECT.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
WHERE'D YOU GET THE SAMPLE?
FROM THIS LIVER.
MY GOD, MAN!
IT'S AN AIRBORNE VIRUS!
WALTER, YOUR AIR HOSE.
HIT THE ALARM!
HELP ME!
[ Alarm Blaring ]
GOD!
OH! THERE'S PRESSURE FAILURE
IN THE DECON LINE!
WELL, YOU'D BETTER
GET INTO THE SLAMMER, SIR.
[ Electronic Voice ]
CODE ACCEPTED.
WHERE IS EVERYBODY?
WHERE ARE THE DOCTORS?
BAYTOS!
THERE'S NOBODY HERE, SIR.
- I SENT THEM ALL HOME.
- JAROD, YOU'VE KILLED ME!
RELAX, WALTER. I TOLD YOU.
I MADE A LITTLE DISCOVERY.
IT'S A DERIVATIVE CROSS
BETWEEN YOUR CAHUENGA VIRUS
AND THE RIFT VALLEY STRAIN.
AN ANTI-VIRUS.
IT SHUTS YOUR STRAIN DOWN.
GIVE IT TO ME, PLEASE.
- I CAN'T.
- JAROD, PLEASE, HELP ME!
LIKE YOU HELPED JON FLORENCE...
BY EXPOSING HIM TO
A LEVEL 5 WITHOUT ANY CURE?
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
WELL, I SURE AS HELL
AM NOT FLORENCE NIGHTINGALE.
BUT, THEN AGAIN,
NEITHER ARE YOU.
HOW LONG, WALTER?
HOW LONG BEFORE JON FLORENCE
STARTED TO SHOW SYMPTOMS?
HOW LONG BEFORE
THE INTERNAL BLEEDING STARTED?
HIS BRAIN TISSUE
STARTED TO LEAK INTO HIS EARS?
HOW LONG BEFORE HIS INTERNAL
ORGANS STARTED TO LIQUEFY?
HOW LONG, WALTER?
GIVE ME THAT SYRINGE.
WHY?
JON FLORENCE
NEVER HAD THIS OPTION.
WHY SHOULD YOU?
- JAROD, IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
- HE KNEW HE WAS GOING TO DIE.
AND I'LL BET THE LAST THING
HE WANTED TO DO WAS JUST TO
SEE HIS FAMILY ONE MORE TIME...
TO SAY GOOD-BYE TO HIS WIFE
AND TO HIS CHILD.
BUT YOU COULDN'T
GIVE HIM THAT PEACE,
COULD YOU, WALTER?
BECAUSE THEN THE TRUTH
WOULD COME OUT ABOUT HOW
YOU WERE TRYING TO PLAY GOD...
WITH ALL THESE
VIRAL EXPERIMENTS.
YOU TOOK JON FLORENCE'S LIFE,
AND YOU RUINED
HIS FAMILY'S AS WELL.
- THAT IS NO ACCIDENT.
- ALL RIGHT, I DID IT.
I ADMIT IT. I KILLED HIM!
THE-THE RESEARCH
WAS VERY VALUABLE.
- PLEASE, GIVE ME THE VACCINE!
- ALL RIGHT, WALTER.
BUT I WILL WARN YOU.
IT'S ONLY SUGAR WATER.
SUGAR WATER?
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO MAKE A VACCINE.
YOU SEE,
I'M NOT REALLY A VIROLOGIST.
- THE TRUTH IS, THIS PLACE
GIVES ME THE CREEPS.
- WHAT?
YOU CAN CHECK OUT
ANYTIME YOU LIKE,
BUT YOU CAN NEVER LEAVE.
NO! NO!
DON'T LEAVE ME! JAROD!
[ Over Monitor ]
JAROD! COME BACK HERE!
JAROD!
WAIT, DON'T!
PLEASE, DON'T LEAVE ME HERE!
PLEASE, DON'T!
HELP! HELP!
AREN'T YOU GONNA TELL HIM
YOU DIDN'T REALLY INFECT HIM?
[ Shouting Continues ]
NAH. WHY DON'T YOU DO IT?
IN 48 HOURS.
HELP! PLEASE!
SOMEBODY, HELP!
AFTER THE POLICE GET THIS.
HELP ME!
OH, NO! GOD!
OH, GOD, HELP ME!
COME BACK!
JAROD! JAROD!
WHAT IS THAT SMELL?
I CAN'T SMELL.
GO LEFT.
YOU TAKE THAT ROOM.
GOOD MORNING, CLASS.
TODAY'S LESSON TAKES US
INTO THE FASCINATING WORLD
OF COCKROACHES.
- NOTHING. HE'S GONE.
- YES, BUT NOT FORGOTTEN.
- [ Groans ]
- THIS IS A BUG MOTEL.
WHEN THE HORMONES
OFF A ROACH'S BODY,
WHICH IS THE WET STUFF
YOU JUST WALKED THROUGH,
COMBINES WITH THE STICKY
STUFF INSIDE OF THE BOX,
WHICH YOU ARE STANDING IN,
IT FORMS A BOND...
WHICH IS STRONGER
THAN EPOXY.
WELCOME TO THE WORLD'S
LARGEST BUG MOTEL.
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
ENJOY YOUR STAY.
CLASS DISMISSED.
I'M STUCK.
♪♪ [ Trumpet ]
[ Pounding On Wall ]
[ Dog Barking ]
CHIVAS ON THE ROCKS.
ONE ICE CUBE.
CLEVER WAY
OF CONTACTING ME, SYDNEY.
NO ONE AT THE CENTRE
WOULD'VE EVER KNOWN
WHAT THIS MEANT.
I HAD TO SEE YOU FACE-TO-FACE.
DID MISS PARKER
TAKE THE BAIT?
PRESUMABLY.
I HAVE TO ASK YOU FOR SOMETHING.
YOU'RE IN NO POSITION
TO ASK ME FOR ANYTHING.
NOT EVEN YOUR FORGIVENESS?
- WHAT?
- FOR KEEPING YOU IN THE CENTRE.
FOR THE LIES ALL THESE YEARS.
DID YOU SEND ME THIS?
NO, I DID NOT.
PARKER DID
WITH YOUR NAME ON IT.
WHAT IS IT?
REMINDERS.
ISSUES I MUST TAKE UP
WITH MYSELF,
GOD,
AND WITH YOU.
- IT'S TOO LATE.
- I COME TO YOU
WITH AN OLIVE BRANCH.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU WANT MY FORGIVENESS?
THEN TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED
TO MY MOM AND DAD.
I CAN'T.
I DON'T KNOW THE TRUTH.
THEN YOU AND THE CENTRE
WILL NEVER GET ME BACK.
AND I CAN'T FORGIVE YOU, SYDNEY.
I CAN'T FORGIVE MYSELF.
[ Ringing ]
BEN HANSEL.
[ Woman ] MR. HANSEL, THIS
IS THE CHICAGO PHILHARMONIC.
WE RECEIVED THE EXTRAORDINARY
GLASS SCULPTURE YOU MADE,
AND WE'D LIKE TO SET UP A TIME
FOR YOU TO MEET WITH
OUR MERCHANDISE COORDINATOR.
WE HAVE NEXT WEDNESDAY
AVAILABLE--
THANK YOU...
FOR EVERYTHING.
WHERE WILL YOU GO NOW?
I'M STARTING A NEW JOB.
YOU'VE GOT ROACHES?
[ Mews ]