[ Young Jarod ]
I JUST WANNA KNOW WHO I AM.
I CAN STAND ANYTHING
FOR THAT.
I'LL NEVER GIVE UP,
SYDNEY, EVER.
IT'S BEEN THREE DAYS,
JAROD, WITH TEMPERATURE
OVER 100 DEGREES.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
GO ON, JAROD.
I CAN DO IT.
I JUST WANNA KNOW WHO I AM.
[ Young Jarod ]
I CAN STAND ANYTHING
FOR THAT.
[ Beeping ]
WHERE DID THEY FIND THIS?
CLEANUP CREW FOUND IT
IN A CABIN ABOUT 50 MILES
SOUTH OF ALBUQUERQUE.
[ Sydney ]
A GIFT FROM JAROD.
HMM.
SO, WHAT DOES IT MEAN?
I'M NOT SURE WHAT
THE ORIGINAL INTENT
OF THE SIMULATION WAS.
I'LL HAVE TO RUN IT
THROUGH THE ARCHIVES.
SAVE YOUR SWEAT.
IT'S JUST ANOTHER DIVERSION.
I BEG TO DIFFER, MISS PARKER.
THIS IS VERY IMPORTANT TO JAROD.
HE'S REACHING OUT,
TAKING A LEAP OF FAITH.
[ Jarod Shouting ]
ALL RIGHT. NOW, REMEMBER WHAT
YOU LEARNED IN CLASS.
I THINK I'M GONNA THROW UP!
OH, NO, NO.
YOU'RE GONNA BE JUST FINE!
WELL, YOU'RE THE EXPERT.
SORT OF.
SORT OF?
EXACTLY HOW MANY TIMES
HAVE YOU JUMPED?
COUNTING THIS?
YES!
ONE.
[ Woman Screaming ]
[ Man Narrating ]
TOUGH JUMP?
I MAY HAVE UNDERESTIMATED
MY PAYLOAD.
WELL, THEY COME IN
ALL SHAPES AND SIZES.
RUB SOME OF THIS ON IT.
WHAT IS IT?
HORSE LINIMENT.
THEY USE IT ON THOROUGHBREDS
WHEN THEY PULL A MUSCLE.
A FEW MORE OF THEM EL PASO
HOUSEWIVES,
YOU'LL BE DRINKIN' THE STUFF.
[ Sighs ] ANOTHER
SATISFIED CUSTOMER.
NICE TO SEE THAT YOU CAN CARRY
YOUR WEIGHT AROUND HERE.
THE INSTRUCTOR JOB IS YOURS
IF YOU STILL WANT IT.
GREAT! IT'S A PLEASURE
TO BE HERE.
GOOD.
CROCKETT. DID I GET A CALL
FROM TASCO?
[ Crockett ]
PHONE HASN'T RUNG ALL DAY.
[ Woman ]
HOW'S THE OLD GIRL HOLDING UP?
[ Scoffs ] I WAS ABLE TO PATCH
THE LEAK IN THE FUEL PUMP,
BUT SHE'S DEFINITELY
ON DEATH'S DOOR.
JUST HOLD HER TOGETHER FOR A FEW
MORE DAYS...
AND I'LL HAVE THAT NEW PLANE
FLOWN IN FROM PHOENIX.
YOUR RÉSUMÉ IS VERY IMPRESSIVE.
82nd AIRBORNE,
ARMY RANGER.
LOFTY CREDENTIALS FOR SOMEONE
LOOKING TO TEACH THE PUBLIC
TO TUCK AND ROLL.
WHY US?
WELL, I'M ON THE RUN
FROM A SECRET ORGANIZATION.
I NEEDED A PLACE
TO HIDE OUT FOR A WHILE.
[ Broots ] WE'VE BEEN OVER THIS
SIMULATION A DOZEN TIMES. I'M
NOT SURE I UNDERSTAND THE POINT.
[ Miss Parker ]
SYDNEY DIDN'T ALWAYS
HAVE METHOD, JUST MADNESS.
IT WAS A PSYCHOLOGICAL STUDY
TO DETERMINE...
IF THE MIND CAN ENABLE
THE BODY TO EXCEED
ITS NATURAL CAPABILITIES...
WHEN AN EMOTIONAL STIMULUS
IS APPLIED.
LIKE WHEN-- WHEN A CAR'S ON TOP
OF A CHILD, AND THE MOTHER
LIFTS IT OFF WITH ONE HAND.
EXACTLY.
[ Man ] MISS PARKER, THIS
BIRTHDAY GIFT JUST ARRIVED.
IS TODAY YOUR BIRTHDAY?
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
OH. YOUNG, I'M SURE.
JAROD.
KNOW THIS MAN?
I'VE NEVER SEEN HIM BEFORE
IN MY LIFE.
INTERESTING.
IT'S A DEAD FLOWER, SYDNEY,
NOT THE SHROUD OF TURIN.
[ Jarod ]
EXCUSE ME FOR SAYING THIS,
BUT IT DOESN'T EXACTLY LOOK LIKE
BUSINESS IS BOOMING.
WE'VE HAD SOME PROBLEMS,
BUT THEY'RE ALL BEHIND US NOW.
PROBLEMS?
I LOST MY PARTNER A COUPLE
OF MONTHS AGO.
TOM MILES? I SAW THE PICTURE
OF THE TWO OF YOU IN THE HANGAR.
HE, UH, MADE A JUMP ABOUT
200 MILES OUT INTO THE DESERT.
TOM WAS ALWAYS TESTING HIMSELF.
TESTING?
HE TOOK ONE CANTEEN OF WATER,
A COMPASS, AND A KNIFE,
AND HIKED BACK IN.
IT WAS THIS...
YEARLY RITUAL.
UH, SOMETHING WENT WRONG
AND... HE DIED.
SO ALL I CAN DO NOW
IS MAKE TOM'S DREAM...
OF TURNING BLUE DESERT
INTO THE BEST SKYDIVING
SCHOOL IN TEXAS COME TRUE.
WE'RE GONNA GET A NEW
JUMP PLANE, REDO THE HANGAR.
MAYBE EVEN BUILD A NEW
INDOOR TRAINING FACILITY.
HMM.
TOM DESERVES THAT.
IT'S NOT MUCH TO LOOK AT,
BUT, UH, THE A.C. WORKS.
THERE'S A PHONE AND VCR.
AND FOR THE MOST PART,
IT KEEPS THE SNAKES OUT.
- WELL, I'M SURE
IT WILL BE FINE.
- [ Horn Honks ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING WAY OUT HERE
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY?
WELL, I HAD SOME BUSINESS
OVER IN MASON COUNTY, SO...
THOUGHT I MIGHT SEE IF
YOU WANTED TO GET SOME LUNCH.
MEAT LOAF'S ON SPECIAL
AT THE DINER.
UNLESS I'M INTERRUPTING
SOMETHING.
OH, JAROD COCHRAN, THIS IS,
UH, SHERIFF DWIGHT KUNKLE.
- SHERIFF.
- MR. COCHRAN.
JAROD HERE IS OUR LATEST
ADDITION TO THE JUMP SCHOOL.
HUH. WHERE YOU FROM?
OH, HERE AND THERE.
WHICHEVER WAY THE WIND BLOWS.
HOW ABOUT THAT LUNCH?
WELL, I WAS JUST GONNA
SHOW JAROD--
OH, NO, NO.
YOU TWO GO AHEAD.
I'LL BE JUST FINE.
NICE TO MEET YOU, SHERIFF.
COCHRAN.
[ Starts Engine ]
[ Man ]
YOU'RE LATE.
I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR YOU.
- EXCUSE ME?
- I WAS TOLD A TRAVELER
WOULD COME SEEKING TRUTH.
- TOLD BY WHOM?
- THE SKY FATHERS.
WHAT YOU WOULD CALL
A GUT FEELING. THEY SAID
YOU WOULD NEED A GUIDE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
SEE WHAT I MEAN?
HOW'D HE DO THAT?
[ Miss Parker ]
WELL?
[ Broots ]
I RAN HIS PICTURE
THROUGH THE SYSTEM.
IF HE'S ANY KIND OF
CENTRE CONTRACTOR,
THEN HE'S EITHER BEEN DELETED,
OR HE'S OUT
OF OUR CLEARANCE LEVEL.
NOBODY'S OUT OF
MY CLEARANCE LEVEL.
WHAT ABOUT THIS?
TORTURE.
TORTURE?
JAROD'S PLAYING GAMES.
WHY?
BECAUSE HE WANTS TO
GIVE ME AN ANEURYSM.
I DON'T KNOW WHY.
IT'S... JUST
WHAT HE DOES.
WHAT ABOUT THE PICTURE?
I BLEW IT UP THREE
WAYS FROM SUNDAY.
SEE, LET ME SHOW YOU.
ALL I GOT IS A STREET SIGN.
BLACK RIDGE LANE.
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT
HELPS WITH ANYTHING.
MAYBE THE LOCATION.
MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT. MAYBE HE
JUST WANTS TO TORTURE YOU.
BROOTS.
WHAT?
ZOOM IN ON THAT.
[ Miss Parker ]
THE REFLECTION
ON THE WINDSHIELD.
[ Keyboarding ]
[ Miss Parker ]
AGAIN.
ONE MORE TIME, SHARPER.
[ Computer Beeping ]
[ Miss Parker ]
MAINE.
I'LL BE DAMNED!
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
LET ME GET THAT.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
ARE YOU OKAY?
I JUST LOST MY GRIP.
WHY DON'T YOU
COME SIT DOWN?
I'M A LITTLE DIZZY.
UH, CAN I GET YOU SOMETHING?
A GLASS OF WATER OR SOMETHING?
NO, I JUST NEED TO
CATCH MY BREATH.
- CAN I ASK YOU SOMETHING?
- SURE.
- WHO ARE YOU?
- [ Chuckles ]
MY NAME IS JAROD.
ANGELA.
I, UH, NEED TO PUT
THESE THINGS IN THE SHED.
NO, NO. LET ME GET THAT.
- ARE YOU LEARNING TO JUMP?
- UH, NO. ACTUALLY, I JUST
STARTED WORKING HERE.
YOU'RE THE NEW INSTRUCTOR.
YOU SOUND DISAPPOINTED.
I JUST DIDN'T EXPECT CAROL
TO HIRE SOMEONE SO SOON AFTER--
WHAT?
BABY'S KICKING.
HE MUST NOT LIKE THE HEAT.
IT'S A BOY?
HIS FATHER MUST BE
VERY PROUD.
HIS FATHER'S DEAD.
THE FIRST RULE OF SKYDIVING
IS TO RESPECT YOUR EQUIPMENT.
BECAUSE WITHOUT IT, YOU DIE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
[ All ]
HAI.
NOW, THE KEY TO A SAFE JUMP
IS TO OPEN YOUR CHUTE
AT THE RIGHT ALTITUDE.
AND WE DO THAT BY PULLING
THE SILVER HANDLE.
WE DO NOT PULL
THE ORANGE HANDLE.
YOU READY TO GIVE IT A TRY?
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE OVER THE TARGET,
AND WE JUMP.
[ Jarod ]
THE GROUND
IS RUSHING TOWARDS US.
YOU ARE READY
TO OPEN YOUR CHUTE.
YOU PULL
THE SILVER HANDLE!
[ Grunts ]
[ Engine Winds Down ]
I GUESS IT LOST SOMETHIN'
IN THE TRANSLATION.
[ Grunting ]
[ Sydney ]
BENJAMIN THOMAS MILLER.
SINGLE.
RUNS THE LOCAL
BED-AND-BREAKFAST.
I'M LOOKING FOR DIRT,
SYDNEY.
THERE ISN'T ANY.
I DON'T THINK HE'S EVEN
HAD A PARKING TICKET.
[ Sydney ] NOT HIM.
WELL, THEN WHY WOULD JAROD
LEAD US HERE?
HE DIDN'T. THE LITTLE
RED NOTEBOOK WAS
THE MISS PARKER EDITION.
MEANING?
HE WANTED YOU HERE,
ALONE.
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
WHAT?
[ Jarod ]
LET'S SEE. IT'S 12:00
NOON, WHERE YOU ARE.
I RECOMMEND
THE MONTE CRISTO.
YOU CAN'T BEAT A SANDWICH
WITH SYRUP.
IT IS A LITTLE BIT FATTENING.
WHAT THE HEY. YOU COULD STAND
TO PUT ON A FEW POUNDS.
HOW WOULD YOU KNOW?
OH, YOU NEVER KNOW WHO MIGHT BE
PEEKING OVER YOUR TRANSOM.
UH, UH, UH. SETTING BACK
THE BATHROOM SCALE THREE
POUNDS, THAT'S CHEATING.
WHAT DO YOU WANT, JAROD?
SAME THING YOU DO.
ANSWERS.
BY NOW, I WOULD IMAGINE
THAT YOU ARE STAKING OUT
THE GREEN RIDGE DINER,
WHERE BEN MILLER IS
FINISHING UP
HIS USUAL LUNCH.
[ Jarod ]
DIET COLA, B.L.T.,
NO MAYO.
I AM IMPRESSED WITH
YOUR EYE FOR DETAIL.
I CAN SEE I'M GOING
TO HAVE TO SECURE
MY CELL PHONE NUMBER.
MMM. THOSE CENTRE OPERATORS,
THEY WILL TRANSFER YOU ANYWHERE
WITH THE RIGHT CLEARANCE CODE.
YOU SHOULD
LOOK INTO THAT.
YEAH, I WOULD. EXCEPT
I'M TOO BUSY CHASING GHOSTS.
- WELL, BEN MILLER,
HE'S MORE OF A SKELETON.
- [ Miss Parker ] SKELETON?
CHECK YOUR CLOSET LATELY?
GET OUT.
EXCUSE ME?
TRY THE MONTE CRISTO.
I HEAR IT'S EXCELLENT.
READY?
HAI!
SAYONARA.
[ Yelling ]
READY?
HAI!
SAYONARA!
[ Yells ]
HEY.
WHAT'S THIS FOR?
FOR LUNATICS.
[ Wind Blowing ]
[ Jarod Laughing ]
THIS WAS AWESOME.
YOU KNOW, THIS THING WOULD
WORK REALLY WELL IN THE SNOW.
[ Clears Throat ]
YEAH.
CAROL BATES SAYS
YOU USED TO BE A SKYDIVER.
YOU MISS IT?
IT?
THE ADRENALINE RUSH.
PUSHING THE ENVELOPE AND
LIVING TO TELL ABOUT IT.
WELL, SOMETIMES THAT ENVELOPE'S
A LITTLE THINNER THAN IT LOOKS.
YOU TALKING ABOUT TOM MILES?
I TOOK HIM UP THAT DAY.
YOU KNOW, THE SAD PART IS,
THAT WAS GONNA BE HIS LAST JUMP.
ISN'T IT A LITTLE DIFFICULT
TO RUN A JUMP SCHOOL
IF YOU DON'T JUMP?
HEY. THIS SCHOOL HAS JUST
BARELY EKED BY FOR YEARS.
TOM DIDN'T CARE ABOUT
ANY OF THAT. HE WAS JUST
A PLAIN OLD SIMPLE GUY.
ALL HE REALLY CARED ABOUT WAS
HIS WIFE AND THAT BABY COMIN'.
[ Sighs ]
HE LOVED THIS PLACE.
HE JUST WANTED TO HAVE A CHANCE
TO SHARE IT WITH HIS SON...
BEFORE SOMEBODY COME ALONG
AND SPOILED IT.
EXPECT HE PUSHED THAT ENVELOPE
ONE TOO MANY TIMES.
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND, TOM
WAS A SURVIVAL EXPERT.
HE SUCCESSFULLY MADE THAT JUMP
AND TREK INTO THE DESERT
A DOZEN TIMES BEFORE HE DIED.
JUST 'CAUSE YOU
CAN DO SOMETHING,
DOESN'T MEAN YOU SHOULD.
BUT, HEY, IT'S THE DESERT.
STRANGE THINGS
CAN HAPPEN OUT THERE.
[ Man ]
SO MANY LIES, SO LITTLE TIME.
YOU NEED SOME SODA.
- WHO ARE YOU?
- TWO FEATHERS, SON OF
WAR EAGLE. EVER HEARD OF ME?
NO.
THAT'S 'CAUSE EVERYBODY
CALLS ME ERNIE.
I'M GUESSING IT'S A PEACH.
- [ Ernie ] HOW.
- [ Jarod Exhales ]
WHAT IS IT YOU WANT?
I TOLD YOU I WAS SENT
TO BE YOUR GUIDE.
YES.
THE SKY FATHERS WHO
SPEAK TO YOU FROM YOUR GUT.
BINGO.
WHERE ARE YOU
GUIDING ME TO?
THE TRUTH.
I KNOW IT'S OVERWHELMING,
BUT I'M AN INDIAN, SO WHAT
DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
MEET ME TONIGHT.
WE CAN TALK LATER.
WAIT.
- HOW WILL I FIND YOU?
- FOLLOW THE PATH
OF THE IRON HORSE.
- THE WHAT?
- THE TRAIN TRACKS. DIDN'T YOU
EVER SEE A JOHN WAYNE MOVIE?
AND BRING SOME OF THAT
LEFTOVER MEAT LOAF WITH YOU.
- WHAT MEAT LOAF?
- [ Wind Blows ]
[ Lamp Shatters ]
[ Exhales ]
HUH.
[ Knocking On Door ]
[ Jarod ]
I DON'T KNOW WHO YOU
THINK YOU'RE DEALING WITH,
BUT I'M GETTING PRETTY TIRED
OF YOUR MAGIC TR--
I HAVE TO ADMIT.
I'VE HAD WARMER WELCOMES.
DID YOU SEE AN OLD MAN?
HUH.
NEVER MIND.
I, UM, WANTED TO APOLOGIZE
FOR THE WAY I ACTED YESTERDAY.
- OH, IT'S OKAY.
- NO, YOU'RE NEW HERE. THERE'S
NO WAY YOU COULD'VE KNOWN.
AND... I'D LIKE TO
MAKE IT UP TO YOU.
HOW ABOUT
A HOME-COOKED DINNER TONIGHT?
THAT WOULD BE WONDERFUL.
GREAT.
HOPE YOU LIKE MEAT LOAF.
[ Door Creaking ]
BE RIGHT WITH YOU.
NOW, WHAT CAN I DO FOR--
I WAS HOPING YOU'D COME.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU LOOK JUST LIKE HER.
LIKE WHO?
YOUR MOTHER.
THANK YOU.
I'M SURE THIS
WON'T TAKE LONG.
SHERIFF, I WAS WONDERING
IF I MIGHT HAVE A MINUTE.
MR. COCHRAN, I'M DUE IN
DALLAS IN ABOUT THREE HOURS.
MAYBE SOME OTHER TIME.
OH, OKAY. I JUST WANTED TO ASK
YOU A QUESTION ABOUT TOM MILES.
BUT WE'LL DO IT
ANOTHER TIME.
WHAT ABOUT TOM?
WELL, I UNDERSTAND THAT
YOU FOUND HIS BODY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MUST HAVE BEEN
A PRETTY GRUESOME SIGHT.
BODY OUT THERE IN THE DESERT
FOR, WHAT, THREE DAYS?
FOUR.
FOUR, UGH.
SEE, WHAT
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IS...
WHY WOULD A SURVIVAL EXPERT
LIKE TOM MILES ALLOW HIMSELF
TO DIE OF DEHYDRATION?
WHAT ARE YOU SO INTERESTED
IN A DEAD MAN FOR?
WELL, I MET HIS WIDOW.
SEEMED LIKE A VERY NICE LADY.
NEVER MIND.
HAVE A VERY NICE DAY.
OH, SHERIFF,
ONE OTHER QUICK QUESTION.
WAS THERE AN AUTOPSY
DONE ON THE BODY?
OF COURSE. JUST BECAUSE
WE LIVE IN THE BACKWATERS
DOESN'T MEAN WE'RE BACKWOODS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
[ Woman ]
SHE ATE THE WHOLE MEAT LOAF?
WELL, THEN IT IS NO WONDER
SHE CAN'T FIND PANTY HOSE...
TO FIT THOSE THICK THIGHS
OF HERS THEN, HUH?
[ Door Opens ]
YEAH.
[ Chuckles ]
OH. I'LL CALL YOU LATER.
[ Jarod ]
AFTERNOON.
BUDDY SLOCUM JR.
I REPRESENT THE SOUTHWEST
REGIONAL OFFICE OF
THE INTERNAL REVENUE SERVICE.
I.R.S.?
I NEED TO HAVE A WORD WITH
A SHERIFF DWIGHT KNUCKLE.
KUNKLE. THE SHERIFF'S NAME
IS KUNKLE.
SHERIFF KNUCK-- KUNKLE
IS IN DALLAS FOR THE AFTERNOON.
WELL, THAT COULD
POSE A DILEMMA.
BUDDY. MAYBE I CAN HELP YOU.
YES. AS A MATTER OF FACT,
MAYBE YOU CAN.
DO YOU HAVE SOME INFORMATION
ON A MR. THOMAS MILES?
WELL, HE'S DEAD.
NOT AS FAR AS THE I.R.S.
IS CONCERNED.
WELL, THANKS AGAIN, MA'AM.
[ Angela ]
TOM WAS GONNA FINISH THE BABY'S
ROOM WHEN HE GOT BACK.
HE MUST HAVE BEEN VERY EXCITED
ABOUT BECOMING A FATHER.
[ Angela ]
IT WAS HIS WHOLE WORLD.
BEFORE TOM WENT OFF
ON THE LAST JUMP,
HE TOLD ME HOW IMPORTANT IT WAS
FOR HIM TO BE A GOOD FATHER,
TO TEACH OUR SON ABOUT LIFE.
HE USED TO SAY THAT
LIFE WAS MEANT TO BE LIVED,
AND DEATH WASN'T
SOMETHING TO BE AFRAID OF.
IS THAT WHY HE MADE
THOSE JUMPS INTO THE DESERT?
CAROL'S RIGHT.
IT'S IMPORTANT THAT HIS SON
KNOW WHO HIS FATHER WAS.
- THE THINGS HE CARED ABOUT.
- CAROL SAID THAT.
SHE SAID THAT IF THE SCHOOL
CLOSED, THEN TOM'S DEATH
WOULD BE MEANINGLESS.
- THANK GOD
FOR TOM'S INSURANCE MONEY.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WE'RE GONNA USE IT
TO REBUILD THE JUMP SCHOOL.
HASN'T BEEN EASY FOR HER.
[ Jarod ]
BECAUSE OF THE BUSINESS?
BECAUSE OF THE HISTORY
BETWEEN THEM.
- THE HISTORY?
- CAROL AND TOM WERE TOGETHER
LONG BEFORE WE MET.
THEY GREW APART, FELL OUT.
HE USED TO SAY
SHE WAS UNHAPPY, BUT HE
NEVER SPOKE BAD ABOUT HER.
I THINK IT'S NICE
THAT SHE WANTS TO KEEP
HIS DREAM ALIVE.
[ Beeping ]
JUST TELL ME YOU'VE GIVEN UP.
[ Young Jarod ]
NO.
ADMIT IT TO YOURSELF
AND I'LL MAKE THIS STOP!
NOT FOR ME.
[ Young Jarod ]
I'LL NEVER GIVE UP.
[ Echoing ]
NEVER GIVE UP.
MR. TWO FEATHERS?
UH, MR. TWO FEATHERS?
ERNIE?
OH!
[ Gasps ]
WOULD YOU PLEASE
STOP DOING THAT?
I SEE YOU REMEMBERED.
THANK YOU.
YOUR MEAT LOAF.
YOU LEFT YOUR HAT.
THANK YOU.
SIT DOWN.
IS THIS WHERE YOU LIVE?
YOU EXPECTED A TEEPEE?
IT'S 43 FEET OF GOOD LIVING,
SATELLITE TV.
I EVEN GET DIRTY MOVIES.
- COMPLIMENTS OF UNCLE SAM.
- UNCLE WHO?
THERE WAS A QUESTION ABOUT
A CERTAIN PIECE OF TRIBAL LAND
AND WHO OWNED IT.
AND THIS WAS YOUR SETTLEMENT?
I WOULD'VE SETTLED
FOR A NEW HAT.
WHITE PEOPLE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
WE LOST THE COUNTRY.
YOU TOLD ME BEFORE THAT YOU WERE
GOING TO GUIDE ME TO THE TRUTH.
OH, THAT.
MY FAMILY'S LIVED UNDER THIS
SKY FOR OVER SEVEN GENERATIONS.
I'VE SEEN MANY THINGS
IN THE DESERT.
THINGS?
I FOUND THE BODY OF THE MAN
WHO WALKS ON CLOUDS.
I THOUGHT SHERIFF KUNKLE
FOUND TOM MILES'S BODY.
IT WOULDN'T BE SMART FOR
AN INDIAN TO RIDE INTO TOWN...
WITH A WHITE WAR HERO
STRAPPED ACROSS
THE GRILLE OF HIS MOTOR HOME.
WHY WOULD A SURVIVAL EXPERT LIKE
TOM MILES DIE OF DEHYDRATION...
WHEN ALL THOSE YUCCA PLANTS
WERE AROUND HIM?
WHEN I SAW HIS FACE,
I KNEW WHAT HAPPENED.
ACCORDING
TO THE POLICE REPORT,
THE WOUNDS ON HIS FACE
WERE INFLICTED BY AN ANIMAL.
IT WAS NO ANIMAL.
IT WAS HIS MADNESS.
I'VE SEEN IT ONLY
ONE TIME BEFORE IN MY LIFE--
DURING THE VISION QUEST.
VISION QUEST?
A YOUNG MAN OF AGE
DRINKS FROM THE ROOT
OF THE BELLADONNA PLANT...
IN THE HOPES OF
GOING TO THE WORLD BEYOND.
IF THE MIXTURE IS WRONG,
HE COULD LOSE HIMSELF, GO MAD.
BELLADONNA.
WHO ELSE KNOWS ABOUT THIS PLANT?
ANYONE WHO'S LIVED THEIR LIFE
IN THE DESERT WOULD KNOW.
I SEE YOUR GUT
TALKS TO YOU TOO.
HMM. THIS IS PRETTY GOOD.
JAROD WORKED THE PLACE
ABOUT A MONTH.
HE WAS QUITE
THE FIX-IT MAN.
HE'S A GENIUS.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
BUT HE COULD FIX A TRACTOR,
TALK YOUR EAR OFF.
THAT FELLA WAS ALWAYS
ASKIN' QUESTIONS.
I DIDN'T COME HERE
TO TALK ABOUT JAROD.
WELL, THAT'S FUNNY. ALL HE
WANTED TO TALK ABOUT WAS YOU.
ME?
HE SAID YOU TWO HAD
GROWN UP TOGETHER.
SEEMED DISAPPOINTED
WHEN I DIDN'T KNOW MUCH.
GUESS YOUR MOTHER NEVER
TOLD YOU ABOUT THIS PLACE.
NO.
SHE DIDN'T.
SHE CAME HERE EXACTLY
THIS TIME EVERY YEAR.
SHE LOVED THE SPRING.
SHE SAID SHE LIKED
WHAT IT DID TO THE WORLD.
AUNT DOROTHY.
EXCUSE ME?
SHE USED TO TELL ME
SHE WAS VISITING HER SISTER.
AH.
I'M SURE SHE HAD HER REASONS.
WHEN YOUR MOTHER DIDN'T
SHOW UP, I GOT WORRIED.
I NEVER KNEW EXACTLY HOW--
I WAS PRETTY YOUNG.
BUT I DO REMEMBER THAT
HER DEATH WAS, UH, SUDDEN.
IS THERE ANYTHING OF HERS--
IT WOULD MEAN A LOT TO ME
IF I COULD SEE WHERE SHE STAYED.
[ Crockett ]
LOOK HERE, CAROL,
IT'S JUST NOT WORKIN' OUT!
I HAVE TO MOVE ON.
ONCE WE GET THE NEW PLANE
FROM PHOENIX, WE'RE FINE.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T GO BACK THERE!
[ Rifling Papers ]
[ Woman ]
TASCO SPORT ADVENTURE.
[ Jarod ] I'M TRYING TO
PUT TOGETHER A VACATION.
YOU COME HIGHLY RECOMMENDED.
YES, SIR. AT TASCO
SPORT ADVENTURE, YOU GET
THE VACATION OF A LIFETIME.
BUNGEE JUMPING AND THEN GOLF,
HELICOPTER SNOW SKIING IN
THE ANDES, OR SHARK HUNTING
OFF THE BARRIER REEF.
ACTUALLY,
I HAD SKYDIVING IN MIND.
YOU'RE IN LUCK! IN TWO MONTHS,
WE'RE OPENING A SKYDIVING SCHOOL
NEAR EL PASO.
[ Jarod ]
WELL, THAT SOUNDS INTERESTING.
VERY INTERESTING.
- UH, I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
- THANKS FOR CALLING.
[ Tools Clanking ]
[ Wrench Racheting ]
OW!
[ Slams Tools Down ]
PIECE OF CRAP!
OH, COME ON, CROCKETT.
GOD! OH--
[ Inhales, Coughs ]
PLANE ONLY HAS TO
LAST A FEW MORE DAYS.
YOU SCARED ME THERE, BUB.
WHY?
BECAUSE YOU THOUGHT I WAS
CAROL? SHE SCARES YOU,
DOESN'T SHE, CROCKETT?
OR SHOULD I SAY ANGUS?
ANGUS MARIN?
WHO ARE YOU?
SOMEBODY WHO FOUND OUT
YOU'RE A WANTED MAN...
AND IS GOING TO USE IT
TO THEIR ADVANTAGE.
JUST LIKE CAROL DID.
YOU SOUND LIKE YOU HAVE BEEN
DRINKING THAT HORSE LINIMENT.
I KNOW CAROL'S USING ANGELA
TO GET TO TOM MILES'S
INSURANCE MONEY.
SO SHE CAN REFURBISH
THIS JUMP SCHOOL...
AND INCREASE THE PRICE
THAT TASCO ADVENTURES
IS WILLING TO PAY FOR IT.
I ALSO KNOW YOU ARE GETTING 25%
OF WHATEVER CAROL'S STAKE IS
IN THE SALE.
WHAT I DON'T KNOW IS WHY.
IS IT BECAUSE YOU KNOW
SHE KILLED TOM MILES?
OR BECAUSE YOU HELPED HER?
THIS WAS HER ROOM.
[ Ben ]
I HAVEN'T TOUCHED ANYTHING
SINCE SHE LEFT.
- [ Soft Chuckle ]
- WHAT?
LOOKING AT YOU STANDING THERE,
I THOUGHT FOR A MINUTE
I SAW CATHERINE AGAIN.
YOU CALL IF YOU NEED ANYTHING.
SEE, TOM AND CAROL COME
OUT HERE AS YOUNG LOVERS,
BOUGHT THIS PLACE TOGETHER.
ONLY IT WAS 60-40,
TOM'S FAVOR.
AFTER THEY BROKE UP,
HE MET ANGELA
AND GOT MARRIED.
HE WAS HERE FOR LIFE,
AND CAROL KNEW IT.
SHE WANTED TO SELL,
BUT HE COULD NEVER
GET THE CASH TOGETHER.
BY THAT TIME, THE PLACE
HAD GOTTEN SO RUN DOWN TILL--
40% OF NOTHING'S
STILL NOTHIN'.
AND THAT'S WHEN THE PEOPLE
FROM TASCO CAME AROUND.
WAVIN' LONG GREEN.
BUT TOM DIDN'T
WANT THE PLACE DESTROYED.
SO, WHEN CAROL COULDN'T
GET HER MONEY AND GET OUT,
SHE JUST SHUT DOWN.
THEN WHAT HAPPENED?
SHE CAME OUT TO THE HANGAR
THE MORNING OF THE JUMP,
SWITCHED TOM'S CANTEEN.
I DIDN'T THINK ANYTHING
ABOUT IT AT THE TIME.
IT DIDN'T MEAN ANYTHING THEN.
BUT LATER ON, AFTER HE DIED,
I GOT TO THINKIN' ABOUT IT.
WHEN I ASKED HER--
SHE THREATENED TO TURN YOU IN
TO THE POLICE.
SHE OFFERED ME A PERCENTAGE,
JUST TO HELP HER GET
THE PLACE TURNED AROUND
FOR THE SALE TO TASCO.
WE LOOKED AT EACH OTHER
AND JUST KNEW.
WILLING TO HATE EACH OTHER
LONG ENOUGH TO GET OUR PAYOFFS
AND GET ON WITH OUR LIVES.
WELL, UNFORTUNATELY
FOR TOM MILES, HE WON'T
BE ABLE TO GET ON WITH HIS.
[ Wrench Clinking ]
[ Southern Accent ]
YES. I'D LIKE TO ORDER
A SLAB OF BEEF RIBS.
WELL, THAT'S FANTASTIC.
BUT I'D LIKE THEM RAW.
YES, RAW.
SO, LET'S GET THIS STRAIGHT.
IF I ARRIVE IN PHOENIX FIRST,
I GET THE PLANE?
WELL, I'LL GET THERE FIRST.
HAVE YOU SEEN CROCKETT?
NO.
IS THERE SOMETHING WRONG?
I JUST GOT A CALL FROM PHOENIX.
THERE'S ANOTHER PARTY
INTERESTED IN THE PLANE.
THEY'RE GONNA MAKE A DEAL
WITH THE FIRST ONE WHO SHOWS UP!
OH. WELL, SHOULDN'T BE MORE
THAN A SIX OR SEVEN-HOUR DRIVE.
I DON'T HAVE SIX
OR SEVEN HOURS.
WELL, I COULD FLY YOU.
YOU'RE A PILOT?
MM-HMM.
HOW LONG TILL
WE CAN TAKE OFF?
TWENTY MINUTES.
[ Ben ]
HOW 'BOUT SOME COFFEE?
[ Miss Parker ] THANK YOU.
HOW'D YOU SLEEP?
WELL.
BETTER THAN THAT,
ACTUALLY.
THIS PLACE TENDS
TO DO THAT TO PEOPLE.
SURE YOU DON'T WANT TO TAKE
SOME OF HER THINGS WITH YA?
NO. I HAVE
EVERYTHING I NEED.
BESIDES, THIS IS
WHERE SHE BELONGS.
YOU WERE IN LOVE WITH HER,
WEREN'T YOU?
YOUR MOTHER WAS
A VERY SPECIAL WOMAN.
THERE WAS A PART OF HER
I KNEW BETTER THAN ANYONE.
BUT THERE WAS A PART OF HER
SHE KEPT HIDDEN.
SEPARATE.
DID SHE EVER
TALK ABOUT HIM?
NO. SHE LEFT IT ALL BEHIND
WHEN SHE CAME HERE.
BUT... SHE ALWAYS MISSED
HER LITTLE GIRL.
I'LL GET YOU SOME BREAKFAST.
THANK YOU.
WHY ARE WE
HEADING NORTH?
WEATHER RADAR.
THERE'S A STORM FRONT
MOVING IN FROM THE SOUTHWEST,
SO I FIGURED IT WOULD BE SAFER
IF WE FLEW AROUND IT.
HOW LONG TO PHOENIX?
ABOUT AN HOUR,
HOUR AND A HALF.
[ Engine Sputters ]
WHAT'S WRONG?
WE'RE LOSING PRESSURE.
I THINK IT'S THE FUEL PUMP.
THIS TERRAIN IS MUCH TOO
DANGEROUS TO LAND.
IF THE OVERFLOW OF FUEL
SHOULD REACH THE ENGINE,
THE WHOLE PLANE COULD EXPLODE.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO JUMP.
JUMP?
JUMP.
RELAX. WE'RE SKYDIVING
INSTRUCTORS, REMEMBER?
WHAT THE HELL DO YOU MEAN
HE WAS POLITE?
YOU JUST GIVE OUT CONFIDENTIAL
CRIME SCENE FILES...
TO ANYBODY WHO
WALKS IN HERE WITH
A SMILE ON THEIR FACE?
HE SAID HE WAS
WITH THE I.R.S.
DAMN IT, AIDA. I'VE
TOLD YOU A MILLION TIMES.
POLICE BUSINESS IS--
[ Jarod On Radio ]
ALPHA-TANGO-997.
THIS IS A MAYDAY.
I REPEAT, THIS IS A MAYDAY.
OUR AIRCRAFT IS ON FIRE.
WE'RE GOING TO PARACHUTE
APPROXIMATELY 37 MILES
DUE NORTH OF FORT HANCOCK.
MAYDAY. MAYDAY.
[ Transmission Turns Off ]
997-- THAT'S CAROL'S PLANE.
YOU CALL THE CIVIL AIR PATROL.
DISPATCH SEARCH AND RESCUE
RIGHT NOW.
GOING MY WAY, SHERIFF?
[ Grunting ]
ARE YOU OKAY?
AH, I THINK I BROKE MY LEG.
HEY.
[ Grunting ]
DON'T WORRY.
SOMEBODY'LL FIND US.
[ Grunts ]
I'M NOT SO SURE.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
THERE'S A CHANCE THAT
NOBODY KNOWS WE'RE OUT HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW IF THE MAYDAY
TRANSMISSION MADE IT OUT.
[ Sighs ]
WELL, WHAT THE HELL
DO YOU SUGGEST WE DO?
[ Jarod ]
THERE'S ABOUT SIX OR
SEVEN HOURS LEFT OF SUNLIGHT.
IF YOU TRAVEL LIGHTLY,
YOU CAN MAKE IT
TO FORT HANCOCK BY DARK.
- ME? WHAT IF I DON'T MAKE IT?
- YOU'LL MAKE IT.
[ Sighs ]
HEAD DUE SOUTH.
AND HERE'S A FULL
CANTEEN OF WATER.
MAKE SURE YOU DRINK
PLENTY OF IT.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT TO
END UP LIKE TOM.
I'LL SEE YOU SOON.
COUNT ON IT.
[ Voice Whispering ]
CAROL.
[ Chanting ]
- [ Voice Whispering ]
CAROL.
- [ Echoing ] WHO'S THERE?
[ Gasps ]
[ Voice Whispering ]
CAROL.
WHAT'S HAPPENING TO ME?
[ Jarod ]
SAME THING THAT HAPPENED
TO TOM MILES.
- TOM?
- NOW, MAYBE YOU CAN IMAGINE HOW
TOM FELT THOSE LAST MOMENTS.
DYING OUT HERE, ALL ALONE.
TOM. TOM, I'M SORRY.
YOU TOOK HIS CANTEEN,
AND YOU POISONED IT
WITH BELLADONNA.
THE HARDER THE SUN BORE DOWN,
THE MORE DELIRIOUS HE BECAME
WITH EVERY TAINTED DRINK.
AND EVERY MINUTE THAT PASSED WAS
JUST ANOTHER AGONIZING MOMENT...
WHEN HE REALIZED HE
WOULD NEVER SEE HIS BABY
THAT HE WANTED SO MUCH.
IT GOT SO BAD THAT
HE WANDERED IN CIRCLES.
HE CLAWED AT HIS OWN BODY
TO FIGHT OFF THE MADNESS
THAT YOU CREATED FOR HIM.
[ Echoing ]
THE MADNESS THAT
YOU CREATED FOR HIM.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
NO.
IT WAS A SCHOOL
AND A FAMILY.
YOU TOOK THAT AWAY!
YOU JUST GAVE IT TO HER!
[ Crying ]
TILL THERE WAS NOTHING
LEFT FOR ME.
SO YOU LEFT A WIDOW BEHIND AND
A BABY TO BE BORN FATHERLESS.
TOM, I JUST WANTED
WHAT I DESERVED.
SOMETHING TELLS ME YOU'RE
GOING TO GET JUST THAT.
[ Cell Phone Rings ]
HELLO, JAROD.
WITH INSTINCTS LIKE THAT,
YOU'LL CATCH ME YET.
NOT IF YOU KEEP THROWING ME
OFF THE TRAIL.
OH, I DIDN'T THROW YOU OFF.
I JUST PUT YOU
ON A DIFFERENT ONE.
IS THAT ALL YOU DO, JAROD?
DIG UP THE PAST?
THAT'S EASY FOR YOU TO SAY.
YOU HAVE ONE.
ALTHOUGH, IT'S NOT QUITE
WHAT YOU THOUGHT IT WAS, IS IT?
HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
[ Angela ]
OKAY, SWEETIE.
LET'S GO NIGHT-NIGHT.
[ Fussing ]
HO, WHITE MAN.
CAME BY TO SAY GOOD-BYE,
THANK YOU.
WELL, SO LONG,
AND YOU'RE WELCOME.
WHEN WE FIRST MET, YOU
TOLD ME YOU WERE GONNA
HELP ME DISCOVER THE TRUTH.
I WAS KIND OF HOPING
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN
ABOUT MYSELF.
ABOUT WHO I AM.
WE EACH TAKE A JOURNEY
WE'RE MEANT TO TAKE.
FOR SOME, IT'S CLEAR.
FOR OTHERS, NOT SO CLEAR.
AM I GOING THE RIGHT WAY?
JUST KEEP LISTENING
TO YOUR GUT.
[ Wind Blows ]
[ Mews ]