THE DECEASED
IS NOT TO BE PICKED UP
UNTIL THIS COMING SATURDAY?
YES, JUST AFTER DAWN.
UM, DETAILS FOR THE ARRANGEMENTS
ARE ALL THERE.
AND A CHOICE OF CASKET
AND CEMETERY.
I WOULD PREFER
A QUIET SERVICE.
OF COURSE, MISS WILL.
THE DECEASED WAS YOUR FATHER?
IS MY FATHER.
IF YOUR FATHER
IS STILL ALIVE, THEN WHY--
JUST HAVE A CASKET READY
SATURDAY MORNING.
PLEASE.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Young Jarod ]
I DON'T WANNA DIE.
BUT I KNOW IT'S TOO LATE
TO CHANGE ANY OF THAT.
[ Young Sydney ]
THERE'S NOTHING
YOU WANNA CONFESS?
[ Young Jarod ]
YOU KEEP ASKING ME
FOR THE TRUTH...
WHEN THAT'S ALL
I'VE EVER GIVEN YOU.
[ Young Sydney ]
EVEN IN THE FACE OF DEATH,
YOU MAINTAIN YOUR INNOCENCE.
YES.
HE'S INNOCENT, SYDNEY.
AN INNOCENT MAN
IS GOING TO DIE.
[ Man ]
OFF THE BUS! MOVE IT!
MOVE IT! MOVE IT!
YOU HEARD THE MAN,
SIDE BY SIDE!
LINE UP AND SHUT UP!
LET'S GO! MOVE IT!
WELCOME TO OAKFIELD
PENITENTIARY, GENTLEMEN.
SOUND OFF.
[ Man Narrating ]
[ Sydney ] THERE'S BEEN
A BREAKTHROUGH CONCERNING
JAROD'S NEXT DESTINATION.
"TOP HAT CAFÉ PAY PHONE.
JANUARY, WEEKEND OF THE 15th,
MEETING WITH COWBOY
REGARDING PARKER BROTHERS."
I DON'T HAVE A BROTHER,
DO I, SYDNEY?
THAT I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT WE DO KNOW IS THE 15th
IS THIS COMING WEEKEND,
AND THAT NOTE IS DISTINCTLY
WRITTEN IN JAROD'S HAND.
- CLEANUP TEAM FIND THIS?
- IN JAROD'S LAST LAIR,
STUCK IN THE TOILET PIPE
AFTER HAVING BEEN FLUSHED.
OKAY, THE ARRANGEMENTS
ARE ALL SET, SYDNEY.
UH, OH, UH--
GO ON, BROOTS.
WHAT ARRANGEMENTS?
MR. BROOTS
WILL BE JOINING US.
UH, THE DIRECTOR THINKS
A LITTLE TECHNICAL SUPPORT
MIGHT HELP.
TECHNICAL SUPPORT?
WELL, SHE THINKS
THAT SOME DETAILS
ARE GETTING OVERLOOKED,
THAT YOU AND SYDNEY ARE MAYBE
A LITTLE TOO EMOTIONALLY
INVOLVED WITH JAROD.
AND YOU'RE THE FIX?
WELL--
[ Snickers ]
AN-- AN OBJECTIVE EYE, MAYBE.
UH, I'LL GET THE CAR.
♪♪ [ Whistling ]
DULLER THAN HOCKEY
IN SEPTEMBER.
[ Man ]
NEVER FORGET, MR. BRADLEY,
THAT IN THIS PLACE,
WE ARE DEALING STRICTLY WITH
A MENTALITY OF DESPERATION.
A DESPERATION BORN
FROM BEING LOCKED DOWN
IN A 10-BY-10 CELL...
FOR 20, 30 YEARS,
SOMETIMES LONGER.
I WOULD SAY THAT DESPERATION
WAS A GOOD WORD FOR THAT, SIR.
A MAN'S FIBER, IF HE
HAD ANY TO BEGIN WITH,
QUICKLY FRAYS.
IT'S YOUR JOB TO KEEP
THOSE FRAYED ENDS KNOTTED.
YOU'RE HERE BECAUSE
OF YOUR EXPERIENCE
UNDER DURESS.
WITH THE CARL WILL EXECUTION
ON SATURDAY, THERE PROMISES
TO BE PLENTY OF THAT.
SOUNDS LIKE HE'S GOT
ALL THE CLASSIC SYMPTOMS
OF A CAREER CRIMINAL.
CARL WILL HAS A CRIMINAL RECORD
DATING BACK 30 YEARS.
CAR THEFT,
ARMED ROBBERY,
A DOZEN OTHER FELONY VIOLATIONS
LEADING TO THE BRUTAL MURDER
OF A FELLOW INMATE.
YOU WORKED FOLSOM
DURING THE '91 INMATE RIOT.
I'M PROUD TO SAY
THAT WE SQUELCHED THAT ONE
WITH EXTREME PREJUDICE.
WE DON'T WIPE NOSES.
WE DON'T LEND SHOULDERS
TO CRY ON.
WE MANAGE, MR. BRADLEY,
WITH, AS YOU SAY,
EXTREME PREJUDICE.
I'M SURE THE EXECUTION
WILL SEND A MESSAGE
TO THE ENTIRE POPULATION.
THAT'S THE IDEA.
HE'S NOT IN THERE,
AND NONE OF THE LOCALS
HAVE SEEN HIM.
MM-HMM.
[ Clears Throat ]
MAYBE WE SHOULD
STAKE HIM OUT.
THEY DIDN'T LET YOU
HAVE A WEAPON, DID THEY?
NO.
AND WHERE DO YOU PROPOSE
WE DO OUR STAKEOUT?
RIGHT THERE.
[ Man ] SO, JAROD,
HOW MANY MEN DID THEY RUN
ON A SHIFT AT FOLSOM?
OH, WE HAD A CREW
OF 35 DURING THE WEEK,
SLIGHTLY LESS ON THE WEEKENDS.
I HEAR WARDEN HARPER'S
A TOUGH MAN.
HIS NAME IS HOPKINS.
RIGHT, HOPKINS.
MORRIS.
AH, JAROD BRADLEY,
TOMMY LARSON.
BRADLEY.
THE GUY FROM FOLSOM?
AND ALL POINTS WEST.
TOMMY CAN
SHOW YOU AROUND.
UH, KEEP BOTH EYES OPEN.
THE ANIMALS
ARE GETTING RESTLESS.
LET ME TAKE YOU OUT,
SHOW YOU THE MAIN YARD.
MOST OF THE POPULATION
SPENDS FOUR OR FIVE HOURS
A DAY HERE.
DIFFERENT ZOO,
SAME ROUTINE.
GOTTA MAKE SURE
THEY DON'T KILL EACH OTHER
AND HERD 'EM IN AT THE BELL.
SEEMS TENSE.
YEAH, WELL, IT'LL EASE UP
AFTER THE, UH, THE EVENT.
THE EVENT?
EXECUTION.
YOU GET IT UP CLOSE
AND PERSONAL.
NEW GUY GETS DEATH WATCH.
WHY ME?
I DON'T KNOW
HOW IT WAS AT FOLSOM,
BUT AROUND HERE,
IT'S CONSIDERED BAD LUCK TO GET
TOO CLOSE TO A CONDEMNED MAN.
THEY MAKE THE NEW GUY DO IT.
[ Man ]
WALKIN' THROUGH.
IS THAT HIM?
[ Buzzer Buzzes ]
- LARSON.
- WHAT?
IS THAT THE MAN
THEY'RE GOING TO KILL?
YEAH, THAT'S HIM.
[ Miss Parker ]
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
YOU'RE BOOKED UP?
WHO THE HELL WOULD
PURPOSELY STAY...
AT THE PARK PLACE MOTEL?
WELL, WE GOT A CONVENTION.
THE ELECTRIC COMPANY
BOOKED THE ENTIRE FACILITY.
DO YOU KNOW THIS MAN?
JAROD.
YEAH, HE COMES THROUGH HERE
EVERY NOW AND THEN.
MATTER OF FACT, HE SAID
SOMETHING ABOUT PASSING THROUGH
THIS WEEKEND.
GOT A MEETING OR SOMETHING.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU BEING FRIENDS OF HIS
AND ALL, YOU AND YOUR BROTHER
AND-- AND YOUR DAD,
YOU CAN STAY
IN THE CELEBRITY ROOM THAT
I KEEP OPEN FOR SPECIAL GUESTS.
CELEBRITY ROOM.
BURL IVES STAYED HERE ONCE.
WE EVEN HAD MAMA CASS.
NOT TO MENTION
THAT OSMOND BOY.
YOU KNOW,
THE GOOFY-LOOKING ONE
WITH THE-- THE BIG EARS.
YOU KNOW, I BET
IT WASN'T DONNY.
MAIL CALL
FOR INMATE COCKRAN.
THANKS.
OH, I'M SORRY.
I WASN'T WATCHING
WHERE I WAS GOING.
YOU OKAY, BOSS?
I'M FINE.
AND THE NAME IS JAROD,
MR.--
COCKRAN, HENRY.
WELL, IT'S NICE
TO MEET YOU, HENRY.
[ Buzzer Buzzes ]
YOU'RE NEW AROUND HERE.
YES, I AM.
AND YOU?
OH, I'VE BEEN WALKING
THESE HALLS FOR 27 YEARS.
THAT'S A LONG TIME.
THERE ISN'T A COCKROACH
I'M NOT ON A FIRST NAME
BASIS WITH.
IS THAT MAIL FROM HOME?
UH, MY WIFE.
SHE WRITES ME EVERY WEEK
LIKE CLOCKWORK.
SENDS ME SEEDS
FOR MY GARDEN.
THESE SHOULD BE MARIGOLDS.
COCKRAN.
YOU GOT SOMEWHERE
TO BE, OLD-TIMER?
KITCHEN, BOSS.
THAT WHAT THEY CALL
EXTREME PREJUDICE AT FOLSOM?
YOU HAVE TO KNOW
YOUR ENEMY.
[ Male Reporter ]
TONIGHT WE BRING YOU
A STORY OF LOVE, LAW...
AND ITS CONNECTION BETWEEN
A MAN ON DEATH ROW...
AND A DAUGHTER WHOSE LIFE
HAS BEEN A FIGHT TO FREE HIM.
TEN YEARS AGO, CARL WILL,
A CAREER CRIMINAL,
WAS SENTENCED TO FIVE YEARS
FOR CAR THEFT.
ONLY WEEKS AWAY FROM PAROLE,
HE WAS INVOLVED
IN A BLOODY ALTERCATION...
INSIDE OAKFIELD PENITENTIARY,
IN WHICH INMATE ANTHONY LEWIS
WAS STABBED TO DEATH.
AFTER A SPEEDY TRIAL CONDUCTED
BY THEN STATE ATTORNEY...
AND PRESENT GOVERNOR
CHARLES EDWARDS,
WILL WAS CONVICTED
OF FIRST-DEGREE MURDER...
AND SENTENCED TO DIE
IN THE GAS CHAMBER,
WHICH IS WHERE THE STORY
TAKES A MOST UNUSUAL TURN.
AT THE TIME OF WILL'S INITIAL
ARREST, HIS DAUGHTER JESSICA
WAS A SENIOR IN HIGH SCHOOL.
JESSICA'S BELIEF IN HER FATHER
FUELED HER TO SPEND
THE NEXT SEVEN YEARS...
IN COLLEGE AND LAW SCHOOL,
AND EVERY DAY SINCE,
FIGHTING TO FREE HER FATHER.
BUT WITH THE GOVERNOR'S DENYING
FINAL APPEAL...
AND THE EXECUTION SCHEDULED
FOR MIDNIGHT FRIDAY,
HER ODYSSEY OF LAW AND LOVE
APPEARS TO BE AT AN END.
[ Jessica's Voice ]
I LOVE MY FATHER,
I BELIEVE IN HIM,
AND I WILL NEVER STOP FIGHTING.
HOW DO YOU RESPOND
TO JESSICA WILL'S CALL
FOR CLEMENCY FROM THE GOVERNOR?
THE GOVERNOR'S REFUSAL
IS THE ONLY ANSWER I NEED.
MISS WILL CALLS
THE QUICK PROCESSING
OF HER FATHER...
A POLITICAL ACT BY GOVERNOR
EDWARDS BASED ON HIS REELECTION
LAW AND ORDER PLATFORM.
- HOW DO YOU ANSWER THAT?
- NO ONE DOUBTS MISS WILL'S LOVE
OR DEVOTION TO HER FATHER,
BUT SHE IS WORKING FROM EMOTION,
AND WE'RE WORKING FROM FACT.
[ Man ]
WARDEN, WHAT FACTS ARE THOSE?
OFFICERS CLANCY AND LARSON
FOUND CARL WILL NEXT TO
THE BODY OF ANTHONY LEWIS,
HOLDING
THE MURDER WEAPON.
UNFORTUNATE AS IT IS,
WHEN YOU CONCENTRATE
TRANSGRESSORS IN THE SYSTEM,
THESE THINGS HAPPEN,
BUT THEY WON'T BE TOLERATED
BY ME OR THE GOVERNOR.
THE TIME HAS COME FOR US
TO DO OUR JOB, AND WE'RE GOING
TO DO IT AT DAWN SATURDAY.
- THANK YOU.
- [ Reporters Clamoring ]
[ Buzzer Buzzing ]
DIDN'T YOU HEAR
IT'S BAD LUCK
BEING AROUND A DEAD MAN?
WELL, I'M THE NEW GUY.
I HAVE NO CHOICE.
BON APPÉTIT.
I'M NOT HUNGRY.
IT'S GRILLED PORTERHOUSE STEAK,
MEDIUM RARE.
POACHED SNAP BEANS.
THAT'S WHAT I ORDERED
FOR MY LAST MEAL.
I KNOW.
THAT WASN'T SUPPOSED TO BE
FOR, UH, TWO DAYS.
WELL, IT'S YOUR FAVORITE.
I FIGURED WHY WAIT.
THEY MOVE IN ON YOU,
DON'T THEY?
THE WALLS.
YOU STARE AT THEM LONG ENOUGH,
AND YOU SWEAR THEY START
CREEPING IN ON YOU.
YOU SOUND LIKE A MAN THAT'S
BEEN ON THIS SIDE OF THE BARS.
IT'S TOUGH...
WHEN YOU DON'T
BELONG THERE.
YOU'RE INNOCENT,
AT LEAST THAT'S WHAT
YOU KEEP SAYING.
NOBODY'S LISTENING.
I AM.
YOU'RE TELLING ME A MAN
WEARING THAT UNIFORM
HASN'T HEARD THIS STORY?
I'VE HEARD THE STORY.
I'M INTERESTED IN THE TRUTH.
I WAS HEADED BACK
TO BLOCK "C"
FROM LAUNDRY DETAIL.
I HEARD VOICES.
SOME PEOPLE STRUGGLING
DOWN THE GANTRY.
TURNED AROUND TO SEE
WHAT THE COMMOTION WAS.
GOT KNOCKED OUT.
WOKE UP IN THIS NIGHTMARE.
CORN BREAD OR FRITTERS?
FRITTERS.
JUST LIKE YOU ASKED.
JUST THE WAY
JESSICA ASKED.
SHE ARRANGED ALL THIS.
SHE LOVES YOU VERY MUCH.
BRADLEY.
THE PRISONER'S MEAL
IS DELIVERED.
[ Over Listening Device ]
OH, DARLIN',
I MISS YOU SO DAMN BAD.
I ACHE ALL OVER THINKING
HOW PRETTY YOU LOOKED
LAYING IN THAT BATHTUB.
THAT MR. BUBBLE
DANCING ON YOUR SKIN
LIKE A LOVE POTION.
AND YOU STOOD UP
AND I DRANK IN THE VISION
OF YOUR PERFECTLY SHAPED--
[ Turns Off Device ]
[ Clears Throat ]
PHONE TAP SEEMS
TO BE WORKING.
I GUESS I'LL POKE AROUND
THE ROOM FOR SIGNS OF JAROD.
I'M GOING TO GO
OUT OF MY MIND.
"RELATIVE THINKING."
"THE INNER MIND."
MY GOD! SYDNEY, IS JAROD
ALL YOU THINK ABOUT?
BECAUSE YOU DON'T?
- THERE IS A LOT MORE
TO LIFE THAN JAROD.
- SUCH AS?
SUCH AS FUN.
SUCH AS SEX.
INTERESTING THAT
IN A CONVERSATION
ABOUT JAROD, YOU MENTION SEX.
WELL, NOTHING
IN THE TOILET.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN
SINCE YOU'VE BEEN
WITH A WOMAN, SYDNEY?
SYDNEY'S PRIVATE LIFE
IS NOT A SUBJECT
FOR PUBLIC DISCUSSION.
WELL, IT'S NOT HEALTHY,
YOU KNOW, KEEPING ALL OF
THAT ANIMAL EMOTION BOTTLED UP.
NEXT THING YOU KNOW,
YOU'LL BE ON THE ROOF
WITH A RIFLE IN YOUR HANDS.
YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN
SEEING A WOMAN.
REALLY. BROOTS.
TELL US ABOUT HER.
THERE'S NOT MUCH
TO TELL REALLY.
WE-- WE MET ONLINE.
YOU PICK UP WOMEN
ON THE COMPUTER?
HOW ROMANTIC.
DETAILS.
WELL, UH,
SHE'S AN ACCOUNTANT.
SHE HAS THREE DOGS
AND A BIRD.
AND, UH, OH!
AND SHE'S A HUGE JOHN TESH FAN.
SOUNDS LIKE
A REAL WILDCAT.
WHAT'S SHE LOOK LIKE?
YOU KNOW, I THINK, UH, I SHOULD
START DUSTING FOR PRINTS.
WE HAVEN'T
ACTUALLY MET... YET.
YOU ARE PATHETIC.
GOD, CAN THEY MAKE IT
ANY HOTTER IN HERE?
[ Miss Parker Groaning ]
[ Sydney ]
YOU ALL RIGHT, MISS PARKER?
I'M OKAY.
IT'S THIS, UH, SWILL
FROM THAT GREASY SPOON.
HOW MUCH MORE EXCITING
CAN THIS GET?
LOOK, MONOPOLY.
♪♪ [ Country ]
PSST. PSST.
YEAH, IT'S AMAZING
WHAT THEY LET SIT DOWN
IN THIS PLACE.
MM, YOU SMELL SOMETHING?
[ Sniffing ]
SMELLS LIKE SOMEBODY'S
ABOUT TO FRY.
WOULD YOU JUST
LEAVE ME ALONE?
PLEASE.
WHAT YOU GONNA DO
IF I DON'T? HUH?
[ Door Bells Ring ]
PULL OUT ONE OF THEM KNIVES
LIKE YOUR DADDY DID?
STICK ME WITH IT?
JESSICA. HI, HONEY.
SORRY I'M LATE.
TRAFFIC WAS A BEAR.
YOU WILL EXCUSE US,
WON'T YOU, GENTLEMEN?
- THANK YOU.
- BET THAT'S HAPPENING
A LOT THESE DAYS.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA.
YOU'RE A GUARD
FROM THE PRISON.
I'M OFF DUTY.
IT'S NOTHING PERSONAL,
BUT IT'S JUST GUARDS
AREN'T HIGH ON MY LIST
OF DINNER COMPANIONS.
I JUST SHARED A MEAL
WITH YOUR FATHER.
HE MISSES YOU VERY MUCH.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
FATE.
AND I DON'T THINK
YOUR FATHER DESERVES HIS.
MY MOTHER LEFT
WHEN I WAS LITTLE,
BUT HE NEVER LEFT ME.
WE LIVED IN
THIS RUSTED-OUT AIRSTREAM
FOR MOST OF MY LIFE.
YOU KNOW,
WE DIDN'T HAVE MUCH,
BUT HE ALWAYS MADE SURE
I HAD WHAT I NEEDED.
LOOK, I'M NOT SAYING
THAT MY FATHER IS
THE EPITOME OF VIRTUE.
I MEAN, HE WAS--
HE WAS PRETTY WILD
WHEN HE WAS YOUNGER.
BUT STEALING CARS
AND COMMITTING MURDER...
ARE WORLDS APART.
HE SPENT FIVE YEARS
IN THAT LOCKUP.
HE WAS A WEEK AWAY
FROM PAROLE.
HE HAD A JOB
ON THE OUTSIDE,
AND I WAS
ON THE OUTSIDE.
HE WOULDN'T HAVE
DONE THAT TO ME.
DID YOU KNOW MONOPOLY
WAS DEVELOPED BY
CHARLES DARROW,
AN UNEMPLOYED HEATING ENGINEER
FROM GERMANTOWN, PENNSYLVANIA
IN 1935?
YEAH, THAT'S FASCINATING.
THE GAME WAS ORIGINALLY
REJECTED FOR CONTAINING
52 FUNDAMENTAL ERRORS,
BUT THERE STILL HAVE BEEN
OVER 100 MILLION SETS
SOLD WORLDWIDE.
YOU SOUND LIKE
QUITE AN EXPERT
ON THE SUBJECT.
MONOPOLY CLUB,
HIGH SCHOOL.
WHAT A SURPRISE.
[ Groans ]
MISS PARKER,
YOU ALL RIGHT?
IT'S JUST SO DAMN HOT
IN HERE.
YOU KNOW-- [ Clears Throat ]
THERE'S SOMETHING WRONG
WITH THIS GAME.
[ Grunts ]
THERE'S SOMETHING WRONG
WITH THIS WHOLE DAMN THING.
NO, THERE'S, UH--
[ Clears Throat ]
THERE'S SOMETHING MISSING HERE.
[ Grunts ]
THE ONLY THING MISSING
IS JAROD.
- [ Groans ]
- MISS PARKER!
GET A DOCTOR NOW!
[ Computer Beeps ]
[ Beeps ]
[ Inmates Chattering ]
NARCISSUS.
I CALL THEM DAFFODILS.
THEY'RE MY WIFE'S FAVORITE.
WELL, I CAN SEE WHY.
THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL.
TALK LIKE THAT,
AND NO ONE WILL BELIEVE
YOU'RE REALLY A BULL.
ONLY THING THE OTHER GUARDS
KNOW HOW TO GROW IS RESENTMENT.
[ Man ]
WALKIN' THROUGH.
IS IT ALWAYS
THIS TENSE AROUND HERE
BEFORE AN EXECUTION?
ALWAYS.
DID YOU KNOW
ANTHONY LEWIS?
NO. HE'D ONLY BEEN HERE
A COUPLE OF DAYS.
COUPLE OF DAYS?
HARDLY SEEMS LONG ENOUGH...
FOR CARL WILL TO GROW
TO HATE HIM ENOUGH
TO WANNA KILL HIM.
STRANGE THINGS
HAPPEN IN STIR.
LIKE THE OTHER INMATES
WHO HAVE DIED IN HERE?
SEVEN IN THE LAST
FIVE YEARS.
ALL ACCIDENTS?
IT'S A LOT MORE
THAN THE NATIONAL AVERAGE.
I WOULDN'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THAT.
OH, COME ON, HENRY,
YOU'RE ON A FIRST NAME BASIS
WITH THE ROACHES AROUND HERE.
WHAT HAPPENED
WITH ANTHONY LEWIS...
AND THE OTHER
DEAD INMATES?
PRISON'S A PLACE
TO KEEP YOUR HEAD DOWN
AND YOUR MOUTH SHUT.
ESPECIALLY THIS PLACE.
AND THIS WARDEN.
[ Whistle Blows ]
LET'S MOVE IT IN.
[ Young Jarod ]
I HAVE TWO MINUTES
LEFT TO LIVE.
MY MOUTH IS DRY.
I'M CALM, BUT I'M SCARED.
I FEEL MY HEART
POUNDING IN MY EARS.
[ Young Sydney ]
IT'S TIME TO TELL THE TRUTH.
I DID.
THIS IS YOUR LAST CHANCE.
I DID TELL THE TRUTH.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO DIE.
CLEAR YOUR CONSCIENCE.
IT IS CLEAR.
I'M AT PEACE.
ROSENBERG WAS TELLING
THE TRUTH, SYDNEY. HE DIDN'T
GIVE THE SECRETS AWAY.
- ARE YOU SURE?
- YES.
AREN'T YOU?
[ Young Sydney ]
YES.
[ Young Jarod ]
BUT IF THEY KNEW
HE WAS INNOCENT,
WHY DID THEY EXECUTE HIM?
[ Young Sydney ]
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
BECAUSE SOMEONE
HAD TO BE GUILTY.
[ Cell Door Clattering ]
TIGHTEN IT.
I DON'T WANT THE PRISONER
TO GO INTO SPASM
AND BREAK THOSE STRAPS.
INITIATE THE SEQUENCE.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
LARSON, DROP THE PELLETS.
[ Beeps ]
WHY THE HESITATION?
MISTAKE
IN COMMUNICATIONS, SIR.
IT WON'T HAPPEN
AT SHOWTIME.
[ Warden ]
YEAH, WELL,
SEE THAT IT DOESN'T.
'CAUSE WE'RE GONNA HAVE
A ROOMFUL OF PRESS BACK THERE
FOR THE REAL EXECUTION,
AND I DON'T WANNA
HAVE TO KILL CARL WILL TWICE.
GET HIM OUT OF THERE.
[ Larson ]
YES, SIR.
THANKS, BRADLEY.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT'S WRONG
WITH ME OR NOT?
I THINK YOU HAVE
AN ULCER.
AND FROM THE WAY YOU WERE
FOLDED UP WHEN I GOT HERE,
IT'S A DOOZY.
- WHAT CAN BE DONE?
- FOR NOW, I'M GOING
TO PRESCRIBE...
A MILD ACID INHIBITOR.
I'M NOT SURE
THAT IT WILL BE HELPFUL,
GIVEN THE FACT
THAT SHE SMOKES...
AND HAS AN UNUSUALLY
STRESSFUL DEMEANOR.
YOU CAN SAY THAT AGAIN.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS
YOU DO, MISS PARKER,
BUT IT'S EATING YOU AWAY
FROM THE INSIDE OUT.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO CHANGE YOUR LIFESTYLE...
OR ELSE.
OR ELSE WHAT?
YOU COULD DIE.
I SUGGEST THAT YOU LEARN
TO CONTROL YOUR EMOTIONS.
LIKE YOUR FATHER HERE.
HAVE A PLEASANT EVENING.
[ Sydney ]
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
[ Broots ] THANKS, DOC.
HE'S RIGHT, YOU KNOW.
IF YOU DON'T KEEP
THOSE FEELINGS
ABOUT JAROD IN CHECK,
IT COULD BE YOUR RUIN.
IT'S A LITTLE LATE
TO BE WORRIED ABOUT MY RUIN.
[ Clamoring ]
MY FLOWERS!
BREAK IT UP!
- NO, BOSS!
- [ Warden ] CLANCY!
CLEAN UP THIS MESS.
GET 'EM BACK
IN THEIR CAGES NOW.
[ Man ]
ALL RIGHT, CLEAR THE YARD!
MOVE IT!
YOU EVER MAKE A MOVE
LIKE THAT ON ME AGAIN,
I'LL PUT YOU IN THIS PLOT.
I JUST DIDN'T WANT
MY FLOWERS TRAMPLED.
WELL, THAT WON'T BE
A PROBLEM NOW, WILL IT?
YOU OKAY?
SURE. FINE.
YOU'RE SURE?
WHERE'S MY WIFE?
SHE DIED THREE YEARS AGO.
CANCER.
I'M SORRY.
PRETTY PATHETIC, HUH?
NO.
YOU LOCK A MAN AWAY
LONG ENOUGH,
IT BENDS HIM,
SOMETIMES
TILL HE BREAKS.
RITA AND ME
WERE MARRIED 43 YEARS.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW THAT,
DID YOU?
NO, I DIDN'T.
I BROKE THE LAW,
AND I'VE PAID EVERY DAY
FOR THE LAST 27 YEARS.
BUT THERE'S CERTAIN THINGS
THAT A MAN...
CAN'T ALLOW
TO BE TAKEN FROM HIM.
HIS PRIDE,
HIS DIGNITY.
I UNDERSTAND RULES.
BUT WHAT WARDEN MICHAELS
DID TO ME WAS WRONG.
ALL I WANTED
WAS TO BE THERE WHEN...
MY RITA WAS LAID DOWN.
I PUT HER THROUGH
A LOT OF PAIN.
AND I JUST WANTED TO BE ABLE
TO PUT FLOWERS ON HER GRAVE...
AND FEEL HER IN MY HEART...
ONE MORE TIME.
HE WOULDN'T GIVE ME
A FURLOUGH.
HELL, THEY--
THEY LET CONS OUT
FOR THAT KIND OF THING
EVERY DAY.
ALL I WANTED TO DO
WAS SAY GOOD-BYE.
IS THAT WHY YOU PLANTED
YOUR GARDEN?
CRAZY, HUH?
I KEEP PRAYING MAYBE...
ONE DAY I'LL ACTUALLY
GET THE CHANCE TO SHOW
HOW MUCH I LOVED HER.
BUT MICHAELS--
HE'S SET ON MAKING...
A STATEMENT
WITH THIS PLACE.
I GUESS MAYBE
THEY WERE MY STATEMENT.
I JUST DIDN'T WANT THEM
TO THINK THEY BROKE ME.
[ Slinky Clanging ]
HEY, BUDDY.
[ Boy ]
HEY, WAIT UP!
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND.
I BROUGHT YOUR KIDS
SOME TOYS.
HI, CUTIE.
GIVE THIS TO YOUR MOTHER.
TELL HER I'LL BE THERE
IN A SECOND, OKAY?
YOU HAVE
A BEAUTIFUL FAMILY.
YOU'RE A LUCKY MAN.
THANKS.
SOMETHING ON YOUR MIND?
CARL WILL.
WHAT ABOUT HIM?
WELL, I'M A LITTLE BIT
EMBARRASSED TO ADMIT THIS,
BUT I'M NOT SURE
I CAN HANDLE THIS EXECUTION.
I KNOW IT'S WHAT WE DO,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN
A MAN DIE BEFORE.
I WAS HOPING
YOU COULD HELP ME.
WELL, YOU'RE TALKING
TO THE WRONG MAN.
YEAH.
I SAW YOUR FACE AS WE WERE
DOING THE WALK-THROUGH.
IT'S PRETTY DIFFICULT
FOR YOU TO IMAGINE CARL WILL
STRAPPED TO THAT CHAIR,
GAS RISING UP,
CHOKING THE LIFE OUT OF HIM.
WHY IS THAT?
IT JUST IS, OKAY?
HMM.
DID YOU EVER NOTICE
THAT THESE THINGS
ARE JUST LIKE GUILT?
YOU CAN MOVE IT
FROM ONE PLACE TO ANOTHER,
BUT IT ALWAYS COMES BACK.
WHO ARE YOU?
SOMEONE WHO DOESN'T WANT
TO SEE AN INNOCENT MAN DIE.
SOMEONE WHO THINKS
THAT JESSICA WILL DESERVES
TO HAVE HER FATHER,
JUST AS MUCH AS THOSE KIDS
DESERVE TO HAVE THEIRS.
I'VE BEEN WALKING
THE YARD FOR 20 YEARS.
IT'S ALL I KNOW.
IT'S TOO LATE
TO START OVER, AND...
I CAN'T AFFORD TO CROSS
A GUY LIKE CLANCY.
YOU'RE AFRAID FOR YOUR LIFE.
YEAH, WELL,
YOU SHOULD BE TOO.
YOU KNOW HOW IT IS
ON THE INSIDE.
THINGS HAPPEN.
AND I'M DAMN SURE NOT GONNA
END UP LIKE ANTHONY LEWIS
AND THE OTHERS.
LEWIS WAS TRANSFERRED IN
FROM JOLIET.
JUST LIKE ALL THE OTHER MEN
WHO DIED HERE.
I PULLED THE INMATES' FILES,
AND I TRACKED THEM.
IT'S REALLY INTERESTING.
EACH ONE OF THEM
BELONGED TO THE SAME
CHICAGO CRIME FAMILY.
MY GUESS WOULD BE
THAT SOMEBODY PAID
TO HAVE THEM SILENCED.
IS THAT THE WAY
THE OPERATION WORKED?
YEAH. CLANCY'S
BROTHER-IN-LAW...
IS A PENCIL PUSHER
AT JOLIET.
HE MADE A DEAL
WITH A RIVAL FAMILY.
THEY TRANSFERRED TARGETS
INTO OAKFIELD.
CLANCY DOES THE JOB.
THEY SPLIT THE MONEY.
ARE YOU A PART OF IT?
NO, I WASN'T.
I DIDN'T FIND OUT UNTIL
AFTER ANTHONY LEWIS WAS KILLED.
AND BY THEN,
I WAS IN TOO DEEP
TO SAY ANYTHING.
WHAT ABOUT CARL WILL?
CLANCY WAS FINISHING UP
ON LEWIS, AND WILL WALKED IN.
I WAS SUPPOSED TO MAKE SURE
THE AREA WAS CLEAR.
HELL, I THOUGHT
HE WAS JUST HITTING
THE GUY UP FOR CASH.
IS THAT WHEN
YOU KNOCKED HIM OUT?
YEAH, WELL, I HAD TO.
CLANCY WOULD HAVE KILLED
THE GUY RIGHT THERE.
CLANCY PLANTED
THE SHIV ON HIM.
BY THE TIME
WILL CAME TO,
IT WAS OVER.
AND NOW
HE'S GOING TO DIE...
FOR SOMETHING
HE DIDN'T DO.
[ Broots ]
THERE'S DEFINITELY SOMETHING
WRONG WITH THIS GAME.
MAYBE NOT ALL THE PIECES
ARE THERE.
THEY'RE NOT,
BUT IT'S MORE THAN THAT.
I HAVE A FEELING
WE'RE NOT SEEING SOMETHING
IMPORTANT WITH THIS WHOLE THING.
[ Pills Rattle ]
SPEAK FOR YOURSELF.
GOT US A STETSON.
[ Gun Cocks ]
WELL, I HEAR THAT.
TWITCH AND YOUR NEXT STOP
IS BOOT HILL.
HEY, RELAX, LITTLE LADY.
I'M JUST THE PONY EXPRESS.
PUT THE PHONE DOWN
AND TURN AROUND... SLOWLY.
THAT'S AN AWFULLY BIG GUN
FOR SUCH A PRETTY LITTLE LADY.
SAVE IT FOR THE HOEDOWN.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WELL, I TOLD YOU.
I WAS PAID TO MAKE A DELIVERY.
YES. WHAT KIND
OF DELIVERY?
HEY, I'M UNARMED.
I SWEAR.
LEFT HAND ONLY.
I KNEW THERE WAS
SOMETHING MISSING.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
THE GAME. CHANCE.
GET OUT OF JAIL FREE.
[ Sydney ]
WHAT DO YOU THINK
IT MEANS, MISS PARKER?
DAMN IT.
I NEED TO SEE
YOUR REGISTRATION BOOK.
[ Clerk ]
OKAY.
[ Muttering ]
[ Pages Turning ]
"JAROD SHORT.
JAROD ST. JAMES.
JAROD VENTNOR.
JAROD CHANCE.
MARVIN GARDENS.
ROOM 5." THE ROOM--
THE ROOM
RIGHT NEXT TO OURS.
[ Sydney ]
"GO DIRECTLY TO JAIL.
DO NOT PASS GO.
DO NOT COLLECT $200."
I AM SICK OF BEING A TOKEN
ON HIS GAME BOARD.
MISS PARKER.
[ Miss Parker ]
GO DIRECTLY TO JAIL.
DAMN YOU, JAROD.
[ Chanting ]
FREE CARL WILL.
HEY, CLANCY.
THE WARDEN JUST CALLED.
HE WANTS YOU
TO MAKE ANOTHER CHECK
OF THE GAS CHAMBER.
MAKE SURE
THERE'S NO MALFUNCTIONS.
IT'S FINE.
I LOADED THE CYANIDE MYSELF
NOT AN HOUR AGO.
HEY, DON'T SHOOT
THE MESSENGER.
GUESS THERE'S SOME KIND
OF ELECTRICAL PROBLEM.
HAVE LARSON CHECK IT.
HIS WIFE JUST CALLED.
HE'S SICK.
MY BUTT.
HE'S YELLOW.
YOU CHECK IT.
I CAN'T.
I'M THE NEW GUY.
I HAVE TO BRING WILL
HIS LAST SUPPER.
ALL RIGHT, DAMN IT.
YOU NEED SOMETHING
DONE RIGHT--
DO IT YOURSELF.
WELL, GOOD THING
WE'RE NOT FRYING THIS GUY.
[ Door Opens ]
WARDEN MICHAELS?
[ Door Closes ]
[ Clancy ]
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
WHO SHUT THE DOOR?
WHO'S THERE?
SCARY, ISN'T IT?
BEING LOCKED UP
LIKE A WILD ANIMAL...
WAITING TO DIE.
FUNNY, BRADLEY.
NOW LET ME OUT.
MM.
I DON'T THINK
I'LL DO THAT.
WHAT THE HELL
DO YOU THINK YOU'RE DOING?
SAME THING
YOU'VE BEEN DOING.
[ Clancy On Intercom ]
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
[ Jarod On Intercom ]
OH, COME ON, CLANCY.
I KNOW YOU KILLED
ANTHONY LEWIS.
YOU SET UP CARL WILL
TO TAKE THE FALL FOR IT.
YOU WERE GOING TO LET
AN INNOCENT MAN DIE...
FOR SOMETHING YOU DID.
[ Clucking Tongue ]
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
I'M YOU--
JUDGE,
JURY--
[ Switch Clicks ]
AND EXECUTIONER.
HOW MANY MEN?
HOW MANY MEN
DID YOU KILL, CLANCY?
FIVE? SIX?
THEY WERE ANIMALS.
I DID THE PUBLIC A FAVOR.
[ Jarod ]
AND YOU ALMOST
GOT AWAY WITH IT.
EXCEPT CARL WILL
WAS AT THE WRONG PLACE
AT THE WRONG TIME.
[ Clancy ]
NAME YOUR PRICE.
[ Jarod ]
MY PRICE?
MONEY.
HOW MUCH IS A HUMAN LIFE
WORTH ANYWAY?
HOW MUCH DID YOU MAKE?
5,000?
10,000 A HEAD?
NAH, I THINK
IT'S TIME FOR JUSTICE
TO WIN THIS ONE.
I'D ASK IF YOU HAD
A LAST REQUEST,
BUT THE TRUTH IS,
YOU DON'T REALLY
DESERVE IT.
IT'S SHOWTIME.
[ Beeps ]
- NO!
- [ Sizzles ]
[ Clancy Yelling, Indistinct ]
DON'T YOU THINK
NOT TELLING THAT MAN...
THOSE CYANIDE CAPSULES
WERE FAKE IS CRUEL
AND UNUSUAL PUNISHMENT?
[ Clancy ]
BRADLEY! AAH!
NAH.
[ Clancy Screaming ]
I, UH, WOULD BE HAPPY
TO ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS
YOU HAVE,
BUT RIGHT NOW,
I'D LIKE TO HUG MY DAD...
AND TELL HIM
HOW MUCH I LOVE HIM.
[ Miss Parker ]
GET OUT OF MY WAY.
[ Reporters Clamoring ]
[ Miss Parker ]
HEY, YOU, OPEN UP.
WE'RE EXPECTED.
[ Buzzer Buzzes ]
NO CIVILIZED PERSON
COULD SIT HERE
IN FRONT OF YOU PEOPLE...
AND TELL YOU THAT
HE ENJOYS GIVING THE ORDER...
TO HAVE CYANIDE PELLETS...
DROPPED INTO ACID
TO KILL SOMEONE.
BUT WE DO THAT TO DETER PEOPLE
FROM COMMITTING CRIMES.
UNFORTUNATELY, THERE ARE EVENTS
THAT WOULD PROVE WE HAVE
CORRUPTION ON OUR STAFF.
AND INSPIRED BY THESE EVENTS,
CHANGES WILL BE MADE HERE...
THAT HOPEFULLY BENEFIT
ALL THE INMATES.
MY RESIGNATION
WILL BECOME FINAL
IN 24 HOURS,
AFTER MY LAST OFFICIAL ACT
AS WARDEN.
[ Man ]
SO, WE UNDERSTAND
YOU LIKE TO PLAY GAMES, MR.--
PARKER. YES.
AND I'VE INVENTED ONE.
I CALL IT
GET OUT OF JAIL FREE.
[ Mews ]