PREVIOUSLY ON THE PRETENDER.
YES, MR. PARKER.
ANGELO IS SEARCHING
THE INTERNET
FOR ANY SIGNS OF JAROD NOW.
SL-27.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN, JACOB?
[ Miss Parker ]
SL 27. WHAT DOES IT MEAN?
[ Tires Screeching ]
DOES HE HAVE A NAME?
THEY'RE CALLING HIM JAROD.
HE MISSES HIS PARENTS.
HE'LL FORGET THEM SOON ENOUGH.
♪ KRI KRA TOAD'S FOOT ♪
♪ GEESE WALK BAREFOOT ♪
- FOUND THESE BLUEPRINTS
IN THE GUTTER.
- HE'S NEARBY. FIND HIM!
LET'S MOVE! GO!
[ Car Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Bottle Rattling ]
[ Clanking ]
[ Footsteps Departing ]
HEY!
BLUE SEDAN.
GET IN!
THIS IS PARKER.
WE'RE IN PURSUIT
OF A BLUE SEDAN.
[ Thumping ]
[ Crying ]
[ Man Narrating ]
[ Knocking ]
CHRISTINE!
CHRISTINE?
JAROD?
I'M SORRY,
CHRISTINE.
I KNOW IT'S LATE.
IT'S 3:00 IN THE MORNING.
GOD ISN'T EVEN AWAKE.
I KNOW. LISTEN,
I NEED TO MOVE BACK IN
FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
NOT SMELLIN' LIKE THAT
YOU'RE NOT.
PLEASE.
LOOK, JAROD,
I OWE YOU BIG TIME FOR
WHAT YOU DID FOR ME, BUT MY
HUSBAND'S COMIN' BACK TOMORROW.
IF AXE FINDS A MAN LIVIN'
UPSTAIRS, HE'LL HAVE A STROKE.
[ Soft Cry ]
OH, MY GOD.
WHERE DID YOU GET IT?
A MAN THREW HIM IN THE DUMPSTER.
OH, MY GOD.
HOW COULD SOMEONE DO THAT?
HOW COULD SOMEONE
THROW AWAY A BABY?
IT'S A CRAZY WORLD.
BABIES HAVIN' BABIES,
PEOPLE DON'T KNOW
WHAT THEY WANT
OR WHAT THEY HAVE.
IT'S FREEZING IN HERE.
YOU HAVE TO CALL THE POLICE.
I'M THE ONLY FAMILY
HE HAS RIGHT NOW.
HE'S COLD, HE'S SCARED,
AND HE'S ALONE.
DON'T YOU LIKE BABIES?
OF COURSE.
IT'S JUST THAT IF AXE
DIDN'T GET THE JOB IN HOUSTON,
HE'LL HAVE A STROKE
IF HE COMES BACK
AND FINDS A BABY HERE.
- HE DOESN'T LIKE BABIES?
- NO.
YES.
THAT'S NOT THE POINT.
- HE'S HUNGRY.
- HOW CAN YOU TELL?
BECAUSE I'M HUNGRY.
WANNA-- WANNA LAY DOWN?
THERE YOU GO.
WHY-WHY WOULD JAROD RISK
GETTING CAUGHT OVER
A RANDOM SET OF BLUEPRINTS?
[ Chuckles ]
WHERE JAROD'S CONCERNED,
THERE'S NEVER ANYTHING RANDOM.
HMM.
BOY GENIUS IS
A REGULAR I.M. PEI.
WAIT.
WHAT'S THIS? SL 27?
I'LL BE AROUND.
♪ KRI KRA TOAD'S FOOT ♪
♪ GEESE WALK BAREFOOT ♪
WHO TAUGHT YOU THAT SONG?
I DON'T KNOW.
MY MOTHER, I THINK.
YOU THINK?
WHEN I WAS LITTLE,
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY FAMILY.
I WAS RAISED
BY SOME PEOPLE--
PEOPLE THAT HAD NO BUSINESS
DEALING WITH CHILDREN.
I'M SORRY.
LOOK, JAROD, I APPRECIATE
EVERYTHING YOU DID FOR ME.
THAT PHONY LAWSUIT
THAT LADY FILED AGAINST
THE SHOP WOULD HAVE BUSTED ME...
IF YOU HADN'T STEPPED IN,
BUT, STILL, I CAN'T LET YOU--
[ Jarod, Babytalk ]
[ Baby Cries Out ]
HOLLER DOWNSTAIRS
IF YOU NEED ANY HELP, OKAY?
CHRISTINE?
THANKS.
[ Man ] DOES HE HAVE A NAME?
[ Man #2 ]
THEY'RE CALLING HIM JAROD.
HE MISSES HIS PARENTS.
HE'LL FORGET THEM
SOON ENOUGH.
[ Tones Beeping ]
[ Ringing ]
THIS IS SYDNEY.
HOW COULD SOMEBODY
ABANDON A CHILD?
JAROD.
I MEAN, SOMETHING
SO VULNERABLE,
SO DEFENSELESS.
HOW COULD THEY DO THAT?
IS THIS ABOUT YOUR PARENTS?
IT'S ABOUT ALL PARENTS.
[ Sydney Sighs ]
WELL, THERE'S
NO EASY ANSWER TO THAT.
WHO KNOWS WHAT, UH--
WHAT PRESSURES SOME PEOPLE FACE.
IS THIS WHAT YOU WERE
LOOKING FOR EARLIER
AT THAT ARCHITECTURAL FIRM?
THOSE BLUEPRINTS?
IS THAT A LEAD TO YOUR PARENTS?
YOU'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
HEY.
[ Clears Throat ]
IT'S, UH,
FOR MY LITTLE GIRL.
SHE'S VERY FORTUNATE TO HAVE
SUCH AN ATTENTIVE FATHER.
I, UH, DID
THE SEARCH YOU REQUESTED.
FOUND TWO INACTIVE
LICENSE PLATES WITH "SL 27,"
BUT BOTH OWNERS
DIED IN THE '70s.
SL 27 IS ALSO THE GENERIC NAME
FOR AN ANTIBIOTIC...
DEVELOPED BY AN ISRAELI
PHARMACEUTICAL COMPANY
IN 1983.
THAT'S BEYOND
THE DATE OF SIGNIFICANCE.
WELL,
IF YOU TOLD ME MORE, SYDNEY,
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO HELP.
BROOTS, IT'S BEST THAT...
NOBODY ELSE
BE INVOLVED IN THIS.
BROOTS,
ANYTHING ON SL 27 YET?
UH--
PERHAPS YOU BOTH
SHOULD HAVE A TALK.
[ Keyboard Clacking ]
[ Knocking ]
SHH.
STILL SLEEPIN'?
LIKE A BABY.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
- SETTING IT UP.
IF ANYBODY FILES A MISSING
PERSONS REPORT WITH THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT, I'LL GET A SIGNAL.
JAROD, YOU CAN'T
KEEP THIS CHILD.
LAST NIGHT IS ONE THING,
BUT SOMEWHERE,
SOMEBODY'S LOOKING
FOR THIS BABY.
I'VE BEEN MONITORING EVERY
POLICE CHANNEL, EVERY TELEVISION
STATION, EVERY NEWSPAPER.
NOBODY'S LOOKING FOR HIM.
BUT, JAROD--
SOMEBODY THREW HIM
IN A DUMPSTER.
DO YOU WANT ME TO TURN HIM OVER
TO THAT PERSON?
IF HIS MOTHER'S
OUT THERE SEARCHING,
I'LL FIND HER.
BUT I'M NOT GONNA
GIVE HIM TO ANYBODY...
TILL I KNOW
HE'S GONNA BE OKAY.
I DON'T WANT HIM
TO GROW UP ALONE.
- [ Baby Crying ]
- ARE YOU HUNGRY AGAIN?
- THAT'S NOT A BOTTLE CRY.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW?
SEVEN YOUNGER
BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
BETTER CHANGE HIM.
[ Crying Continues ]
I KILLED THE SECURITY CAMERAS,
AND I SWEPT THE ROOM FOR BUGS.
I THINK WE'RE SAFE.
YOU THINK?
ONE NEVER KNOWS
IN THE CENTRE, DO ONE?
LET'S PROCEED.
THIS BELONGED TO
ONE OF THE CHILDREN MY MOTHER
RESCUED FROM THE CENTRE.
LOOK AT THIS.
"SL 27."
WHY DID YOU KEEP
THIS INFORMATION SECRET?
WHY, I COULD ASK
THE SAME QUESTION OF YOU.
WHEN MY BROTHER
REGAINED CONSCIOUSNESS,
HE WROTE THIS TO ME.
HMM.
THERE HAS TO BE A CLUE
IN THE CALCULATIONS
THAT JAROD DROPPED.
BROOTS, KEEP ON SEARCHING
FOR THAT CONNECTION.
LOOK, I DON'T KNOW IF
YOU GUYS MISSED IT, BUT, UH,
THE ONLY PEOPLE WHO KNOW
ABOUT THIS SL 27 THING
ARE EITHER DEAD OR COMATOSE.
AND THOSE PEOPLE
ARE IMPORTANT TO US...
LIKE YOUR DAUGHTER
IS TO YOU.
I'M ASKING FOR YOUR HELP,
BROOTS,
AS A FRIEND.
PLEASE.
[ Buzzing ]
WHAT IS HE DOING?
HE APPEARS TO BE
EXPRESSING HIS INDIVIDUALISM.
IS THAT GOOD?
[ Raines ]
IT'S DANGEROUS.
ANGELO, I WANT YOU
TO RUN A CHECK...
ON EVERY ASPECT
OF CENTRE SECURITY.
EVERY SYSTEM, EVERY LEVEL,
EVERY MODE OF
ACCESS AND EGRESS.
OPTICAL, PHYSICAL, ELECTRONIC--
[ Wheezing ]
EVERYTHING.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
ANGELO?
[ Buzzer Clicks Off ]
[ Chatter, Baby Crying ]
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
I'LL BE RIGHT WITH YOU.
YES, I'M LOOKING AT THE FILE.
WE'VE PLACED A CALL TO
THE BIOLOGICAL GRANDPARENTS,
BUT THE STATUS
IS STILL UNCLEAR.
- SURE. CAN I HELP YOU?
- WE'D LIKE TO TALK TO SOMEBODY
ABOUT A MISSIN' CHILD.
I'LL BE ONE MORE MINUTE.
NO, IT'S AGAINST THE LAW...
TO PREMATURELY PLACE A CHILD
WITHOUT THE SIGNATURE OF
A BIOLOGICAL FAMILY MEMBER.
I REALIZE YOU LOVE THE BABY,
BUT THIS IS THE WAY
IT HAS TO BE HANDLED.
I KNOW THIS IS HARD, JAROD,
BUT I THINK
IT'S THE BEST THING--
JAROD?
ARE YOU INSANE?
YOU CAN'T JUST WALK OUT
WITH THIS BABY.
WELL, I CAN'T
LEAVE HIM WITH THEM.
JAROD, HE DOESN'T BELONG TO YOU.
[ Sighs ]
I KNOW.
HE BELONGS WITH HIS PARENTS,
OR WITH SOMEONE WHO LOVES HIM.
TWENTY-FOUR HOURS.
THEN WE TAKE THE BABY
TO THE POLICE NO MATTER WHAT.
DEAL?
DEAL.
ONE MORE THING.
GIVE HIM A NAME, WILL YA?
HE HAS A NAME.
I JUST HAVE TO
FIND OUT WHAT IT IS.
WHAT IS IT?
THEY ALL HAVE RED DECALS.
THE MAN WHO DUMPED THIS BABY
HAD THE EXACT SAME DECAL
ON THE BACK OF HIS CAR.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYIN'?
A COP THREW THIS BABY AWAY.
TALK TO ME, BROOTS.
YOU'LL NEVER GUESS
WHAT I FOUND OUT.
THE ARCHITECTURAL FIRM
YOU CHASED JAROD FROM WAS--
THE SAME ONE
THAT BUILT THE CENTRE.
HOW DID YOU KNOW THAT?
[ Ringing ]
THIS IS SYDNEY.
[ Jarod ]
ANY LUCK?
WITH WHAT?
WELL, HELLO, MISS PARKER.
SL 27.
THOSE CALCULATIONS, JAROD--
WHAT DO THEY MEAN?
JUST DIGGING UP
SOME MORE DIRT
ON THE CENTRE.
I DON'T FOLLOW.
DO THE MATH, SYDNEY.
IT DOESN'T ADD UP.
I'M SURPRISED THAT BROOTS
HASN'T FIGURED IT OUT YET.
- DIRT.
- I GOTTA GO.
IT'S THE BABY'S NAP TIME.
DID HE SAY BABY?
I'LL BE DAMNED.
6.32 MILLION
CUBIC FEET OF DIRT...
WAS CARTED OFF
FOR THE CENTRE'S
UNDERGROUND CONSTRUCTION.
BUT THE CENTRE'S
26 SUBLEVELS ONLY OCCUPY...
6.16 MILLION CUBIC FEET.
THERE'S ENOUGH MISSING DIRT
FOR ANOTHER SUBLEVEL.
[ Sydney ]
SL 27.
SUBLEVEL 27.
THIS IS MY MOTHER.
WE'RE GOING TO FIND YOURS.
I PROMISE.
[ Christine ]
WELL, THAT'S A SIGHT.
YOU AND AXE EVER THINK
ABOUT HAVING KIDS?
AXE?
NO. NO WAY.
BESIDES, I GOT THE SHOP
TO WORRY ABOUT.
ANY LUCK
WITH THAT LICENSE PLATE?
NOT YET.
I HAVE TO GET INSIDE
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT...
AND FIND OUT
WHO WAS DRIVING THAT CAR,
BUT I'M GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP.
JAROD, I'VE GOT CUSTOMERS.
I CAN'T GO CHASIN'--
CHRISTINE?
SOMEBODY TOOK MY SPOT.
AXE!
YOUR HUSBAND'S GONE TWO WEEKS,
AND ALL YOU CAN SAY IS "AXE"?
- HOW'D IT GO?
- AH, CAME UP EMPTY.
WHO ARE YOU?
HI. I'M JAROD.
- WHO'S THIS?
- UM, I CAN EXPLAIN. UH--
WOULD YOU LOOK AT THEM EYES?
DO YOU MIND?
NO, NOT AT ALL.
[ Chuckling ]
THAT'S A FINE-LOOKING BOY.
IT-IT IS A BOY?
YES.
HEY, HEY.
YOU LIKE KIDS?
LIKE 'EM?
I'D HAVE A WHOLE TRIBE
IF CHRISTY WOULD COOPERATE.
YOU EVER NEED A BABYSITTER,
I'M YOUR MAN.
I'LL REMEMBER THAT.
BETTER MOVE THE TRUCK.
[ Woman Over Scanner,
Indistinct ]
ANYTHING COME OVER THE SCANNER?
NOT YET.
WHY DID YOU LIE ABOUT AXE?
I GREW UP WITH
SEVEN BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
I WAS THE OLDEST,
AND MY MOTHER WAS--
WELL, SHE WASN'T WHAT
YOU'D CALL "HANDS ON."
WHAT ABOUT YOUR FATHER?
HE WAS BUSY WITH
HIS OTHER FAMILY ACROSS TOWN.
IT WAS UP TO ME TO MAKE SURE
ARI AND WILLIAM WERE FED...
AND MATTY WAS DRESSED,
AND JEREMY DIDN'T STAY UP LATE,
AND ELLA DID HER HOMEWORK.
I GOT OUT OF LITTLE ROCK
AND MOVED IN WITH AXE.
I WANT TO BE ABLE TO THINK
ABOUT CHRISTINE FOR A WHILE.
DOES THAT MAKE ME A BAD PERSON?
NO.
IT MAKES YOU HUMAN.
[ Man ] SEE YOU LATER, FRANK.
[ Woman Over Loudspeaker ]
BILL, PICK UP LINE TWO.
[ Man ]
WE BETTER PUT IT UP
ON THE LIFT.
[ Woman Over Loudspeaker ]
CHUCK, COME TO THE PARTS DESK.
HEY, SPORT--
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS UNIT?
NO PROBLEM.
ACCIDENTALLY CLIPPED A JUNKIE
WHO DECIDED NOT TO COOPERATE.
GUESS HE'LL COOPERATE NEXT TIME.
GET THIS UNIT FIXED.
I WANNA GET OUT OF HERE FAST.
WHATEVER YOU SAY, UH,
DETECTIVE--
GEARY, DAVID W.
THOSE LOOK STRAIGHT TO YOU?
- YEAH.
- I'LL BE BACK.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Broots ]
OKAY, IT'S RIGHT
AROUND HERE SOMEWHERE.
WHAT IS?
SEWER ACCESS.
BROOTS, THE SEWER MAIN IS ON
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE COMPLEX.
I KNOW.
WHICH MAKES ME WONDER WHY
THERE'S A MANHOLE COVER
RIGHT HERE.
HELP ME, SYDNEY.
[ Air Hissing ]
OH!
- [ Sydney ] CAN YOU SMELL THAT?
- SMELL IT? I CAN TASTE IT.
[ Air Hissing ]
AFTER YOU.
HOW-HOW DO YOU KNOW
IT'S NOT WIRED DOWN THERE?
I RAN CENTRE SECURITY
FOR THREE YEARS.
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
YEAH, WELL, YOU DIDN'T KNOW
ABOUT SL 27.
GET IN.
YOU KNOW,
I'M NOT SURE
MY MEDICAL INSURANCE
COVERS THIS SORT OF THING.
SYDNEY, PUT SOME LIGHT
ON ME.
OW!
[ Broots ]
WHAT DIED DOWN HERE?
WHAT DIDN'T?
LET'S GO.
OKAY.
[ Announcer, Indistinct ]
[ Axe Chuckles ]
YOU SEE THAT?
NOW SOMETIMES, IT'S BETTER
TO BE LUCKY THAN GOOD.
ME AND MY OLD MAN
USED TO WATCH HOOPS ON THE TUBE.
I FIGURED SOMEDAY,
ME AND MY KID WOULD DO THE SAME.
CHRISTINE TOLD ME
WHAT'S GOING ON.
YOU REALLY THINK
THAT COP'S INVOLVED?
HIS NAME IS DAVID GEARY.
HE'S A SPECIAL INVESTIGATOR
FOR D.A. MITCH MEYERS.
- UGH, BUREAUCRATS.
- SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE NOT
A BIG FAN OF CITY HALL.
I SPENT 20 YEARS
DRIVIN' A GARBAGE RIG
FOR THE CITY.
COUPLE OF MONTHS AGO,
I BLOW OUT MY BACK
LIFTIN' AN INDUSTRIAL BIN.
CITY CANS ME,
CUTS OFF MY DISABILITY CHECKS.
I CAN'T GET ANOTHER JOB.
YOU'RE A GARBAGEMAN?
SANITATION ENGINEER.
WOW.
YOU KNOW, JAROD,
I SEEN A LOT OF DIRTY THINGS
ON THE STREET.
BUT WHY ANYONE
WOULD WANT TO HURT SOMETHING
AS WONDERFUL AS THIS...
IS BEYOND ME.
YEAH.
- [ Beeps ]
- WHAT'S THAT?
A MISSING PERSONS REPORT
WAS JUST LOGGED ON TO
THE POLICE DATABASE.
IT'S THE FIRST MATCH
I'VE FOUND.
JEANETTE CONNELLY.
REPORTED MISSING BY
HER NEXT-DOOR NEIGHBOR...
ALONG WITH HER
FIVE-MONTH-OLD SON... MICHAEL.
HELLO, MICHAEL.
OF COURSE THERE'S
A MISSING PERSONS ON HER.
SHE'S MISSING.
DON'T GET YOUR PANTIES
IN A WAD.
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
[ Woman Over Radio ]
OFFICER'S REQUESTING BACKUP
AT SAN PEDRO AND 9th.
[ Broots ]
THERE MUST BE
A HUNDRED ROOMS DOWN HERE.
WHAT WAS THIS PLACE?
WHATEVER IT WAS,
IT MUST'VE BEEN ONE HELL
OF A FIRE THAT STOPPED IT.
YES. THERE WAS A RUMOR
OF A FIRE IN THE SUMMER OF '82.
I SPENT THAT SUMMER
IN FRANCE WITH MY FATHER.
I WISH I WAS THERE RIGHT NOW.
[ Sydney ]
RUMOR IS IT WAS THE FIRE
THAT LEFT RAINES...
CHAINED TO HIS OXYGEN TANK.
TOO BAD IT DIDN'T
FINISH THE JOB.
[ Broots ]
HEY, LOOK.
FOOTPRINTS.
AND THEY'RE FRESH.
WHOA.
[ Broots ]
WHO PLAYED WITH TOYS DOWN HERE?
[ Miss Parker ]
A JACK-IN-THE-BOX?
FASCINATING.
- BROOTS.
- HUH?
- CHECK OUT THE SUIT.
- [ Broots ] IT'S ALWAYS BROOTS.
[ Yelling ]
THERE'S A-- THERE'S A
BULLET HOLE IN HIS EYE.
- COME ON.
- SOMEHOW, I GET THE FEELING
HE'S THE LUCKY ONE.
[ Beeping ]
[ Raines ]
WHAT IS IT, ANGELO?
SUBLEVEL SECURITY ALERT?
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Woman Over Police Radio,
Indistinct ]
[ Jiggling Lock ]
SHE'S NOT THERE.
POLICE OFFICER, MA'AM.
IT'S NOT LIKE JEANETTE
TO DISAPPEAR,
NOT WITH THAT NEW BABY.
SHE'S A NICE GIRL, SMART.
I TOLD EVERYTHING
TO THE OTHER POLICEMAN.
OTHER POLICEMAN?
- WHEN?
- TEN, 15 MINUTES AGO,
BEFORE YOU GOT HERE.
- [ Man ] DISPATCH, THIS IS 36.
- [ Man #2 ] GO, 36.
[ Man #1 ]
UH, WE FOUND A JUMPER BELOW
THE EAST RIVER BRIDGE.
FEMALE CAUCASIAN, EARLY 20s,
NO I.D.
MAY HAVE BEEN THERE A FEW DAYS.
TRANSPORTING HER TO ST. MARY'S
UNDER SUICIDE WATCH. OVER.
[ Man #2 ]
COPY THAT, 36.
WHAT ABOUT JEANETTE?
DON'T WORRY, MA'AM.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF JEANETTE.
[ Broots ]
WHOA!
[ Glass Breaking ]
OH, GOD.
SYRINGES?
WHAT IS IT?
THIS PLACE HAS
ALL THE COMPONENTS
OF A SIM LAB.
[ Broots ]
I NEVER KNEW THERE WAS
ANOTHER SIM LAB IN THE CENTRE.
[ Sydney ]
NEITHER DID I.
[ Broots ]
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
BIRTHING TABLE.
WITH SHACKLES?
[ Pager Beeping ]
UH-OH.
- IT'S MR. RAINES.
- WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
MISS PARKER.
WHAT IS THIS PLACE?
WHATEVER IT WAS,
IT WASN'T A FILING ROOM.
THESE HAVEN'T BEEN BURNT.
THESE WERE BROUGHT HERE.
ALL THESE FILES PERTAIN
TO THE PRETENDER PROJECT.
THIS BOX IS ALL ABOUT JAROD.
WHAT IS THAT?
A HOOD.
MUST'VE BEEN JAROD'S.
SYDNEY, THERE IS
NO DATE OF DEATH...
LISTED FOR
JAROD'S PARENTS.
AS FAR AS THESE DOCUMENTS
ARE CONCERNED, THEY WERE ALIVE
WHEN JAROD WAS BROUGHT HERE.
JAROD WAS STOLEN.
I THINK YOU SHOULD
LOOK AT THIS ENTRANCE RECORD.
THERE'S NO NAMES,
NOTHING TO FOLLOW.
HMM.
BUT THERE IS A SIGNATURE BY
A SPECIAL EXPEDITER WHO
BROUGHT JAROD TO THE CENTRE.
SPECIAL EXPEDITER--
JACOB.
THAT SIGNATURE
IS MY BROTHER-- JACOB.
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
WHAT?
RAINES HAS ANGELO SANITIZING
THE SECURITY SYSTEM.
DOES HE KNOW WHERE WE ARE?
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
- YOU DON'T THINK?
- YES. NO! I DON'T KNOW!
IT WAS WEIRD.
RAINES WAS REAL SUSPICIOUS,
AND ANGELO JUST KEPT GIGGLING.
AND, MAN, YOU'RE NOT GONNA
BELIEVE HIS HEAD.
JUST KEEP YOURS COOL.
IT'S RAINES.
HE KNOWS.
JUST GRAB THE FILES.
THESE FILES HAVE BEEN
COLLECTED BY SOMEONE.
REMOVING THEM
WILL AROUSE SUSPICION.
THIS MAY BE OUR ONLY CHANCE.
I WANT TO FIND OUT THE TRUTH
AS MUCH AS YOU DO.
BUT AT THIS POINT,
CAUTION IS KEY.
DETECTIVE DAVE GEARY.
YOU'VE GOT THAT JANE DOE.
[ Jarod ] COME ON. COME ON.
[ Woman ]
STILL CHECKING, DETECTIVE.
SUICIDE ATTEMPT.
[ Woman ]
IT'S JUST NOT COMING UP.
OH, HERE IT IS.
ROOM 708.
JEANETTE.
JEANETTE, WAKE UP.
PLEASE, NO MORE.
I DON'T NEED ANY MORE SEDATIVES.
I'M NOT CRAZY.
I KNOW.
OH, NO, NO.
I DIDN'T TRY TO KILL MYSELF.
THERE WAS A MAN,
AND HE THREW ME OFF THE BRIDGE.
IT WAS A POLICEMAN.
WHY WON'T ANYONE BELIEVE ME?
- I BELIEVE YOU.
- WELL, WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME IS JAROD.
I'M HERE TO HELP YOU.
- HE TOOK MY BABY.
- I HAVE YOUR BABY.
HE'S WITH ME.
WHERE'S MICHAEL?
HE IS SAFE, BUT WE MUST
GET OUT OF THIS HOSPITAL.
THE MAN WHO TRIED TO KILL YOU
IS HERE.
[ Woman Over P.A. ]
DR. PETERSON, CALL YOUR SERVICE.
[ Chatter, Indistinct ]
[ Engine Starting ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
I WAS SO AFRAID
I WOULD NEVER SEE HIM AGAIN.
WHERE'D YOU FIND HIM?
THAT'S NOT IMPORTANT.
WHAT'S IMPORTANT IS
YOU'RE TOGETHER NOW.
JEANETTE,
WHY WOULD A POLICE DETECTIVE
WANT YOU AND MICHAEL DEAD?
WAS IT BECAUSE OF
MITCH MEYERS?
YEAH.
IS MICHAEL MITCH'S SON?
I WAS WORKING AS AN INTERN
IN HIS OFFICE.
I THOUGHT HE WAS GOOD.
I THOUGHT HE MEANT
THE THINGS THAT HE SAID.
WE HAD AN AFFAIR.
HE SAID HE DIDN'T LOVE
HIS WIFE ANYMORE,
AND HE WAS GONNA LEAVE HER.
I MEAN, I COULD BARELY
PAY FOR MY RENT,
SO I TOLD HIM HE HAD TO TAKE
RESPONSIBILITY FOR HIS SON.
AND?
HE SAID HE WOULD DO
THE RIGHT THING,
AND I-I BELIEVED HIM.
I MEAN, I DIDN'T THINK--
IT'S OKAY.
DETECTIVE GEARY CAME,
AND HE TOLD ME...
THAT MITCH WANTED TO SEE ME
BECAUSE HE WANTED TO HELP US.
AND I-- I DIDN'T THINK.
WE JUST GOT IN THE CAR,
AND THE NEXT THING I KNEW,
I'M BEING DRAGGED OUT
ON THE BRIDGE, AND ALL I COULD
HEAR WAS MY MICHAEL CRYING.
I OUGHTA BREAK
THE BASTARD'S NECK.
NOW CAN WE GO TO THE POLICE?
[ Jarod ]
NO.
WE HAVE TO PLAY
A LITTLE POLITICS
WITH THE D.A. FIRST.
I WANNA HELP.
FOR MICHAEL.
ISN'T TOMORROW GARBAGE DAY?
MITCH MEYERS, PLEASE.
IT'S URGENT.
[ Meyers ]
JEANETTE, LISTEN TO ME.
WHEN HE WAS BORN--
[ Jeanette ]
HIS NAME IS MICHAEL.
RIGHT. WHEN MICHAEL WAS BORN,
I THOUGHT I COULD FINALLY
MAKE THE BREAK.
THEN I STARTED THINKING HOW
IT MIGHT LOOK-- MY WIFE, MY
CHILDREN, YOU BEING SO YOUNG.
EVERYTHING I HAVE WORKED FOR--
ALL THE GOOD I HAVE DONE-- IT
WOULD BE GOING DOWN THE DRAIN.
SO YOU TRIED TO KILL US?
NO, THAT'S NOT WHAT I WANTED.
THAT'S NOT WHO I AM.
I LOVE YOU.
LOOK, IF YOU DON'T WANT
THE TRUTH PLAYED OUT
ON THE 11:00 NEWS,
YOU HAVE DETECTIVE GEARY
BRING $50,000 TO THE ALLEY
WHERE HE LEFT MICHAEL AT 2:00.
[ Truck Approaching ]
POLICE OFFICER.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO TAKE
THIS TRASH ANOTHER TIME.
WE COLLECT IT NOW.
YOU GUYS DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOIN'.
YOU FEELING NAKED?
A LITTLE VULNERABLE?
IT'S TERRIFYING, ISN'T IT?
BEING AT
SOMEONE ELSE'S MERCY,
COMPLETELY DEFENSELESS...
LIKE A LITTLE BABY...
TOSSED IN A DUMPSTER
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
YOU THREW AWAY
AN INNOCENT BABY.
[ Click ]
I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR THIS
MOMENT EVER SINCE I SAW YOU,
STANDING IN THE ALLEY.
AS DISTRICT ATTORNEY,
I HAVE WORKED HARD
FOR THIS CITY...
TO REPAIR THE FAITH,
THE BELIEF AND THE LEADERSHIP...
OF YOUR ELECTED OFFICIALS.
EXCUSE ME. MRS. MEYERS?
HI.
MY NAME IS JEANETTE CONNELLY.
...FAMILY VALUES,
RESPONSIBILITIES--
YOUR HUSBAND AND I
HAVE BEEN HAVING AN AFFAIR.
I AM A MAN WHO
BELIEVES IN COMMITMENT.
JAN-- MY WIFE OF 15 YEARS--
MY TWO BEAUTIFUL DAUGHTERS--
JESSICA AND LINDSAY.
I KNOW WHAT IT TAKES
TO BUILD A SUCCESSFUL FAMILY.
IT TAKES HONESTY.
[ Jeanette Over Speaker ]
YOU TRIED TO KILL
ME AND OUR SON.
[ Meyers Over Speaker ]
JEANETTE, LISTEN TO ME.
I WAS FRIGHTENED OF
WHAT YOU MIGHT DO, MIGHT SAY.
EVERYTHING I HAVE WORKED FOR--
ALL THE GOOD I HAVE DONE-- IT
WOULD BE GOING DOWN THE DRAIN.
SO YOU TRIED TO KILL US?
NO, THAT'S NOT WHAT I WANTED.
THAT'S NOT WHO I AM.
I TOLD GEARY TO FRIGHTEN YOU.
THAT'S ALL.
I DIDN'T KNOW HE WAS GONNA
TAKE IT AS FAR AS MURDER.
YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE ME.
[ Groans ]
OH! I ALMOST FORGOT.
NOW THEY'RE STRAIGHT.
[ Michael Crying ]
THANKS, AXE.
BYE-BYE TO JAROD.
HEY. COME HERE.
BYE, JAROD.
THANKS, CHRISTINE.
HEY, LITTLE MAN,
IT WAS VERY NICE TO MEET YOU.
I WANT YOU TO DO ME A FAVOR.
I WANT YOU TO ALWAYS
LISTEN TO YOUR MOM.
NEVER, EVER FORGET HER.
OKAY?
THERE'S MY BOY.
HI! HOW'RE YOU DOIN'?
THANK YOU.
GOOD LUCK.
SAY BYE-BYE, SWEETIE.
BYE.
[ Sydney ]
BROOTS HAS CIRCUMVENTED
THE SECURITY SENSORS.
WE HAVE 10 MINUTES.
LET'S JUST TAKE A CLOSER LOOK
AT THOSE FILES
AND GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
IT'S ALL GONE.
RAINES.
[ Sydney ]
NO. IF RAINES KNEW
WE FOUND THOSE FILES,
WE'D BE DEAD.
WELL, IF HE DIDN'T
TAKE THEM, WHO DID?
[ Mews ]