[ Clicking ]
WHY AM I HERE, SYDNEY?
I WANT YOU TO EXAMINE
SOME PHOTOGRAPHS.
IS HE A WARRIOR?
[ Young Sydney ]
YES, A SOLDIER
IN SOUTHEAST ASIA.
WHY DO I HAVE TO
LOOK AT HIM?
THERE ARE PEOPLE
WHO BELIEVE THIS PHOTOGRAPH
WAS MANUFACTURED,
CREATED.
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT YOU THINK.
HE'S AFRAID,
SAD.
[ Young Sydney ]
HE'S MISSING.
THE PEOPLE WHO LOVE HIM WANT
TO KNOW IF HE'S STILL ALIVE.
LIKE MY PARENTS?
[ Gunfire ]
[ Gunfire Continues ]
WHY ARE YOU SO INTERESTED
IN MR. STARR?
[ Miss Parker ]
IT'S A FAMILY MATTER.
COULD YOU DESCRIBE
HIS MANNER, HIS MOOD,
YOU KNOW?
UH, I TELL YOU--
THAT OL' BOY
WAS MULTIFACETED.
HE WALKED IN HERE, AND HE
DIDN'T KNOW A PICKLE BARREL
FROM A GUN BARREL.
AND IN LESS THAN 24 HOURS--
[ Laughing ]
HE'S DOING THIS.
10:19.
THEY'RE ALL LIKE THIS.
DAMNED IF I KNOW
WHAT IT MEANS.
- OH, AND THEN
THERE WAS THE SLUGS.
- WHAT ABOUT THE SLUGS?
HE PAID EXTRA TO COME IN
AFTER HOURS AND DIG 'EM
OUT THE BACK WALL.
SAID HE WANTED TO STUDY 'EM.
HE WAS REAL BIG
ON STUDYIN' THINGS.
[ Laughing ]
- LIKE I SAY, THIS OL' BOY
WAS MULTIFACETED.
- MULTIFACETED.
[ Laughing ]
DID HE HAPPEN TO SAY
WHERE HE WAS GOING?
HE WAS STAYING AT THE LODGE
UP NEAR THE HIGHWAY.
YOU MIGHT CHECK THERE.
THANK YOU.
SURE ENOUGH.
CAN I?
FREE COUNTRY.
OH, HEY!
WHEN YOU FIND HIM,
GIVE HIM HIS TOY.
HIS TOY?
YEAH. WHEN HE WAS THROUGH
SHOOTING, HE'D RUN THAT
ALL AROUND THE PLACE.
[ Laughing ]
THAT OL' BOY WAS JUST
A BIG KID, THAT'S ALL.
FUNNY, HUH?
- HYSTERICAL.
- HERE.
[ Whirring ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Siren Continues ]
[ Siren Stops ]
[ Police Radio Chatter,
Indistinct ]
WAS I GOING TOO FAST
WHEN I PASSED THAT TRUCK?
NO, SIR.
WHEN YOU PASSED ME.
[ Man Narrating ]
[ Man ]
I WANT MY LAWYER.
I GOT RIGHTS!
YOU BETTER RELAX.
YOU HEAR ME?
SHUT UP AND DON'T MOVE.
WANT A BEER OR CAPPUCCINO
OR SOMETHING?
HA-HA.
LET'S SEE
WHAT WE GOT HERE.
OH, BOY! A BONA FIDE
THREE-TIME LOSER, FRANKIE.
WE KNOW WHAT THAT
MEANS, DON'T WE?
AUTOMATIC JAIL TIME, ISN'T IT?
CONGRATULATIONS.
THOUGH IT DOES SEEM
A LITTLE HARSH,
CONSIDERING THAT YOU GOT
ONLY-- WHAT?
SIX DOLLARS AND 37 CENTS
OFF AN OLD LADY.
YOU ALMOST GOT AWAY
WITH IT TOO.
YOU ARE WHAT WE CALL
A TOP-NOTCH CRIMINAL.
WHERE'S MY COFFEE, FRANK?
RUN, YOU LITTLE PUKE!
- [ Grunts ]
- OW!
MAN, MAYBE I SHOULD'VE
GOT HIM A DECAF.
THAT LOOKED LIKE IT HURT.
SEE WHAT HAPPENS WHEN YOU
ACT LIKE AN IDIOT?
PUT THE TRACK STAR
IN HIS CAGE.
DON'T RIP THAT PRETTY SHIRT.
- SLICK MOVE. CARL BISHOP.
- HOW YOU DOIN'? FRANK MEYERS.
JAROD STARR.
TWO R's.
- HEY, LIKE RINGO.
- WHO'S RINGO?
THAT'S FUNNY.
HOW COME I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU
AROUND HERE BEFORE?
HE JUST TRANSFERRED IN
FROM CHICAGO.
YOU'RE LATE AGAIN TODAY,
AND I'M STILL WAITING ON
THOSE TRANSFER PAPERS.
I WAS COMING TO TALK TO YOU--
BISHOP, MEYERS, YOU TWO WERE DUE
IN MY OFFICE A HALF HOUR AGO.
YEAH. WELL, WE'VE
BEEN KIND OF BUSY.
- I WANT YOU BOTH INSIDE NOW.
- DETECTIVE, GIVE US A BREAK.
WE'VE GONE OVER THIS ALREADY.
NOW.
THAT WOMAN NEEDS A HOBBY.
SHE'S JUST DOING
HER JOB, FRANK.
- WE'LL SEE YOU LATER, CHICAGO.
- LOOK FORWARD TO IT.
[ Meyers ]
YEAH, NICE MEETING YOU.
- DID I MISS SOMETHING?
- TYPICAL I.A. FROST.
- SHE'S INTERNAL AFFAIRS?
- DETECTIVE KAREN SWINDELL.
DON'T GET ANY IDEAS,
ROMEO.
SHE'S THE ORIGINAL
ICE PRINCESS.
YOU WERE SAYING SOMETHING
ABOUT TRANSFER PAPERS.
COME ON, SARGE.
YOU KNOW HOW IT IS
WITH RED TAPE. THEY SHOULD
BE ALONG ANY DAY NOW.
UNTIL I GET THE REST
OF YOUR DOCUMENTATION,
YOU'RE GONNA
BE RIDING A DESK
INSTEAD OF A BIKE.
YOU DON'T WANT ME
TO START THINKING
YOU'RE UP TO SOMETHING.
ME? SARGE,
I'M CLEAN AS A WHISTLE.
GET BACK TO WORK.
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
CAN I HELP YOU, OFFICER?
MA'AM, DID YOU, BY ANY CHANCE,
HAPPEN TO NOTICE THE COLOR--
WHOA! IS THAT A TWIN CAM?
EXCUSE ME?
YOU GUYS BORE OUT
THE CYLINDER HEADS, DON'T YOU?
MAN, I'D LOVE TO SOUP UP
MY HONEYPOT.
YOUR HONEYPOT?
MY HOG.
I WAS GOIN' TO
BLOW OUT THE HEADERS
AND OPEN UP THE CYLINDER BLOCK,
BUT MY SOCIAL SECURITY CHECK
WAS LATE.
- MILLIE!
- HEY, MILL!
YOU'RE LOOKIN' GOOD!
RIDE... YOU DEVILS!
[ Laughing ]
RODE WITH THOSE DUDES
IN JACKSONVILLE.
MA'AM.
MILDRED REYNOLDS.
FRIENDS CALL ME MILLIE.
MILLIE.
DID YOU HAPPEN TO NOTICE
THE COLOR OF THE LIGHT BACK
THERE IN THE INTERSECTION?
WHAT LIGHT?
WONDER BOY CHECKED OUT OF THIS
DIRT-WATER TOWN THREE DAYS AGO.
THAT'S ALL
HE LEFT BEHIND.
WHERE'S THE DRIVER?
USING THE FACILITY.
GUY HAS THE BLADDER
OF A SQUIRREL.
[ Siren Chirping ]
HMM. WHAT NOW?
- AFTERNOON, MISSY.
- SHERIFF.
WOULD YOU MIND
TAKING OFF YOUR JACKET?
EXCUSE ME?
OH, IT'S NOTHING PERSONAL.
I'D JUST LIKE YOU TO TAKE OFF
YOUR JACKET, PLEASE.
I WILL NOT.
PLEASE.
[ Miss Parker ]
YOU ARE FIRED!
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
I'VE SEEN DELIVERANCE.
YOU WANNA GIVE ME
ONE OF THESE?
OH! THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH.
MY, MY!
GUESS YOU
CAN PUT SOME CUFFS
ON THIS YOUNG LADY.
MA'AM, YOU'RE UNDER ARREST
FOR VIOLATION OF
THE CRIMINAL CODE 369.7.
AND WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
CARRYING A CONCEALED WEAPON.
IT SAYS SO RIGHT HERE
IN THE BOOK.
HIGHLIGHTED IN YELLOW.
[ Sheriff ]
I GUESS YOU'LL BE
GOING WITH ME.
JAROD.
[ Exhales ]
SO LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT.
THIS STARTS OUT
AS A PART OF THIS,
BUT THEN YOU PUNCH IT OUT,
AND YOU SELL IT
AS A SEPARATE PRODUCT.
I THINK YOU GOT IT.
DOUGHNUT. DOUGHNUT HOLE.
I DON'T MEAN
TO BELABOR A POINT,
BUT IF THE HOLE IS HERE,
WHY DO YOU CALL THIS
THE HOLE?
THE TRUTH IS, I'VE ALWAYS
WONDERED THAT MYSELF.
BUT DON'T TELL MY BOSS.
I WOULDN'T WANT HIM TO THINK
I DON'T KNOW THE BUSINESS.
I PROMISE.
AND I'LL HAVE
ANOTHER ONE, PLEASE.
ON THE HOUSE.
OH. IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I'D RATHER EAT IT HERE.
GOOD MORNING,
MR. KEMBROOK!
HE SEEMS VERY SAD.
[ Woman ] POOR MAN.
HE HASN'T BEEN THE SAME
SINCE MARVIN WAS KILLED.
MARVIN.
HIS SON.
HE WAS A GUARD
AT THE BOSWELL JEWELERS.
ABOUT A MONTH AGO,
HE WAS SHOT
TRYING TO ROB IT.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU KNOW
THE FAMILY PRETTY WELL.
HMM. SINCE I WAS BORN.
MR. KEMBROOK ANYWAY.
I'M AFRAID
YOU'VE LOST ME.
THE KEMBROOKS GAVE MARVIN
UP FOR ADOPTION
WHEN HE WAS JUST A BABY.
A FEW YEARS AFTER
MRS. KEMBROOK DIED, MR. KEMBROOK
STARTED SEARCHING FOR HIS SON.
- FOUND HIM SIX MONTHS AGO.
- HE MUST HAVE BEEN VERY HAPPY.
[ Woman ]
THEY BOTH WERE.
TURNS OUT MARVIN
WAS LOOKING FOR HIS PARENTS
THE WHOLE TIME TOO.
CAN YOU IMAGINE MEETING YOUR
OWN PARENTS FOR THE FIRST TIME
WHEN YOU'RE A GROWN ADULT?
GUESS IT WOULD BE
PRETTY EMOTIONAL.
OH, YEAH.
EVEN AFTER ALL THOSE YEARS,
THEY STILL LOVED EACH OTHER.
WHAT MAKES YOU SO SURE?
BECAUSE THEY WERE BLOOD,
AND THERE'S NOTHING
STRONGER THAN THAT.
[ Door Bells Jingling ]
[ Woman ]
MRS. MORGAN, WE MAY HAVE
A SIGHTING ON YOUR DAUGHTER.
MY PEOPLE ARE FLYING
TO NEW YORK AS WE SPEAK.
IF ALL GOES WELL,
YOU SHOULD HAVE YOUR ARMS
AROUND CATHERINE...
BY TOMORROW NIGHT.
THANK YOU.
GOD BLESS YOU TOO.
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
I DON'T KNOW WHO I AM.
[ Miss Parker ]
NOW, LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU STOPPED ME BECAUSE OF
AN ANONYMOUS PHONE CALL?
[ Sheriff ]
UH-HUH.
DO YOU MIND TELLING ME
HOW YOU KNEW THIS PERSON
WAS TELLING THE TRUTH?
HE SOUNDED HONEST.
IT'S OFFICIAL.
I'M IN HELL!
OH, NOW, DARLIN',
YOU DID HAVE THAT
CONCEALED WEAPON ON YOU,
AND YOU'LL BE ABLE TO POST BAIL
AS SOON AS JUDGE HARGRAVE GET
BACK FROM THAT BASS TOURNAMENT,
AND WE SIGN OURSELVES
SOME PAPERS.
- WHEN EXACTLY IS THAT?
- DAY AFTER TOMORROW.
[ Sydney ]
THANKS.
THE ENTIRE LEGAL STAFF
AT THE CENTRE...
IS ON THEIR ANNUAL RETREAT
IN THE SOUTH OF FRANCE,
SO IT WILL BE
AT LEAST 72 HOURS BEFORE WE
CAN EVEN REACH A LAWYER.
HE KNEW THAT.
DAMN IT, SYDNEY.
HE'S UP TO SOMETHING.
AND HE NEEDS ME
OUT OF THE WAY
FOR THREE DAYS.
[ Sydney ]
10:19.
COULD BE A TIME REFERENCE.
FORGET THAT!
JUST GET ME A LAWYER.
ANY LAWYER.
[ Granger ]
MOST MISSING PERSONS CASES FALL
INTO ONE OF THREE CATEGORIES:
ABDUCTIONS, RUNAWAYS
OR ABANDONMENT.
I'M LOOKING FOR MY PARENTS.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
I CAN HELP?
I READ IN THE PAPER THAT YOU
HELPED REUNITE A FATHER AND SON
AFTER 25 YEARS.
FRIENDLY WARNING:
THEY DON'T ALL TURN OUT
THAT WAY.
THERE'S A RISK A PERSON TAKES
WHEN THEY SEARCH FOR THEIR PAST.
IT'S NOT ALWAYS
WHAT THEY HOPE FOR.
I'D BE WILLING TO RISK ANYTHING
FOR THE CHANCE TO FIND OUT.
ARE THEY STILL ALIVE?
[ Young Sydney ]
JAROD, IS HE STILL ALIVE?
THE EYES.
WHAT ABOUT THE EYES?
HE WANTS TO CRY,
BUT HE CAN'T.
WHY NOT?
HE FEELS ALONE, FORGOTTEN.
HE JUST DOESN'T CARE
ANYMORE.
CARE ABOUT WHO?
HIMSELF.
HE'S GIVEN UP.
I WON'T GIVE UP, SYDNEY.
[ Echoing ]
I'LL NEVER GIVE UP.
OFFICER STARR?
JAROD.
HMM?
I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU KNEW IF YOUR PARENTS
WERE STILL ALIVE.
I WAS NEVER TOLD THE TRUTH.
WHY NOT USE THE POLICE DATABASE
TO INITIATE A SEARCH?
I CAN'T.
THIS IS PROBABLY GONNA
BE HARD TO UNDERSTAND,
BUT I DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
SEVENTY-TWO HOURS.
WITHOUT A NAME--
I HAVE A PICTURE.
THIS IS MY MOTHER.
AT LEAST THAT'S
WHAT I WAS TOLD.
AND MY FATHER MIGHT HAVE
BEEN AN AVIATOR.
- IN THE SERVICE?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
- THANK YOU.
OFFICER STARR.
THERE'S A GROUP--
PEOPLE LIKE YOURSELF.
THERE'S A MEETING HERE
TOMORROW NIGHT
IF YOU'RE INTERESTED.
SOMETIMES IT HELPS
JUST TO KNOW
YOU'RE NOT ALONE.
[ Sighs ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Man Laughing ]
MISS PARKER.
YOU WANTED A LAWYER?
HENRY?
OH.
[ Chuckling ]
TELL ME YOU'RE KIDDING.
HENRY J. MONROE JR.,
ESQUIRE.
FINEST ATTORNEY
IN CEDAR POINT.
TRUTH BE KNOWN,
THE ONLY ATTORNEY
IN CEDAR POINT.
[ Wheezing Laugh ]
HE KNEW THIS.
[ Desk Sergeant ]
MA'AM, THERE'S NOTHING
I CAN DO.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THIS IS A DEATH SENTENCE
FOR ME.
- MILLIE?
- WHAT?
FINALLY! SOMEONE
WITH HALF A BRAIN
IN THEIR HEAD.
YOU KNOW THIS WOMAN?
WE'VE MET.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
I, UH--
I ACCIDENTALLY SIDESWIPED
A MEAT WAGON...
DOWN ON
BISCAYNE BOULEVARD.
NOW THEY WANT TO PUT ME
IN CEMENT BOOTS AND DUMP ME
INTO THE CAUSEWAY.
SHE RAN AN EMPTY COUNTY
AMBULANCE OFF THE ROAD,
AND WE'RE SUSPENDING
HER DRIVER'S LICENSE.
CAN YOU GIVE US
A MOMENT, PLEASE?
BE MY GUEST.
I WOULDN'T TRUST THAT ONE
AS FAR AS I CAN THROW HER.
MILLIE,
THIS IS VERY SERIOUS.
WHAT IF THAT AMBULANCE
WAS CARRYING SOMEBODY
TO THE HOSPITAL?
GEEZ, I DON'T WANT
TO HURT ANYBODY.
LOOK, MY, UH--
MY HUSBAND'S DEAD,
AND MY KIDS ARE ALL GONE.
THEY'RE ON THEIR OWN.
I'M 73 YEARS OLD,
AND I'M ALONE.
YOU TAKE MY BIKE,
YOU TAKE MY INDEPENDENCE.
YOU TAKE THAT,
YOU MIGHT AS WELL BURY ME...
'CAUSE I'LL--
I'LL BE DEAD.
A LOVELY RUBY, EMERALD
AND SAPPHIRE TRIO...
BORDERED BY DIAMONDS.
HOW MUCH IS IT?
ONLY $4,000.
HMM. THAT'S NOT ENOUGH.
WELL, I DO HAVE
THIS BRILLIANT...
PRINCESS-CUT DIAMOND
WITH A TRILLION
ON EITHER SIDE...
FOR 5,000.
WITH TAX
THAT WOULD BE 5,328.
THAT'S PERFECT.
I'LL TAKE IT.
YOU DO REALIZE THIS PURCHASE
IS GOING TO MAX OUT
YOUR CREDIT CARD.
THAT'S THE IDEA.
[ Chuckling ]
[ TV: Indistinct ]
[ Man ]
AN ODYSSEY OF SEARCHING
FOR THE PAST...
CAME TO A DRAMATIC
AND EMOTIONAL CONCLUSION
EARLIER THIS MORNING...
AS HAROLD KEMBROOK
NERVOUSLY WAITED FOR THE DOORS
OF THE TAXI TO OPEN...
AND DELIVER HIS SON,
GIVEN UP FOR ADOPTION...
SOME 25 YEARS EARLIER.
AS FATE WOULD HAVE IT,
HIS SON,
MARVIN HOWARD KEMBROOK,
HAD SPENT THE LAST 11 YEARS
ON THE VERY SAME HUNT...
FOR HIS TRUE IDENTITY.
ALSO ON HAND TO WITNESS
THE EMOTIONAL REUNION...
WAS SUSAN GRANGER,
THE WOMAN INSTRUMENTAL
IN BRINGING THE TWO MEN
TOGETHER, FATHER AND--
[ TV: Off ]
[ Knocking On Door ]
JUST A SECOND.
YOU STARR?
THAT'S ME.
YOU ORDERED THE DOUGHNUTS.
RASPBERRY SUPREMES?
WHATEVER.
[ Jarod ]
MMM! THIS SHOULD COVER IT.
HEY.
I'M GONNA GO OUT
ON A REAL LIMB HERE
AND TAKE A GUESS...
THAT YOU'RE
A BIG DOUGHNUT FAN?
THEY'RE VERY GOOD.
WHAT ARE YOU,
LIKE, A COP?
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
THAT'S FUNNY.
DETECTIVE SWINDELL?
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND
IF I SKIP THE BIRTHDAY SONG.
I NEVER ACTUALLY
LEARNED THE WORDS.
YOU READ MY FILE.
THAT'S MY JOB.
IT'S A BAVARIAN CREAM.
I WAS THINKING ABOUT
GETTING YOU A RASPBERRY SUPREME,
BUT SOMEBODY ATE THE LAST ONE.
BUT THIS ONE'S
VERY GOOD.
MOST UNIFORMS DON'T WANT
TO SOCIALIZE WITH I.A.
THE TRUTH IS, I'M THINKING
ABOUT PUTTING IN FOR A TRANSFER
TO INTERNAL AFFAIRS,
AND THE EXAMINATION REQUIRES
THAT THE APPLICANT BREAK DOWN
AN ACTUAL CASE FILE--
- AND YOU WANT MY HELP.
- I HEARD YOU WERE
VERY THOROUGH.
UH, DO YOU HAVE ANY
PARTICULAR CASE IN MIND?
YES, I DO.
ARE YOU GOING
TO EAT THAT?
SO, ACCORDING TO
THE FIELD REPORT,
BISHOP AND MEYERS
RESPONDED TO A ROBBERY CALL
AT THE JEWELRY STORE.
WHEN THEY GET THERE,
A SECURITY GUARD,
MARVIN KEMBROOK,
IS ROBBING
THE PLACE...
WITH AN ACCOMPLICE.
SO THIS ACCOMPLICE
SHOOTS KEMBROOK,
AND THEN HE GETS AWAY.
THIS SOUNDS MORE LIKE
AN UNSOLVED HOMICIDE THAN
AN I.A. INVESTIGATION.
FORENSICS
WENT OVER THAT STORE
WITH A FINE-TOOTH COMB.
THEY DIDN'T FIND A PRINT,
A FIBER, NOTHING.
SO THIS ACCOMPLICE
WAS EFFICIENT.
[ Chuckles ]
IF YOU'RE EVER GONNA MAKE IT
IN I.A., YOU HAVE TO REALIZE
THAT PART OF THE JOB...
IS TO GET INSIDE THE HEADS
OF THE PEOPLE INVOLVED
IN THE CASE.
MARVIN KEMBROOK SPENT MOST
OF HIS LIFE IN FOSTER HOMES.
WHEN HE WAS 18,
HE JOINED THE MARINES.
I LOOKED UP HIS MILITARY FILE.
HE TESTED IN THE LOWEST
FIVE PERCENT OF HIS UNIT,
SPENT 10 YEARS IN UNIFORM
AND NEVER BUSTED CORPORAL.
NOT EXACTLY
A CRIMINAL MASTERMIND.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT A YOUNG MAN
WHO JUST FOUND OUT WHO HE WAS,
WHERE HE CAME FROM.
HE HAD $2,000
IN HIS BANK ACCOUNT.
HIS BILLS WERE PAID.
YOU WANT TO TELL ME
HE'D THROW ALL THAT AWAY
FOR A FAST SCORE?
SO IF YOU DON'T THINK
THAT KEMBROOK WAS INVOLVED,
AND THE ACCOMPLICE
WAS FICTITIOUS,
WHO DID IT?
THERE WAS ONE PIECE OF HARD
EVIDENCE LEFT AT THE SCENE--
THE SLUG THEY DUG OUT
OF MARVIN KEMBROOK'S CHEST.
FIND THE GUN
THAT FIRED THAT BULLET,
AND YOU FIND THE REAL KILLER.
OH, MAN!
[ Toilet Flushing ]
WHAT, YOU'RE LATE AGAIN,
HUH?
THE DESK SARGE IS GONNA
HAVE MY BUTT IN A SLING
IF SHE CATCHES ME.
CAN YOU DO ME A FAVOR?
WHAT'S UP?
MY TRANSFER PAPERS
GOT SENT TO MY HOUSE
BY MISTAKE.
WOULD YOU GIVE THEM TO HER,
AFTER I'M GONE?
NO PROBLEM.
THANKS.
HEY, LISTEN. YOU KNOW,
I'M KIND OF NEW AROUND HERE
AND DON'T KNOW MANY PEOPLE.
I WAS THINKING MAYBE I COULD
TAKE YOU AND YOUR PARTNER
TO LUNCH ONE DAY.
MY TREAT.
YEAH, SURE.
HOW 'BOUT TOMORROW?
GREAT.
I LOOK FORWARD TO IT.
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
HEY, PARTNER.
HOW'S IT GOING?
ALL RIGHT, BRO.
READ THIS. I THINK
WE FOUND THE GUY
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR.
YEAH?
[ Woman ]
IT'S BEEN ALMOST 11 YEARS...
SINCE MY SON DISAPPEARED,
AND THERE ISN'T A DAY
THAT GOES BY...
THAT I DON'T THINK
I SEE HIM,
STANDING
ON A STREET CORNER...
OR PASSING BY
ON A CITY BUS.
MY FRIENDS, THEY ALL SAY,
"YOU SHOULD LET IT GO."
BUT, I MEAN,
HOW DO YOU DENY YOURSELF?
HOW DO YOU JUST...
WALK AWAY FROM YOUR LIFE?
YOU DON'T.
WE'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR MORE YEARS
THAN I WANT TO REMEMBER,
MORE YEARS THAN ANY OF US
WANT TO ADMIT.
YOU PEOPLE KNOW MY STORY,
WHAT HAPPENED TO MY SON.
[ Woman's Voice Overlapping ]
I'M HERE TO TELL YOU THAT
YOU SHOULD NEVER GIVE UP.
NEVER STOP LOOKING FOR
THE PEOPLE THAT YOU LOVE
BECAUSE IT'S WORTH IT,
EVEN IF IT'S
FOR JUST A MOMENT.
YOU KNOW,
WE SIT HERE AND WE...
TALK ABOUT HOW MUCH
WE MISS THEM AND...
HOW MUCH WE LOVED THEM.
IN THE END, I THINK IT'S--
I THINK IT'S THE LITTLE THINGS
THAT WE MISS THE MOST.
THE WAY WE SEE OURSELVES
IN OUR CHILDREN.
[ Voices Overlapping ]
THE WAY HE SAT IN A CHAIR.
HIS LAUGH.
THE WAY HE STIRRED
HIS COFFEE.
[ Jarod's Mother's Voice ]
NEVER GIVE UP...
EVER.
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Man ] AH, BABY, YOU ARE
BUMMING MY TRIP, MAN.
[ Millie ]
PINT-SIZED NERD!
NERD? I'M REAL, MAN.
[ Millie ]
YOU WEREN'T LOOKING
WHERE YOU WERE GOING!
I WASN'T GOING ANYWHERE.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO YELL.
I'M NOT DEAF.
NO, YOU'RE BLIND, LADY.
YOU GOTTA TAKE A CHILL--
WELL, I WANNA TELL YOU.
YOU JUST BETTER HAVE
A LITTLE RESPECT!
- WHAT SEEMS TO BE THE TROUBLE?
- FEEBLE KNIEVEL HERE ALMOST CUT
ME IN HALF WITH HER TRICYCLE.
YOU LITTLE PUNK!
OKAY, OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
THAT IS ENOUGH.
YOU, STAY HERE.
YOU, COME WITH ME.
LOOK AT THAT.
IS THAT IT?
YEAH.
IT'S NOTHING THAT A LITTLE
SANDPAPER AND TOUCH-UP PAINT
WON'T CURE.
YOU DO HAVE INSURANCE?
YEAH, BUT I'M NOT GONNA LET
THAT OLD BAG GET AWAY.
SHE ALMOST WASTED ME,
MAN.
WHAT HAVE WE HERE?
AN EXPIRED
LICENSE PLATE.
THAT'S GONNA COST YOU
ABOUT A HUNDRED BUCKS
IN FINES.
AND I COULD, OF COURSE,
SEARCH YOUR VAN.
SANDPAPER
AND TOUCH-UP PAINT ON--
MM-HMM.
HAVE A NICE DAY.
AND YOU, YOUNG LADY,
YOU'RE COMING WITH ME.
OH. WHERE?
THERE.
[ Meyers ]
SO WHAT DID YOUR WIFE
DO NEXT?
SHE WALKS IN,
SHE PACKS HER BAGS,
AND THEN SHE SPLITS.
OUCH.
YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING ME.
WHY WOULD I MAKE UP
A STORY LIKE THAT?
THEY ARE SO UNBELIEVABLE.
IT'S INCREDIBLE. NEXT TIME
I TALKED TO HER, WE WERE IN SOME
LAWYER'S OFFICE, 100 BUCKS PER.
- SOUNDS LIKE MY LAST WIFE.
- OH, NO.
- MARRIAGE NUMBER THREE?
- NO. FOUR.
FOUR? GEEZ!
WHAT, YOU GOT, LIKE,
A THOUSAND KIDS?
- NO, SIX. SIX REAL GOOD KIDS.
- AND THEY DON'T LOOK LIKE HIM.
SHUT UP, FRANK.
MUST BE TOUGH
MAKING ENDS MEET,
WITH ALL THOSE OBLIGATIONS.
I MAKE SURE EVERYBODY'S
WELL TAKEN CARE OF.
STILL, YOU KNOW,
THERE'S GOTTA BE
A BETTER WAY.
- WHAT, LIKE CHICAGO?
- CHICAGO?
YEAH, WE KNOW ABOUT
THE INVESTIGATION,
THE PAYOFF MONEY YOU WERE
COLLECTING FROM THE DEALERS
ON THE SOUTH SIDE.
- YOU READ MY FILE.
- NEW GUY COMES IN,
WE CHECK HIM OUT.
YOU'D DO THE SAME THING.
YOU HAD NO RIGHT
TO READ MY FILE.
BESIDES, THEY NEVER
PROVED ANYTHING.
IT PROVES THAT YOU
CAN COVER YOUR TRACKS,
SO TAKE IT EASY.
FRANK AND I DO THE JOB,
BUT WE'RE ALWAYS LOOKING
FOR NEW OPPORTUNITIES.
- ISN'T THAT RIGHT, FRANK?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
TAKES A SPECIAL KIND OF COP
TO DO WHAT WE DO.
WE THINK YOU'RE THAT COP.
THAT'S ALL.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
YOUR CREDIT CARD
CAME BACK INVALID.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
TRY RUNNING IT THROUGH
THE RIGHT WAY.
I KNOW HOW TO DO MY JOB.
I TRIED IT THREE TIMES, OKAY?
LOOK, THERE'S SOME MISTAKE,
OBVIOUSLY.
- I ALWAYS PAY OFF
MY CREDIT CARD.
- THERE'S NO MISTAKE.
FRANK, LOOKS LIKE WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TO BAIL THIS DEADBEAT OUT
BEFORE HE PULLS HIS GUN...
AND TRIES TO SHOOT HIS WAY
OUT OF HERE.
LOOK, I GOTTA TAKE MY KID
TO LITTLE LEAGUE PRACTICE.
THANKS, BUDDY.
DROP BY THE PARK
IN A COUPLE OF HOURS.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT THEN, OKAY?
I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
YEAH, YOU DO THAT.
GOT A LITTLE
SOMETHING RIGHT HERE.
THANKS FOR LUNCH.
YEAH.
[ Granger On Phone ]
WE GOT A RED FLAG
ON YOUR MOTHER'S PHOTO.
SOMEPLACE IN DELAWARE.
DELAWARE?
MEAN ANYTHING TO YOU?
[ Jarod ]
IT USED TO.
WELL, SOMEONE PICKED UP
THE GLOBAL SCAN ON THE NET
THAT WE SENT OUT.
WE GOT AN ANONYMOUS
PHONE CALL.
WHOEVER IT WAS, RECOGNIZED
THE WOMAN IN THE PICTURE
AND HAS A NAME,
BUT THEY'RE ADAMANT ABOUT
NOT SENDING ANYTHING OVER THE
COMPUTER SYSTEM OR PHONE LINES.
I MEAN, IT SEEMS STRANGE.
YOU WANT TO GO FORWARD
WITH THIS?
YES.
OKAY.
THEY'RE SENDING THE INFORMATION
BY SPECIAL COURIER.
I'LL CALL YOU
THE SECOND IT GETS HERE.
THANK YOU.
[ Footsteps ]
[ Woman ]
BROOTS?
WE JUST GOT A SIGNAL
ALERT ON JAROD.
WHERE?
A MISSING PERSONS AGENCY
IN MIAMI.
BUT WE ALSO MONITORED
A RESPONSE SIGNAL EMANATING
FROM INSIDE THE CENTRE.
SOMEONE ON THE INSIDE
MADE CONTACT
WITH THIS AGENCY?
WELL, WHAT KIND
OF INFORMATION
WAS BREACHED?
WE-- WE'RE NOT SURE.
HAS ANYONE ALERTED
MISS PARKER?
WE THOUGHT
YOU'D WANT TO.
I'D RATHER STICK MY HEAD
IN A BEAR TRAP.
[ Bat Hitting Ball ]
[ Bishop ]
YEAH!
SO HOW MANY OF THESE JOBS
HAVE YOU PULLED?
WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE?
WE'RE THROWING YOU A ROPE.
THE QUESTION IS, ARE YOU
SMART ENOUGH TO GRAB IT?
WHY DO YOU NEED A THIRD GUY?
'CAUSE WE HAD PROBLEMS
THE LAST TIME OUT.
WE NEED A THIRD GUY
TO PLUG UP THE LEAKS.
HOW DOES IT WORK?
WE USE THE SECURITY CODES
SUPPLIED BY THE STORES.
- LOW RISK, HIGH REWARD.
- OH, YEAH.
WHAT IF SOMETHING
GOES WRONG?
IT WON'T.
HUMOR ME. WHAT IF
SOMEBODY WALKS IN?
WE'RE WEARING BLUE.
WE'RE THE GOOD GUYS.
THEY'RE NOT GONNA SUSPECT US
OF A CRIME. THEY'LL THINK
WE'RE RESPONDING TO ONE.
WHAT IF THEY PULL A GUN?
THEN WE TAKE 'EM DOWN.
I MEAN, WE JUST MAKE IT
LOOK LIKE, UH, WE STOPPED
A ROBBERY IN PROGRESS.
- WE'RE HOME FREE.
- IS THAT WHAT HAPPENED
WITH MARVIN KEMBROOK?
- WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
- [ Jarod ] COME ON.
I READ YOUR FILES TOO.
WHAT I DON'T UNDERSTAND IS,
HOW DID YOU TAMPER WITH
THE BALLISTIC REPORT?
- WHAT?
- THEY NEVER MADE A MATCH TO THE
WEAPON THAT KILLED KEMBROOK.
INTERNAL AFFAIRS
ALWAYS CHECKS THE WEAPONS
OF THE FIRST OFFICERS...
THAT ARRIVE AT THE SCENE
OF A HOMICIDE.
THINK I WAS WRONG
ABOUT YOU, JAROD.
LET'S GO, FRANK.
WHOA, WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO RISK EVERYTHING.
ALL I'M ASKING IS,
IF SOMETHING GOES WRONG,
DO I HAVE A WAY OUT?
THROWAWAY. ANKLE HOLSTER.
UNREGISTERED.
SOMETHING GOES DOWN, WE USE IT.
PUT IT IN THE TRUNK OF MY CAR,
WAIT FOR THE HEAT TO BLOW OVER.
LOOK, ARE YOU IN OR WHAT?
- I'M IN.
- GOOD.
I'M GLAD YOU'RE
ON THE TEAM, STARR.
BUT IF YOU CROSS ME,
I'LL PUT A BULLET IN YOUR HEART.
DAD! DAD!
LET'S GO!
ALL RIGHT!
TOMMY. ATTABOY.
OHH!
YOU LOOKED GREAT
OUT THERE.
WANT ICE CREAM?
[ Tommy ]
YEAH!
I PLAN ON SUING
THIS ENTIRE DIRT-WATER TOWN
FOR EVERY PENNY IT'S WORTH.
MY CARD.
STANTON.
- LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
- OH, MISS PARKER.
DO YOU KNOW A MAN
BY THE NAME OF BROOTS?
TAKE A MESSAGE.
HE SAYS HE LOCATED THE TARGET!
GRACIAS.
DE NADA.
[ Jarod's Mother's,
Kembrook's Voices ]
HIS LAUGH.
THE WAY HE STIRRED
HIS COFFEE.
MOM?
[ Sighs ]
[ Cell Phone Rings ]
[ Phone Beeps ]
STARR HERE.
IT'S SUSAN GRANGER.
YOUR ENVELOPE IS HERE.
I'M ON MY WAY.
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Miss Parker ] YOU KNOW, SYD,
I OUGHTA HAND IT TO HIM.
HE ALMOST KEPT ME
OUT OF THE PICTURE
LONG ENOUGH.
- HE WANTS TO KNOW THE TRUTH.
- HE CAN'T, AND YOU KNOW IT.
HMM.
IT'S ONLY BECAUSE
OF HIS HEART.
- WHAT?
- THAT WE ARE THIS CLOSE,
MISS PARKER.
JAROD KNEW THAT IF HE SENT
THAT PHOTOGRAPH ONLINE,
WE'D FIND HIM.
HE'S WILLING TO RISK EVERYTHING
FOR AN IDENTITY,
FOR A LIFE.
THAT'S WHAT I'M COUNTING ON.
[ Tires Screech ]
I THOUGHT YOU SHOULD BE
THE ONE TO OPEN IT.
I'M SO NERVOUS.
[ Door Opens ]
IT ISN'T EVERY DAY
YOU FIND OUT WHO YOU ARE.
[ Clamoring ]
WHAT IS GOING ON OUT HERE?
WHO ARE YOU PEOPLE?
- WHERE IS HE?
- [ Gun Cocks ]
I WON'T ASK AGAIN.
SAM. SAM, HE'S GOING
TO THE ROOF!
STOP, OR I SWEAR
I'LL SHOOT YOU
IN THE BACK!
JAROD!
SAM, GET HIM.
YOU SENT THIS, DIDN'T YOU?
I WAS WITH YOU,
MISS PARKER.
SO CLOSE...
AND YET SO FAR.
HI.
THIS IS OFFICER STARR.
I WAS WONDERING IF YOU
COULD DO ME A FAVOR.
[ Bishop ] WE GOT 15 MINUTES
BEFORE THE SECURITY CAR
COMES BACK AROUND.
- YOU GOT THE ALARM CODE,
RIGHT, FRANK?
- YEAH.
I'LL SHUT OFF THE JUICE,
THEN CLIP THE VIDEO LINES
TO THE SURVEILLANCE CAMERAS.
ONCE WE'RE INSIDE, FRANKIE'S
GONNA GO TO THE MANAGER'S
OFFICE AND GET THE GEMS.
YOU HIT THE GOLD CASES.
I'LL KEEP AN EYE
ON THE FRONT.
- WHAT IF THE SECURITY GUARD
IS EARLY?
- HE WON'T BE.
- WHAT IF YOU'RE WRONG?
- IF I'M WRONG, THEY'RE DEAD.
THE CLOCK IS RUNNING,
GENTLEMEN.
LET'S DO THIS THING.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
LET'S DO THIS.
FRANK, YOU ALL RIGHT?
I GOT THE MANAGER'S OFFICE.
STARR.
COINS, RINGS AND CHAINS,
ALL RIGHT?
STAY AWAY FROM
THE STUPID COSTUME CRAP.
LET'S DO IT.
- [ Imitates Gunshot ]
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I WAS JUST WONDERING
HOW MARVIN KEMBROOK FELT
THE NIGHT HE DIED.
[ Scoffs ]
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT
LATER, OKAY?
HE ANSWERS AN ALARM.
HIS HEART IS POUNDING
AT THE POTENTIAL DANGER.
HE FEELS AFRAID,
WITH GOOD REASON.
HE JUST GOT HIS LIFE BACK.
HE JUST FIGURED OUT WHO HE WAS.
HE JUST REDISCOVERED
HIS FAMILY.
IMAGINE HIS RELIEF
WHEN HE GETS THERE AND FINDS TWO
POLICE OFFICERS ON THE SCENE.
THE GOOD GUYS.
HIS RELIEF DIDN'T LAST
VERY LONG, DID IT?
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST
FOR THE MURDER
OF MARVIN KEMBROOK.
MAYBE I DON'T WANT
TO BE ARRESTED.
[ Gun Clicks ]
YOU'RE GOING TO JAIL.
YOU AND MEYERS.
ALL RIGHT, STARR.
I'M JUST GONNA PUT
THE GUN DOWN.
HEY, WHAT THE HELL
IS GOING ON?
SORRY ABOUT THAT, JAROD.
I DON'T DO JAIL.
TOO MANY MOUTHS
TO FEED.
OH, MY GOD.
CALL IT IN, FRANK.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED
TO TELL 'EM?
TELL 'EM THE TRUTH.
TELL 'EM ONE OF OUR FINEST
WAS GUNNED DOWN TRYING
TO PREVENT A ROBBERY.
[ Bishop ] WE TURNED UP
THE ALLEY HERE AND SAW SOMEBODY
RUNNING OUT THE BACK DOOR.
FRANK AND I WENT INSIDE,
IDENTIFIED OURSELVES
AS OFFICERS,
BUT THE PLACE WAS EMPTY
EXCEPT FOR THE BODY.
THE BODY?
OFFICER STARR APPARENTLY
WAS THE FIRST ONE
ON THE SCENE.
WE CAME BACK OUTSIDE
AND SEARCHED
THE ADJACENT AREA,
BUT THE SHOOTER
WAS LONG GONE.
IS THAT THE WAY IT HAPPENED?
MEYERS!
YEAH. YEAH,
THAT'S HOW IT HAPPENED.
SHOW ME.
YES, MA'AM.
LET'S GET THE LAB BOYS DOWN HERE
TO CHECK OUT THAT SLUG.
[ Officer ]
RIGHT AWAY, DETECTIVE.
CARE TO REVISE YOUR STORY,
OFFICER BISHOP?
THE BODY WAS LYING RIGHT HERE.
I SWEAR IT. I SAW IT MYSELF.
KEYS.
- KEYS?
- LET'S HAVE A LOOK IN
THE TRUNK OF YOUR CAR.
[ Engine Running ]
- LET'S ROLL!
- HOLD ON TIGHT!
I'M LEGAL!
[ Laughing ]
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST
FOR THE MURDER
OF MARVIN KEMBROOK.
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT
TO REMAIN SILENT.
IF YOU GIVE UP THE RIGHT
TO REMAIN SILENT,
ANYTHING YOU SAY CAN AND WILL
BE USED AGAINST YOU
IN A COURT OF LAW.
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT
TO SPEAK WITH AN ATTORNEY--
[ Imitates Gunshot ]
JAROD WAS IN YOUR SIGHT.
YOU COULD'VE KILLED HIM.
WHAT MADE YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND?
I JUST MISSED, SYDNEY.
NO MORE, NO LESS.
[ Phone Rings ]
HELLO. JAROD.
I TOLD YOU
WHEN I WAS 11 YEARS OLD
THAT I WOULD NEVER GIVE UP,
AND I NEVER WILL.
I KNOW YOU WON'T, JAROD.
MISS PARKER WON'T EITHER.
GOOD-BYE, SYDNEY.
HOLD IT.
JUST TELL ME ONE THING,
JAROD.
WHAT DO THE NUMBERS MEAN?
WHAT?
10:19.
IT'S WHO I AM, SYDNEY.
IT'S WHAT YOU MADE ME.
[ Line Clicks,
Dial Tone Hums ]
[ Chuckles ]
WHERE WILL HE GO NOW?
SOUTH.
WHAT MAKES YOU SO SURE?
INSTINCT.
♪♪ [ Brass Band: "O Canada" ]
[ Clucks Tongue ]
[ Mews ]