I CAN'T SEE ANYTHING.
I NEED TO GO LOWER.
THE CHILD IS JUST
BELOW YOU, JAROD.
COLLAPSE IS IMMINENT.
YOU HAVE TO ABORT.
I CAN SAVE HIM, SYDNEY.
I CAN SAVE HIM!
- YOU HAVE TO ABORT.
- NO!
[ Young Jarod Yelling ]
NO!
YOU'RE DEAD.
I COULDA DONE IT.
WHAT? SAVE HIM?
YOU CAN'T SAVE
EVERYONE, JAROD,
NO MATTER HOW HARD
YOU TRY.
[ Squeaking ]
[ Man ]
JAROD HALSTROM.
[ Chuckles ]
HE WAS THE COOLEST Ph.D.
WE'VE HAD IN THIS PLACE.
HE HAD A PRIVATE GRANT,
RENTED THE LAB
FROM THE UNIVERSITY...
AND PAID ME MUCHO DINERO.
WHAT KIND OF RESEARCH
WERE YOU DOING?
NADA.
ALL WE DID WAS EAT PEZ,
WATCH FRANKENSTEIN MOVIES
AND PLAY WITH MICE.
THE LIVE ONES ANYWAY.
LIVE ONES?
YEAH, HALF OF THEM
WERE DEAD OR COMATOSE.
SEE, JAROD USED TO
INJECT THEM WITH SOMETHING,
AND THEN STARE AT THEM
FOR HOURS.
IT WAS KINDA GHOULISH.
THEN HE DONATED
HIS LITTLE CRITTERS
TO THE SCHOOL WHEN HE LEFT.
EXCEPT FOR THIS WHITE ONE.
JAROD CALLED HIM JACOB.
JACOB?
- HMM?
- NOTHING.
WELL, JAROD USED TO CARRY
JACOB AROUND IN HIS POCKET
LIKE IT WAS HIS BEST FRIEND.
THEY'RE DISTANT COUSINS
ACTUALLY.
[ Phone Ringing ]
EXCUSE ME.
I HAVE TO GET THAT.
NO DEAD FIREMAN
OR WOUNDED CAMERAMAN.
MAYBE HE'S GETTING BORED.
MM-MMM.
JAROD WILL NEVER BE BORED
IN THE OUTSIDE WORLD.
HE'S TRYING TO SAVE LIVES.
[ Siren Wailing ]
WE HAVE A FEMALE,
LATE 20s, LEG FRACTURE,
POSSIBLE VERTEBRAL FRACTURE
WITH INTERNAL BLEEDING.
WE STARTED HER ON AN I.V.
OF NORMAL SALINE, WIDE OPEN.
SHE'S CODING! MOVE!
COME ON, COME ON, COME ON.
STAY WITH ME!
[ Man Narrating ]
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
[ Broots ]
UH, MISS PARKER,
HAVE YOU SEEN SYDNEY?
- DO I LOOK LIKE A LEASH?
- HE'S, UH, HE'S MISSING.
SYDNEY'S MISSING
WHEN HE'S HERE.
WELL, ACTUALLY, HE WAS
A NO-SHOW AT THE SIM LAB.
HE LEFT FOUR SETS OF TWINS
TWIDDLING THEIR, UH, 16 THUMBS.
SYDNEY'S A NO-SHOW FOR A ROOMFUL
OF HUMAN BOOKENDS?
[ Quietly ] SECURITY
REPORTED SOME DRUGS MISSING...
FROM THE CENTRE
PHARMACEUTICAL LAB.
A NURSE SAYS SHE
SAW SYDNEY LEAVING THERE
EARLY THIS MORNING.
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
I'LL TALK TO YOU LATER.
- [ Chattering ]
- YOUR DAUGHTER NEEDS YOU.
[ Chattering Continues ]
- TRAUMA FIVE, STAT.
- SHE HAS A LITTLE GIRL.
OKAY, WE'LL TAKE IT
FROM HERE, JAROD. JAROD.
SHE HAS A LITTLE GIRL.
SOMEONE GET HIM
OFF MY PATIENT.
JAROD, WE'RE DONE.
[ Water Running ]
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
I'M GONNA STAY HERE
FOR A WHILE.
SHE'S GOIN' INTO SURGERY.
I KNOW.
I JUST WANNA MAKE SURE
SHE'S ALL RIGHT.
OH, NO, NO, NO.
LOOK.
OKAY, I'VE BEEN ONLY
DRIVING WITH YOU, WHAT,
A COUPLE WEEKS, RIGHT?
TAKE MY WORD FOR IT. YOU GET
TOO PERSONAL WITH A CLIENT,
THAT'S JUST ENERGY YOU CAN'T
SPEND SAVING THE NEXT ONE.
ALL RIGHT? WE DO OUR BEST
FOR THESE PEOPLE,
THEN WE MOVE ON.
YOU CAN'T TRAIN YOURSELF
TO THINK THAT WAY,
THIS JOB WILL KILL YOU.
[ Man ]
NOT IF I DO IT FIRST.
WHY DON'T I HAVE PROPER
TREATMENT REPORTS
ON YOUR LAST FIVE DELIVERIES?
DELIVERIES?
DR. FLETCHER,
MEET JAROD RANDOLPH.
I HOPE YOUR PARTNER'S
BETTER AT DRIVING THEM IN THAN
HE IS AT DOING HIS PAPERWORK.
I WILL GET TO THAT PAPERWORK
WHEN I GET A BREAK, ALL RIGHT?
I PROMISE.
YOU BETTER.
[ Beeping ]
[ Miss Parker ]
SYDNEY MADE QUITE A HEIST
FROM THE CENTRE PHARMACY.
CYLIN,
TRIPHENYLMIDE,
D-- UH--
DIFLUTAZENIL.
UH, A REVERSAL AGENT,
A NEUROSTIMULANT
AND AN ANTIDEPRESSANT.
HUH.
GREAT. GREAT.
NOW SYDNEY WILL TURN UP
IN SOME HOP HOUSE, AND WE'LL
LOSE JAROD'S TRAIL AGAIN.
START DECRYPTING HIS FILES.
MAYBE THERE'S A CLUE THERE.
UH-- UM--
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Keyboarding ]
YOU'RE--
YOU'RE INVADING MY SPACE.
CLOSE IS GOOD.
[ Chattering ]
WHY IS THERE A SEVERED
ANIMAL'S LIMB HANGING
FROM YOUR REARVIEW MIRROR?
IT'S A RABBIT'S FOOT.
TECHNICALLY, IT'S A PAW.
WHAT, YOU MEAN
YOU'VE NEVER SEEN
ONE OF THOSE BEFORE?
IT'S LUCKY.
NOT FOR
THE THREE-LEGGED RABBIT.
[ Dispatcher, Indistinct ]
SURE, YEAH.
COFFEE TIME.
WOULD YOU GUYS KEEP IT DOWN?
I'M TRYING TO SLEEP HERE.
YOU MIGHT GET MORE REST
IF YOU TURN DOWN YOUR MUSIC.
SELF-HYPNOSIS.
TRYING TO STUDY
WHILE I SLEEP.
THE NEW ENGLAND
JOURNAL OF MEDICINE.
I'M IMPRESSED.
YEAH? TELL THE ADMISSIONS BOARD
AT ATLANTA.
I AM OUT OF THE E.M.T. BUSINESS
COME THIS FALL,
WITH A LITTLE LUCK.
HAVE YOU TRIED
A RABBIT'S FOOT?
I'M A FOUR-LEAF CLOVER
PERSON MYSELF.
OH, MAN, VARGAS IS HERE.
WHO'S VARGAS?
MAX VARGAS,
STATE BOARD OF INSPECTION.
I DIDN'T THINK THE INSPECTION
WAS GOING TO BE
FOR ANOTHER TWO WEEKS.
THIS GUY IS
A BIGGER PAIN IN THE ASS
THAN THE SUITS AT THE HOSPITAL.
ARE THOSE THE SAME PAINS
IN THE ASS WHO CALL ME AT HOME
LOOKING FOR THEIR PAPERWORK?
YOU MUST BE RANDOLPH.
WHAT'S IT LIKE BEING
INDEPENDENTLY WEALTHY?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
WELL, YOU'VE BEEN
HERE A MONTH...
AND YOU HAVEN'T DONE YOUR W-4,
SO YOU MUST HAVE A LITTLE
NEST EGG STASHED AWAY SOMEWHERE.
IT MUST HAVE SLIPPED
THROUGH THE CRACKS.
WELL, IT'S MY JOB
TO FILL IN THOSE CRACKS.
MAYBE YOU AND I
SHOULD GO TO THE OFFICE
AND FILL THESE FORMS IN,
SO THE BOOKS
HAVE A SEMBLANCE OF ORDER.
OH, UH, MR. VARGAS, JAROD AND I
HAVE A UNION-GUARANTEED
COFFEE BREAK NOW.
YOU'LL BE USING IT
TO FILL OUT THESE FORMS.
I'LL HAVE THEM ON YOUR DESK
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
SEE THAT YOU DO.
[ Rolling Thunder ]
IT'S SWEET THAT YOU
TALK TO HIM, SYDNEY.
SOME PEOPLE THINK
THEY'RE NOT AWARE.
HMM.
HE NEEDS TO KNOW
HE'S NOT ALONE.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
JACOB.
I HAVE DISCOVERED
THIS EXPERIMENTAL RESEARCH--
THE HALSTROM TECHNIQUE.
JAROD SENT IT TO ME.
IT'S A LONG SHOT,
BUT IT'S OUR BEST HOPE.
I PROMISED YOU...
I WOULD NEVER GIVE UP.
-[ Honking, Crashing ]
-[ Young Jacob ] SYDNEY! SYDNEY!
[ Monitor Beeping ]
[ Mr. Chambers Reading ]
"WHILE SYDNEY CARTON...
"AND THE SHEEP OF THE PRISONS
WERE IN THE ADJOINING
DARK ROOM,
"SPEAKING SO LOW
THAT NOT A SOUND WAS HEARD,
MR. LORRY LOOKED AT JERRY
IN CONSIDERABLE DOUBT
AND MISTRUST."
[ Jarod ] HE'S A STOCKBROKER
FROM ALPHARETTA.
HIS NAME IS JERRY MITCHELL.
QUEEN OF MERCY, THIS IS UNIT 45.
WE'VE GOT A MALE, MID 50s,
POSSIBLE HEAD TRAUMA, YOU COPY?
QUEEN OF MERCY?
COUNTY GENERAL'S CLOSER.
QUEEN OF MERCY'S GOT
THE BEST HEAD TRAUMA
CENTER IN ATLANTA.
I UNDERSTAND THAT,
BUT THIS GENTLEMAN
NEEDS IMMEDIATE--
STABILIZE HIM.
I'LL DO THE DRIVING.
WE COULD HAVE HAD HIM
IN TREATMENT AT COUNTY
EIGHT MINUTES AGO.
HEY, OUR STOCKBROKER
COULDN'T BE IN BETTER HANDS.
THAT'S WORTH EIGHT MINUTES
OF HIS TIME.
I HOPE YOU'RE RIGHT.
I MADE A JUDGMENT CALL.
YOU GOT A PROBLEM WITH THAT?
NO. NO PROBLEM.
[ Clears Throat ]
NOTHING OBVIOUS
ON SYDNEY'S E-MAIL.
PHONE RECORDS
ARE ALL CENTRE RELATED.
YOU'D THINK HE'D OCCASIONALLY
CALL A 900 NUMBER
TO SPICE UP HIS LIFE.
WHAT ABOUT
HIS REGULAR MAIL?
MEDICAL JOURNALS,
PLANT WORLD MAGAZINE.
BOOK OF THE WEEK CLUB.
GIVE ME THAT.
ANNUAL DONATION
TO THE MOUNT PLEASANT HOME.
AN HISTORICAL SOCIETY MAYBE?
IT'S WHERE HE GOES
FOR CHRISTMAS EVERY YEAR.
DR. COREY.
I OWE YOU AN APOLOGY.
I SHOULD HAVE RELINQUISHED
THE GURNEY. ONCE WE'RE
IN THE E.R., IT'S YOUR PATIENT.
DON'T SWEAT IT, JAROD.
AT LEAST YOUR HEART
WAS IN THE RIGHT PLACE.
BY THE WAY,
THAT YOUNG MOTHER YOU BROUGHT IN
IS GOING TO BE FINE.
THAT'S WONDERFUL.
I'M NOT USED TO
SEEING AN E.M.S.'er
GET SO PERSONALLY INVOLVED.
I FIND IT DIFFICULT NOT TO.
SOMETIMES I FEEL LIKE
I KNOW WHAT MY PATIENT
IS GOING THROUGH.
I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
IS THAT WHY YOU'RE
FOLLOWING UP WITH STEVEN?
I'VE SEEN THIS INJURY
A HUNDRED TIMES,
AND I'M USUALLY ABLE
TO STABILIZE THE PATIENT,
BUT THIS ONE--
IT'S LIKE I PULLED OUT
ALL THE STOPS,
BUT HE STILL
GOT AWAY FROM ME.
STEVEN IS LUCKY
TO HAVE A DOCTOR
THAT CARES SO MUCH.
ARE YOU OKAY?
IT'S JUST THAT YOU CAN'T
ALWAYS HELP THEM ENOUGH,
AND I DON'T LIKE THAT FEELING.
WELL, I THINK
THAT GOES WITH THE JOB.
IT DOESN'T MAKE IT
ANY EASIER TO LIVE WITH.
YOU'RE NOT THINKING
OF TRANSFERRING
SOMEPLACE ELSE?
THERE'S A RESEARCH POSITION
AT CORNELL MED.
I'M THINKING
I'LL HAVE AN EASIER TIME
DEALING WITH THE MICE.
DON'T BE SO SURE
ABOUT THAT.
LOOK, DO YOURSELF
A FAVOR.
REALLY THINK
ABOUT YOUR DECISION.
THIS HOSPITAL
NEEDS PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
"IT IS A FAR,
FAR BETTER THING
THAT I DO,
"THAN I HAVE EVER DONE;
"IT IS A FAR, FAR BETTER REST
THAT I GO TO,
THAN I'VE EVER KNOWN."
HOW ABOUT A BREAK
BEFORE WE START
THE NEXT BOOK?
- HE LIKES DICKENS.
- DICKENS IS HOPEFUL.
EVEN HIS SADDEST ENDINGS
ARE UPLIFTING.
I BROUGHT YOU SOME COCOA.
APPRECIATE
YOUR VISITS, JAROD.
YOU'D THINK YOU'D GET
ENOUGH OF HOSPITALS
IN YOUR LINE OF WORK.
WELL, THIS HOSPITAL
COULD USE SOME MORE VOLUNTEERS.
HOW'S STEVEN DOING?
THEY STARTED HIM
ON A NEW TREATMENT CALLED
THE TREFOIL THERAPY.
IT WAS DEVELOPED AT YALE.
IT DELIVERS NEUROSTIMULANTS
DIRECTLY TO THE HYPOTHALAMUS.
UM, I HAVE A FRIEND
WHO'S IN A COMA.
THEY SAY IT HAS
A 20% SUCCESS RATE.
ONE OUT OF FIVE
COMES OUT OF IT.
- AND FOUR DON'T.
- HE FITS THE PROFILE.
THEY SAID IF ANYONE
WOULD ACCEPT THE TREATMENT,
STEVEN WOULD.
HE'S A FIGHTER.
RIGHT, HON?
RIGHT.
DO YOU MIND?
SO, STEVEN WAS A WRESTLER.
TOOK FIRST PLACE
IN THE STATE FINALS
HIS SENIOR YEAR.
HE WAS BEHIND IN TWO
OUT OF HIS FIVE MATCHES.
BUT HE CAME BACK.
PULLED IT OUT.
WELL, YOU MUST BE
VERY PROUD.
HE NEVER GAVE UP.
WE'D CHEER HIM
FROM THE STANDS.
I THINK HEARING US
MADE HIM TRY HARDER.
BUT I REALLY DO BELIEVE
THAT PEOPLE IN A COMA--
THEY HEAR EVERYTHING
THAT GOES ON AROUND THEM.
ENJOY THE COCOA.
[ Woman On P.A. ]
DR. MICHAELS TO ADMITTING.
"CHAPTER ONE.
"TREATS OF THE PLACE
WHERE OLIVER TWIST WAS BORN...
AND OF THE CIRCUMSTANCES
ATTENDING HIS BIRTH."
WELL, ARE YOU GONNA
OPEN THE LETTER?
YES.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
FOR GOOD LUCK.
ALL RIGHT. I'LL OPEN IT.
[ Exhales ]
OH, MY GOD.
I'M... IN!
ALL RIGHT!
YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
A WONDERFUL DOCTOR.
I'D BETTER BE.
I'M ABOUT TO BE
$100,000 IN DEBT.
IF IT ISN'T
THE INVISIBLE MAN.
I SHOULD, UH,
CALL MY FAMILY
WITH THE NEWS.
I FOLLOWED THROUGH
ON YOUR PAPERWORK.
NOT ONLY HAVE YOU NOT FILED
YOUR PAYROLL DOCUMENTS,
YOU DON'T SEEM TO
HAVE ANY DOCUMENTS
THAT SUPPORT YOUR IDENTITY.
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
YOU DON'T EXIST.
I WANT YOUR NAME,
YOUR ADDRESS,
YOUR SOCIAL SECURITY NUMBER
YOUR NEXT OF KIN,
YOUR REFERENCES.
THE WHOLE KIT,
THE WHOLE CABOODLE,
I WANT IT NOW.
- RIGHT AFTER LUNCH.
- YOU BETTER GET WRITING,
OR I'M TAKING YOU
OFF THE STREETS.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
LET'S INCREASE THE, UH,
CYLIN TO 436 MILLIGRAM
PER LITER.
AND THE DIFLUTAZENIL,
LET'S GO 275.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'VE BEEN MISSING
FOR THREE DAYS, JACOB.
I CAN'T KEEP COVERING FOR YOU
WITH MR. RAINES.
I'VE HAD PERSONAL BUSINESS.
YOU NEVER KEPT SECRETS FROM ME.
SYDNEY, I--
I HAVE ETHICAL CONCERNS
ABOUT OUR WORK.
DON'T START WITH THAT RUBBISH.
WE'RE NOT DOING ANYTHING WRONG.
OPEN YOUR EYES, SYDNEY.
THEY ARE OPEN, JACOB.
I SEE THE OPPORTUNITY
TO DO WHAT WE'VE BEEN
WORKING FOR ALL OUR LIVES.
GET YOUR MIND OFF OF YOUR CAREER
FOR ONE SECOND, WILL YOU?
I'M TALKING ABOUT THE CHILDREN.
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
[ Jarod ]
HELLO, SYDNEY.
ANY PROGRESS?
[ Sydney ]
HALSTROM'S TECHNIQUE,
IT'S JUST BRILLIANT.
IT COULD HELP
A GREAT MANY PEOPLE.
ONE AT A TIME.
HOW'S JACOB?
NOTHING YET,
I'M AFRAID.
TELL ME, JAROD.
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
THE MEDICAL PROFESSION.
IT'S ABOUT THE RELIEF
OF SUFFERING.
REMEMBER?
[ Phone Beeps ]
♪♪ [ Whistling ]
HEY, JACOB. JACOB,
HOW YOU DOING? HOW YOU DOING?
DID YOU HAVE
A GOOD DAY? HMM?
DR. COREY, GOOD MORNING.
HEY.
I WANTED TO CHECK ON THE STATUS
OF THE STOCKBROKER THAT RENNERT
AND I BROUGHT IN YESTERDAY.
WE DAMN NEAR HAD TO
LIFE-FLIGHT HIM TO COUNTY.
I THOUGHT THIS HOSPITAL
HAD THE BEST HEAD TRAUMA UNIT
IN THE CITY.
HEAD TRAUMA WAS DOWNGRADED
MONTHS AGO, ALONG WITH
A THIRD OF OUR BUDGET.
YOU GUYS SHOULD KEEP UP
WITH CURRENT EVENTS.
WHAT'S WITH HER?
SHE'S LIKE YOU.
SHE CARES TOO MUCH.
[ Chuckles ]
I CAN'T WAIT
TILL THURSDAY.
- WHAT HAPPENS ON THURSDAY?
- MY TRANSFER CAME THROUGH.
- I AM OUT OF THE E.R.
- SARAH.
THEY NEED YOU HERE.
[ Chuckles ]
LOOK, I HAVE BEEN THROUGH THIS
WITH EVERYONE I KNOW.
I'LL GIVE YOUR REGARDS
TO THE MICE.
[ Man ]
LET'S GO! LET'S MOVE!
RIGHT IN HERE!
[ Woman ]
WHAT DO YOU GOT?
[ Chattering ]
[ Woman On P.A. ]
DR. FLETCHER
TO ADMINISTRATION, PLEASE.
TO ADMINISTRATION.
SYDNEY.
SO, WHO'S MR. X?
NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.
YOUR BUSINESS
IS MY BUSINESS.
JAROD CAN WAIT.
I CAN'T.
GO PACK YOUR BAGS.
YOU'RE COMING WITH ME.
YOU ARE NOT WELCOME HERE.
ALL I HAVE TO DO
IS CALL THE SWEEPER TEAM.
MM-HMM.
I HAVE PRIORITIES.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
WHO WAS ON DUTY LAST NIGHT?
WHO WAS ON DU--
SOMEBODY WAS HERE LAST NIGHT?
WHO WAS ON DUTY?
DON'T YOU HAVE THAT
IN ONE OF YOUR FILES?
- IF I DID, WOULD I ASK YOU?
- WHAT DID YOU LOSE?
THERE'S SOME
PERSONNEL FILES MISSING,
INCLUDING YOURS, I MAY ADD.
WELL, I'M NOT GOING TO
FILL OUT ANY MORE PAPERWORK.
YOU WON'T HAVE TO,
RANDOLPH. JAROD.
BORN IN SEATTLE.
ATTENDED
MILLBROOK ELEMENTARY.
PHOTOGRAPHIC MEMORY.
AND I'M SURE I HAVE
ENOUGH IN HERE RIGHT NOW...
TO RUN A BACKGROUND CHECK
ON YOU.
I'M THINKING ABOUT
GOING INTO PEDIATRICS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I THINK A DOCTOR
NEEDS TO HAVE
A STRONG SENSE OF ETHICS.
WHAT?
HEY, WHERE WE GOING?
[ Jarod ] TRYING OUT
A DIFFERENT ROUTE TODAY.
DIFFERENT ROUTE?
MM-HMM.
PEACHTREE ATHLETIC CENTER
TO QUEEN OF MERCY HOSPITAL.
IT'S INTERESTING.
THERE ARE TWO OTHER HOSPITALS
THAT ARE MUCH CLOSER BY.
NEITHER ONE OF THEM
ARE QUEEN OF MERCY.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- ETHICS.
STEVEN CHAMBERS WAS INJURED
DURING A WRESTLING MATCH.
YOU AND RENNERT TOOK HIM ALL
THE WAY FROM THE ATHLETIC CENTER
TO QUEEN OF MERCY HOSPITAL.
EXPLAIN TO ME
WHY A SEASONED E.M.T....
WOULD TAKE A CRITICAL PATIENT
SO FAR OUT OF THE LOOP.
JAROD, WE DID
THE BEST WE COULD.
BY MY CALCULATIONS,
IT TAKES AT LEAST
25 MINUTES...
TO GET FROM
THE ATHLETIC CENTER
TO QUEEN OF MERCY.
WHAT EXACTLY
DID YOU DO FOR HIM?
WATCH HIM FALL
DEEPER INTO A COMA?
RENNERT MADE
THE JUDGMENT CALL.
I LOOKED AT RENNERT'S RECORD
FOR THE LAST FIVE YEARS.
HE TOOK AT LEAST 30 PATIENTS
TO QUEEN OF MERCY HOSPITAL...
THAT SHOULD HAVE GONE
SOMEWHERE ELSE.
THIRTY PATIENTS
WITH EXPENSIVE INJURIES...
THAT HAVE INSURANCE
TO PAY FOR IT.
GOD KNOWS HOW MANY OTHER PEOPLE
ENDED UP LIKE STEVEN CHAMBERS.
A DOCTOR HAS TO
HAVE ETHICS, JULIE.
PEOPLE'S LIVES
ARE IN THEIR HANDS.
THERE HAD BEEN A-- A HAWKS GAME
THAT NIGHT, AND WE HIT
THE SPILLOVER TRAFFIC.
WE JUST SAT THERE.
ALL I COULD DO WAS TO
TALK TO STEVEN, YOU KNOW,
TRY TO KEEP HIM AWAKE,
WHILE RENNERT KEPT TELLING ME,
"WE'RE DOING THE RIGHT THING."
YOU COULD HAVE FILED
A COMPLAINT AGAINST HIM.
IT WAS MY FIRST WEEK
UNDER THE REDS, JAROD.
IT TOOK ALL THE GUTS I HAD
JUST TO TELL HIM
WE WERE GOING THE WRONG WAY.
RENNERT, HE WARNED ME
NEVER TO SECOND-GUESS HIM
IN HIS RIG.
I DIDN'T WANT ANY TROUBLE.
I JUST-- I JUST
WANNA HELP PEOPLE.
[ Raines ]
BROOTS.
MR. RAINES.
WHERE ARE THEY?
WHO?
I-I'M NOT SURE.
UM, THAT IS, I-I KNOW
WHERE I THINK THEY MIGHT BE.
- TELL ME.
- WELL, UH--
THEY WEREN'T VERY SPECIFIC.
THEY BOTH JUST TOOK OFF
WITHOUT SAYING MUCH.
HOW'S YOUR LITTLE GIRL?
YOU KNOW, UH,
THEY-- THEY DID SAY SOMETHING
ABOUT THE MOUNT PLEASANT HOME.
SY-SYDNEY GOES THERE
FROM TIME TO TIME.
I KNOW WHERE HE GOES.
[ Nurse ]
I'VE INCREASED THE DOSAGE.
YOU'RE AWARE
IT'S THREE TIMES MORE
THAN YOU ORIGINALLY REQUESTED?
MM-HMM.
ALL RIGHT.
I HAD NO IDEA.
[ Sydney ]
NOT MANY PEOPLE DO.
SYDNEY, WHAT HAPPENED?
[ Young Jacob ]
I'M TALKING ABOUT THE CHILDREN.
WHAT'S SO TROUBLING
ABOUT CHILDREN,
FOR GOD'S SAKES?
- DO YOU KNOW HOW WE GOT
THOSE CHILDREN?
- I KNOW WHAT I NEED TO KNOW.
NO, NO, YOU KNOW
WHAT THE CENTRE
WANTS YOU TO KNOW.
YOU-- YOU ALWAYS DO THIS.
YOU ALWAYS PUSH AWAY
WHAT DOESN'T FIT INTO YOUR
PRISTINE VIEW OF THE WORLD.
AND ALL YOU WANNA DO
IS POISON THE GOOD THINGS
IN YOUR LIFE.
- SYDNEY!
- [ Crash ]
[ Raining ]
JACOB. JACOB!
JACOB!
[ Sydney ]
IT WAS MY FAULT.
I KNEW THE ROAD,
KNEW EVERY CURVE.
SYDNEY, IT COULD HAVE
HAPPENED TO ANYBODY.
UH-UH.
A LATER SIMULATION BY JAROD
SUGGESTED OTHERWISE.
I SHOULD BE THE ONE
LYING IN THAT BED.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
[ Monitor Beeping Faster ]
JACOB.
JACOB, ARE YOU THERE?
"'I SHOULD NOT LET YOU
DEPART FROM ME THUS.'
"'YOU SHOULD, LADY,
AND I KNOW YOU WILL,'
REJOINED THE GIRL, RISING.
'YOU WILL NOT STOP MY GOING
BECAUSE I HAVE TRUSTED
IN YOUR GOODNESS.'"
IT'S A LOVELY STORY.
I'M EAGER TO SEE
HOW IT TURNS OUT.
FOR THE BEST, I'M SURE.
I BROUGHT YOU SOME COFFEE.
THANK YOU.
I DON'T THINK
HE'S GOING TO WAKE UP.
[ Jarod ]
DON'T SAY THAT.
I'VE GIVEN UP HOPE.
I KNOW RICHARD HAS TOO.
HE JUST WON'T ADMIT IT.
THERE'S STILL SO MUCH
YOU COULD TRY.
THE HOSPITAL THERAPY--
IT FAILED.
THE TREATMENT'S
RUN ITS COURSE.
DID THEY TRY
INCREASING THE DOSAGE?
INCREASING,
DECREASING, DILUTING.
IT'S JUST NOT WORKING.
THERE'S ANOTHER THERAPY
I KNOW ABOUT.
IT'S CALLED
HALSTROM'S TECHNIQUE.
YOU CAN'T GIVE UP.
STEVEN'S FOUGHT SO HARD.
THERE'S A BOY
IN CLEVELAND.
HE NEEDS A HEART.
WE'RE TRYING TO
DECIDE WHAT TO DO.
AT THIS POINT,
IT WOULD TAKE A MIRACLE.
JUST IN CASE,
I WANT TO FINISH THIS
WITH HIM, SO...
HE KNOWS HOW IT ENDS.
"'OF WHAT USE THEN
IS THE COMMUNICATION
YOU HAVE MADE,' SAID ROSE.
'THIS MYSTERY
MUST BE INVESTIGATED.'"
JACOB.
[ Sighs ]
- I CAN SAVE HIM!
- YOU HAVE TO ABORT.
I CAN SAVE HIM, SYDNEY.
NO!
- YOU CAN'T SAVE
EVERYONE, JAROD.
- WELL, I HAD TO TRY.
- [ Sighs ]
- [ Cell Phone Ringing ]
- YES.
- SYDNEY.
HALSTROM'S TECHNIQUE,
IT'S FLAWED.
THE EFFECT
IS ONLY TEMPORARY.
THANKS, JAROD. THANKS.
I HAVE, UH, TRIED TO
COME HERE AS OFTEN AS I CAN,
BUT MY WORK
KEEPS ME OCCUPIED.
I MISS YOU.
WERE YOU AWARE
ALL THIS TIME?
JACOB, THE NIGHT
OF THE ACCIDENT,
IT STAYED WITH ME.
I PROMISED YOU I WOULD DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER
TO BRING YOU BACK.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE LYING HERE.
YOU DIDN'T DESERVE THIS.
SL-27?
- WHY WASN'T I TOLD?
- IT DOESN'T CONCERN YOU.
IT'S CENTRE BUSINESS.
IS HE AWAKE?
I'D LIKE MY QUESTION
ANSWERED.
- ANSWER MY QUESTION.
- HE'S AWAKE.
IS HE TALKING?
NOT YET.
DON'T LET HIM.
SIR?
JACOB IS A THREAT
TO CENTRE INTERESTS.
YOU HAVE AN OBLIGATION
TO PROTECT THOSE INTERESTS.
DO YOU HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH THAT?
NO, SIR.
A SWEEPER TEAM...
WILL BE SENT
TO ASSURE YOU DON'T.
MAKE SURE JACOB
NEVER WAKES UP AGAIN.
[ Rolling Thunder ]
[ Phone Beeps ]
HEY. ANOTHER DAY
ON THE LIFELINE, EH, JAROD?
HMM.
MR. RENNERT,
WOULD YOU LEAVE
MR. RANDOLPH AND ME...
- ALONE FOR A MOMENT?
- WE WERE JUST ABOUT
TO START OUR SHIFT.
YOU AND I ARE GONNA HAVE TO
COVER A LITTLE GROUND BEFORE I
LET YOU OUT ON THE STREET AGAIN.
ALL RIGHT.
I RAN A BACKGROUND CHECK
ON YOU, DESPITE YOUR LACK
OF PAPERWORK,
AND SOME INTERESTING DATA
SPEWED FORTH.
BECAUSE THE ONLY
JAROD RANDOLPH I COULD FIND
IN THE STATE ARCHIVES...
WEIGHS 286 POUNDS,
AND HE'S BLACK.
IT'S TIME YOU PUT
YOUR CARDS ON THE TABLE, MISTER.
I CAN'T EVEN VERIFY
THAT YOU'RE TRAINED
FOR THIS JOB.
AND DESPITE THE MOUNTAIN
OF PHONE CALLS THAT
I'VE RECEIVED PRAISING YOU,
I NEED TO KNOW THAT
THE PEOPLE YOU'RE ASSISTING
ARE IN THE RIGHT HANDS.
WELL, I GUESS MY LUCK
JUST RAN OUT.
GIMME ONE GOOD REASON
NOT TO CALL THE COPS.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
SO, I HEARD THAT, UM,
VARGAS RODE YOU PRETTY HARD
LAST NIGHT, HUH?
I THINK THERE'S GONNA BE
SOME CHANGES IN THIS UNIT.
[ Woman ]
UNIT 45, THIS IS DISPATCH.
WE HAVE A CYCLIST DOWN
ON THE CORNER OF
PEACHTREE AND DUNWOODY.
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Man On Radio ] NINE-YEAR-OLD
MALE WITH A BLOCKED AIRWAY,
UNCONSCIOUS, NOT BREATHING.
[ Continues Indistinct ]
[ Woman ] WE COPY.
[ Groaning ]
IT'S OKAY.
[ Groans ]
GONNA TAKE GOOD CARE
OF YOU. JUST RELAX.
PUPILS ARE UNEVEN.
WE SHOULD C-SPINE HIM.
LOOK AT THAT. GUY CAN AFFORD
A ROLEX, YOU THINK
HE'D INVEST IN A HELMET.
GUESS I'M THE LAB RAT NOW,
HUH, DOC?
[ Groaning ]
SYDNEY'S IN THE LOUNGE.
KEEP AN EYE OUT.
MR. RAINES INSISTS I WATCH.
[ Plastic Gloves Crinkling ]
WE'RE DONE HERE.
HE SLIPPED BACK INTO THE COMA.
HE WROTE SOMETHING DOWN FIRST.
I'M HAPPY FOR YOU.
SOMEBODY PAGED ME?
THAT WAS ME,
DR. COREY.
OH.
HERE.
WHAT IS THIS?
JAROD WANTED YOU
TO SEE THIS.
STEVEN CHAMBERS?
A CASE CAN BE MADE
FOR NEGLIGENCE
ON RENNERT'S PART.
YOU MAY WANT TO
LISTEN TO THIS.
[ Siren Wailing
On Walkie-Talkie ]
[ Rennert ]
UH, QUEEN OF MERCY,
THIS IS UNIT 45.
WE'VE GOT A DOWN CYCLIST,
UH, POSSIBLE HEAD INJURY.
QUEEN OF MERCY?
GRADY MEMORIAL
IS A FASTER RUN.
I'M NOT GOING THROUGH
THIS AGAIN, ALL RIGHT?
QUEEN OF MERCY'S MY CALL.
RENNERT, THIS GUY
IS FADING ON ME.
THEN YOU KEEP HIM ALIVE
TILL WE GET TO QUEEN OF MERCY!
COME ON!
[ Chattering ]
[ Man ]
COMING THROUGH, PEOPLE.
[ Knocking ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
HEY.
HMM.
IS THIS
WHAT SOMEONE'S LIFE
IS WORTH TO YOU?
HEY, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THIS IS ABOUT.
THIS IS ABOUT YOU
AND THIS AMBULANCE DRIVER...
ENDANGERING THE LIVES
OF PATIENTS SO YOU CAN
CASH IN ON THEIR INSURANCE.
IT'S ABOUT WATCHING
A YOUNG MAN'S LIFE
JUST FADE AWAY.
STEVEN CHAMBERS
TRUSTED YOU.
YOU DIDN'T CARE
ABOUT HIS LIFE.
ALL YOU CARE ABOUT
IS WHAT'S INSIDE
THIS ENVELOPE.
NO, NO, NO,
THIS IS A SETUP, MAN.
THIS IS NOT FAIR.
WHAT'S NOT FAIR IS STEVEN
CHAMBERS'S PARENTS ARE GONNA
HAVE TO UNPLUG THE MACHINES...
THAT ARE BREATHING LIFE
INTO THEIR ONLY SON.
- I'M OUTTA HERE.
- COME WITH ME, SIR.
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
HEY! HEY!
OH, MAN.
THI--
OH, RENNERT.
YOU MIGHT NEED THIS.
"I HAVE SAID THAT
THEY WERE TRULY HAPPY;
"AND WITHOUT STRONG AFFECTION
AND HUMANITY OF HEART,
"AND GRATITUDE TO THAT BEING
WHOSE CODE IS MERCY,
AND WHOSE GREAT ATTRIBUTE
IS BENEVOLENCE TO ALL THINGS
THAT BREATHE--"
WE NEED TO DO THIS.
"WITHIN THE ALTAR
OF THE OLD VILLAGE CHURCH...
"THERE STANDS
A WHITE MARBLE TABLET,
"WHICH BEARS AS YET
BUT ONE WORD: 'AGNES.'
"THERE'S NO COFFIN
IN THAT TOMB;
"AND MAY IT BE MANY, MANY YEARS
BEFORE ANOTHER NAME
IS PLACED ABOVE IT.
"BUT IF THE SPIRITS OF THE DEAD
EVER COME BACK TO EARTH...
"TO VISIT SPOTS HALLOWED
BY THE LOVE, THE LOVE
BEYOND THE GRAVE,
"THOSE WHOM THEY KNEW IN LIFE,
"I BELIEVE THAT THE SHADE
OF AGNES SOMETIMES HOVERS
AROUND THAT SOLEMN NOOK.
"I BELIEVE IT, NONETHELESS,
"BECAUSE THAT NOOK
IS IN A CHURCH...
"AND SHE WAS WEAK
AND ERRING."
[ Sustained Tone ]
"THE END."
ALL DONE.
IT'S GOOD THAT OLIVER
FOUND A FAMILY.
- DARLING.
- I KNOW.
[ Priest Praying,
Indistinct ]
[ Sobbing ]
GODSPEED, MY SON.
[ Takes Deep Breath, Exhales ]
YOU WERE RIGHT, SYDNEY.
WELL, I HAVE TO
GET BACK TO WORK.
SO, YOU'RE STAYING.
WHO WANTS TO BE AROUND
A BUNCH OF MICE ANYWAY?
WHERE YOU GOING?
CLEVELAND.
[ Female Dispatcher ]
AIRLIFT FOUR,
WHAT'S YOUR E.T.A.?
[ Man ]
UH, WE'LL BE TOUCHING DOWN
IN 15 SECONDS. OUT.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Monitor Beeping ]
ANY CHANGE?
NO.
SINCE HE, UH, SLIPPED BACK
INTO THE COMA,
THERE'S BEEN NOTHING.
IT'S NOT FAIR.
WHAT ISN'T FAIR?
SOME PEOPLE,
THEY JUST FIGHT SO HARD,
BUT THEY JUST DON'T MAKE IT.
OH, YOU CAN'T SAVE
THEM ALL, JAROD.
YOU MAY BE A PRETENDER,
BUT YOU'RE HUMAN.
RIGHT.
HALSTROM'S TECHNIQUE,
DID IT HELP AT ALL?
IT HELPED ENOUGH.
[ Phone Beeps ]
[ Mews ]