[ Man Narrating ]
PREVIOUSLY ON THE PRETENDER.
[ Sydney ]
HIS NAME IS ANGELO.
THINK OF HIM LIKE A SPONGE--
SOMEONE WHO CAN ABSORB
THE INTELLECTUAL, EMOTIONAL,
EVEN THE PHYSICAL
TRAITS OF OTHERS.
HE WILL FIND JAROD FOR US.
[ Miss Parker ]
HE BETTER, SYDNEY.
HE JUST BETTER.
[ Keyboard Clacking ]
YES, MR. PARKER.
HE'S SEARCHING THE INTERNET
FOR ANY SIGNS OF HIM NOW.
WE'LL FIND JAROD...
AND WHOEVER
INSIDE THE CENTRE
IS HELPING HIM.
[ Phone Hangs Up ]
KEEP WORKING, ANGELO.
KEEP WORKING.
[ Explosion]
[ Man ]
WHOO-WHEE!
YOU SEE?
GET TOO CLOSE
TO THAT BAD BOY...
AND YOU'LL BE A-PICKING
YOUR NOSE WITH YOUR WRIST.
[ Chuckling ]
NOW, YOU BOYS
ARE 21, AREN'T YA?
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
FILL UP
THEIR TRUNK, EUGENE.
- NOW, WHERE WERE WE?
- YOU WERE TELLING US
ABOUT MR. NOBEL.
YEAH, OLD NOBEL WAS LIKE
A PICASSO OF GUNPOWDER.
- HE INVENTED
THE BIG BERTHA, YOU KNOW.
- THE BIG BERTHA?
THE MOTHER OF ALL ROMAN CANDLES.
THREE TIME-DELAYED
SPARKLE EXPLOSIONS...
WRAPPED IN A COLOR-SPRAY
SMOKE BANGER,
LINED WITH QUARTER STRANDS
OF T.N.T.
- SOUNDS IMPRESSIVE.
- PUT ON
A NEW YEAR'S EVE SHOW...
THAT PUT OLD DICKIE CLARK
TO SHAME.
[ Chuckling ]
I DON'T KNOW WHERE HE WENT.
JUST DISAPPEARED.
YES.
HMM.
HE HAS A HABIT
OF DOING THAT.
THANK YOU.
THERE IS NO WAY
THAT JAROD COULD HAVE
KNOWN WE WERE COMING.
ZERO.
HAVE YOU NOTICED THAT
IT NEVER SEEMS TO WORK
THE OTHER WAY, SYD?
MAYBE THERE IS A REASON.
STAY FROSTY, NOBEL.
IT'S ALL BEING RECORDED
FOR POSTERITY.
THIS WAY.
THE NOTE THAT WAS FAXED SAID
WE'D FIND THE BOMB OVER HERE.
CARLSON.
[ Beeping ]
HELLO.
OH, YEAH.
BAD BETTY.
FAX BOMBER'S USUAL.
WHOA, COWBOY.
BETTY NEEDS HER BEAUTY REST,
OR SHE'S A REAL WITCH
TO WAKE UP NEXT TO.
TOOLS.
WHOA. I FOUND SOMETHING.
LOOKS LIKE A NOTE.
HE ALWAYS LEAVES ONE.
WHAT'S IT SAY?
"CATCH ME IF YOU CAN,
YOU MISCREANTS."
"MISCREANTS"?
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
[ Rapid Beeping ]
IT MEANS "GET THE HELL
OUTTA HERE"! MOVE! MOVE!
[ Coughing ]
IS IT ALWAYS LIKE THIS?
WELCOME TO
THE BOMB SQUAD, JAROD.
[ Man Narrating ]
[ Chatter On Police Radio ]
SO, NOBEL,
NOW YOU KNOW...
WHAT A CLOSE ENCOUNTER WITH
THE FAX BOMBER FEELS LIKE, HUH?
MM-HMM.
MAN, I WISH
I COULD HAVE BEEN HERE.
CAN'T IMAGINE WHY, SIR.
- MY EARS ARE STILL RINGING.
- USED TO BE SOME SCUMBALL
WENT TO MAKE A BOMB THREAT,
THEY'D PICK UP THE PHONE
LIKE A DECENT HUMAN BEING.
NOW WHAT?
THEY FAX 'EM IN.
- SCUMBALL?
- SORT OF LIKE A MISCREANT,
ONLY DIFFERENT.
[ Forced Laughing ]
SOMEONE MARK THE CALENDAR.
LAMONT MADE A FUNNY.
NOW, THIS BOMBER
FAXES HIS THREATS IN.
THAT'S A UNIQUE M.O.
MUST HELP HIM COVER HIS TRACKS.
WELL, THIS GUY DOESN'T NEED
ANY HELP. WE HAVE RUN...
EVERY PIECE OF EVIDENCE
HE'S LEFT BEHIND THROUGH
THE BEST TECHNOLOGY WE HAVE:
D.N.A., HAIR SAMPLES,
FIBER, IMPRESSIONOLOGY--
GUY LEAVES US NOTHING
TO FOLLOW. NOTHING.
WE GOTTA CATCH
A BREAK SOMETIME.
SO YOU, UH-- YOU PEOPLE, YOU
STAY HERE AND KEEP AFTER THIS.
I'M GONNA GO
LIE TO THE PRESS.
[ Groans ]
WHAT'S THE MATTER, CARLSON?
YOU CATCH A LITTLE MORE
STEEL LAST NIGHT?
HEY, LAMONT, WHY DON'T YOU BE
A GOOD CIVIL SERVANT? GET
THE TWO HEROES SOME COFFEE.
HE LOVES ME.
DID YOU HAVE ANOTHER BOMB
GO OFF ON YOU BEFORE?
I GOT A LITTLE SHRAPNEL
IN MY SHOULDER DURING THE WAR.
HERO HERE'S THE ONLY GUY
REFERS TO GRENADA AS A WAR.
- I GOT THE MEDALS TO PROVE IT.
- COME ON. YOU KNOW
THE ONLY MEDALS...
THAT COUNT
IN YOUR FAMILY ARE THE ONES
YOUR BIG BROTHER WON IN 'NAM.
I HEARD THAT YOU BROUGHT
THE LAST TWO OF THE FAX BOMBER'S
DEVICES IN INTACT.
I GOT LUCKY. HEY.
DON'T YOU WORRY ABOUT IT, J.
ONE DAY THIS FAX BOMBER'S
GONNA SLIP UP.
WHEN HE DOES, WE'RE GONNA
BE THERE TO CATCH HIM.
I JUST HOPE THE S.O.B.
BLOWS HIMSELF UP.
[ Man ] THE DETONATOR WAS
CONNECTED TO AN ACCELERATOR.
THIS IS A DANGEROUS
NEW ESCALATION
FOR THE FAX BOMBER.
HAND THOSE OUT,
WILL YOU, JOHN?
THIS IS MY SIGHT PROFILE
OF THE BOMBER.
IT INCLUDES A, UH,
COMPUTER-GENERATED
COMPOSITE SKETCH...
BASED ON SOME
INCOMPLETE INFORMATION.
HE LOOKS LIKE MY UNCLE FRED.
LOOKS LIKE
EVERYONE'S UNCLE FRED.
BASED ON HIS, UH,
FAXED THREATS
AND OTHER DATA,
THE BOMBER IS A LEFT-HANDED,
DISGRUNTLED EX-CITY WORKER.
THE CHANCES ARE HE'S ALREADY
EXPRESSED HIS DISCONTENT.
- WE ALL KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS.
- BACK TO THE CRANK FILES.
EXCELLENT, LAMONT.
NOW, I EXPECT...
THAT ALL OF YOU PEOPLE
WILL PUT IN WHATEVER
OVERTIME IS NECESSARY...
TO SCREEN THOSE FILES
AND TO INTERVIEW
EVERY POSSIBLE PERP.
QUESTIONS? NO? GOOD.
GO TO WORK.
EXCUSE ME. LIEUTENANT CHOMSKY,
DO YOU HAVE A MOMENT?
SURE.
I'VE BEEN GOING OVER
YOUR FILE ON THE FAX BOMBER,
AND WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, SIR--
YOU KNOW, WHEN PEOPLE SAY,
"ALL DUE RESPECT,"
THEY GENERALLY DON'T HAVE IT.
SIR, IT-IT'S JUST THAT
I THINK THAT YOUR PROFILE
OF THE PERP...
IS EXACTLY WHO
HE WANTS US TO THINK HE IS.
I THINK THAT HIS GRUDGE AGAINST
THE CITY AND EVERYTHING ELSE
ABOUT HIM IS A MISLEAD.
GUY'S HERE A WEEK,
HE'S ALREADY
BUCKING FOR MY BARS.
NO, SIR. I JUST HAPPEN
TO HAVE A DIFFERENT OPINION.
BASED ON WHAT?
I KNOW PEOPLE.
I'M LISTENING.
THE D.N.A.
AND THE IMPRESSIONOLOGY...
ALL CAME UP EMPTY.
HE'S TRYING TO LEAD US
DOWN A HIGH-TECH PATH,
BUT I BELIEVE
THAT WE CAN SNAG HIM
WITH A LOW-TECH SOLUTION.
HE'S RIGHT-HANDED,
BUT HE WANTS US
TO BELIEVE HE'S A LEFTY.
THE VERTICALS
AND THE HORIZONTALS
ARE ALL JAGGED,
WHICH WOULD INDICATE
THAT HE'S BEEN WRITING
WITH HIS SUBDOMINANT HAND.
YOU'RE A GRAPHOLOGIST?
UH, NO, SIR, BUT I WAS
A PALM READER ONCE.
SHALL I TELL YOU
ABOUT YOUR FUTURE HERE?
SIR, I BELIEVE
THAT OUR BOMBER...
IS A CITY EMPLOYEE WHO IS NOT
NECESSARILY DISGRUNTLED.
HE'S ENJOYING
WATCHING US RUN AROUND...
ALMOST AS MUCH AS HE ENJOYS
SETTING OFF EXPLOSIONS.
IF YOU WANT TO SUGGEST THAT,
UH, THIS CLOWN IS SOME KIND
OF A MERRY PRANKSTER,
I RECOMMEND THAT YOU
TALK WITH RACHEL NEWTON.
RACHEL IS GONNA SPEND
THE NEXT YEAR OF HER LIFE...
LEARNING HOW TO READ BRAILLE
BECAUSE OF THE FAX BOMBER.
I WASN'T TRYING
TO TRIVIALIZE THAT, SIR.
NO, NO. I KNOW YOU WEREN'T.
YOU WERE JUST TRYING TO
MAKE, UH, AN IMPRESSION,
SHOW OFF YOUR ERUDITE
EUROPEAN UPBRINGING.
MY WHAT?
THE CADENCE
IN YOUR VOICE--
YOU WERE RAISED BY
A FRENCH NANNY. WELL,
COULD BE BELGIAN, I SUPPOSE.
HOW DID YOU KNOW THAT?
OH, I KNOW
ABOUT PEOPLE TOO.
[ Sydney Speaking
Foreign Language ]
[ Continues ]
[ Miss Parker ]
DAMN IT, BROOTS.
YOU SAID WE HAD HIM CORNERED.
BUT WE DID.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
JAROD HAPPENED.
OH, SPARE ME, SYDNEY.
ALL I KNOW IS
THAT I'M FED UP...
WITH ALWAYS BEING
A STEP BEHIND HIM.
[ Raines ]
SO AM I.
- UH, I-I GOTTA GO.
- STAY HERE, MR. BROOTS.
- WHAT BRINGS YOU DOWN
FROM THE TOWER, SIR?
- PLUMBING.
PLUMBING?
I'VE COME
TO PLUG A LEAK.
- HEY.
- HEY. WHAT'S UP, NOBEL?
THE FAX BOMBER,
A.K.A. UNCLE FRED.
OKAY.
NOT MY FINEST HOUR,
BUT, HEY,
NOBODY GOT A GREAT LOOK
AT THIS GUY, SO THE SKETCH
IS, YOU KNOW, SKETCHY.
THIS IS
A FASCINATING MACHINE.
YEAH. THIS HERE IS
A DECATRONICS TURBO
GRAPHICS II WORKSTATION.
THIS LITTLE BAD BOY
MAKES COMPOSITES,
PUTS DISGUISES ON PORTRAITS,
AGES MISSING KIDS,
WHICH IS WHAT I'M DOING NOW.
THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
SOME OF MY BEST WORK'S BEEN
ON THE BACKS OF MILK CARTONS.
[ Chuckling ]
THINK OF THE D.T.G. II...
AS SORT OF A HIGH-TECH
MR. POTATO HEAD.
- MISTER WHO?
- POTATO HEAD.
OH. NOW,
THIS IS INTERESTING.
YOU CALL HIM MR. POTATO HEAD,
YET HIS HEAD IS
HIS WHOLE BODY?
YEAH.
COOL, HUH?
HE COMES WITH LITTLE
INTERCHANGEABLE EARS,
EYES
AND LITTLE HATS.
OLD SPUD MAN IS THE ORIGINAL
MASTER OF DISGUISE.
YOU KNOW, THIS WOULD MAKE
A WONDERFUL TOY FOR CHILDREN.
HEY, NOBEL, CRANK FILE
JUST TURNED UP A HOT ONE.
LET'S RUN.
HMM.
[ Doorbell Ringing ]
OH, GOD.
WHAT'D HE DO?
CURTIS! THEY FINALLY
CAME TO ARREST YOU!
CURTIS!
BUSY, MA!
MRS. HARING,
WE'RE NOT HERE
TO ARREST YOUR SON.
I KNEW SOMEDAY THE COPS WOULD
SHOW UP AND TAKE HIM AWAY.
- CURTIS!
- I SAID, GET OFF MY BACK!
- MA'AM, WE JUST WANTED TO--
- THIRTY YEARS OLD, AND HE
STILL LIVES IN MY BASEMENT.
DAY IN AND DAY OUT,
WRITING HIS LITTLE LETTERS.
I SHOULD'VE BOUGHT
STOCK IN BIC.
DON'T SAY NOTHING, MA.
THIS IS ALL GOING ON TAPE
SOMEWHERE. I KNOW IT.
LISTEN TO THAT.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S DONE
TO MY SOCIAL LIFE...
HAVING HIM
DOWN THERE?
YOU'RE NOT GETTIN'
NOTHIN' OUT OF ME.
I'M IN THE PRIME OF MY LIFE.
I SHOULD GO OUT,
GET MYSELF SOME NICE SHOES
AND FIND MYSELF A MAN.
- MA!
- SIR,
DID YOU WRITE THESE LETTERS
TO THE UTILITIES COMMISSION?
AND I'LL WRITE A HUNDRED MORE
TILL THEY GIVE ME BACK
MY WORKMAN'S COMP.
I GOT AN INOPERABLE HERNIA
WORKING FOR THIS CITY,
AND THEY THREW ME
TO THE WOLVES.
HOW'D YOU GET THAT LETTER?
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
I'M CARLSON.
THIS IS, UH, NOBEL.
HOLD STILL, MAN.
I CAN'T SEE
YOUR BADGE NUMBER.
HE DON'T HAVE NO HERNIA.
HE JUST DON'T WANNA MOVE
OUT OF THE BASEMENT.
SHUT UP, MA! YOU KNOW
HOW MY LEGS TINGLE EVERY
TIME I SIT FOR TOO LONG.
YEAH, AND I KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE SITTIN'!
SIR, WE'RE NOT HERE TO TALK
ABOUT YOUR WORKMAN'S COMP.
WE WANT TO ASK YOU
SOME QUESTIONS
ABOUT YOUR WHEREABOUTS.
HEY, IF YOU THINK
YOU GOT SOMETHING ON ME,
YOU COME BACK WITH A WARRANT.
TILL THEN,
ME AND MY MOTHER'S GOT NOTHING
TO SAY TO YOU MISCREANTS.
I SHOULD'VE MARRIED
A DENTIST.
AT LEAST THEN
HIS TEETH'D BE BETTER.
MA!
THIS GUY'S CLASSIC
BOMBER MATERIAL.
FORMER CITY WORKER,
DOMINEERING MOTHER,
BASEMENT WORKSHOP,
A LITTLE ANTISOCIAL BEHAVIOR.
I'M NOT CONVINCED.
HUH?
HE'S WRITTEN 253 LETTERS
TO THE CITY AND COUNTING.
IF HE'S CROSSED
THE THRESHOLD
INTO PLANTING BOMBS,
DON'T YOU THINK
HE WOULD HAVE GIVEN UP
THE CORRESPONDENCE?
DID YOU NOTICE WHAT
HE CALLED US IN THERE?
MISCREANTS.
RIGHT. NOBODY USES THAT WORD
EXCEPT FOR THAT GUY AND--
THE FAX BOMBER.
I'M GONNA GET
UNDER THIS GUY'S SKIN
BEFORE HE HURTS SOMEONE ELSE.
[ Electronic Squawking ]
WAKE UP! WAKE UP!
GOOD MORNING!
...FIVE, SIX,
SEVEN, EIGHT,
NINE, TEN--
YOU CAN STOP COUNTING.
YOU'RE HERE.
OH. [ Chuckles ]
YOU MUST HAVE STEPPED
INTO THE ROOM.
IT'S 11 STEPS TO THE DOOR.
I DID.
THAT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S FUNNY, DR. JAROD.
I USED TO HATE MATH IN SCHOOL.
NOW MY ENTIRE LIFE
IS BASIC ARITHMETIC.
NINE STEPS FROM MY BED
TO THE BATHROOM,
14 STEPS TO THE HALLWAY,
SEVEN STEPS TO THE CHAIR.
JUST BE HAPPY
IT'S NOT LONG DIVISION.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY.
WHY DON'T WE GO OUTSIDE?
OH, NO. I-- I-I THINK
I'D RATHER STAY HERE.
RACHEL,
YOU HAVE TO GO OUTSIDE
SOMETIME.
BUT IT WAS SUCH A NICE DAY,
I DECIDED TO GO
ON THE ROOFTOP AT CITY HALL.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED
THE LAST TIME I WENT OUTSIDE.
YOU WERE IN THE WRONG PLACE
AT THE WRONG TIME.
BUT THAT IS NOT
YOUR FAULT.
YOU CAN'T STOP
LIVING YOUR LIFE
BECAUSE OF IT.
I HEAR HE SET OFF
ANOTHER BOMB.
YES, HE DID.
THANKFULLY,
NOBODY ELSE WAS HURT.
YOU KNOW, WHEN I HAD
MY EYES BEHIND A CAMERA,
I COULD SEE THINGS
NO ONE ELSE COULD SEE.
I COULD TAKE
A THOUSAND SHOTS...
AND TELL YOU
WHICH ONE WAS PERFECT
BEFORE IT WAS EVEN DEVELOPED.
I CAN REMEMBER DETAILS
OF NEARLY EVERY PICTURE
I EVER TOOK.
THAT'S IRONIC.
THEY TELL ME
HE WAS THERE THAT DAY.
THAT I MUST HAVE SEEN
THE MAN WHO DID THIS TO ME
AS HE WAS SETTING HIS BOMB.
BUT AS HARD I TRY,
I CAN'T REMEMBER.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
THEY THINK ONE OF US...
IS LEAKING
INFORMATION TO JAROD.
[ Sighs ]
OH, I WISH I HADN'T EATEN
THAT POPPY SEED MUFFIN.
THEY'RE GIVING US
A POLYGRAPH, YOU IDIOT,
NOT A URINE TEST.
I THOUGHT IT WAS BOTH.
IT SHOULD BE,
FOR YOU.
WHAT-WHAT IS THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO HANDLES
THE INFORMATION AROUND HERE.
I'M SORRY.
I'M IN A FILTHY MOOD.
LET'S NOT ACCUSE EACH OTHER.
OH, THAT MEANS A LOT
COMING FROM JAROD'S TEDDY BEAR.
MISS PARKER.
TO CALIBRATE THE MACHINE,
PLEASE ANSWER THE FOLLOWING
QUESTION UNTRUTHFULLY.
ARE YOU
ELEANOR ROOSEVELT?
YES.
HAVE YOU PURSUED JAROD
TO THE BEST OF YOUR ABILITY?
YES.
[ Raines ]
BECOME HER, ANGELO.
TELL ME IF SHE IS LYING.
[ Man ]
DID YOU WILLFULLY
MISFIRE YOUR WEAPON...
WHEN ATTEMPTING TO APPREHEND
JAROD IN MIAMI, FLORIDA?
WHAT?
YES OR NO, PLEASE.
NO.
SMOKING IS NOT PERMITTED
DURING A POLYGRAPH.
HAVE YOU RECEIVED...
A PERSONAL MESSAGE
FROM JAROD?
IT WAS A BUNNY.
YES.
DID YOU SECRETLY
CONTACT JAROD VIA
A SECURE INTERNET CONNECTION?
YES.
DID YOU ATTEMPT TO PROVIDE HIM
WITH CLASSIFIED INFORMATION?
YES, BUT WITH A VIEW
TO BRINGING HIM HOME.
HAVE YOU EVER SECRETLY
MET WITH JAROD?
MM-MMM.
NO.
IS HE LYING?
IS HE THE ONE?
HAVE YOU EVER USED
A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCE?
[ Clears Throat ]
NO.
WERE YOU IN THE LAB
WHEN INFORMATION REGARDING
JAROD'S ORIGINS WAS LEAKED?
YES.
DID YOU LEAK THE INFORMATION
JAROD RECEIVED...
VIA SPECIAL COURIER
IN MIAMI, FLORIDA?
NO.
HAVE YOU EVER LIED
TO THE CENTRE?
NO.
[ Gasping ]
HE'S THE LEAK,
ISN'T HE, ANGELO?
SO, YOU'VE DECIDED TO PUT IN
A TRANSFER TO FORENSICS, HMM?
I'VE JUST BEEN
SIFTING THOUGH ALL
THE FAX BOMBER DEBRIS.
YOU WENT OVER THREE THOUSAND
PIECES OF EVIDENCE HERE?
THREE THOUSAND
AND TWENTY-FIVE.
- I'VE SPECIFICALLY BEEN
STUDYING THE WIRES.
- NO, NO, NO.
THE FEDS, THEY COVERED EVERY
CENTIMETER OF THAT COPPER.
I KNOW.
I'VE BEEN STUDYING
THE ENCASEMENTS.
THERE'S NO PATTERN.
THIS GUY IS RANDOM...
EXCEPT FOR
THE DETONATOR CONNECTORS.
HE'S VERY SENSITIVE
ABOUT THEM.
HE WANTS TO BE SURE.
THAT'S WHY THEY ALL
HAVE EXACTLY THE SAME
PARALLEL CUT PATTERN.
COME ON.
EXACTLY THE SAME?
EXACTLY.
NOTICE THE ANGLE
OF THE GROOVES
ON THE PARALLELS.
GIVES US SOMETHING
TO RUN DOWN WITH
THE KNIFE MANUFACTURERS.
AND THE CUT CONTOURS
CONFIRM THAT HE'S--
RIGHT-HANDED.
YES, SIR.
LOW-TECH.
VERY.
MMM.
HELLO.
HEY.
HEY. HOW'S THE SPUD
OF A THOUSAND FACES?
WELL, I ONLY HAVE
THE 13-PIECE SET SO,
TECHNICALLY,
THIS ONE'S ONLY GOT, UH--
ONE HUNDRED AND SEVENTY-NINE.
I HAVE A PROJECT FOR YOU.
I'M UP TO MY EARS
IN MILK CARTONS HERE.
WELL, THIS ONE'S
VERY SPECIAL TO ME.
IT'S MY MOTHER.
I WAS WONDERING...
IF YOU COULD AGE HER
30 YEARS.
I WANT TO SEE
WHAT SHE WOULD LOOK LIKE.
[ Pager Beeping ]
I'LL MAKE IT
WORTH YOUR WHILE.
HEY, I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.
THANKS.
ALL RIGHT.
[ Siren Wailing ]
IT'S RIGHT OVER THERE UNDER
THE BUS. IT'S RIGHT OVER THERE
UNDER THE BUS.
DID THE THREAT
COME IN BY FAX?
IT WAS MORE OF A PHONE CALL.
ONE OF MY DRIVERS
FOUND THE UNCLAIMED SUITCASE
ON THE 3:15 FROM TRAVERSE CITY.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL TAKE IT FROM HERE.
THANKS.
HEY, CAN YOU GUYS
KINDA HURRY UP?
'CAUSE I GOT BUSES BACKING
UP ON ME HERE, MAN, AND I--
TAKE AS MUCH TIME
AS YOU NEED THEN.
THANKS.
YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
COME ON.
[ Buzzing ]
[ Horn Honks ]
GOT A BACKACHE?
[ Switches Off ]
THEY TOLD ME WE WOULD
HAVE A LOT OF HOAX CALLS
IN TRAINING,
BUT I NEVER THOUGHT
IT WOULD FEEL LIKE THIS.
LET GO, J.
THAT'S EASY
FOR YOU TO SAY.
- IT WAS PRETTY TENSE
BACK THERE.
- DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
- THAT'S NICE WORK.
- OH. YEAH.
FROM MY ARMY DAYS.
LET ME GUESS.
- YOU GOT DRUNK ONE NIGHT.
- BLITZED. [ Chuckles ]
MY WHOLE UNIT.
AFTER GRENADA,
THEY STATIONED US DOWN
AT FORT BUCHANAN, PUERTO RICO.
I DO NOT REMEMBER
ONE THING THAT HAPPENED
THAT ENTIRE MONTH,
EXCEPT FOR THIS
NEEDLE ARTIST.
HE WAS A
SHRIVELED-UP LITTLE
PUERTO RICAN GUY...
WHO HAD A HOLE-IN-THE-WALL
SHOP IN OLD SAN JUAN.
HE INKED EVERY SINGLE GUY
IN THE WHOLE PLATOON--
THE WHOLE PLATOON.
YOU KNOW HOW MANY EAGLES
THIS GUY HAD TO DO
IN ONE NIGHT?
GIVE US A BREAK,
WILL YOU, CARLSON?
YOU PARTNER WITH THIS GUY
TOO LONG, YOU KNOW HIS OLD UNIT
LIKE IT WAS YOUR OWN FAMILY.
[ Rachel ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M GOING TO TURN THIS SPACE
INTO A DARKROOM.
I LIVE IN A DARKROOM.
GOOD.
BECAUSE I NEED YOU...
TO DEVELOP A ROLL
OF FILM FOR ME.
OH, THAT SMELLS
FAMILIAR.
- I THOUGHT YOU'D REMEMBER IT.
- IS THIS SOME KIND
OF NEW THERAPY?
CALL IT A SIMULATION.
SIMULATION?
MM-HMM.
I'M GOING TO CREATE
AN ENVIRONMENT...
WITH ALL THE STIMULI
YOU NEED TO RECREATE AN EVENT,
AND FOR YOU
TO BECOME SOMEONE.
WHO DO YOU WANT ME
TO BECOME?
YOURSELF.
OH!
OH, MY CAMERA.
OH, I HAVEN'T
TOUCHED THIS SINCE THE--
WELL, SINCE THE DAY
AT CITY HALL.
NOW I WANT YOU TO DEVELOP
THAT ROLL OF FILM,
THE PICTURES
YOU TOOK THAT DAY.
OH, BUT THERE'S
NO FILM IN IT.
I KNOW.
I WANT YOU TO DEVELOP
THE PICTURES IN YOUR MIND.
I'M ON THE ROOFTOP
AT CITY HALL.
NATURAL LIGHT IS AT ITS-
ITS PERFECT ANGLE.
THE BUILDING IS--
IS CLOSED.
IT'S SUNDAY.
AND I'M, UH, GETTING
LAST-MINUTE SHOTS
FOR MY GALLERY OPENING.
[ Jarod ]
ARE YOU ALONE?
I THINK.
I-I DON'T SEE ANYONE.
I DON'T--
I DON'T SEE ANYONE,
BUT I FEEL A--
A TINGLE
ON THE BACK OF MY NECK.
[ Footsteps ]
I DON'T SEE ANYONE,
BUT I HEAR SOMETHING.
WHAT DO YOU HEAR?
FOOTSTEPS,
WALKING QUICKLY AWAY.
BUT, UH, YOU DON'T THINK
ANYTHING ABOUT IT...
BECAUSE YOU HAVE
OTHER PICTURES TO TAKE.
IT'S RIGHT
BEFORE IT HAPPENS.
WE CAN STOP THIS
IF YOU WANT.
NO.
I WALK OVER
TO WHERE THE FOOTSTEPS
ARE COMING FROM,
BUT HE'S GONE.
RACHEL,
DO YOU SEE THE BOMB?
IT'S ONLY AN INSTANT
BEFORE THE FLASH.
DO YOU SEE HIM?
NO.
BUT...
I SMELL SOMETHING.
I SMELL--
YOU SMELL HIM.
IT MUST BE, UM--
I DON'T-- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT IS.
IT-IT'S COLOGNE.
NO, IT-IT'S, UM,
MEDICINE, MENTHOL.
- WHAT ATHLETES PUT
ON SORE MUSCLES.
- LIQUID HEAT.
THANK YOU.
- ARE YOU STEVEN JOHNSON?
- YEAH.
SPECIAL AGENT
JAROD WEBSTER.
F.B.I.?
WHAT DID I DO?
NOTHING, MR. JOHNSON.
I'M JUST DOING
A SECURITY CHECK...
ON ONE OF YOUR
OLD ARMY BUDDIES,
DANIEL CARLSON.
HE PUT YOU DOWN
AS A REFERENCE.
IF YOU WANT TO CLEAR CARLSON,
YOU'RE TALKING TO THE WRONG GUY.
- WHY'S THAT?
- CARLSON TALKS A GOOD GAME,
BUT THE REST OF THE SQUAD
HAD TO CARRY HIM
EVERY STEP OF THE WAY.
WELL, THE WAY HE PUTS IT,
YOU WERE A VERY TIGHT UNIT.
WE'D PROBABLY HAVE SHOT HIM
OURSELVES IF HE HADN'T CAUGHT
THE SHRAPNEL IN THE SHOULDER.
HE HAS THE COMPANY TATTOO
ON HIS FOREARM.
YOU DON'T SEE ANY
MORONIC LITTLE BIRDS
ON ME, DO YOU?
HELL, CARLSON COME IN
ONE DAY ALL DRUNK,
QUEER LITTLE BIRD ON HIS ARM,
TALKING ABOUT HOW HE WANTED
THE REST OF US TO GET 'EM.
GUY'S A DANGEROUS LITTLE
WANNABE.
WELL, THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR YOUR TIME.
HEY, WHAT'S THE LITTLE WEASEL
APPLYING FOR, ANYWAY?
- BOMB SQUAD.
- GOD HELP US ALL.
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Jarod ]
YOU PAGED ME?
[ Man ]
OH, YEAH, DUDE.
SORRY SANTA WAS A LITTLE LATE,
SHE'S STILL BEAUTIFUL.
NOW, UM, YOU SAID
YOU'D MAKE IT WORTH MY WHILE.
PATIENCE, MR. POTATO HEAD.
THANK YOU.
OKAY.
JAROD, THE FAX BOMBER
JUST BLEW HIMSELF UP.
WHERE'S CARLSON?
HE PHONED IT IN.
[ Sirens Wailing ]
LET ME THROUGH!
LET HER THROUGH. THIS IS
HER HOUSE. THIS IS HER SON.
LET HER THROUGH.
ARE YOU HURT?
I WASN'T HOME LAST NIGHT.
I HAD A DATE.
CURTIS? CURTIS,
MAMA'S HERE.
MA'S HERE, HONEY.
I HAD A FEELING ABOUT THIS GUY.
I CAME OVER HERE TO SEE
IF I COULD GET HIM TO TALK.
HE MUST HAVE SEEM ME COMING
BECAUSE THE WHOLE PLACE WENT UP.
- IT KNOCKED ME ALL THE WAY BACK
TO THE END OF THE DRIVEWAY.
- IT WAS A NICE PLAY, CARLSON.
GET YOURSELF CLEANED UP.
YOU LOOK LIKE HELL.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN
IT WAS HIM.
ANOTHER CROISSANT,
MISS PARKER?
COLD COFFEE'S PLENTY.
HE ALWAYS SEEMED
TO BE...
A STEP AHEAD,
AND THEN SUDDENLY,
WE WERE A STEP BEHIND.
BROOTS HAS THE CLASSIC
NONCONFRONTATIONAL
PERSONALITY.
I DOUBT HE WOULD PUT
HIMSELF IN HARM'S WAY.
[ Car Engine Starts ]
[ Miss Parker ]
WHERE THE HELL
IS HE GOING NOW?
PRIVATE INVESTIGATOR?
COULD HE HAVE FOUND JAROD?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT SOMEBODY
JUST PUT THEMSELVES
IN HARM'S WAY.
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
THE SAME BOMBER, WHO WAS SO
INTELLIGENT HE DIDN'T LEAVE...
AS MUCH AS A SPECK OF D.N.A.
BEHIND, ACCIDENTALLY BLOWS UP
HIS OWN MOTHER'S HOUSE?
DON'T START WITH ME, NOBEL.
AND WHY WOULD HE KEEP ALL OF
HIS BOMB-MAKING EQUIPMENT...
IN A BOX IN THE GARAGE
WHEN HE HAD HIS OWN
BASEMENT WORKSHOP?
MAYBE HE WAS FEELING THE HEAT
AND WAS PLANNING TO MAKE A MOVE.
I DON'T THINK HE'S OUR MAN.
WHY?
IS HE LEFT-HANDED?
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
HE IS.
THE ISSUE OF GUILT
IS UP TO A JURY.
OUR JOB-- COLLECT EVIDENCE.
[ Alarm Chirps ]
[ Man ] NOW WE HAVE AN EXCLUSIVE
WITH OFFICER DAN CARLSON
OF THE CITY BOMB SQUAD.
SO, YOU DEFUSED
HIS DEVICES AND
BROUGHT HIM TO JUSTICE.
HOW DOES IT FEEL
TO BE THE MAN WHO
UNCOVERED THE FAX BOMBER?
I'M JUST GLAD
THIS NIGHTMARE FOR THE CITY
IS FINALLY COMING TO AN END.
NOT QUITE.
HERE.
[ Gun Cocks ]
WHAT DO YOU--
WHAT IS THIS?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
SWEEPERS? IN MY HOUSE?
[ Crying ]
THAT'S ALL RIGHT. THAT'S
OKAY. IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HE'S IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE CUSTODY BATTLE.
THE P.I. WAS TRYING TO
DIG UP SOMETHING ON THE EX
HE COULD USE IN COURT.
THE PLANE TICKET?
TIME FOR LITTLE SUSIE
TO FLY HOME TO MOMMY.
AT LEAST
WE'VE CLEARED HIM.
CLEARED HIM?
HE LIED TO THE CENTRE.
HE NEVER SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT BEING MARRIED.
HE WANTED HIS PRIVACY.
NONE OF THAT JUSTIFIES
WHAT WE DID.
YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT.
YOU'RE LATE.
WELL, I SPENT ALL MORNING
ON THE PHONE WITH A LAWYER.
HE DROPPED MY CASE.
HMM.
I'M SORRY TO HEAR THAT.
MMM.
ARE YOU, MISS PARKER?
THANKS TO YOU, MY DAUGHTER
HASN'T STOPPED CRYING
SINCE LAST NIGHT.
TOMORROW, I HAVE TO SEND HER
BACK TO HER MOTHER, WHICH IS
A PLACE SHE DOESN'T WANT TO GO.
NONE OF THAT HAS ANYTHING
TO DO WITH THE CENTRE.
I WORK HERE.
I SOLD MY SOUL
TO BE IN THIS PLACE.
I'M NOT SELLING HER.
SO DON'T MESS WITH HER.
AND DON'T MESS WITH ME.
HEY, LAMONT,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING TONIGHT?
HEY, CARLSON.
WHAT?
YOU'D BETTER TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS.
WHAT?
UGH. THIS IS
SOME KIND OF HOAX.
NOW, WE KNOW
THE-THE FAX BOMBER
IS IN A HOSPITAL BED.
WELL, I GUESS HE
CHECKED HIMSELF OUT.
LET'S GO.
MAIN ELEVATOR BANKS.
RIGHT OVER THERE.
- COME ON!
- MAYBE WE SHOULD WAIT
FOR BACKUP.
AND MISS OUR CHANCE
TO BE HEROES?
COME ON.
WHOA.
ANOTHER BAD BETTY.
OH, GOD.
LET'S NOT RUSH
INTO ANYTHING HERE.
OH, LOOK.
HE LEFT A NOTE.
CAREFUL. SLOW.
"THIS TIME IT'S REAL."
HMM. SEE?
NO!
[ Bell Dings ]
FORGET IT, CARLSON.
THIS IS THE EXPRESS.
IT WON'T STOP FOR 60 FLOORS.
UH-OH.
SIXTY FLOORS IF WE'RE LUCKY.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- BAROMETRIC DETONATOR.
DESIGNED TO DETONATE
AT ALTITUDES 600 OR 700 FEET.
MY GUESS IS WE'RE GOOD
FOR 45, 50 FLOORS, TOPS.
- WE GOTTA GET OUT OF HERE!
- NO, WE'VE GOTTA
DEFUSE THIS BOMB.
NO, THERE'S NO TIME!
OH, THERE'S PLENTY OF TIME.
IT SHOULD BE EASY FOR YOU.
IT'S JUST LIKE
ALL THE OTHER BOMBS
YOU USED TO MAKE.
HUH?
YOU KNOW,
THE BOMBS YOU DEFUSED...
SO YOU COULD BE A HERO
JUST LIKE YOUR BIG BROTHER WAS?
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
JUST YOUR AVERAGE,
EVERYDAY MISCREANT.
AND SOMEONE WHO DOESN'T THINK
THAT RACHEL NEWTON SHOULD HAVE
LOST HER EYESIGHT...
SO THAT YOU COULD BE
PUT IN THE LIMELIGHT.
NOW, LISTEN TO ME JAROD.
I DID NOT EXPECT
ANYBODY TO GET HURT.
TELL THAT TO CURTIS HARING.
HE WAS THE GUY
YOU TRIED TO BLOW UP,
SO YOU COULD
COVER YOUR TRACKS.
ALL RIGHT! THAT'S ENOUGH!
NOW, COME ON! DEFUSE THIS THING!
NOT SO COOL UNDER PRESSURE
WHEN IT'S NOT YOUR OWN BOMB.
BUT YOU SEE,
PEOPLE THAT PLANT BOMBS,
THEY'RE COWARDS AT HEART.
AND SINCE I PLANTED THIS ONE,
I DON'T WANT TO STICK AROUND
TO WATCH IT BLOW.
- [ Bell Dings ]
- UH-OH.
TWENTIETH FLOOR.
BETTER GET TO WORK.
HOPE YOU CAN FIGURE OUT
WHICH WIRE TO SNIP.
BYE-BYE, HERO.
NO! JAROD!
JAROD!
[ Beeping ]
[ Thudding ]
I GUESS THAT'S WHY
THEY CALL IT THE EXPRESS.
[ Rapid Beeping ]
[ Electronic Male Voice ]
TEN, NINE, EIGHT,
SEVEN, SIX,
FIVE, FOUR,
THREE, TWO,
ONE.
KABOOM.
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST,
CARLSON.
[ Curtis ]
...THAT ALL OF YOU
AT CITY HALL...
WILL PAY EGREGIOUSLY
FOR WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO ME.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU WANT TO SAY THAT?
SAY WHAT?
"EGREGIOUSLY"?
WHO'S WRITING THIS LETTER?
I WAS ONLY MAKING
A SUGGESTION.
IT'S MY LETTER!
ALL RIGHT, ALREADY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
MA!
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT IT MEANS.
DO TOO!
WELL, I CAN SPELL IT.
JUST WRITE IT!
E, G, R--
GET MY DICTIONARY!
I'M NOT GOING
IN THAT SMELLY BASEMENT.
OHH! THERE'S A FLY ON ME.
"EGREGIOUSLY."
A FLY ON ME!
AAH!
[ Knocking ]
[ Jarod ]
MORNING, MAY.
WHERE'S RACHEL?
THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU SHOULD SEE.
TOOK HER ABOUT A HALF HOUR
TO GET DOWN THERE.
BUT SHE GOT THERE
ALL BY HERSELF.
HE'S STILL SEARCHING,
MR. PARKER.
BUT WE WILL
FIND THE LEAK.
I PROMISE YOU THAT.
DID YOU FIND
SOMETHING, ANGELO?
KEEP WORKING.
[ Keyboard Clacking ]
[ Mews ]